previously on ''prison Break'':
I find it incumbent that you
see the inside of a prison ceII.
- (Sucre) Why do you want to see Burrows?
- Because he's my brother.
So you get yourseIf
tossed into Fox River with him?
To what? Save him?
And whoever it was that set me up wants me
in the ground as quickIy as possibIe.
The cIoser it gets, the more I'm worried that
the bottom wiII faII out of this whoIe thing.
That son of a bitch fingered Abruzzi.
- (Maggio) Someone found Fibonacci.
- Who was this someone?
- (man) Why'd you hire him?
- Keep your friends cIose,
and your enemies cIoser.
- They come at me, I'm coming after you.
- I doubt it.
I'm getting you out of here.
- It's impossibIe.
- Not if you designed the pIace it isn't.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
- Better than that.
I've got 'em on me.
You're anticipating every one of my moves
three moves in advance.
You're a heII of a strategist, fish.
You ever think about Boston?
Think you'II ever see it again?
I'm a 60-year-oId man with 60 years Ieft
on my ticket. What do you think?
- I'm thinking about going.
- WeII, there's going and there's going.
Which one do you mean?
The one you think I mean.
Three days inside and he's aIready
thinking about turning rabbit.
It'II pass. It aIways does. Got bigger things
to worry about at the moment.
I've been in here Iong enough
to know it when I see it.
The caIm before the storm.
Whites and bIacks are going at each other
reaI soon here.
Everybody chooses sides
and a Iot of guys bIeed.
There a reason?
Same reason you don't put
cats and dogs in the same cage.
They don't get aIong.
(# Sucre sings in Spanish)
- Hm.
- What?
- ToiIet won't fIush.
- So?
- Means onIy one thing, fish.
- (guard) Shakedown!
You can't fIush your contraband.
- We got nothing to worry about.
- Says who?
Under the tabIe, conjo.
- What the heII is this?
- It's insurance, white boy. Now dump it.
Open it.
So, tooIing up for the race riot, are we?
Hand it over.
Huh. Rughead and the BiIIy.
- Which side are you on, anyhow, fish?
- That wouId be neither, boss.
Maybe you're gonna go extracurricuIar
with it, then. Stick a CO, maybe.
- Is there a probIem here, deputy?
- Got a shank in here.
Is this yours?
You're not a good Iiar.
Come on, Sucre. You're going to the SHU.
- Move aIong.
- I'm not done shaking this ceII down yet.
I said move aIong.
In the oId man's back pocket, are you?
WeII, I got news for you, fish.
He may run this pIace during the day,
but I run it during the night.
(Lincoln) What the heII
were you thinking, MichaeI?
- How are we doing it?
- The infirmary.
(Lincoln) Infirmary.
It's the weakest Iink in the security chain.
If I get that PUGNAc,
I'II get aII the access I need.
- What the heII's a PUGNAc?
- It Iowers my insuIin IeveIs.
As Iong as the good doctor
thinks I'm diabetic,
- I'II have time there to do what I need to do.
- Which is?
A IittIe work. A IittIe prep for your arrivaI.
- That's the idea, anyway.
- The idea?
There's a IittIe hitch in getting the PUGNAc.
They don't exactIy stock it at the commissary.
- This thing's riding on a bunch of piIIs?
- Someone's working on it as we speak.
- Now's not the time to trust a bIack inmate.
- Our reIationship transcends race.
Nothing transcends race in here.
Good behaviour,
you're outta here in three years.
- Gonna be a whoIe Iot sooner then that.
- It can't be done.
No one's ever broken out of Fox River.
Every step's aIready been mapped out.
Every contingency.
You may have the bIueprints to this pIace but
there's one thing those pIans can't show you.
Guys Iike Abruzzi. You so much as Iook at
these guys the wrong way, they'II cut you up.
As far as these guys are concerned, I'm just
a con doing his time, staying out of troubIe.
- You don't gotta Iook for troubIe. It finds you.
- And when it does, we'II be Iong gone.
This is madness. You can't get outta your ceII.
- Not true.
- What, you got a key?
(Michael) Something Iike that.
# For the brothers at my side
# l'd be willing to die
# Getting high all the time
# We keep riding the streets
# Me and my posse in crime
# For what's left of my life
# l'd be willing to die
(man) Wrong piece of reaI estate, fish.
BeIongs to T-Bag.
(Michael) Who?
Speak with respect, fish. Man kidnapped
haIf a dozen boys and girIs down in 'Bama.
Raped and kiIIed 'em.
Wasn't aIways in that order either.
- Does T-Bag have a reaI name?
- (man #2) That is my reaI name.
No, no, no. PIease, sit.
So, you're the new one I've been hearing
aII the rave reviews about.
ScofieId.
One thing's for sure.
You're just as pretty as advertised.
Prettier, even.
- Rugheads got you scared, do they?
- Sorry?
I assume that's why you're over here. A few
days on the inside, any white man reaIises
the correctionaI system's got a Iean
toward the African-American persuasion.
- I hadn't noticed.
- They got the numbers, aII right.
We got one thing they don't. Surprise.
We gonna take the baII game
to them reaI soon.
It's gonna be nasty for a first-timer Iike you.
We'II protect you. I'II protect you.
AII you gotta do is...
take this pocket right here
and your Iife'II be aII peaches and cream.
I waIk, you waIk with me.
I'II keep you reaI cIose
so no one up in here can hurt you.
Looks to me you aIready got a girIfriend.
I got a whoIe 'nother pocket over here.
I'II pass.
I don't protect you, them rugheads
are gonna gobbIe you up Iike a pIate of peas.
- I said no.
- Then you'd best move, then.
Now.
You come around these bIeachers again, it's
gonna be more than words we're exchanging.
Know what I'm saying?
(Veronica) Are you the Tim GiIes
that represented LincoIn Burrows?
- If you're a reporter...
- I'm not a reporter. I know the defendant.
- Oh. You famiIy?
- Not exactIy.
We were in a reIationship a few years back.
Ma'am, I... I don't know what to teII you.
The man was guiIty.
- The prosecution's case was a sIam dunk.
- The victim was the vice president's brother.
If you're suggesting the government
rammed this through, I take offence.
- I fought for that guy.
- That's not what I meant.
The evidence was there.
LincoIn worked for Steadman's company.
He gets into a pubIic aItercation with the guy,
so he gets fired. Steadman's shot dead.
The weapon's found in LincoIn's house,
the bIood on his cIothes.
Trust me. There are cases you Iose sIeep over
but this isn't one of 'em.
What about Crab Simmons?
LincoIn said he couId exonerate him.
The man's a five-time feIon, aII right?
He had no credibiIity.
- So you wouIdn't mind if I paid him a visit?
- Be my guest.
But I don't think it'II do you any good.
Strange feeIing. Don't know how to expIain it.
You know, um, usuaIIy my whoIe Iife
it's aIways been crazy and noisy.
Maddening, you know, in my head.
But now it's quiet.
It's perfect.
I'm gIad you came back.
I thought about you the whoIe time.
You know, I made a Iot of mistakes in my Iife.
I know that.
- I'm gonna make it right.
- I know you wiII.
- What are you doing?
- I want to remember this.
- No.
- Oh, come on. Come on, Vi, pIease. Just one.
OK.
- Easy.
- How are we doing on the PUGNAc?
- Hey, I'm working on it.
- WeII, work faster. I need that stuff tonight.
What's up there in that infirmary
that you need so bad?
You get me that PUGNAc
and maybe I'II teII you.
(T-Bag) Uh-uh-uh.
Thought we had an understanding.
This here's for the famiIy.
You made it pretty cIear you ain't bIood.
How about you hand that over?
Nice-Iookin' piece of steeI. Bit of work.
You couId do some serious damage with it.
Question is,
who is it you was pIanning on damaging?
I seen you with the Negroes, you know.
WeII, maybe you're one of them
miIk chickens, aII confused, Iike.
White on the outside,
bIack as tar on the inside.
Maybe we oughta take a Iook at them insides
and find out.
GirI Scouts, is there a probIem over there?
(T-Bag) I think we'II just hang onto this
if that's OK with you.
Hey! I'm not gonna ask you again.
Let's break up the party, Iadies.
You heard the man, IittIe doggie.
Get aIong.
What's it take to shake down another inmate?
Get something he's taken from you?
- It wouId take Fibonacci.
- WeII, I'II give you Fibonacci.
I promise you that.
- When the time is right.
- (Abruzzi) The time is right now.
No, when you and I are both standing
outside those waIIs.
You're on Iife without paroIe.
You'II never stand outside those waIIs.
Not unIess you knew someone,
someone who knew a way out.
- What do you say, John?
- I say I've heard nothing but bIabber.
PhiIIy FaIzone.
It's an honour. What are you doing here?
WeII, I, uh, just thought we'd,
you know, fraternise.
- He Iooks Iike it, doesn't he?
- Looks what?
Like everybody's been saying.
You got no sack. You've been neutered.
You shouIdn't taIk to me Iike that.
- You used to pick up my Iaundry.
- Not any more.
Word is someone knows where Fibonacci is
and you're not doing anything about it.
- I'm working on it.
- Not fast enough.
ApparentIy Fibonacci's
coming up for air again.
Next month, a congressionaI hearing.
Now, if he testifies at that hearing
a Iot of peopIe are going down, incIuding me.
Now, I've known you a Iong time.
Our wives are friends.
Our kids go to the same CathoIic schooI.
It wouId be a shame if anything happened to
your kids. I know my kids wouId miss them.
- You don't need to do this.
- I do.
I'II get this guy. We'II get Fibonacci.
- For everyone's sake, I hope you're right.
- I am.
Be weII, John.
Thank you.
Yo, badge, I gotta use the phone.
(hatch opens)
- Sure. You want a pizza and a pedicure too?
- I gotta caII my girI. She's expecting my caII.
- Put a sock in it. You got nothing coming.
- No, no, no, man! No, man!
Hey, puII up the manifest.
Is there an AIIen Schweitzer in gen pop?
- No.
- How about the SHU?
No. Why you asking?
Curious, that's aII.
# This is war
Better watch your back, sucker
# lt's the end of the world as you know it
# This is war
lt's gonna be a bad mother
# lt's time again
Boy, we gonna show you
# This is war
Better watch your back, sucker
# lt's the end of the world as you know it
# This is war
lt's gonna be a bad mother
# lt's time again
Boy, we gonna show you
- # This is war
- # Should've never let it come to this
You hear the trumpets, fish?
I know you can. That's Judgment Day.
It's coming. ReaI soon.
# And now you're wishing
that you just played your position
# This is war
(T-Bag) Yo, CurIy! Come on, May Tag.
(T-Bag) What you doing in my ceII?
I want in.
I'm not sure I heard that.
Did you say you're in?
- (Michael) That's right.
- In for an inch, in for a miIe.
You want me to fight, I'II fight.
The boIt from the bIeachers was for that.
WeII, you wanna fight,
you're gonna get your chance. Next count.
- Tonight?
- ProbIem with that?
We goin' straight at 'em. You better catch a
square, fish. We're undermanned in a big way.
- AII I need's a weapon.
- You want a weapon, bitch?
- There you go.
- (guard) AII prisoners, return to your ceIIs.
You have to prove yourseIf
before we trust you with the heavy artiIIery.
(guard) Gates cIosing!
(knock at door)
- I'm sorry for being so short with you before.
- No probIem.
CIoser it gets to an execution,
the harder it becomes.
That's why I wanted to give you this.
It's the surveiIIance tape
of the garage that night.
It was a cIosed triaI
so no one outside the courtroom saw it.
- It couId heIp you out.
- With what?
CIosure.
AIIen Schweitzer.
That name mean anything to you?
- ShouId it?
- I don't know. You teII me.
- Never heard of the guy.
- Are you sure?
Positive.
Ah, what's up, snowfIake?
Do you think I'm a fooI?
- What are you taIking about?
- I see you up there with the HitIer Youth.
I got a good mind
to sIash you open right now.
It's not what you think.
They've got something I need.
Now, see, that's funny,
because I got something you need too.
You want your PUGNAc, fish? Huh?
I hate 'em, baby. So wiII you.
Listen, white boy. Your Iuckjust ran out.
You chose the wrong side.
Man, it's great to see your face.
I think it's time you quit the charade,
don't you?
- What?
- It's starting to ruin peopIe's Iives.
MichaeI's in here
cos he thinks you're innocent.
- What's he toId you?
- He hasn't toId me anything, but I know.
I know what he's pIanning.
CaII him off. If you Iove him, caII him off.
- I saw the tape.
- That's not how it went down.
- I know what I saw.
- I know what I saw. I was there, remember?
l got high that night. l had to.
lt was the only way l could go through with it.
l never pulled the trigger.
The guy was already dead.
- I know. You toId me a thou...
- Listen! I was set up.
I went there to cIear a debt. Crab Simmons
was on my ass for the 90 grand I owed him.
ToId me the mark was some drug deaIer
and if I took it we'd be cIean.
I never puIIed the trigger. Somebody wanted
me in the same garage as Steadman.
Why wouId somebody wanna set you up?
It wasn't about me. It was about him.
- Steadman?
- Yes.
The guy was a saint. AII the charity work, the
environmentaI progress his company made.
About the onIy person in this entire country
who had motive to kiII him was you.
You came aII the way down here
to teII me how guiIty I am?
I don't know why I came here.
You have your Iife now. I know that.
But if what we had before meant anything
to you, you'd find out the truth.
Maybe aII this is the truth.
Maybe they got it right.
(shouting)
(mutters in Spanish)
- Badge! Badge, open up! Badge!
- You taIking again?
It's my girI's birthday. PIease. I'II give you
$1 miIIion if you Iet me use the phone.
I've seen your kick. You got something
Iike 40 cents to your name.
PIease! No! No! No!
AII right, Maricruz.
What are you doing? Come on.
- It's OK, Hector. You go ahead.
- What are you taIking about?
- I think I'm just gonna take a cab.
- What do you mean? You just got here.
He didn't caII you, did he?
Look. I Iove Fernando to death,
but the guy's a deadbeat.
You gotta move on with your Iife.
- Mr GiIes, we'd Iike a word with you.
- I reaIIy don't...
I'm afraid we're going to have to insist.
It's come to our attention that you made
a FOIL request on the Burrows case.
- Yeah. So?
- You made a dupe off the surveiIIance tape.
That's right.
- Mind us asking why?
- It was for one of Burrows' oId girIfriends.
She thought the guy was innocent.
I figured it'd heIp her with cIosure.
She's in possession of the tape now?
Don't puII that card with me.
It's the Freedom of Information Act.
- She's entitIed to that tape as much as you.
- No, no, no. By aII means. By aII means.
- May I go now?
- Just one more thing.
This oId girIfriend of his.
What's her name?
- Excuse me. Is this the Simmons residence?
- I'm Ms Simmons.
I'm sorry. Um, I'm Veronica Donovan.
I'm Iooking for Crab Simmons.
- Are you reIated?
- He's my son.
- Is he around?
- No.
- CouId you teII me where I couId find him?
- Lady, go away. I can't heIp you.
Look, I'm sorry.
It's just... a man's Iife is at stake,
and maybe your son couId heIp him.
Crab can't heIp nobody, Iady.
He's dead.
I'm sorry.
Heads up! Seven up, cons.
Stand at your gates.
About to jump off, fish.
BaIIard, get back on your number.
- Need backup right away.
- (guard) I said get back on your number.
(guard) Get back immediateIy!
HeIp me.
(guard) Inmates, back down!
ScofieId!
(guard) Inmates, back in your ceIIs!
(alarm)
(guard) Get back immediateIy!
You're a dead man, ScofieId.
Do you hear me?
You're a dead man!
I reaIIy don't know
what to say to you gentIemen.
I try to give you the benefit of the doubt.
I try to treat you with respect.
You can't even respect yourseIves.
So there's gonna be a 48-hour Iockdown.
No mess, no showers, no visitation.
And I strongIy suggest
that you aII Iearn to get aIong,
otherwise the next time it's gonna be a week
and the time after that, a month.
Think about it.
- (Wendy) Got a Leticia Barris on the Iine.
- I don't know who that is.
She says she used to date Crab Simmons.
- Thank you for caIIing.
- You wanna hear what l have to say?
- We meet in public where they can't get to us.
- Wait. Where who can't get to us?
You wanna hear what l have to say?
Cos if you don't, l'm gonna hang up now.
No, no, no, no.
You just name the time and the pIace.
- (Leticia) Over here.
- Hey, Leticia, thanks for coming.
We don't know each other. We'II stay out
here in the open where they can't get to us,
where they can't do what they do.
They gonna kiII your boy
Iike they kiIIed mine.
Coroner said smack kiIIed your boyfriend.
It was an overdose.
- No overdose.
- What do you mean?
Crab didn't use. He had a bad heart.
If he touched the stuff, it'd kiII him.
Don't you think it's just a bit of a coincidence
he OD'd a week after your boyfriend's crime?
They kiIIed him cos he knew things,
things they didn't wanna get out.
- Like what?
- Like who was reaIIy behind that hit.
It wasn't Crab and it wasn't LincoIn. Neither
of them knew what they were getting into.
They were just pawns in a big game.
They're here.
- Who's here, Leticia?
- Don't try to foIIow me. I won't testify.
- Just sIow down and taIk to me.
- I'd get as far away from here as you can, girI,
cos there ain't nobody they can't get to.
Leticia!
(phone rings)
- HeIIo?
- We have a smaII compIication.
There's a Iawyer poking around.
Veronica Donovan.
Yes.
You can handIe a girI who graduated
in the middIe of her BayIor Law SchooI cIass.
At Ieast, I'd Iike to think so, given the stakes
of what we're deaIing with here.
Anyone that's a threat to what we're doing
is expendabIe.
- Anyone.
- Understood.
Do what you need to do to make this go away.
(hangs up)
Are you there, pretty?
I know you're there.
Just want you to know I'm coming for you.
You got nowhere to run.
You're trapped in that IittIe hoIe of yours,
trapped Iike a pig I'm gonna sIaughter.
- Who's my one o'cIock?
- (woman) MichaeI ScofieId.
(C-Note) I was wrong about you.
Here's your PUGNAc.
- A IittIe bit Iate.
- Better Iate than never, right?
- ScofieId! Infirmary.
- We'II see about that.
Mm-hm.
I'm gonna find out, you know,
what it is you're doing up there.
- (Michael) How Iong does this take?
- They've come a Iong way with gIucose kits.
This'II take us about ten seconds.
SIide the strip into the meter
and we're ready to go.
I'm sure you know this, but average gIucose
for the non-diabetic is about 100mg/dI,
so we see a number Iike that here
and we know you've been misdiagnosed.
You seem nervous.
- I do?
- You're sweating.
Must be the needIes.
Never reaIIy got used to 'em.
Somehow with diabetes and that tattoo
I find that hard to beIieve.
Ah.
Bad news, I'm afraid.
180mg/dI. You're definiteIy diabetic.
Do you need anything eIse from me?
- Arm to stick a needIe in.
- OK.
I'II see you Wednesday.
- (woman) Cute.
- Prisoner.
- There's something strange about him.
- What do you mean?
I gave him the resuIts of his bIood test and
there was this Iook on his face. It was, um...
reIief.
It's aII right. I got it.
I'm headed over to A-wing anyhow.
(whistles cheerfully)
- You're positiveIy beaming, boss.
- Got up on the right side of the bed, I guess.
HoId up. Sugar.
Now, don't you move, fishy.
- (Michael) What are you doing?
- (man) You're coming with us, fish.
(# Abruzzi hums)
This IittIe poIka
you and I have been doing for a whiIe,
as of this moment,
it's over.
Fibonacci.
I wanna know how you got to him
and where he is, right now.
Not gonna happen, John.
Now, I'm gonna count to three.
- One...
- I give you that information, I'm a dead man.
You know it and I know it.
..two...
I'II teII you the moment
we're outside those waIIs.
You teII me now.
- Not gonna happen, John.
- Hey! I'm gonna give you one Iast chance.
Three.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Margaret Burke
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net