SCOFIELD: Previously on Prison Break.
LINCOLN: Did you see the guy
in the viewing room?
SCOFIELD: No.
It was Dad.
I know that guy.
KATIE: What is it?
It was fused into MichaeI ScofieId's skin.
-Where'd it come from?
-As far as I can teII, a guard's uniform.
SUCRE: What"s wrong?
The bIueprints,
the ones we need to get
from the psych ward to the infirmary,
they're gone.
Hey, that's Iooking good.
You're making some reaI progress.
The pIaster adds a Iot of weight.
I may have to add reinforcements.
Whatever it takes, as Iong as you get done
in time for the anniversary.
It'II be done. HoId this.
You know, the Shah Ioved his Taj so much
that he buiIt another tempIe
just Iike it on the other side of the river.
It was an absoIute mirror image.
Except it was darker,
it was Iike a bIack Taj MahaI.
Never heard of it.
WeII, that's 'cause it was never compIeted.
He was overthrown by his favorite son
before he couId finish it.
-Sounds Iike a myth.
-No, it's 100¡ã/¡£ true.
I think.
Excuse me, Warden.
Dr. Tancredi is here to see you.
Thank you.
POPE: Adams, pIease escort Mr. ScofieId
back to his ceII.
-Doctor, what can I do for you?
-ActuaIIy, it's about ScofieId, sir.
Come in.
-What about ScofieId?
-The burn on his back is fairIy serious.
He seems to be recovering.
At first, I assumed
he was being assauIted by another inmate,
but I found this embedded
in the skin on his back.
-What's this?
-It's fabric.
Came from a guard's uniform.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to remember those bIueprints,
what we Iost to the burn.
Without them,
we'II never be abIe to navigate those pipes
beneath psych ward.
-Any Iuck?
-No.
I spent a Iot of time
studying those bIueprints,
tracing them night after night,
considering every possible route
to the infirmary,
It's Iike trying to take a test
you studied for 10 years ago.
(CELL GATES BUZZING)
PI!
-How do they get Iike that, I got no idea.
-I do.
-Tugging on too many pockets.
-She tug on your pocket?
I may be sociaI, but that's
the boundary Iine even I won't cross.
So how about it, Fish?
When we roIIing out?
-One hiccup Ieft, but I'm working on it.
-Yeah, and what is that?
Our road map's
a IittIe incompIete at the moment.
I don't get it.
Why not just go down there again?
'Cause, one, I don't have
the guard's uniform anymore,
which means I can't get across the yard
or past the orderIy.
And two, even if I did,
it's a mess down there.
I need this.
-You think you're gonna remember it?
-Not with you hounding me.
Time to wrap it up.
We're going to
have you start exterminating.
-We're not done in here.
-WeII, you Iook done to me.
No, CO,
we stiII got the carpet to do, man.
No, BeIIick is going to bring
professionaIs in to do that.
Wants the job done right.
-When's that going to happen?
-Tomorrow.
We got a reaI probIem on our hands,
don't we?
Rug monkeys gonna come in here,
tear up that carpet
and that hoIe's gonna be smiIing up
at them.
-We'II have to fiII it in.
-We just dug that bitch.
AII we need is a piece of pIywood
and a coupIe inches of that
fast-setting concrete on top of it.
The carpet guys wiII never know
there's anything beneath it.
And the night we break out,
we'II just smash through
with a sIedgehammer.
WeII, okay. Let's get on it.
We've onIy got a coupIe hours
to get this thing done.
Hey, Tweener. You met Avocado?
Yo, what's up?
Lookit. She's just a baby.
Hit road.
Have a seat.
So...
ScofieId.
What's the 91 1?
It's 41 1, and I don't know, man.
I ain't up in his car.
You know,
Avocado's Iooking for a new ceIIie.
Boss, come on, man,
I'm trying to break bread with the man,
but I can't get jack
unIess I can get to the tabIe.
You know what I'm saying?
ScofieId got his own peeps up in PI.
He don't need me.
-How Iong this stuff take to dry?
-One, two hours.
Fire on the Iine.
This pIace is sweet.
I heard we're getting sateIIite.
-Yeah, aII the porn you can watch, boss.
-Good, good.
You know, you girIs
have done such a good job,
I thought you couId use
an extra pair of hands on the crew.
(WHISTLES )
What's up?
(T-BAG HUMMING)
Hey, man, Iook at my brush.
It's aII sticking together.
Somebody needs to go cIean them out.
According to rank, that wouId be you.
What do I gotta do?
There's a hose out by the shed in the yard.
You can use that.
CIean those, too.
AII right.
Sorry I busted up the party, yo.
Who is he?
For your purposes, aII you need to know
is that man in the photo
used to work for the Company.
He went rogue.
And how's he invoIved in this situation?
He's Burrows' father.
Wait, wait, wait.
You picked the son of a Company man
to be our patsy? Did the Company know?
The Company did know.
That was the whoIe point.
How about you eIaborate on that?
How about you
stop with aII the questions?
You are a gIorified bodyguard, that's it.
Your job's to be seen, not to be heard.
Is that understood?
-How cIose are we?
-Oh, we're good to go, baby.
Got another badge.
What is this, happy hour?
ScofieId? Pope wants to see you.
The rest of you round up,
you're done in here.
Hey, CO Patterson said
we had tiII the end of the day to finish up.
And I say you're done.
There's a coupIe hours of work
I want done in the yard before sundown.
Come on, Iet's go.
-We're dead.
-We're not. I'II get it done.
-It's gotta be done tonight.
-I said I'II get it done.
ScofieId, Pope's waiting.
Hey, Linc.
You going to Iet me out?
No, Linc, just came to Iet you know
they set a new date.
DOC refiIed aII the paperwork.
Execution's a week from Friday
at midnight.
You going to Iet me out in the yard
or what?
UnIess I hear it from the Pope himseIf,
I can't do it. I'm sorry.
Come on, man, 10 minutes.
That's aII I'm asking.
Ten minutes.
I'm sorry.
Some guy just waIks into the courtroom,
drops off some medicaI records,
LincoIn gets a stay of execution,
then ''poof,'' he disappears into the coId.
Who do you think it couId be,
some anti-death penaIty fanatic?
Oh, come on, in this case, I doubt it.
But without a name or a paper traiI,
we got no way of getting to him.
So once again we have nothing.
I wouIdn't exactIy caII
a two-week stay nothing, okay?
It's more than we had yesterday.
Can I ask you a question?
Do you reaIIy think that
you're going to get to the bottom of this?
That they'II Iet you
get to the bottom of this?
These guys don't exist.
You go after them with the Iaw,
and they'II just use it against you.
We're doing the best we can, okay?
Law's the onIy way we're going
to bring them to justice, LJ.
They gunned my mother down, man.
You think I give a damn about justice?
I want them.
I wanna do to them what they did to me.
Come on, LJ.
It's for the courts to decide, not us.
Look, they're going to sIip up, okay?
They're going to Ieave a piece of evidence
that can't be refuted.
And we're going to be waiting
to naiI them when they do.
Maybe they aIready sIipped up.
Up at the cabin, at the weII.
Quinn.
-Somebody covered it up.
-They must have come and gotten him.
There's onIy one way to find out.
Look, there's his ceII phone.
Easy.
Okay, a IittIe Iower!
A IittIe more.
Okay, I got it.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
PuII me up.
WouId you give us a minute, Gary?
MichaeI, I want you to be
absoIuteIy honest with me.
Dr. Tancredi found this
embedded in your fIesh
when she was treating you.
ApparentIy, it came
from a guard's uniform.
Have you been assauIted by an officer?
MichaeI, MichaeI,
I need an answer.
This is not about
sticking to the inmates' code anymore.
This is about officer misconduct.
That's my responsibiIity.
You wouIdn't want to see me
Iose my job now, wouId you?
No, of course not. You have been
very good to me and my brother.
Then I need to know
where you got that burn. Right now.
Otherwise, your ass is going to soIitary.
You understand?
It's your choice.
Don't... Hey, pIease, Iisten to me.
-CooI down!
-Listen to me, don't do this!
Don't do this!
MichaeI!
No!
MichaeI?
-Linc?
-What the heII are you doing in here?
Linc, we're in a Iot of troubIe now.
What happened?
The Pope asked some questions
that I couIdn't answer.
About what?
He's got proof that I was
where I wasn't supposed to be.
He doesn't know it, but sooner or Iater
he's going to put the whoIe thing together.
There's no way out of this.
Yeah, there is.
-You just got to keep the faith.
-No.
I put my bIood into this,
and it's coming apart.
Listen to me.
The whoIe point of soIitary is to break you,
make you crazy.
You got to keep strong, you hear me?
Don't Iet them break you.
I put my bIood into this.
Look, baby, I'm so sorry it took me so Iong
to get back to you.
Turns out that our division is not
getting mobiIized for a coupIe more days.
When I didn't hear from you,
I didn't know what to think, baby.
I got so worried. I started
watching the news, Iooking for casuaIties.
I'm so sorry about aII this.
You gotta beIieve that.
I started caIIing
the rear detachment office,
asking if there was some sort of probIem
with the 1 17th.
No.
There"s not a problem with the 1 1 7th,
We"re coming back, lt"s a snafu, that"s all,
A couple more days,
and we"ll be on those hops, baby,
That's not what
the rear detachment officer said.
He said the 1 1 7th wasn"t coming home
for another six months,
What? No. That can't be right.
That's what he said.
You know what it is?
It's because we're transpo.
You know, technicaIIy
we're on a Ioan-out from the 140th.
I mean, that's why he said that.
-The 140th?
-Yeah, yeah.
It's just a few more days.
That"s all, l mean,
you don't need to go caIIing anyone.
l"ll be back, okay?
I wiII caII you
as soon as I know the exact date.
Okay?
-l love you,
-I Iove you.
-MichaeI's in the SHU.
-Oh, God, the hits just keep coming!
Last thing we wanna do now
is panic, feIIas.
Oh, it's panic time, oId head.
We got an unfinished hoIe
in that room over there
that ScofieId was supposed to fiII tonight.
Come tomorrow 8:00 a.m.,
they rip up that carpet, our game is over.
UnIess someone eIse fiIIs it.
That's right, papi,
You're the onIy one
with a toiIet open to the outside worId.
You're saying
I go out there by myseIf tonight?
-That's exactIy what we're saying.
-Are you kidding? That's impossibIe.
Look, I don't wanna hear impossibIe
from you right now!
I got peopIe waiting on me,
peopIe that I'm gonna Iose,
unIess you man up
and get some cojones, comprende?
That's easy for you to say, pendejo,
It ain't your ass on the Iine.
AII of our asses are on the Iine.
And you're the onIy cat
that can do something about it.
Yeah, maybe I can get out of my ceII.
And maybe
I can get into the guards' room.
But even if I do, and I fiII that hoIe in,
I'II stiII be in that room.
I'II be seaIed in. There's no way out.
-ScofieId must've had a way.
-He did.
The grate at the saIIy port.
Oh, that's right. The one out there
in the middIe of the open?
Yeah, so you better Iace up, amigo,
'cause you're gonna have to
make a run for it.
That's 10 years on my bid if I get caught.
Then you better figure out a way
not to get caught.
GUARD: Line it up!
Tonight, primo, It's gotta be tonight.
MichaeI. You okay?
What you doing?
I'm trying to remember
what's beneath psych ward.
You're thinking about the wrong thing.
You got to think about
how to get out of here.
MichaeI.
Man, come on. TaIk to me.
Uh-uh.
AbsoIuteIy not.
If I'm gonna be the one doing that running,
you gotta do some Iifting, too.
I mean, you know
what you're asking of me?
You gotta do it for the team.
Hey, sister. Your bIoomers are showing.
They aren't showing, baby,
they're fIying. ProudIy.
I take it you are a party girI.
(DOOR CLOSES )
-LJ? Come on, we're Ieaving.
-Okay.
We get Quinn's phone powered up and
it couId be a goId mine of information.
-No. Doesn't fit.
-We just need to find the right adapter.
What about Quinn?
Are we just gonna Ieave him here?
You mean the guy
who shot me in the back?
Yeah, we're just gonna Ieave him here.
You teII anyone about this, and I...
Capitol Hill saw
its first deadlock of the term
on the Senate floor this morning,
The hotly contested energy bill
ended up in a 50-50 tie,
That means it will now be up to
Vice President Reynolds
to cast the deciding vote,
I know I sound Iike a broken record,
but you work too hard.
You need to get out,
hang out with your friends more.
What about men?
If this is your expos¨¦ on my sociaI Iife,
it's about to be a reaI sad one.
I...
I've had some bad Iuck
when it comes to reIationships.
You had bad Iuck or you had bad boys?
I think I've managed to have
a IittIe of both.
Yeah, you know, you're right.
I don't tend to go for the nice guys.
I Iike the ones
with the deep-seated emotionaI issues
I can internaIize and make my own.
Mmm-hmm. Like ScofieId?
-Nope, not Iike ScofieId.
-Don't Iie to me.
Every time he comes in for his shot,
you spend 20 minutes
roIIing up his sIeeve.
You know what? I think he's interesting.
And I think he's attractive,
but he's stiII an inmate.
I can promise you one thing.
And that's that you wiII never see
anything happen
between me and an inmate.
MichaeI.
(MUMBLING) I put my bIood into this.
What? What'd you say?
I put my bIood into this.
(GRUNTING)
(CHATTERING ON RADIO)
(BUCKET CLATTERING)
GUARD: Stop! Freeze right there!
Get down on your knees!
-PIease don't shoot! Don't shoot!
-Freeze right there!
(ALARM BLARING)
You know the state of IIIinois
doesn't Iook too kindIy upon prisoners
who try to escape.
Charges are fiIed,
you get sent back to county
for three months.
Come back here with 10 more years
added to your bid.
-I wasn't trying to escape.
-Sure you weren't.
You were just out there
howIing at the moon.
If I were you,
I'd better start taIking, mano,
I stayed out after yard today.
I waited under the bIeachers
untiI it got dark.
Something was gonna come
over the waIIs.
Drugs is aImost as bad as escape.
Last guy had heroin sIingshot
over the waII
got a nickeI added to his bid.
-It wasn't drugs.
-Then what the heII was it?
Frisk him !
What do we have here?
A pair of grunds?
You risked going to the SHU
for a pair of grunds?
HeII, you risked adding extra time
to your bid, aII for a pair of panties?
My girI just wanted me to know
she was thinking about me, boss.
You got a reaI beefer on your hands,
don't you?
I know, boss.
It's the dumbest thing I've ever done.
I'm just scared that being here,
I'm gonna Iose her.
-He did it for Iove.
-Then you understand.
Yeah, sure, Sucre. I understand.
Don't Iet me catch you aIone
next time, okay?
-Sucre!
-Sink?
Sucre.
-Where's MichaeI?
-Other side of you.
SUCRE: MichaeI! MichaeI!
MichaeI!
MichaeI, come on.
Badge!
(BANGING)
Yeah?
Check out my brother.
He's not responding.
-What?
-ScofieId. Check him out.
He's not responding. PIease.
(DOOR OPENS )
ScofieId.
-I need a medic in 12 now. I repeat, now.
-What?
There's an eIectronics store
on Eighth Avenue. Grab his phone.
We'II be back in 10 minutes.
Stay on the couch.
(PHONE RINGS )
KRAVECKI: (ON MACHINE) Hi,
you"ve reached Owen Kravecki,
l can"t come to the phone right now,
You reaIIy think you're gonna get
to four buttons before I get to one?
Leave a message, and l"ll return your call,
Thanks, Have a great day,
Light on 12.
WouId you wait outside, pIease?
MichaeI?
Okay, you're going to feeI my fingers
on your wrist.
Come on, I need your eyes.
I'm going to take a Iook at that hand.
You're going to be okay.
-Sucre got...
-I heard.
Papi better had did us right, man.
Hope he had enough time.
Looks Iike we're about to find out.
REYNOLDS: Make it fast,
I thought we picked
LincoIn Burrows off the street
because he was some IowIife
who couIdn't defend himseIf.
Now I Iearn it's aII about his father,
some oId spook
that the Company"s
trying to settle a score with?
WeII, fortunateIy for us,
the Company's agenda and our agenda
have the same endgame.
Caroline, l"ve been doing this for 15 years,
and it's never been about anything
other than you, your famiIy,
and most importantIy, this country.
Now, l need to know
who l"m working for here,
You are working for me.
Promise me that.
I promise you, PauI. I got to go now.
And to what do I owe this honor?
To the vote on the Senate fIoor
this afternoon.
Look, I get it.
The vote comes down to me, I vote ''no.''
It'II get done.
WeII, actuaIIy, we are going to need you
to vote ''yes'' on this one.
I want to make sure I heard you straight.
You want me to vote
on the environmentaIists' side?
This isn't about a vote.
This is about you
and how you Iook to voters.
Now, we have a nation that is growing
increasingIy hungry for aIternate energy.
So if you come across as more centrist,
you'II appeaI to the broader swath
of the eIectorate,
the very peopIe
who wiII get you eIected next year.
Besides, once that biII
hits the President's desk, he'II veto it.
Then we'II get preciseIy what
we aIways wanted anyway, won't we?
You probabIy don't have
a hair on your body, do you?
Just back your punk ass up.
Hey, Tweener! Get over here.
Looks Iike Avocado
has taken a shine to you.
-I couId set you up as ceIIies if you want.
-Stop it, aII right?
I got something for you this time.
ScofieId and his boys,
they're up to something.
How about being a IittIe more specific?
Whatever it is, it's got to do
with that room they're fixing.
Something to do with the carpet.
Excuse me, feIIas.
Out of the way!
(DOOR BUZZES )
MichaeI!
MichaeI! MichaeI!
He's totaIIy non-responsive,
so start him on chIorpromazine.
And I beIieve he's in danger
of a psychotic break.
I want you to notify me immediateIy
if and when that happens.
GUARD: AII right.
SARA: Thank you.
Come on.
Come this way.
Come on. Here you go.
Watch your step.
CIean him up.
(DOOR OPENING)
(GUN CLICKING)
You scared me.
Put it down. You're not a kiIIer.
You don't want to make
any rash mistakes here, LJ.
-Don't move!
-Go easy, go easy...
Shut up!
LJ, there's other ways out of this,
you know, okay?
I can heIp you beat this rap,
but if you puII that trigger,
you reaIIy wiII be a kiIIer,
and then I can't heIp you, okay?
I'm government, LJ.
There's a Iot of things I can do for you.
The onIy thing you can do for me is die!
Drop your weapon!
I said drop your weapon!
Guess you're going to have to take
a rain check on that one, huh?
COP: Drop the gun now!
No. I did what you said.
BELLICK: You brought me a piIe of crap.
There was nothing there.
Boss, come on, man.
I just need some more time.
You had your time.
You're a waste of my fries.
Open on 88!
Boss, come on, man!
(DOOR BUZZING)
Dude, just give me another try.
CIose on 88!
Have at it.
Boss.
Boss!
COP: You're Iucky.
Kid's got a warrant for doubIe homicide.
-Oh, dear. Are you serious?
-Did you have any prior contact with him?
-Any idea why he chose your house?
-No, none.
I mean, he was screaming something Iike,
''You kiIIed my mom,''
and going on
about me being a government agent, and...
I don't know, it just seemed Iike that kid
was on drugs or something.
What do you do for a Iiving, Mr. Kravecki?
I'm a regionaI saIes manager
for a dehydrated meat distributor.
-What, you mean Iike jerky?
-Yes.
-You a fan?
-What kind?
BuffaIo.
Have some. ReaIIy.
I'm swimming in the stuff.
One hour tiII Iunch.
So, what's the probIem?
You're Iooking at it.
ABRUZZI: What, Haywire?
-Yep. He's my new ceIImate.
They think I have schizoaffective disorder
with bipoIar tendencies.
Your tattoos.
What about them?
-What are they of?
-They're just tattoos.
The man's got a maze on his skin.
Why wouId he do that?
Why wouId he put a maze on his skin?
It's a pathway.
Where does it Iead?
HeIIo, roomie.
You were right about my tattoo.
It is a path, just Iike you thought.
And I need you to remember
when you saw it, Haywire.
I need you to remember
what it Iooked Iike.
Do you think you can do that for me?
Who are you?
www.tvsubtitles.net