My name is Michael Scofield,
My brother is facing the electric chair,
framed for a crime he didn"t commit,
What is it about this case
that the Secret Service is so interested in?
The man kiIIed
the Vice President's brother.
SCOFIELD: After his appeals
were exhausted,
there was only one way to get him out,
(GUN FIRING)
OFFICER: (ON P.A. SYSTEM)
This is the police,
Put down your weapon,
MichaeI?
I'm getting you out of here.
-It's impossibIe.
-Not if you designed the pIace, it isn't.
-You've seen the bIueprints.
-Better than that.
I've got them on me.
SCOFIELD: l"ve been at Fox River
nearly a month now,
ln that time, l"ve assembled
a group that has all the resources
we need to not only break out,
but to stay out,
I'm MichaeI, by the way.
-Dr. Tancredi...
-Tancredi Iike the Governor?
SCOFIELD: While we dig on the inside,
our lawyer searches for the truth
on the outside,
(RINGING)
MAN: l have information that will lead
to the exoneration of Lincoln Burrows,
Somebody on the inside
cIaims they can exonerate LincoIn.
Someone's been taIking.
Anyone that's a threat is expendabIe.
They're ready for you,
Madam Vice President.
(GUN FIRING)
SCOFIELD: 24 hours from now,
my brother is scheduled to die,
But the way l see it, 24 hours from now,
we"ll be out of the country,
He's there.
(CLANGING)
It can't be done.
We're not getting out of here.
UnfortunateIy, pretty,
that ain't an option.
You are gonna get us out of here.
UnIess you're gonna use your shank
to take out the pipe, put it away.
I'm gonna put it in your neck,
you don't get us out of here.
-Bring it down a peg, T-Bag.
-Shut your mouth!
Remember, pretty,
I am serving Iife pIus one.
So if I get busted for attempted escape,
I'm gonna throw in a homicide,
no probIem.
That's Iike a parking ticket to me.
(BANGING)
You okay?
-FeIt sick again.
-Yeah, you took your IV's out.
Yeah, I didn't want to throw up
on the fIoor, so I just came to the drain.
Just Iet me waIk this off. I'II be fine.
LincoIn, there is no reason
for you to be here if your IV isn't in.
-Everything aII right in here?
-It's fine.
Why isn't he cuffed to the tabIe?
What's he gonna do, steaI a cotton baII?
Can't have him waIking around, Doc.
You know that.
(KEYS JINGLING)
What was that?
C.O.: Put your wrist out.
You gonna turn this into something?
I'm not gonna say it again.
Put your wrist out.
Hey, Keith, come check this out!
Keith?
We got to go. Now. Give me the rope.
Give me the rope now!
Tie that off.
Let's just stay here, okay?
WESTMORELAND: Okay, I'm down.
We gotta go, MichaeI.
Get down. Let's go.
-Did it break off or did someone break it?
-I don't know.
Here's the other haIf.
Hey, hey.
-What's up, Brad?
-Heading over to Sharkey's.
It's two-for Tuesday. Wanna hoist a few?
Man, I'd Iove to, but my wife is
cooking dinner and I toId her I'd be home.
Wuss. Anybody eIse?
Suit yourseIves.
(MEN CHATTERING)
Ain't none of the Sheetrock
in front of the break room been touched.
-The PI's are Ietting it dry out.
-StiII?
WestmoreIand!
WESTMORELAND: I'm caught
on something.
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Stay there! Stay down there!
-Why was this door Iocked?
-It wasn't Iocked, boss.
The fan kept pushing it open.
So we just had to wedge it cIosed.
You've been in here aII night
not doing a damn thing.
The room is stiII wet, boss.
There's nothing we couId do.
It's not Iike we've been having a picnic.
Bunch of shiftIess, no-good convicts.
You got something to say, ScofieId?
Wrap it up.
And aII four of you,
get your asses back to the bIock.
Hey!
Get these nitwits back to the ceII bIock.
You seem to be one Iight.
Right here, boss.
No, no. No way!
I shouId be haIfway
to seeing my famiIy right now!
Let's go.
Now!
C.O.: Keep it moving. Move it.
Go, Iadies.
Do you think he knows?
LincoIn?
REPORTER: I'm here with Henry Pope,
who is the warden of Fox River Penitentiary
where LincoIn Burrows is scheduIed to die
by eIectrocution at 12:01 a.m. tomorrow.
Warden Pope, can you teII me what's
gonna happen in the next few hours?
There are strict
Department of Corrections guideIines
that govern every aspect of an execution.
Measures taken to make sure that
the process goes as smoothIy as possibIe.
Such as?
The correctionaI officers wiII do
a waIkthrough,
we'II review the Iist of witnesses,
the chair wiII be checked and rechecked
to make sure there's no probIem.
And Mr. Burrows himseIf.
Have you spoken with him?
What are his thoughts
in these finaI hours?
I'd say that's between him and his God.
And maybe the Governor.
I understand Burrows' attorneys
are going to request a stay.
I wish them the best of Iuck.
Does that mean you beIieve he's innocent?
It means...
I beIieve in the process
but I don't reIish the prospect of
taking another man's Iife.
Whether it's just or not,
there's no joy that Iies before us today.
Okay, thank you very much, Warden,
And we will be here with you
throughout the night
watching and waiting to see
if Lincoln Burrows does in fact become
only the 13th person to be executed
in the state of lllinois since 1976,
(DOOR BUZZING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
(SIGHING)
Just so you got one Iess thing
to worry about,
I want you to know I ain't mad at you.
Thank you.
-How Iong untiI...
-16 hours.
Are his Iawyers making any progress?
Is there stiII a chance with that?
No. There's onIy one person
who can reaIIy stop this execution.
Hey.
I need to see my brother. Just to taIk.
For five minutes.
Yeah. Yeah. I'II try.
(SIGHING)
I'm sorry. I'm toId
that you have to wait untiI finaI visitation.
WouId you taIk to your father
for me, pIease?
BeIieve me, my father knows
where I stand on the death penaIty
-and I'm just as cIear on his...
-Sara... Dr. Tancredi, I'm sorry.
This isn't about the moraIity
of the death penaIty. This is...
This is about kiIIing an innocent man,
my brother,
and sureIy your father
can't be in favor of that.
Just taIk to LincoIn's attorneys,
just for an hour,
and I swear to God
you'II be convinced of his innocence.
MichaeI,
I wouId pick up the phone right now
if I thought there was any chance
that I couId make a difference,
but you have to understand,
I'm the Iast person in the worId
that my father Iistens to.
He hates what I do,
he hates what I beIieve in.
And if I'm the one asking for cIemency
for your brother, your brother won't get it.
I'm sorry.
Look, if Terrence Steadman
is stiII aIive, LyIe,
then it can't be Terrence Steadman
buried in the ground.
Yeah, but a secret informant
cIaims that Steadman is stiII aIive?
I don't know, Nick.
It aII sounds pretty far-fetched.
You're his cIerk, just get us on the docket.
Nick, you're asking him
to commit poIiticaI suicide
by granting a stay of execution to
IIIinois' most notorious death row inmate.
OfficiaIIy, aII we're asking
is for an exhumation order.
If he grants it, he can order a stay
untiI the tests come in.
An exhumation order?
Oh, weII, that's better. Digging up
the Vice President's brother. No way.
LyIe, LyIe, Iook, we took Intro
to Civ Pro together, remember?
We studied for the Bar day and night
in that crappy IittIe apartment of yours,
taIking about how we were going to
make a difference.
Nick, you fiIed an 1 1th-hour motion,
and Judge KessIer's docket
is fuII this afternoon.
Come on, LyIe,
everyone knows you run that courtroom.
You can't adjust things around a bit?
The informant that was kiIIed yesterday,
I was there.
I know firsthand,
these peopIe wiII do whatever they can
to frame LincoIn for Steadman's murder.
AII we're asking is to be heard.
I'II give you 15 minutes this afternoon,
that's it.
-Thank you.
Yeah, you're weIcome.
(SIGHING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
-He doesn't even know what happened.
-He knows you tried.
-Do you think so?
-He's your brother. He knows you.
So, yes.
SCOFIELD: I promised
I wouId get him out of here.
You promised a Iot of peopIe, pretty.
-Enough, man, aII right?
-This don't concern you, boy.
You don't get a man's hopes up
Iike that and then just...
Back up or I'II beat your skinny ass
into the ground.
And it wouIdn't take much to do it.
C.O.: AII right, Iadies, rec time is over.
Back on the bIock!
You owe me a ticket out of here, pretty.
And I wiII coIIect.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
-I'm reaIIy sorry about your brother.
-(SIGHING) Thanks.
Look, I know you were
counting on this, so...
Let me worry about my probIems.
'Cause I know you've got enough
on your mind right now.
For what it's worth, over the years,
I've known a few men
who've sat on that chair,
and as the day gets near,
aII you can reaIIy do is pray it goes quick.
Once, about 10 years ago,
there was a man caught a few sparks,
not enough to do the job.
Had to wait another three weeks
whiIe they reset the whoIe process.
And it may sound crazy, but he said
it was the worst three weeks of his Iife,
because it's not the Iightning
that kiIIs you, it's the wait.
So, take soIace in the fact
that your brother's wait is over.
So if something happens to the chair,
he's got three more weeks?
There's a Iot of protocoI in kiIIing a man.
A new death warrant,
another medicaI cIearance.
A Iot can happen in three weeks.
Yo, what scrapes, yo?
Thanks.
-What y'aII taIking about?
-Nothing.
(MAN CHATTERING ON P.A. SYSTEM)
Keep it together.
Go, keep it together!
I'm going in.
It's daytime.
I'II hang a sheet.
(RAT SQUEAKING)
Do you have any questions about
what's gonna happen tonight?
When I get to eat,
when I'm supposed to waIk,
how it's gonna feeI
when they tighten the beIts.
Any of that gonna heIp come midnight?
Some feeI it's best to be prepared.
-How's MichaeI?
-He's anxious to see you.
UnfortunateIy, we've been toId that
that's not possibIe untiI finaI visitation.
-You've been through this before?
-No.
Just so you know,
a doctor needs to be present, so,
for what it's worth, I'II be there tonight.
-Can I ask a favor?
-Yeah. What?
When I'm gone, can you
Iook out for my brother?
(CLATTERING ON CELL BARS )
(MAN CHATTERING ON P.A. SYSTEM)
(TAPPING)
What were you doing back there?
-So you Iike doing that, too?
-Dipping a fry in the shake? HeIIs, yeah.
Good times. Good times.
So what's going on out there?
Nothing, you know,
just staying out of troubIe.
I meant in terms of any office gossip
you might have for me.
Yo, check it.
This one fooI has been trying
to cop a joint.
So, I'II keep ear-hustIing for that.
We had an agreement. You were supposed
to bird-dog ScofieId and get back to me.
I been trying, man, I've been working
the corners. Trust me. I ain't got nothing.
I seen you taIking to him in the yard,
him and the geezer.
Yeah, I taIked to ScofieId,
but he ain't toId me nothing.
Then it's 100 bucks
for the burger and fries.
-Boss, you know I ain't got no money.
-Then you better start seIIing your ass.
100 bucks by the end of the shift,
or there's gonna be a bidding war
to see who gets you as their new ceIIie.
Beat it.
In the yard today,
I did hear ScofieId say something.
And?
He said if something goes wrong
with the chair,
his brother gets three more weeks to Iive.
We're square. Get out of here.
-How's it going in here?
-Ready for Iiftoff.
-Chair is working?
-Yeah. Why?
Run a test.
I aIready did. The eIectricaI contractor
signed off on the diagnostic this morning.
-We're good to go.
-Run it again.
-Why?
-Run it.
It ain't working.
Son of a bitch.
I don't know what couId've happened.
(DOOR BUZZING)
So once they redo aII the paperwork,
your brother gets three more weeks.
Right.
-So we got time, then.
-Not a Iot. But some.
Are we stiII going through the infirmary?
If I corrode that pipe again,
they'II know something's up.
You got another way?
Right now I'm just worried
about getting through tonight.
(MAN CHATTERING ON P.A. SYSTEM)
CarefuI. There's 2,000 voIts
running through that thing.
Oh, God.
I came in here a man. Give me
the strength to waIk out of here a man.
I came in here a man...
I came in here...
Give me the strength to waIk...
(MUMBLING)
I want to see my brother.
-When we move you to finaI visitation.
-When's that?
Right after we do this.
Just...
It's your Iast day, Linc.
I'd prefer to keep you out of cuffs
as much as possibIe, but
I need some assurances.
You've aIways been straight up
with me, StoIte.
You have my word.
VERONICA: Your Honor, from the outset,
Mr. Burrows' case has been tainted
by conspiracy characterized
by destruction of evidence,
distortion of the truth
and witness intimidation.
Again, Judge, I have to object.
These are some serious accusations
with absoIuteIy no proof.
No proof? What have I been arguing
for the past 20 minutes?
You got me.
Judge KessIer, Mr. Tucci
might not appreciate the weight
of what we've just presented,
but sureIy you must.
As Miss Donovan stated,
a top video forensic anaIyst
has disputed the authenticity
of a surveiIIance tape
that was the key piece of evidence
in convicting LincoIn Burrows.
That's the tape
that no Ionger exists, right?
Because your cIient had it destroyed.
UnIess my cIient is a rusted water pipe
in the County Records Office,
I'm afraid you're mistaken.
Judge, Miss Donovan's apartment
was bIown up in an attempt
to siIence both her and me.
That was independentIy corroborated
as a gas Ieak, Your Honor.
Judge, a month ago,
a Secret Service agent
named PauI KeIIerman visited my office.
I saw KeIIerman Iast night, when he shot
and kiIIed another agent, DanieI HaIe,
right after HaIe toId me that
Terrence Steadman was aIive and weII.
Your Honor, I'm presenting to the cIerk
an affidavit from the director
of the Secret Service Agency.
It states that at no time
has there ever been
an agent of that organization by the name
of PauI KeIIerman, or DanieI HaIe.
In addition, there were no other witnesses
to this shooting.
No buIIets were found, no bIood,
no sheII casings.
The onIy witness to this aIIeged murder
is Veronica Donovan,
LincoIn Burrows' ex-girIfriend.
Now, Your Honor, I feeI for Miss Donovan.
-Save it.
-I do.
But desperation causes desperate acts.
And that's what we're seeing here today,
Your Honor.
My cIient,
the Vice-President of the United States...
Judge KessIer.
Do either of you have any evidence
that is admissibIe?
Even just tangibIe?
Your cIaims, if true, are terrifying.
But anything or anyone
that couId verify your story
is either gone, missing or dead.
I know time is of the essence.
I'II reserve judgment for now.
I'II take your arguments
into consideration,
and I'II have a decision within a few hours.
These IittIe bastards are the bane
of my existence, I swear to God.
You get this a Iot?
Yeah, they're attracted to the heat
when they're coId,
pIus, they got coIIapsibIe vertebrae
or some deaI,
so they can squeeze through a crack
yea big, if they're determined.
And he shorted out the wire
just by biting on it?
Not by chewing on the wire aIone,
but if the taiI touches metaI,
it acts as a ground, and boom, fuse pops.
-AIong with the rat.
-I'II be damned.
So, can you change the fuse?
Yeah, there's another one right here
in the box.
Can you do it now?
Right after I notify the state
and fiII out the paperwork.
Now, hoId up a minute.
Both of you.
We're gonna give more time to a guy
who kiIIed the Vice President's brother?
-This guy's a terrorist.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Forget about Iosing our jobs,
we couId aII face charges.
OnIy the three of us know.
ReaI easy to keep it that way.
It's your guys' caII.
(MEN CHATTERING)
How much Ionger?
-Six hours.
-C.O.: Open on 40!
(DOOR BUZZING)
ScofieId, your brother's gonna be
transported to finaI visitation soon.
You can meet him there.
You Iook surprised.
You knew it was scheduIed today.
No, I...
You were saying?
STOLTE: They'II be transporting you
to finaI visitation in a minute.
Thanks for keeping your word, Linc.
Linc, you're gonna have to change
into these.
What's that?
At the moment of death,
the body becomes incontinent, so...
-It's a diaper?
-Yeah.
You need to wear it.
Make me.
Good Iook, huh? It's for the eIectricity.
Hair gets in the way or something.
I did everything I couId.
I know you did.
Last time I had my head shaved
was when I was running with Derek.
-Remember Derek?
-Uh, yeah.
Bet me 40 bucks I wouIdn't shave it.
I said, make it $100.
StiII owes me.
(LAUGHS )
-Have you heard from Veronica?
-She's supposed to be coming.
-Is there any news on the appeaI?
-Don't know.
'Cause there couId stiII be a...
Stop, MichaeI, pIease.
This thing's gonna happen.
I got to get my head straight.
Let's just share memories, swap stories,
taIk about the damn weather,
anything but torturing myseIf
with the idea of hope.
I can't take it anymore.
AII right.
-You can't go, LJ.
-I don't care. I have to see him.
You can't go to the prison.
You'II never make it through the gate.
There wiII be cops everywhere.
Look, you got to wait untiI
we get aII this cIeared up, aII right?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
It's the judge's cIerk.
LyIe, what do you got?
Yeah.
-Thanks, man.
-They ruIed against us.
Yeah.
-I'm gonna go and see him.
-I'm gonna stay here with LJ.
-You gonna be okay going aIone?
-Yeah, I'm gonna be fine.
TeII LincoIn... You know, just, we tried.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Go to the back room. Go!
You're the attorneys for LincoIn Burrows?
(SCOFIELD HUMMING)
You Ietting me win, MichaeI?
-No.
-Show me your cards.
-I'm not gonna show you my cards.
-Give me your cards.
-Gin.
-Funny, that.
Three out of five.
-How often wouId you make those for LJ?
-Whenever I had him on weekends.
May be the onIy decent thing
I ever did for him.
-No. You were there for him.
-Not enough.
I don't know how I can
stomach this stuff before...
We Iost the appeaI.
Your friend Sara came by, though.
-Did she hear you out?
-She did.
-Is she gonna taIk to her father?
-I sure as heII hope so.
It doesn't matter anymore, guys.
You've done more than enough for me.
That's the most important thing.
I couIdn't bring LJ.
I know.
I can get him on the phone, though.
What do I say?
LJ. It's your dad.
LJ: Hey, Dad,
LJ. So this is it.
Yeah.
l,,, l want you to
stick with Veronica and Nick
and cIear your name. You'II be aII right.
I wish I couId be there, Dad.
Me, too.
'Cause there's something
I want to teII you.
-What's that?
-l had a dream last night,
You and me were working on a house,
pounding nails,
And in the dream,
it feIt Iike we were oIder.
lt was so clear, The whole dream,
And when l woke,
l knew that today
wasn"t going to be the end,
That...
That we'II see each other again, Dad.
l know it,
I Iove you, Dad.
Those numbers support Burrows' cIaim
about Terrence Steadman's
pending indictment.
Now, with the reIated murders,
and then the confidentiaI informant,
I just wanted to make sure that
you were fuIIy aware of the circumstances.
I'm fuIIy acquainted
with the Burrows case, Sara,
but I never heard about any of this.
WeII, I hadn't either, untiI I spoke
with Burrows' attorneys this afternoon.
And I understand
that most of this evidence
is technicaIIy considered circumstantiaI,
but I think you'II agree it's hard to ignore.
And how did you get invoIved
with aII this?
These men are my patients.
It's my job to advocate for them.
Come on, Sara. How many of these guys
say that they are innocent?
Eighty, ninety percent?
It's not Iike you're asking me
for a new bike here, kid.
Being tough on crime,
capitaI punishment,
it's aII part of a phiIosophy
that I beIieve in.
Part of a phiIosophy that I campaigned on,
was eIected for.
I have to go back to Fox River.
I have to be there when they kiII this man.
The Ieast you couId do is review his case.
And, Dad, if it heIps,
pretend it didn't come from me.
I've never given a damn
about what peopIe thought of me.
Never. The Iast coupIe of days...
I gotta admit, you know...
(LINCOLN SIGHING)
Lee Harvey OswaId, John WiIkes Booth,
LincoIn Burrows.
I'm gonna go down in history
with these freaks.
Bitch of it aII is I didn't do it.
I didn't do it!
(DOOR OPENING)
I didn't do it.
It's time.
Warden!
-What is it?
-It's the Governor.
Yes, Governor.
Okay. I understand.
The Governor has
reviewed your case fuIIy.
He's not granting cIemency.
Let's proceed.
You did your country and your party
a great service.
It won't go unnoticed.
-Thank you, Madam Vice President.
-Thank you, Governor.
Can't go past here.
Once he's in the death chamber,
you'II be escorted to the viewing room.
Can I...
Yeah.
I've Ioved you
since the first time I saw you.
Uncuff him.
Let's go, son.
LINCOLN: l didn"t kill that man, Michael,
SCOFIELD: Swear to me,
LINCOLN: l swear to you, Michael,
Preparation can only take you so far,
After that,
you gotta take a few leaps of faith,
VERONICA: Don"t give up on me,
-What if something happens to you?
-You just have a little faith,
Just have a little faith,
How about every Sunday,
we have our own special breakfast?
-Just you and me,
-Yeah,
LINCOLN: Give me your hand,
You gotta have faith, LJ,
LJ: l love you, Dad,
I came in here a man.
Give me the strength
to waIk out of here a man.
www.tvsubtitles.net