(man) previously on ''prison Break'':
I didn't kiII him.
- The evidence says you did.
- I was set up.
put down your weapon.
I find it incumbent
you see the inside of a ceII.
- I'm Iooking for Burrows.
- (Sucre) Man kiIIed the VP's brother.
- Why do you want to see him?
- He's my brother.
- I'm getting you out.
- ImpossibIe.
Not if you designed the pIace.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
- Better.
I've got 'em on me.
- You find out who's trying to bury him.
- Nobody is.
The evidence was cooked.
- There's a Iawyer poking around.
- Anyone that's a threat is expendabIe.
- I'm gonna kiII that scum.
- You kiII him, you kiII our ticket out of here.
- Where's Maricruz?
- She's with me now.
Fish, I gotta be back in.
Nick, Project Justice. My boss may not think
LincoIn's case is worth Iooking into, but I do.
When do we get started?
This waII is just the beginning.
There's a Iot of reaI estate
in between here and the outside.
That is a transfer request. MichaeI ScofieId
is getting shipped out tomorrow.
- About your transfer request for ScofieId.
- More specificaIIy, why you denied it.
Look, Mr KeIIerman, do I come to your house
and teII you where to put your furniture?
- We're just asking for professionaI courtesy.
- A federaI courtesy in a state penitentiary.
Most peopIe wouId be happy
to have a body taken off their hands.
These men are my responsibiIity.
From the minute they waIk in
to the time they've paid their debt to society,
I'm responsibIe.
UnIess he's done something
I don't know about,
he is gonna stay here at Fox River
under my watch.
Mr Pope, in our Iine of work,
just about everyone has done something
that someone doesn't know about.
- What's this?
- Right now, just a piece of history.
Whether it becomes a current event,
now, that's up to you.
My wife aIready knows about ToIedo.
Does she reaIIy?
You're a smart man, Warden.
I'm sure you can find a reason
ScofieId's presence is no Ionger required
at this particuIar correctionaI faciIity.
I need some more PVC here, boss.
- Boss?
- Sure thing, Burrows.
I don't wanna check for spIinters.
I want every piece accounted for.
Sure.
I got a ripped fertiIizer bag inside.
Hey, you!
You!
Get in there and cIean it up before this whoIe
pIace starts smeIIing Iike San Juan.
(mutters to himself)
OK, he's on his way. Do you mind teIIing me
what this is aII about?
These are the guys we're breaking out with.
I don't think so, fish.
That was not our agreement.
I'm not gonna work with this crazy rhino.
- Keep pushing it, John.
- Yeah, I keep pushing it, you know. Huh?
What's your deaI, man?
Touch my brother again and I'II show you.
Brother? Your brother?
We've got a few minutes. Are we gonna spend
'em spitting on each other or taIk business?
The reason we're aII here today
is we have a decision to make.
EngIish, Fitz, or Percy.
If we're gonna puII this off,
we need to take one of them out.
And you want us to teII you which one?
I just want you to heIp me get to them.
I'II take it from there.
- You're crazy.
- AII I need is five minutes.
- You won't get five seconds.
- I thought you had everything worked out.
We're not breaking out of a Jamba Juice.
It's gonna take more than digging a few hoIes.
There are eyes, ears, dots that couIdn't be
connected from the outside.
- And EngIish, Fitz or Percy?
- One of those dots.
And how exactIy
are you supposed to puII this off?
With a IittIe heIp from my friends.
Sucre, hoId up. ScofieId, you've got company.
Why do I get the feeIing that there's more
to you than meets the eye, ScofieId?
Anything you wanna teII me?
Some other reason you're in here
besides hoIding up a bank?
- You're being transferred.
- What?
We're moving you over to StatesviIIe.
- You can't do that.
- Yes, I can. I'm the boss here.
This is my house.
- Three weeks.
- What for?
LincoIn Burrows.
He's being executed in three weeks.
I'm aware of that. What's that to you?
He's my brother.
When I knew I was being sent to prison,
my attorney petitioned the DOC.
- So you couId be near him.
- That's right.
Don't take that away from me.
Not untiI it's over.
I'm not the one behind the transfer.
You're up against much bigger fish than me.
I'II arrange for you to say goodbye.
You ship out tomorrow.
(faint organ music)
I'm going into the waIIs,
see if I can access the roof.
Were you gonna teII me about the transfer?
- I'm taking care of it.
- You're taking care of it?
Sounds to me Iike you're reaching.
Maybe. A IittIe.
A IittIe.
I'd made my peace, then you give me the one
thing a man in my situation shouIdn't have.
- Hope. And now that's gonna be taken away.
- Don't do this, Linc.
I got three weeks.
What do you want me to do?
(boy) Come on, MichaeI.
- Bring her back.
- You know I can't do that.
But, Iook, there's some stuff that I can do.
It's not gonna be the same,
but we're gonna figure it out.
And no matter what,
it's stiII gonna be me and you.
OK, but what if something happens to you?
You just have a IittIe faith.
Just have a IittIe faith.
(Nick) If we beIieve LincoIn, this tape is a Iie.
- It has to be.
- But you saw it. It's aII there.
But maybe what we're Iooking for
is what's not there.
- OK. Steadman. See, what's he Iooking at?
- A car? A pedestrian?
(Nick) His eye Iine is high.
He's Iooking into the camera.
He might as weII be saying ''cheese''.
- Now he just sits there.
- For 10, 15 seconds, as if he was...
- Waiting for someone.
- Right.
There. That's a nine miIIimetre.
ShouIdn't there be a kick?
- LincoIn's pretty strong.
- Yeah, but strong enough to bury a recoiI?
Now, you shoot someone,
supposedIy for revenge.
Do you take the time to go in and hit
the gIove box? Or get the heII out of there?
Feds said he was trying
to make it Iook Iike a robbery.
Look. Look at LincoIn's angIe
as he Ieaves the frame.
Mm.
He waIks away from the car.
Now, this guy, who convenientIy hides his
face from the camera, comes back in. Why?
To expIain the bIoody pants they'd aIready
pIanted in his apartment. Nick, this is great.
- Who shaII we go to?
- Nobody. Yet.
To the unbiased eye, we're backing a horse
that died in the gate. A Iot of conjecture.
We don't have anything.
We need some evidence.
Look, if LincoIn didn't fire this gun,
somebody with serious skiIIs
worked on this to prove he did.
Fine, but how do we prove that?
- I know a guy.
- You know a guy?
Yeah, I know a guy.
Thanks.
We need to have a powwow. There's been taIk
about you packing your bags.
Don't beIieve everything you hear.
I'm not going anywhere.
I have a reaIIy hard time trusting you, fish.
The important thing
is that we stay on scheduIe.
- Yeah? EngIish, Fitz and Percy?
- EngIish, Fitz or Percy.
Wanna know which one we shouId take out?
With aII due respect, I don't need opinions.
I need answers.
The warden Ieaves at five tonight,
so by five after five we need that key.
And how is this key
gonna give you the answers?
I'II worry about that.
Worry about getting the key.
Hey. This key better be worth it.
Understand?
Afternoon, Mr ScofieId.
I need to know
if there's a way to bIock a transfer.
- There's about 50 ways.
- AII right. I'II take the quickest.
You fiIe a motion for what they caII
an interIocutory injunction.
- How Iong does that take?
- How fast can you write?
A man can cIaim aImost anything
vioIates his constitutionaI rights.
EnvironmentaI issues, aIIergies,
reIigious requirements - take your pick.
- What if they don't buy it?
- They're required to hear your motion.
TiII they do, you can't be transferred.
HeII, they've been trying to move
my tired, grey behind for ten years.
God bIess the American IegaI system.
Why do you want to stay in here so badIy?
There's someone here
I can't bear to Ieave behind.
I guess that means
we've got something in common.
- The state's requiring a physicaI for Burrows.
- You heard the news?
- No, what?
- They're brothers.
- Who?
- Burrows and ScofieId.
MichaeI ScofieId?
Heard it from one of the COs over in Gen Pop.
He didn't say anything about it?
No.
It must be hard to be so cIose to your brother
and not be abIe to do anything to heIp him.
- What's this?
- A IittIe bathroom reading.
- WestmoreIand again?
- ScofieId. He's bIocking his transfer.
Even if the motion is denied,
it's gonna take 30 days to process.
And that means...
AII right, I'm going in.
I'm gonna need your heIp.
In in? Now? I thought you were waiting tiII...
I need to make sure I know how I'm getting
up there so when the time comes...
In case you didn't notice, the Iights are aII on.
You've got a Iive studio audience, fish.
How are you gonna get around that?
Don't we have some Iaundry to do?
Just to be cIear,
I ain't touching your drawers.
(guard #1) Eyes straight ahead.
- Keep it moving.
- (guard #2) Eyes front.
- (guard #1) Keep it moving. Keep it moving.
- Him.
(guard #1) Get him up. Hit him.
(guard #2) Stay down.
Come on.
Fish. I can't deaI with that.
Fish. Come on.
Yo, fish. Fish, you're taking too Iong, bro.
This ain't gonna fIy. The Ricans, we've got
geneticaIIy higher bIood pressure, you know?
My cousin, he died from too much stress.
You said he was moving in on your girI.
My other cousin,
but thanks for bringing that up.
Look, the good news is I can get to the roof.
- So what happens now?
- Now?
It's aII about timing.
(watch beeps)
- It's a top-doIIarjob. You know who did it?
- No. Do you?
PeopIe who do this kind of work
are ghosts, man.
The guy behind the guy behind the guy,
you know?
Can you see anything that proves
the tape might have been doctored?
The thing's cIean. No footprints.
UsuaIIy, you peeI the video back,
anything bogus comes off.
Now you see it, now you don't.
But not this one.
It's Iaced. Ingrained.
Whoa, whoa.
- You see something?
- The probIem with eyes is they pIay tricks.
But your ears - ears don't Iie.
Here's the audio track from the tape.
- Sounds pretty true?
- Yeah.
But noise is aIive.
See, it doesn'tjust die Iike that.
Stripped down,
those IeveIs shouId be dancing.
A room that size wouId give you
a bIam, bIam, bIam, bIam, you know.
Off each waII, a spIit second after the other.
On yours,
the reverb's bouncing at the same time.
- What does that mean?
- The sound of a gunshot.
It wasn't recorded in that room.
- WouId you testify to that?
- Oh, uh, I don't know.
The tape's a dupe.
For aII I know, you guys tampered with it.
Look, if you want me to testify in court, I'm
gonna need to get my hands on the originaI.
- (pope) How are those aIIergies?
- Excuse me?
- (pope) In your motion, you cited chronic...
- Sinusitis.
It's not an aIIergy, actuaIIy.
It's a bacteriaI infection.
The moist air from the river aIong
the east waII heIps keep me, you know...
cIear.
I'm impressed. Not even a week here
and you're working it Iike an oId con.
You've got one up on me.
You know why I needed to fiIe those motions,
but I have no idea
why you needed to transfer me.
Traffic controI, ScofieId.
That's aII. Traffic controI.
It's coming up on five o'cIock. CaII it a day.
- I don't think I can do that.
- Why not?
If I Iet go of this support,
the whoIe thing's coming down.
See, the Taj was designed using axiaI force -
a series of internaI forces
aIong the IongitudinaI axis.
- Yeah. How much Ionger?
- Depends on how Iong it takes to dry.
If you need me to Ieave,
I can show your secretary how to hoId it.
You can stay. There'II be a guard outside.
Just check in with Becky
and she'II have somebody escort you back.
- AII right.
- And, ScofieId.
I wanna thank you for showing up today.
I wouId've understood it if you didn't.
- We had a deaI.
- Right.
StiII, thanks. My wife is gonna Iove it.
You're weIcome.
- (man) See you tomorrow, sir.
- (woman) Good night, Warden.
(door closes)
We'd just happen to be two peopIe
who happen to know each other,
who happen to show up at the same movie
theatre at what happens to be the same time.
(woman laughs)
You know, from this angIe, you Iook
just as good as you did when we first met.
- How about from this one?
- Even better.
- Oh.
- Uh-uh. Those are for your guests.
- Guests?
- Your associates.
They said you had a meeting.
They're in the den.
Evening, Warden.
There's nothing I can do. I'm obIigated to fiIe
every motion so a hearing can be scheduIed.
- And how Iong does that take?
- A month, maybe two. It's out of my hands.
Why do I feeI you're not disappointed?
May I ask you a question, Warden?
More of an observation, reaIIy.
I was Iooking at the morgue photos
from that boy back in ToIedo - WiII CIayton -
and, my Lord,
if he wasn't the spitting image of his daddy.
The appIe feII reaI far from the tree
with that one, didn't it?
It feII off the tree, feII aII over the pavement.
You son of a bitch.
Your wife gave you a pass on the affair,
but that's aII the forgiveness she's got Ieft.
EspeciaIIy when it comes to
an iIIegitimate chiId.
What happened with young WiII, Warden?
- Get out of my house.
- Lose ScofieId's paperwork.
- Are you staying for dinner?
- Thanks, but I think we're on our way.
Judy, it was a reaI pIeasure.
Thank you. And thatjust may have been
the best iced tea I've ever had.
Warden, better do everything you can
to hoId on to this one.
- I wiII.
- Good.
- Is everything aII right?
- Oh, yeah. Just fine. I, uh...
I just have a IittIe unfinished work
to take care of. I'II be right in.
OK.
He's aII cIear.
- Evening, LincoIn.
- Doctor.
I'm supposed to give you
a physicaI this evening.
Let me apoIogise for the dose of irony
we're about to participate in.
It's aII right. Just doing yourjob.
Yeah, weII...
Letting them know you're heaIthy enough to
execute is not why I went to medicaI schooI.
- I apoIogise.
- It's OK.
AII right.
I'm gonna need
a famiIy medicaI history from you.
Any aiIments or conditions
that are hereditary. Let's start with your mom.
- Cancer. Liver.
- OK. Father?
SpIit when I was young.
SibIings.
Anyone besides MichaeI?
Fox River's a smaII town, LincoIn.
PeopIe around here don't have
a whoIe Iot to do besides time and taIk.
Are you cIose?
(Linc) We were.
- (Sara) How about now?
- Huh?
How about now?
(Linc) He's been abandoned his whole life.
Dad, Mom - she died young -
and now me.
Think that's why he's here?
Cos your death wouId feeI Iike
it's happening again
(Linc) l abandoned him a long time ago.
That's why he's here.
- (watch beeps)
- (buzzer)
(guard) Gates cIosing.
- It's time.
- Time?
Oh, God. Here we go again.
Count's in 15 minutes. What are you doing?
- Trust me. The Iess you know, the better.
- The Iess I know? You got me in the dark.
That's exactIy where you wanna be.
(man) Don't normaIIy find you here
at this hour.
Are you seeking his forgiveness? Or advice?
I reaIIy don't know any more, Ben.
AII I know is my son WiII
was my responsibiIity.
- If I'd stayed in his Iife, I couId've saved it.
- His death was an accident, Henry.
He was a criminaI,
and an addict, but he was onIy 18 years oId.
His mother made it cIear you couIdn't be
in his Iife if you weren't gonna be in hers.
When you chose to stay with Judy,
you understood that.
I not onIy understood it, I was gratefuI for it.
I toId myseIf I was respecting her wishes.
I cursed her under my breath
whiIe every day I thanked God
for aIIowing me to wash my hands of her.
Of ToIedo.
AII of it.
So I ran home,
to Judy,
and I buried the secret.
But I never got a chance to...
to bury my... my son.
What kind of a person does that, Ben?
Sacrifices somebody eIse's Iife
just to make their own Iife easier.
You can argue with me aII night. BeIieve me,
I haven't got anything better to do.
But it won't change the fact that I can't
just hand out originaI copies of evidence.
- If you couId just take a Iook...
- I don't care. I can't give it to you.
What if we brought somebody here?
Your supervisor couId monitor them.
He'd strip down and swear
on a stack of BibIes. Whatever.
Wait. What did you say
the docket number was?
It's 296 SPE.
- What's wrong?
- Come with me.
Last night a pipe burst upstairs,
fIooded the pIace.
FiIes from over 100 cases -
pretty much Iost aII of them, incIuding yours.
- Just this room?
- Some kind of freak accident.
(buzzer)
(whistle)
- (guard) Count 'em.
- (Bellick) CaIIahan, Knight.
MaIinowski, PohIen.
(watch beeps)
Chance, Graziano.
ScofieId, Sucre.
ScofieId, get the heII out here.
We got a runner.
(alarm)
(pA) Lockdown.
Lockdown!
(inmates shout)
AII right. For the Iast time, pi¨¾ata.
Where the heII's ScofieId?
He's gone, you're gone. You hear me?
(radio) Call it off, Captain.
l got Scofeld right here.
- Where?
- (radio) ln the warden's office.
Are you Iooking at him?
Stop trying to nail the secretary
and check the damn office.
Captain, he's gone.
(alarm continues and dogs bark)
- The man can'tjust vanish.
- I know, sir.
- He never checked out? The rear door?
- StiII Iocked. I checked.
How the heII did he...?
- What's going on?
- You're in the warden's office.
I couId kiII you and the paperwork
wouIdn't need more than a date.
- TeII me, what were you doing in here?
- AII right, Deputy. That's enough.
The work wasn't dry.
You said to stay untiI it was.
- You were in here?
- Yes, sir.
- It's true. I never saw him Ieave.
- I must not have seen him.
This is ridicuIous. This prisoner
was out of his ceII. He missed the count.
(pope) I understand, Deputy.
The thing is,
Mr ScofieId is not our probIem any more.
There was an error in his paperwork.
He's gonna be transferred.
That's not possibIe.
Escort the prisoner back to his ceII.
Warden, aII I need is three weeks.
- Get off me!
- Come on!
Henry, pIease. I just need a IittIe time.
Just give me the time.
Any chance you want to write this off
as a coincidence?
Me neither.
How couId they know we were coming?
Three hours ago, we didn't know.
- We're pissing someone off.
- You say that Iike it's a good thing.
PeopIe start breaking the Iaw,
you know you're getting warm.
We stiII have our copy of the tape, so maybe...
- Nick.
- Stay here.
Whoever it was has gone.
Does it Iook Iike they got anything?
No.
Everything's exactIy the way I Ieft it.
What? What?
- What?
- The tape. It's gone.
- Are you sure?
- How?
- Think this through.
- How couId they know?
- Wait. Does anyone eIse have a key?
- No.
- Are you sure this is where you put it?
- You were here. I was taIking to you.
I waIked toward the cabinet, and I said...
What?
Veronica, are you OK?
Veronica.
- (buzzer)
- (Bellick) Open up!
Breakfast, gentIemen. Let's move it.
Sucre, Iet's go. ScofieId, wait here.
I'm sure your ride'II be aIong any minute now.
This can't be it.
It can't end Iike this.
(Bellick) Let's move it.
- (Michael) Fitz.
- What?
We were gonna take Fitz out.
It was as cIear as day.
And the cops? How Iong did it take them
to respond? You got aII the timing down?
Think we wouId've made it?
Sucre, now.
(# ''Orange Sky'' by Alexi Murdoch)
# Well, l had a dream
l stood beneath an orange sky
# Yes, l had a dream
Hey, fish face, where are you going?
# With my brother standing by
CaII my wife. TeII her to get the kids
and get the heII out of the country.
# l said, brother, you know, you know
# lt's a long road we've been walking on
Sorry.
# You know it is, you know it is
# Such a long road we've been walking on
Don't forget to buckIe up.
- (pope) What's he doing out of his ceII?
- (guard) He's being transferred.
No, there must be some mistake.
This man fiIed a motion yesterday.
He has a medicaI condition
which precIudes transfer.
Sinusitis, right?
Sinusitis.
Take the prisoner back to his ceII. But yank
his rec time. He missed count Iast night.
Hey.
You're home earIy. Everything OK?
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
There's just...
Judy,
there's someone I need to teII you about.
- (phone rings)
- (woman) Yes?
- (Kellerman) The transfer did not go through.
- (woman) Disappointing.
- (Kellerman) We can refle, but...
- (woman) It's a waste of time.
I think it's time we stopped
beating around the bush,
and go after the damn bush.
(Kellerman) Burrows.
What do you want done?
(woman) Take the only thing
Burrows has left- time.
After all, the chair isn't the only way
to take a man's life in prison.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Jo CIarke
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net