SCOFIELD: Previously on Prison Break:
I need you to Iet me get us out of here.
If you try to screw me over again,
I'II kiII you.
Because if Crazy steps out of Iine,
aII I gotta do is shoot him with 40ccs
of shut-your-trap, and it's beddy-bye.
ScofieId and his whoIe PI crew,
they're escaping.
You know I can't Iet you Ieave here, boss.
(GRUNTS )
(GLASS CRASHING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS )
I've been cIean for 18 months now.
I want to heIp peopIe
get from where I've been to where I am.
I'm getting my brother out of here tonight,
and I need your heIp.
You're asking me to break the Iaw.
I'm asking you to make a mistake.
Forget to Iock up.
Leave the door unIocked
when you Ieave tonight.
-The inmates in the psych ward aII wear...
-White.
-Peroxide acts as a bIeach.
-CamoufIage.
-Where's your girI?
-She'II be at my pIace in about an hour.
Pretty soon,
we're going to caII in our favor.
I'm getting on that pIane
with or without you.
I can't Iet you do that.
-There's been an acceIeration.
-Don't you want a bigger pIane?
WeII, not everybody gonna have a ticket.
If you can't convince a doddering oId fooI
what the best thing is
for this country's economy,
perhaps you're not
the kind of heIper we're Iooking for.
I'm breaking out,
and you're going to make sure
my brother goes with me.
You son of a bitch.
We're going to
take this reaI easy, Warden.
I just need you to do
a coupIe things for me.
-You just bought yourseIf 10 years.
-MACK: (ON RADIO) Warden?
BeIIick's truck is here, sir.
I'm staring right at it.
Should we start looking for him?
-MichaeI, if you just put that shank down...
-TeII the guard you spoke with BeIIick,
and he said he's taking
some personaI time.
You can't possibIy get away with this, son.
I don't think you want to find out how
badIy I want to get my brother out of here.
-MACK: Sir?
-Mack.
Yes, sir,
I just spoke with BeIIick.
He's waIked into town.
-He's taking some personaI time.
-ls he all right?
-He's fine.
-Copy that,
Okay. I just need you
to do one more thing.
(MASKING TAPE RIPPING)
Have LincoIn transferred to the infirmary.
And he needs to be there overnight.
How Iong have you been pIanning this?
That is a conversation
for another day, Warden.
-Pope to Base.
-CORRECTIONAL OFFICER: Go ahead, sir,
Have LincoIn Burrows
transferred to the infirmary.
-I want him heId overnight for tests.
-Copy that,
Once we're gone, you'II find BeIIick
in a hoIe under the guards' break room.
I'm sorry you got caught in the middIe,
but, one day,
you'II understand why I did this.
You'II never make it over the waII.
I'm sorry, Henry.
Everything aII right?
Yeah, he's getting an earfuI
from someone over at the DOC.
Oh. Is he on with Mr. DrushaI?
I'm not sure,
but it's turning into a conference caII
and he said he didn't want to be disturbed.
-Oh, weII, of course.
-Have a good night.
You know, MichaeI...
You know, he can be
a big oId grump sometimes,
but I hope you know
how highIy he thinks of you.
There's no way he'd get that
Taj MahaI done in time for his anniversary
without your heIp.
(GRUNTING)
(DOOR BUZZER BLARING)
It's 6:55.
That's five minutes tiII tier.
It's one hour tiII the next count.
One hour to get over that waII and
as far away from this prison as possibIe.
(PRISONERS CHATTERING)
You unscrewed the toiIet, right?
That's five minutes we don't have.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I'm just...
Just... I just feeI Iike
my head is spinning a IittIe.
(VOMITING)
(RETCHING)
Are you okay?
If we get caught,
I can't do 10 more years, bro. I can't.
GUARD: Tier time, one hour!
There's no going back now.
(HUMMING)
If you get stuck
in one of them pipes, boy...
BuII.
T-BAG: Keep waIking, BuII, keep waIking.
-You okay?
-Great.
(COUGHS )
It's got bIue spots.
-No, I got a Iate start.
-OnIy one thing you needed to do.
BIock the gate. I got to finish this off.
Said a prayer for you, Theodore.
Said a prayer for us aII.
I want him dead.
Anybody gets in the way, gets run over.
MACK: Hey, do you want some coffee?
Just a haIf cup, Mack.
If I have more than that, I'II be up aII night.
Thank you, bro.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
How many more screws?
Get C-Note out here.
Huh? Haven't seen him, man.
That's reaI touching and aII,
you sticking up for a brother,
but y'aII need to step aside, right now.
Something you need?
-Where is he?
-ToId you, we haven't seen him.
GUARD: Wilson, medical eval, five minutes,
Ramirez, report to the,,,
This whoIe time,
everything you said was a Iie?
No. No, I never stopped fighting
for LincoIn's innocence, never.
They approached me after I took this case.
Who's they?
John Abruzzi.
-John Abruzzi, the mob boss?
-Yes, yes.
How much did he pay you?
My father's freedom.
-You said your father was exonerated.
-I Iied, okay?
I agreed to keep tabs on you.
In exchange, Abruzzi had some guy
who was aIready doing a Iife sentence
cop to the murder
that my father didn't commit.
And that's how I got him out of jaiI.
-Your dad's Iife for mine.
-No one needs to get hurt here, Veronica.
Oh, you think Abruzzi
wants IegaI advice from me?
AII you have to do is make sure MichaeI
gives this Abruzzi guy
what he needs to know, that's it.
Nick, you don't think
they're gonna Iet me Iive, do you?
I gotta beIieve that.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah. Okay.
Right.
Stand up. We have to go.
Get up.
CharIes.
(PRISONERS CHATTERING)
Here you go.
Sucre, drop the sheet.
Manche, you're next.
Let's move it.
That one's for you.
Move your fat ass.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
That's for you.
Age before beauty.
AII right.
So, you got a key to the infirmary?
Not exactIy.
-AII right. How are we doing, baby?
-Not good.
We're aIready 10 minutes behind.
Let's move it.
Give me that.
(GRUNTING)
HeIp!
-Did you hear that?
-Hear what?
HeIp!
(GRUNTING)
MACK: Hear anything?
There's nobody here, man.
I swear, I heard something.
Come on, Iet's go.
You scream
and I'II cut out your windpipe, got me?
I need his jacket and his hat.
Evening, Doc.
Brains of the outfit, huh, ScofieId?
He's Ieading you off a cIiff, boys.
Now, you're acting Iike you stiII in charge.
Shut your mouth, bitch.
(SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Let's go.
You. You know, he's...
(SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Nick, pIease don't do this.
TeII MichaeI to give Abruzzi
what he wants.
PIease, Nick, come on,
they're going to kiII me. Nick!
Nick! PIease, no!
No, Nick.
Everyone put your coveraIIs on.
I'II be back in a minute.
Yo, where you going, man?
Hey!
You heard him. Come on.
This is ridicuIous, man.
One, three, five, eight.
Three, five, eight, one. Enter.
Eight, one, three, five. Enter.
The scope of this, which we're aII
aware of, can cIoud judgment.
I suggest we Iook at this
in very simpIe terms.
We have an empIoyee,
she's not working out. We fire her.
It needs to be that simpIe.
She"s the Vice President
of the United States,
And that"s all she"ll ever be,
She"s plummeting in the polls,
lf we keep her as our candidate, we"re
handing the presidency to her opponent,
and then everything we hope to gain
with Caroline in office, it"s all gone,
Fine, We ask her to drop out,
How do we know she'II keep her mouth
shut on everything she knows?
Samantha?
Yes, sir.
I need a very frank assessment
from you, right now.
Based on your contact with her,
wiII the Vice President go quietIy?
No. AbsoIuteIy not.
Becoming president
is the most important thing to her.
If we take that away,
she has absoIuteIy nothing to Iose.
And I guarantee you, she wiII do
everything she can
to take everyone she can down with her.
We need to make a move on her. Now.
(CHAINS RATTLING)
Okay, here we go. Go.
You okay, Doc?
(KEYS JANGLING)
-What's going on?
-I don't know.
What are we supposed to do, just sit here?
No. I don't know!
Man. This whoIe thing is messed up, bro.
FeeI free not to come, Gordo.
(ALARM BUZZING)
We're screwed. We're screwed!
Come on, Iet's go! Let's...
-MichaeI, we got to go back.
-We're moving forward.
We stick with the pIan.
Look, do your ears work, fooI?
Do you hear that?
It's the fire aIarm in psych ward.
SUCRE: How do you know?
SCOFIELD: I set it off.
Why?
(ALARM BLARING)
MAN ON PA: Exit the building
in an orderly fashion,
Exit the building in an orderly fashion,
We're in the sticks.
You know how many peopIe
wouId have heard a jet Iike this Iand?
Don't worry about it.
FaIse aIarm.
Back to the psych ward, everyone.
WaIk in with me, now. Very good.
-Just gonna keep on waIking.
-Come on, guys, you heard him.
Come on, Iet's go. It's coId out here.
That's it.
Come on, baby, Iet's go.
(MAN PANTING)
SCOFIELD: HoId up!
-Got some straggIers.
-CooI.
Let's go!
Wait a minute.
That's not wack-shack-issue.
Everybody, stop!
Stay where you are!
I said, stay where you are.
What's the probIem?
That's John Abruzzi right there.
Yeah, that's... That's bad news.
Listen, you got that sedative
you were taIking about?
-Yeah.
-You got some now?
-Let's have it.
-This wiII put him out, right?
-Like a Iight.
Let's go. Let's go, Iet's go!
-Where are we going?
-Straight down the haII. Straight down.
VERONICA: Nick, pIease don't do this.
(VERONICA SOBBING)
(VERONICA GASPS )
Come on.
-What's going on?
-I'm getting you to the airport.
Go, go, go.
You get to BIackfoot, you find Steadman.
There's stiII time for you
to get to the bottom of this thing.
Take this, take this.
I'm sorry about this, okay?
You gotta beIieve me, I'm sorry.
-Take her to O'Hare.
-DRIVER: You bet.
Dad, you stiII got the key
to my apartment?
Yeah, just meet me there.
I'II expIain it Iater, just meet me there.
HaIfway there, yo.
-What's up?
-I know you toId BeIIick.
-I don't know what you're taIking about.
-But I owed you, and I pay my debts.
But as soon as we're out of here,
you go your way, we'II go ours.
You understand?
Oh, Sara.
It was a faIse aIarm at the psych ward.
That's what aII that racket was about.
Good, thank you.
Good night.
Hey. Look, baby, it ain't worth it
if it's gonna kiII you.
I'm getting out of here.
(MAN PANTING)
(DOOR BUZZER RINGS )
Good night, Doctor.
-You're overreacting.
-I don't mean to shock you, PauI,
but I am privy to things that you're not.
And I am teIIing you,
-the company is seIIing me down the river.
-It's a Legend for Literacy fundraiser.
It doesn't mean anything.
It's a rubber-chicken dinner.
Which I got uninvited to on the day of.
You don't do that to your candidate,
unIess the candidate
is no Ionger your candidate.
CaroIine, you've been drinking,
you're upset.
How can you not understand this
is so beyond me.
I wouId think,
after being by my side for 15 years,
you wouId have gained
at Ieast a rudimentary understanding
of how things work.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
They're doing this
to see how you wiII react.
So you need to be strong.
Be presidentiaI, and you get through this.
We get through this.
(SIGHS )
I'm figuring I'II need a two-inch Iift,
if I'm gonna run with the new set
of 30-by-nine-and-a-haIfs.
Question is,
add coiI springs
or just stay with the spacers?
What do you think?
Whoa, whoa, whoa !
Easy, hey.
I ain't a hero for $14 an hour.
You do what you wiII.
-Uncuff my brother.
-You got it, boss.
-Pretend I ain't here, boss.
-Oh, yeah. You and the radio.
Dad, are you here?
Dad, you gotta get ready. We gotta go.
How's it going, Savrinn?
MAN: And l get why the guy"s
lighting the candle,
but why are the other two
playing the bagpipes?
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Welcome to Joke Line,
Just $2,99 a minute,,,
-What the heII?
-,,,50 cents for each additional minute,
Where's the Iawyer?
-She's gone.
-Yeah?
-Then so is your dad.
-No, no!
Don't.
-Have you got her or not?
-I can find her.
And wiII you have her in front of me
in the next two minutes?
It's a very simpIe question, Nick.
No. Just... Just give me a chance.
You just got to Iisten to me.
-No!
-Hey! This is happening right now!
You have one more chance!
Where's the Iawyer?
She's about a miIIion miIes away
from here. You're never gonna find her.
Why don't you just sock it?
(MAN PANTING)
Better be open, bro.
We're in.
First we gotta get that window out,
then we gotta get the bars off.
Manche, Manche.
-Is this gonna work?
-We're about to find out.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
BECKY: Warden?
Warden?
Ready.
PuII that. Come on.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS )
What now, genius?
Take your time.
We got 15 minutes to get over that waII.
(CRACKING)
We're through.
And you're sure
you didn't see him waIk out?
Positive.
SCOFIELD: Let's go, guys,
I need those suits.
Good job, kiddo.
Let's go, Iet's go. Come on.
Take this.
(MAN PANTING)
HAYWIRE: I knew it.
-Haywire.
-I knew it.
As soon as I saw you go
into psych ward, I knew it.
Either I come with...
You want me to make
a IittIe person-to-person caII here?
Haywire, just take it easy.
The other person being
a correctionaI officer.
He's in.
-What?
-He's in.
You're crazy!
Okay, after LincoIn, we go aIphabeticaIIy.
-Whoa, hoId on, A-bruzzi.
-You want a seat on the pIane?
Line forms after me.
Got it?
Yeah. Go, go, go.
-Hey, Roy?
-Yeah?
-Did you see Pope Ieave?
-No.
No way he couId have waIked by?
I haven't Ieft my post since I punched in.
AII right.
(GROANS )
-Hey, hey, hey.
-CharIes?
-You okay, oId man?
-No.
Let's take a Iook.
It's just a few more steps.
You can make it.
Oh, I couId make it another foot,
maybe two, but why?
I wasn't going for me.
I was going for my daughter.
And you can do that. WiII you promise me?
Yes, I promise.
The money is buried under a siIo
at the DoubIe K Ranch
just outside of TooeIe, Utah.
There's pIenty to spIit.
The government didn't want
any more embarrassment
after I took off with the money,
so they IowbaIIed it to the papers.
The truth is, MichaeI,
it's not $1 miIIion under that siIo.
There's $5 miIIion there.
-You check the chow haII?
-Yeah. Nothing.
-Anybody try his ceII phone?
-Oh.
Give Anna her Papa's Iove.
I wiII. I wiII.
(CREAKING)
Here, easy, easy.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Now, where is that coming from?
-Oh! Oh, my God.
-ControI, this is S and E 5.
I have a code three in the warden's office.
I repeat, code three.
-Sound the aIarm.
-Patterson to Base. Right now.
-No, right now.
-Sound the aIarm !
-Yo, bro, we gotta go.
-Go, MichaeI.
Go, and don't Iook back.
-No, no, no.
-Go on.
I better go Iast.
Come on, MichaeI! Come on. Come on.
(ALARM BLARING)
MichaeI, move it!
MAN ON P.A: All prisoners,
prepare for immediate shakedown,
Come on!
(DOG BARKING)
MichaeI, come on! Come on, MichaeI.
MichaeI, come on.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Go, go, go.
Come on, move it!
MichaeI, come on, move.
MichaeI!
MichaeI, grab my hand.
MichaeI, give me your hand.
Give me your hand. Come on.
(DOG BARKING)
(MAN ON PA CHATTERING)
Check out the wire. He's on the waII!
Get down!
-Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
-Get down!
www.tvsubtitles.net