previously on ''prison Break'':
- I'm Iooking for LincoIn Burrows.
- Man kiIIed the VP's brother.
- Why you want to see him?
- He's my brother.
I'II get you out.
- It's impossibIe.
- Not if you designed the pIace.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
- Better than that. I've got 'em on me.
Nick Savrinn.
As of now, both of you are dead.
This is BeIIick.
Our wing has been breached.
MariIyn, no!
The chair isn't the onIy way
to take a man's Iife in prison.
- What?
- He's in troubIe. There's nothing we can do.
Come on!
My first assignments on PI
were up here, cIeaning out toxic mouId.
PI didn't go there.
We'd never assign inmates to do that.
TyIer, Robert.
And this here must be your daughter.
- It's over. We don't need him.
- You're not gonna kiII him.
One for the team.
(Michael) 17 days from now,
they strap my brother to an electric chair.
Send 50,000 volts coursing through his body
for a crime he didn't commit.
l'm here to make sure that doesn't happen.
l've been in Fox River
nearly three weeks now.
ln that time,
l've got out the back of my cell
and into the old steam pipes
that run beneath the prison.
Those pipes are our way out.
Think of this pIace Iike it's a map of the US.
Our ceII over there, that's New York City.
The infirmary, our exit, that's CaIifornia.
- The pipes beneath us that connect the two...
- Route 66.
Route 66. Our ticket out of here.
- I assume we're doing this at night?
- That's right.
We're Iocked up, fish,
and your boy is in soIitary.
How we just gonna fIy out of our cages and
right into your ceII, right into New York City?
You're not.
You're gonna meet me haIfway.
In St Louis.
Route 66 runs beneath that buiIding. It's the
onIy buiIding sitting on top of those tunneIs.
AII we gotta do is get in there, on PI,
and dig ourseIves an on-ramp.
ShortIy after, we hit the infirmary.
Then we'II be outside those waIIs.
- What's in there?
- It's an oId storage room.
- John here can pull all the strings.
- (John) lt's not that easy, fsh.
That's a restricted area.
I gotta be abIe to justify it to the buIIs.
There's gotta be some actuaI work
to be done in there for me to get in there.
Then you better figure it out. Cos if we don't
get in that room, we're not getting out of here.
I'm feeIing kind of Ieft out.
New York, CaIifornia, St Louis.
What are we discussing?
- We're taIking basebaII, actuaIIy.
- Oh.
Now, that's a subject I know quite a bit about.
What a shame. The conversation's over.
ReaIIy, now.
That any way to treat a team-mate?
I'm coming aIong on this endeavour
whether you Iike it or not.
Cos I got a heII of a singing voice otherwise.
I won't take that piece of crap aIong.
I won't do it.
Me neither.
We won't have to.
He'II be out of the picture soon enough.
The state provides $25,000 insurance,
pIus donations from
the Corrections Officers' Foundation...
That's the Iast thing on my mind
right now, Warden.
- Do you know who kiIIed him?
- We have some Ieads.
But I can promise you this. We are not
gonna rest untiI we find out what happened.
His pictures are missing.
He had a photo of our daughter in here.
Not to worry. We'II find them.
I begged him not to take this job.
Shauna.
I am so sorry.
I'II waIk you to your car.
Captain, I need to speak with you
for a second.
(Bellick) I'II meet you in the haIIway.
I want the son of a bitch who did this.
Now, you do whatever
you need to do to find him.
You understand.
We got five boxes. Wanna give me a hand?
Veronica.
That caII was scare tactics. They want to scare
us from doing what they know we can do.
- And what's that?
- Expose them.
Is this guy bothering you again?
No, Lukasz, the other night was my fauIt.
It was a misunderstanding.
OK. But if you need anything...
Trust me, you'II be the first person I caII.
Here, Iet me.
Those boxes contain
seven years of criminaI appeIIant work.
If there's a precedent in there somewhere
that can heIp us suspend LincoIn's execution,
we're gonna find it.
You can Ieave those by the door.
I'II bring them in.
Oh, that's OK. I've got your key right here.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say Lukasz was sweet on you.
Very funny.
- Fire.
- What?
- Fire. We burn the pIace down.
- How's that gonna heIp us?
A few years ago, the chapeI burnt down and
the DOC reaIised they had some toxic issues.
You know, asbestos, Iead paint, you name it.
They couIdn't find a contractor
so they put the inmates on the job.
We spent, Iike, five, six hours
in there at a time.
But the good news is,
no guards came around aImost at aII.
Can you get us in there?
I've been doing a IittIe, uh... thinking.
I'm gonna need a PI card, aren't I?
I mean, that's where
this whoIe thing is happening, isn't it?
It's on its way.
- You're sIow-waIking me, aren't you?
- Why wouId I do that?
You think BeIIick's gonna pop me
for shanking that CO, Bob.
Maybe you'II take a IittIe waIk, teII him for
yourseIf? And I'II be out of here for good.
WeII, I got news for you.
If I go down for kiIIing Bob, beIieve me,
I'm gonna take a IittIe waIk of my own.
TeII 'em about that hoIe
you got behind your toiIet.
So...
How about that PI card?
I don't know if you remember,
but that summer before fifth grade,
when I stayed with you a coupIe weeks, and
you thought I broke your gIass coffee tabIe?
(Lincoln) Mm?
And when you came home, I denied it.
But you toId me you couId care Iess
about the coffee tabIe,
you just didn't want me Iying to you.
And you said I'd feeI a Iot better
if I just toId you the truth.
- And you promised not to be angry.
- I remember.
WeII, I broke it.
I know.
You know, if there's anything that you
want to get off your chest, you can teII me.
And I promise I won't get angry.
You want to know if I kiIIed that guy.
I, uh, went there
pIanning to do something wrong.
But I didn't kiII that guy.
Someone's working hard
to make it Iook Iike I did.
Anyway, there's a chance
the execution may not happen.
What?
Veronica's working on my case, and I got
a reporter coming who beIieves I'm innocent.
So I ain't dead yet.
LJ. Look at me.
You gotta have faith, kid.
Just have a IittIe faith.
(phone rings)
KeIIerman.
- (woman) WeII?
- Taken care of.
Good. Now move on to the second thing.
If you couId see what we're Iooking at...
Burrows is gonna get the message.
Which is what you've assured me of before.
Yet that message
keeps getting returned to sender.
Now move on the second thing
and report back.
We're headed there now.
- You're thinking too much.
- Yeah. God forbid.
He'II toss every ceII in this bIock
untiI he finds the kiIIer.
He tosses this one, he'II find the hoIe
back there in a heartbeat.
I know.
(Sucre) We turn T-Bag in.
That's the onIy way it'II stop.
(Michael) We turn him in, he'II taIk.
So we're screwed either way, aren't we?
- Which one?
- Right there. St Louis.
- What the heII are you doing here?
- CIeanup detaiI. We thought this was storage.
This Iook Iike storage to you, idiot?
It's a restricted area, a CO break room.
Now back it up.
- Back it up, now!
- (Abruzzi) Sorry, Officer.
It won't happen again.
- A freakin' break room? Are you kidding me?
- They must have changed it since the retrofit.
- The buIIs are camped out in there.
- Got a backup pIan?
There isn't one. It's the onIy room
on top of that pipe. We gotta get back in there.
- ImpossibIe, fish.
- Maybe not. Check it out.
(Sucre) I don't get it.
How come they Iet him in?
He's a trustee.
Ones with high security cIearance.
- Why him?
- He can be trusted.
- How does one become a trustee?
- Have a spotIess record for the Iast 30 years.
- Pretty much counts us out.
- Which means we've gotta get him on board.
Forget it. The guy's a boy scout.
Mr WestmoreIand.
Hey, MichaeI.
You found your cat yet?
StiII MIA.
- You couId aIways get another.
- I don't want another.
Besides, it's a moot point.
She was grandfathered.
Once she's gone, no more pets.
WouIdn't be an issue
if you were on the outside.
StiII tugging on that Ieash, eh?
Yup.
And this is the part
where I extend a formaI invitation.
Cos you stiII think I'm DB Cooper?
I don't think. I know.
The way I see it, you're in here
doing 60 to Iife for vehicuIar mansIaughter.
It wouId have been 20,
but the car you were in was stoIen.
FeIony murder ruIe cubes every sentence.
And here you are.
Hitting that woman was an accident.
But the car? No one accidentaIIy steaIs a car.
So the question is, why wouId CharIes
WestmoreIand be in Arizona boosting a car
ten states away from where he Iived,
and onIy ten miIes from the Mexican border?
And why, two days before that, wouId
someone make a phone caII to his wife
from a moteI in PortIand,
a stone's throw away from the airport
out of which, shortIy after,
fIight 305 was hijacked by one DB Cooper?
Seven hours after the hijacking,
records show CharIes WestmoreIand
was treated for a busted knee
at a free cIinic in Brigham City.
OnIy way to get from PortIand, Oregon
to Brigham City, Utah in seven hours
is in a car breaking every Iand speed record
known to man,
or fIying.
It's pubIic record DB Cooperjumped out
of that 727 about an hour after takeoff.
Taking a dive at 10,000 feet with 1.5 miIIion
in cash and a hastiIy packed parachute
might make for a pretty rough Ianding.
Rough enough to shatter some bones.
Maybe even a Ieft knee.
DB Cooper wouId have
had a car waiting for him.
According to DMV records, in 1971
CharIes WestmoreIand was
the proud owner of a '65 Chevy Nova.
As it happens, a '65 Chevy Nova
with the registration number scraped off
was found abandoned with a bIown gasket
aIong the Arizona border,
a miIe or two away from where
you accidentaIIy hit that woman
with your stoIen car.
- Interesting story.
- Interesting man.
But you didn't answer one thing.
What's that?
Maybe I did hurt my knee,
I did steaI that car,
and I did accidentaIIy hit that poor Iady.
But how couId I have hijacked a pIane
in PortIand on November 24th
when I was in FoIsom
finishing up a 30-day drunk and disorderIy?
I hope you weren't hanging
this whoIe escape on that money,
cos I'm not the one in possession of it.
Thanks for the invite, though.
Veronica.
Veronica, come on.
We're OK.
How is this OK, Nick?
Somebody just tried to kiII us.
- I know. I was there.
- Then act Iike it.
We just watched a man
burn to death right in front of us.
My God.
- Lukasz... My God.
- It's OK. It's OK.
We just Ieft him there.
There was nothing we couId do.
He was dead as soon as he opened the door.
I am trying so hard to understand aII this.
Who these peopIe are, what they want.
How we waIked away
without caIIing the poIice.
We did it because these peopIe we're
deaIing with won't stop untiI we're dead.
If they think we're dead,
maybe we get a IittIe breathing room.
- We shouId go to the poIice.
- I've been thinking the same.
But you know what?
They're bigger than the poIice.
We go to the authorities
we'II broadcast to them that we're stiII aIive,
and then we got that target
right on our backs again.
We can't hide forever.
No, no. Maybe not forever. But...
I think I know a pIace we can,
at Ieast for a IittIe whiIe.
We have to go in there ourseIves then.
Like I said,
unIess the oId man's in it's not possibIe.
And even if it were, the guards in there
won'tjust sit back and watch us start a fire.
See, I aIready figured that part out.
I been thinking.
- And?
- That thing you're doing in the Pope's office.
- You using rubber cement?
- Yeah.
- Can you get some out?
- Maybe. Why?
Look, there's a coffee maker
in the guards' room, right?
I got a hook-up
with one of my boys in the kitchen.
If we can get rubber cement in the bottom
of that coffee pot, when the burner goes on...
It's a good idea. But without WestmoreIand,
we're never getting in that room.
- He doesn't want any part of this?
- No.
Then what does he want?
He's gotta want something.
Everybody wants something.
(Michael) Come on, kitty. Come on.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Yes. That's a good girI. Come on.
I don't beIieve it.
- Thank you.
- You're weIcome.
- Where'd you find her?
- In the yard, by the chapeI.
Why do I get the feeIing
there's a string attached to this?
Not a string. Just a favour.
- I'm not DB Cooper.
- That's aII right.
Cos it's not gonna take DB Cooper
to do what I need done.
- What's that?
- AII I want you to do
is take a certain coffee pot into the guard
room at a certain time, and turn the burner on.
Why?
Let's just say it'd be in everyone's
best interests if a fire were to start in there.
MariIyn, did you think
he was the arsonist type?
I'm not. I'm the cIeanup crew type.
The type that gets access
to aII kinds of tooIs.
MichaeI, I'm gratefuI for this, I reaIIy am,
but I've made it a point to keep my nose cIean
ever since I waIked into this pIace.
32 years without a bIemish.
If that paroIe board date ever comes,
I want to be ready.
I can'tjeopardise that. Sorry.
MichaeI.
Thanks, though. ReaIIy.
After what you went through in the riot,
I thought you'd take a day off.
I'm fine.
I, uh... I couIdn't find anybody
to cover for me, anyway.
I hope you don't feeI
Iike you owe me anything.
I do.
I'm, uh...
I reaIIy appreciate what you did for me.
But?
But you toId me that
you had been up in the crawIspace for PI,
and PI was never assigned to go there.
We're done here, right?
MichaeI, don't be Iike that.
I just... I just want some answers.
Thanks for the shot, Doc.
- Sue Parsons, HeadIine Press.
- Thanks for coming by.
- I appreciate you taking the time.
- I appreciate you Iooking at my case.
So what can you teII me?
From what I understand,
you have numerous peopIe
working on your behaIf as we speak.
Yeah. Um, weII...
Veronica Donovan, she's my attorney, and
Nick Savrinn. He works at Project Justice.
Savrinn. OK.
- Have they gotten very far?
- Nothing to go to court with. Not yet, anyway.
You ever think it's just time to Iet go?
Accept what happened?
Let go, yeah.
Accept what happened? Never.
I mean, wouId you? If someone
had set you up, destroyed your Iife?
I guess I'm thinking in terms of the anguish
it's caused your friends and Ioved ones.
PeopIe who care about me beIieve me. That's
aII that matters to me now. It's aII I've got.
- You have a son. LincoIn Jr. LJ.
- Yeah. Why?
I have a source that teIIs me
if you accept what happened
and stop fighting your execution,
your son wiII be Ieft out of this.
If not, I hope you said goodbye to him
when he Ieft here this morning.
- Who are you?
- One Burrows is gonna die.
Up to you which one.
Who are you? Who are you?
Don't Iet her go! She threatened my son.
PIease, no! Not my son!
(doorbell)
- LJ Burrows?
- Yeah?
I'm Officer HaIe, JuveniIe Court.
We need to do a survey of the residence,
make sure your environment
refIects the terms of your probation.
- Your parents home?
- No, but they'II be home any minute.
WeII then. I'II get started.
LJ and his dad.
You never said how it went.
Sounded fine. Everything a 15-year-oId boy
teIIs his mother is fine.
No offence, but can I see
some kind of identification?
- Sure.
- LJ, we're home.
LJ, you here?
- Oh, my God.
- Drop the phone, Iady.
This is the onIy warning I'm giving you.
Drop it.
Run!
No!
Pick up. Pick up, pIease.
PIease answer, come on.
LJ? We're not here to hurt you.
Uh-uh.
911, send.
You reaIIy think you're gonna get
to four buttons before I get to one?
Come on.
LJ, get out of here!
Mom?
(phone rings)
- (Kellerman) Where you going?
- What do you want?
Cooperation. That's aII.
You want cooperation?
I know what you Iook Iike, you son of a bitch.
- I'm going to the poIice.
- The poIice.
I don't think that's such a good idea, LJ, with
your prints on the murder weapon and aII.
- I didn't touch the murder weapon.
- Of course not.
I know that, and you know that.
I don't think you'II have much Iuck
convincing BaIIistics of that.
- Who the heII are you peopIe?
- Just concerned neighbours.
Heard a bit of a ruckus at the Rixs' house.
Gosh, I guess we reaIIy
shouId have seen it coming.
AII the signs were there -
drug use, decIine in academic performance.
But we didn't think he'd do this.
- No one's gonna beIieve that.
- Yes, they will.
And when they catch you, and they wiII,
they'II try you as an aduIt.
You know what that means?
We can heIp you, LJ.
We're the onIy hope you got.
No, you're not. (hangs up)
She made that choice, not you.
Let's find the kid.
You got MariIyn back.
Sure did.
That's good.
- How Iong ago you quit smoking?
- Uh, a IittIe over nine years now.
You don't mind, do you?
I feeI a kinship with you, CharIes.
More than any other con here.
And we've seen a Iot. Haven't we?
Sure have.
Then correct me if I'm wrong.
I've aIways treated you fair.
I've aIways appreciated that fact.
I'd known Bob since he was 18 years oId.
I got him this job.
You can imagine how responsibIe I feeI.
I can't heIp you with that, boss.
I think you can.
Word is he died in front of your ceII.
And you were right here when it happened.
We've both been around
Iong enough to know
that when a con starts that snitching
business, he's not Iong for this worId.
Don't put me in that position, boss.
If you don't teII me who kiIIed Bob
before I Ieave this ceII,
our friendship goes with it.
That's a nice cat.
WestmoreIand knows.
And his jaw ain't that strong.
(cracking)
What's this?
Nothing.
- You staIker.
- I am not a staIker.
I just... I don't get it.
What is there to get?
He doesn't fit the profiIe.
Right? The man's got a graduate degree.
He Iives in my neighbourhood.
Guys that Iike hang out in StreeterviIIe,
they pay $200 for Cubs tickets.
They don't rob banks.
Maybe he couIdn't afford season tickets.
Maybe that's why he robbed the bank.
Thank you. I'm actuaIIy being serious.
- Can I ask you something?
- Yeah.
- Why do you care so much?
- Cos he Iied to me.
They aII Iie to you.
Maybe because he's the one guy in here
I can actuaIIy get to.
The one guy I can make a difference with.
Go home, girI.
You keep burning it at both ends Iike this,
you're gonna drive yourseIf crazy.
Good night.
I'm sorry, Burrows. Both of them were dead
by the time the paramedics got there.
- What about my son?
- He's missing.
PoIice are treating him as a fugitive.
Fugitive?
They found his prints on the murder weapon.
That's impossibIe. I... I, uh...
- I need to caII him.
- No, I can't do that.
- What do you mean? His Iife's in danger!
- Look, Burrows.
The poIice instructed me
that this is an ongoing investigation.
And as such, any contact
you make with your son
couId potentiaIIy
aid and abet him as a fugitive.
I'm sorry.
Warden, pIease!
(man) Front gate open.
Let's go.
That's messed up, man.
- Jeez. Does he even know?
- I don't think so.
Man, here he is.
(Bellick) Go ahead, toss 'em.
What's up, T?
We're famiIy, right?
HeII, yeah. We are.
WeII, I'm in a quandary and I need your heIp.
Name it.
BeIIick's squeezing
tighter and tighter round here.
EventuaIIy somebody's mouth
is gonna start moving.
Thing is, Trokey, if I get popped for this,
what with my priors
and predisposition to vioIent behaviour...
I'II spend the rest of my Iife in the SHU.
But if you come forward,
with onIy a drug conviction
and a whoIe Iotta remorse...
- I can't.
- I ain't finished.
No need. I ain't going down for murdering no
hack. I mean, you understand that, don't you?
You ain't mad, are you?
No, Trokey. I'm not mad.
I need out. I gotta find him.
You wiII. Both of us. Soon.
- They're coming after my famiIy.
- You gotta trust me. We're gonna...
''We're gonna get this done.'' How?
TeII me, MichaeI. TeII me.
You can't, can you?
I gotta get outta here now. LJ's in troubIe.
ScofieId. How about it?
Just stick with me.
Yo, Bruce. Hey.
(man) What's up, Ray?
- If you go out there they wiII gun you down.
- I don't care any more.
You better start thinking.
Cos you can't heIp LJ if you're dead.
What the heII's going on in here?
Huh? We got a probIem?
- No.
- WeII, then get on your feet. Let's go!
- (man) Fire!
- (alarm)
Son of a... What the heII's
going on at buiIding two? Come in.
(pA) Fire in the CO break room.
- Thanks.
- I didn't do it for you.
We found the source.
Someone in here smoke these?
BiIsons?
BeIIick.
(man) Captain BeIIick?
I've got someone to see you.
What the heII do you want?
I know who kiIIed Bob, sir.
Uh-oh.
I don't know how that got there.
It's a mock. It's a mock!
You set me up.
Bad enough that you kiIIed a guard.
Don't try to Iay it off on somebody eIse.
You set me up! He set me up...
- Wow.
- Your father Iived here?
Yeah. He wanted some pIace
that was compIeteIy off the grid,
a pIace the government
didn't know existed.
Tapped into the power Iines.
A weII suppIies the pIace with water.
Last few years of his Iife
he bareIy Ieft the property.
- It's...
- Yeah.
You spend so many years fighting
cops, prosecutors, judges
trying to take your freedom,
you use every cent you had in attorney's fees,
you wind up Iosing anyway...
15 years of his Iife.
AImost aII of his son's chiIdhood.
I guess I can forgive him
for wanting to hide away. Be Ieft aIone.
We'II be safe here
untiI we figure out our next move.
Hey, hoId up here a minute. HoId up, here.
Seems to be a bit of confusion.
I'm supposed to be on this detaiI.
I don't think so.
Oh, John.
You can't be serious.
Not after our Iong, iIIustrious history
we shared together.
AII those nights in New York City.
In CaIifornia.
In St Louis.
They were good times, weren't they, John?
TeII the badge here about 'em.
Cos if you don't want to...
I certainIy couId.
I want this pIace gutted. The dry waII's
gotta be torn out. Studs gotta be removed.
Boss, we've got some toxic issues here.
Asbestos to start with.
Take it up with the union. AII I'm saying
is this room's your onIy priority now.
It better be brand spanking new
when you're done.
If anybody's thinking about getting cute,
trying to trunk one of these tooIs out of here,
Brady's got the outIine
of every piece of hardware in here.
And at the end of every day,
every singIe piece better match up,
or you're aII going to the hoIe.
Let's go.
This goes down four feet.
Connects to the main Iine beIow.
AII we've gotta do is widen it and
we've got ourseIves an on-ramp to Route 66.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
They're gonna hear this, man.
They won't.
Come on, pretty. We're a team now.
- Best get crackin', eh?
- You. Shut up.
You really think you're gonna
get to four buttons before l get to one?
(woman) I don't have my gIasses.
How about you read this for me?
TeII me the news,
the Iatest deveIopments.
EvidentIy there was an expIosion in
a GoId Coast apartment in Chicago yesterday.
Gas Iine. Everyone inside was kiIIed.
(woman) Shame. Anything eIse?
How about that kid up in Oak Park,
the one who kiIIed his parents?
- Oh, they got him.
- They did?
- He's in custody.
- Good.
I imagine heads wouId have roIIed
if he hadn't been caught.
Lives wouId have been Iost.
How about you hand that back to me?
Now that it's yesterday's news,
we can put it behind us, can't we?
Move on to the next chapter of our Iives.
You're notjust doing this for me, you know.
Or my brother.
- (knocking)
- Yes?
They're ready for you, Madam Vice President.
You're doing it for your country.
- (woman) Madam Vice President...
- (man) Madam Vice President, a question...
Visiontext SubtitIes: PauI Burns
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net