(HORNS HONKING)
SCOFIELD: Rough night?
I got your message. What's the probIem?
Lost my keys.
-Where'd you find them?
-Four feet that way.
Must've dropped them.
(GRUNTING)
How you doing? It's been a whiIe.
Fine. How are you?
CoId.
Man, I...
I need to taIk to you about something.
-Grab some Iunch at Fascetti's?
-I have to get back to work.
Speaking of which,
I heard you got fired a few weeks ago.
What was it this time?
You reaIIy want to know?
Or are you just enjoying the view
from your high horse?
You know what I want?
To not have to be the oIder brother
to my oIder brother.
What you doing here, Crab?
Long time no see, Mr. Linc.
Where you been?
-Here and there.
-Mmm-hmm.
I'm gonna get your 90 grand, aII right?
Oh, reIax, man,
that debt aIready been paid.
-By who?
-Someone who Iikes to do peopIe favors.
I don't know what it is
you think you're getting,
but Iet's be cIear about something.
It's gonna be a few days
before I get the money Iined up.
Let's not kid ourseIves.
You can't get anywhere
near that kind of money.
So Iet's taIk about
what you can do for me.
REYNOLDS,， (ON TV) Allies are like family,
We have disagreements,
but we always seem to
smooth things out by Thanksgiving,
Okay, if you had to choose,
Vice President ReynoIds or Kathy in HR?
-I'II take door number three.
-Come on. If you had to choose.
That chick in HR.
MichaeI never cared much for bIondes.
-V.
-How you doing, MichaeI?
Good. I'm good. How are you?
I'm okay.
You know, I'm over at GIazer and Ross.
Lawyer number 97. Benefits are good.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON SOUND SYSTEM)
How's LincoIn?
You guys haven't taIked?
No, not for a few years.
He kind of dropped off the radar.
How is he?
He's...
He's Linc.
I don't care who the guy is.
I ain't kiIIing no one.
I must have missed the part
where I gave you a choice.
HALE: BIack Ieather jacket.
Two buttons down the front,
three on each sIeeve.
One missing on his right... No, Ieft arm.
Jeans. Faded.
Stain on the Ieft knee.
He does bad things to good peopIe.
Think of this as a $90,000 buIIet.
You start fresh,
and you keep me from finding out
if there's someone in your Iife
you wiII do something for.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, I shouId caII you a cab.
You know how you can teII God is a man?
Shoes.
Easy.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I'm sorry.
VERONICA: What?
It's...
You gonna answer it?
He'II Ieave a message.
He aIways does.
MichaeI, it's Linc.
I need your heIp, bro.
I'm in something reaI bad.
I can't get out of it.
(SIGHING) I need you to straighten me out.
My head is aII messed up and...
Anyway, it's reaI important, bro.
You gotta caII me.
You gotta caII me now.
I can't do this.
I know.
I'II caII you a cab.
(FOOT CRUSHING CIGARETTE)
-Did we get him?
-I beIieve we did, partner.
(CHATTERING)
(LAUGHING)
SUCRE: Are you kidding me?
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
MANCHE: Nando, we shouId've
whooped that guy's ass.
PIease. OnIy time I seen you
whoop some ass
is when that oId man
cut in front of you at Arby's.
(CHUCKLES ) Yeah,
and he was Iike 102 and bIind.
MANCHE: With a pIastic hip.
Oh, my God.
What?
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
WOMAN,， (ON PA) Dr, Davis, telephone,
please, Dr, Davis, telephone, please,
-Hey, they're waiting for you in 4B.
-Oh, puII his fiIm.
-I'II be there in a minute.
-Okay.
Sergeant FrankIin,
you never cease to amaze me.
Is there anything you can't get here?
AII right, a deaI's a deaI.
Prison guard duty. Away from the front.
Safest pIace you couId be.
Thank you.
And my wife and daughter
back home thank you too, sir.
These coaI seams are pretty significant.
-Hey.
-Hi.
WouId you give us a minute? Thanks.
Have you been watching the news?
-Why?
-It's LincoIn.
-I didn't do it.
-Terrence Steadman.
The Vice President's brother.
Do you have any idea
what they're gonna do to you?
I didn't do it, man. It was a setup.
I didn't do it.
You knew him.
-Who?
-Steadman.
No.
-You worked for his company.
-So what?
From which you were fired
a few weeks ago.
I Ioaded containers in the warehouse.
Never met the guy. What the heII, Mike?
You sound Iike
one of the damn detectives.
-I'm just saying.
-You think I did it?
I heard you owe someone 90 grand.
-Who toId you that?
-PeopIe taIk.
And I know Steadman had a Iot of money.
I may be a Iot of things,
but I'm not a murderer.
Then what were you doing
in that garage Iast night?
You admitted to the poIice you were there.
HonestIy, Linc,
I don't know how it's come to this.
And you can't keep
bIaming Mom for dying
and Dad for Ieaving,
because I was there, too.
Difference is, I got out.
Mom had Iife insurance.
I took my haIf, put myseIf through schooI.
What did you do with your haIf, Linc?
Everything's not how it Iooks, MichaeI.
I hope for your sake that's true.
Here...
-Here is where we want the turn to anger.
-Trust me, that won't be a probIem.
Now remember to stress his record
as a repeat offender.
We need the pubIic behind us
if we want the death penaIty.
And where are we
with Governor Tancredi?
He has aspirations. He won't be a probIem.
MAN: Thirty seconds,
Madam Vice President.
VERONICA: The papers
have aIready crucified him.
The poIice say they got a phone caII
right after the murder
from someone cIaiming they saw LincoIn
running from the parking garage.
He was into someone for 90 grand.
What do you need that kind of money for?
Drugs, bribes?
Forget about what you want to be true.
Let's Iook at this objectiveIy.
-Maybe you shouId too.
-I am.
AII right, you know what?
I promised I wouIdn't say anything,
but I'm getting tired of you
taIking about him
Iike he's some guy from the neighborhood
that you used to know.
-He's your brother.
-I know.
And I know he heIped you out
with your dad back in the day,
but you shouId see
the kind of person he is now,
the kind of peopIe he keeps friends with.
You want to know
what the 90 grand was for?
-I think I do.
-You.
What do you mean?
The money you got
when you were 18 years oId
from your mother's Iife insurance?
The money that paid for your degree,
that got you this job,
that bought you your Ioft?
Your mother never had Iife insurance.
That money came from LincoIn.
-How?
-He borrowed it.
He knew it wouId be tough to pay back,
but that didn't matter,
because he thought you deserved it.
He aIso knew you'd never accept it
if you knew it came from him.
MichaeI, you are where you are
because of your brother.
You're teIIing me
he is where he is because of me?
Why?
Why didn't you teII me about the money?
-No need to.
-Oh, Linc.
Who toId you? Veronica?
What did she make of aII this? About me?
-I don't know.
-GIad she got out when she did, huh?
You know how she feeIs about you.
It's been the same way
ever since we were kids.
Yeah.
Linc,
-I owe you an apoIogy.
-For what?
The night you caIIed.
If we'd taIked,
-maybe I couId have stopped you.
-Hey, hey, hey, hey.
This ain't your fauIt.
Then who's is it?
Listen up. You need to forget about this.
Move on. Work hard. Do what you do.
I can't do that.
Oh, yes, you can. And you wiII.
Here's the part I don't understand.
All the evidence is lining up
in a path that leads directly to you,
They say they have you on tape.
Pulling the trigger,
If you didn't kiII Terrence Steadman,
how the heII did someone
make it Iook Iike you did?
Perfect.
MANCHE: Perfect's a strong word, coz.
SUCRE: I got strong feeIings, bro.
I'm teIIing you, she might be the one.
-She from the bIock?
-Nope. Uptown. PiII HiII.
(CHUCKLING)
You think you couId hoId on
to a girI from the PH?
I want to take her out to dinner.
You'II see. SomepIace reaI nice.
Come on, Fernando.
How are you going to afford
a pIace Iike that?
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
-Open the drawer!
-Hey, hey, okay!
-Open the drawer, co┰o!
-Okay, okay!
-Quick! Quick!
-AII right, okay!
-Now!
-Here.
ActuaIIy, this is aII I need.
Okay.
C-NOTE,， l appreciate your business, man,
I'II have that in here for you
about next week.
(CHUCKLING)
(WHISTLING)
(MAN SHOUTING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(ELECTRICAL JOLTING)
(MAN GROANING EX CRUCIATINGLY)
(SARA EX CLAIMING)
I brought you a gift from the hospitaI.
I'm teIIing you, it is Iike Christmas.
(LAUGHING)
And you work at the North PoIe.
If the North PoIe had gunshot wounds
and cancer patients...
SeriousIy, I don't know
how you work there.
What do you mean?
SARA: I Iike to heIp peopIe.
You Iike heIping yourseIf.
(SARA LAUGHS )
And you Iike heIping your friends.
(HORN HONKING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(THUDDING)
Oh, my God.
WOMAN: Can you hear us? Are you okay?
(ALL CLAMORING)
Can you hear us? Are you okay?
(DlSTORTED VOlCE) Help, somebody!
Who"s got a telephone? Call 91 1!
Oh, my God! Can anybody heIp...
CaII 91 1 ! HeIp!
Are you a doctor?
Can you help him?
WeII, do something!
At ease.
The whiskey that you ordered, sir,
wiII be here in a coupIe of days.
That's fine. I actuaIIy brought you here
to taIk to you about something eIse.
-Prisoner-abuse report you fiIed?
-Yes, sir.
I need to know how far
you're wiIIing to go with this.
Whatever it takes, sir.
I particuIarIy have no Iove
for the desert donkeys,
but I do have some
for the Geneva Convention.
Something Iike this gets out,
it might open up our boys
-to simiIar treatment from the enemy.
-I understand that, sir.
But I'm not pIanning
on caIIing a press conference.
What I'm saying is,
what I saw was wrong,
and someone
needs to take responsibiIity for it, sir.
AII right.
PIease take Mr. FrankIin into custody.
Yes, sir.
What? What the heII is going on, sir?
Sergeant FrankIin,
I'm hereby recommending
that you be dishonorabIy discharged
from the United States Army.
-What? For what?
-For engaging in iIIegaI bIack-market...
-You asked me to get that stuff, man!
-I kept it to myseIf.
Maybe you shouId Iearn to do the same.
You can't do this.
You can't do this! You cannot do this!
(GAVEL BANGING)
Has the jury reached a verdict?
-We have, Your Honor.
-What say you?
In the matter of The People
of the State of lllinois vs, Lincoln Burrows,
on the count of murder in the first degree,
we find the defendant guiIty.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
The defendant wiII remain in custody
untiI one week from today,
when we commence the penaIty phase.
LincoIn.
I'm so sorry, Linc.
Don't be. It's not your fauIt.
Know what I Iike?
How after we make Iove,
you get this IittIe puddIe of water
in your beIIy button.
Fernando, that's sweat.
And get out of there! It's disgusting there!
I think it's beautifuI.
(RAZZING)
I think you're beautifuI.
What do you want, Fernando?
Oh, you got to give me
a few more minutes...
Stop.
From the future.
What do you want from the future?
WouId you run if I said ''you''?
WouId you chase me if I did?
DARlUS,， l don"t get it,
AII these commerciaIs show brothers
Iearning computer skiIIs,
new technoIogies.
UncIe Sam didn't teach me nothing
but cadence and kiII.
-You check over at the Price-Mart?
-Ain't hiring.
EspeciaIIy with a brother
with a dishonorabIe discharge.
Goes right to the bottom of the piIe, man.
How Iong you think you can keep this up?
UntiI somebody gives me a job.
No, I'm taIking about Iying to Kaycee.
Your unit's been on Ieave
for a Iong damn time now.
Pretty soon they gonna stop thinking
you're Iucky,
and she's gonna start asking questions.
Yeah, weII, then I need to start
finding some answers.
Look, I happen to know
of an empIoyment opportunity.
Come on, man, you know
I don't get down Iike that.
-It's just driving a truck.
-Yeah.
A to B. That's it.
UncIe Sam taught you
how to drive trucks, didn't he?
Yeah. And he aIso taught me
to Iook inside.
It might be iIIegaI, but it's aIso rent.
A to B, your caII.
Yeah.
-They didn't even Iet her testify.
-Who?
Leticia Barris.
And that cop?
-Changed his story a dozen times.
-What part of ''move on'' don't you get?
After Mom died,
when it was just you and me,
I remember having troubIe sIeeping.
Never knowing where you were.
But when I'd wake up in the morning,
there'd be this paper bird,
an origami crane, sitting next to my bed.
And I never knew what it meant exactIy,
but I figured it was your way
of Ietting me know
you were checking in on me.
Anyway,
I Iooked it up.
The crane.
It stands for famiIiaI obIigation.
Watching out for your own.
Maybe it's my turn to watch out for you.
So same time tomorrow.
No, man,
they're transferring me to a prison
where I'II wait untiI they execute me.
-Can I stiII visit?
-Yeah.
It ain't that far. PIace caIIed Fox River.
-Fox River?
-Yeah.
Why?
Nothing.
How come there's four?
WeII, Mommy's new friend
is coming over for dinner again.
(GROANING)
Again? He just came over Iast night.
-I Iike him.
-WeII, I do, too.
And I want you both to be extra poIite,
because he's stopping by MaIarkey's
on his way home from work,
and he's bringing us a reaIIy good meaI.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
In fact, you two go wash your hands.
Evening, Mrs. HoIIander.
Don't you Iook IoveIy this evening.
(DOGS BARKING)
SUCRE: I'm gonna do it.
Do what?
I'm gonna propose to Maricruz.
Are you serious?
When?
As soon as I can afford the ring.
So what, Iike 10, 20 years?
What's your probIem, man?
Why can't you just be happy for me?
I'm just trying to protect you.
What, you think you can give her
everything she wants?
Takes more than money to do that.
You know I Iove you, coz.
Just think
you shouId Iook at the reaIity here.
SeriousIy, primo,
how are you gonna afford
a ring for a girI Iike that, huh?
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
-Open the door!
-Hey, okay, okay!
Oye, co┰o, now!
Hey, this fine?
ActuaIIy, I'm gonna need
a IittIe bit more this time.
Okay, okay.
Here you go.
-I'm sorry.
-Okay.
(SIREN WAILING)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
-Anyone asking questions?
-Not Ioud enough to hear.
God,
I can't remember the Iast time
I was this much of a nervous wreck.
SchooI board, second term, 1992?
SecIuded, no reaI access roads,
perfect for what you're Iooking for.
OnIy one probIem.
-What's that?
-It's over $2 miIIion.
WeII, didn't my poor brother, Terrence,
Ieave something for me in his wiII?
You'd have to ask
your accountants, ma'am.
TeII them to use that money.
I'm paying for his mistake.
He can pay for the damn house.
And I've been cIean for 18 months now.
I'II teII you, I've never been happier.
That actuaIIy might be the wrong word.
I'II be honest,
there were times I was using,
I feIt pretty damn happy.
But what I feeI is different now. I feeI...
I feeI joy.
So here I am. I know that
aII I can do every day
is the next right thing.
And I think for me right now,
that means going back to work.
I...
I don't know, maybe counseIing.
I want to heIp peopIe
get from where I've been to where I am.
Hey, Sara.
You used to be a doctor, right?
-I stiII am, in theory. Why?
-WeII, I was just thinking,
I might know of a job opening
where I work.
ReaIIy? Where's that?
-You ever heard of Fox River?
-The prison?
Yeah. I know it sounds Iike a strange idea.
Maybe...
Maybe you and I couId...
Maybe we couId taIk about it over dinner.
I got a gift card to the Red Lobster
over off the interstate.
Oh, my God.
Thank you. ReaIIy.
I...
Tonight's kind of my night
to work on my resume.
Yeah.
-Of course.
-Sorry, I...
But thank you, reaIIy, for the referraI.
Fox River.
Yeah.
(SIREN WAILING)
You know,
math was never my best subject, either.
But I got through it
by Iearning some new tricks.
-You want to Iearn some tricks, Gracey?
-Like what?
Like your nine-times tabIes.
Ready? Nine times one is...
Nine.
-Nine times two is...
-Eighteen.
Nine times three is...
Twenty-seven!
ExactIy. You got it. Now keep on going.
Mommy, Mommy,
did you see what Teddy taught me?
Yes. That's great, honey.
Go show your brother.
-Zack, Iook. Nine times one...
-Thank you.
Nine?
GRACEY: Nine times two?
ZACK: Eighteen.
Nine times three?
Nine times four?
MAN,， (ON TV) Welcome back to
America's Most Wanted.
Right, right, Ieft, Ieft, right, right.
Right, right, Ieft, Ieft.
Left.
Left, Ieft, right, Ieft right, boiIer room,
Ieft, Ieft, Ieft, right.
Left, Ieft...
(SIGHING)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
-There you go.
-Hey. Thank you.
Let me get your change.
Do you want your change?
Keep it.
DEDE: And this is his.
(SIGHING)
Love it. That's different.
-Hey.
-Daddy!
-Hey, sweetheart.
-Come here.
-Hey, there.
C-NOTE: Hey.
You know I got...
I got to teII you something,
and it's gonna be reaIIy hard to hear.
Okay.
What?
WeII, the thing is,
I'm being shipped back off.
-What?
-Yeah.
My unit just got caIIed back
for another tour, baby.
(SIGHING) I can't beIieve it.
DepIoyment orders just came down.
You know, with the ItaIians
puIIing out and everything.
TeII them no, Daddy.
DARIUS: Yo, B.
KAYCEE: Come here.
Can you give me a hand
with something out back?
Okay.
(SIGHING)
That's my sister you Iied to in there.
Which is why I know you're going to
take care of them when I'm gone.
This is crazy.
Maybe. But so is the way
I got kicked out of the Army.
So is the way
I got busted for driving that truck.
And so is the way
I feeI about that woman up in there.
She married a miIitary man
who knows
how to take care of his business.
Now if I Iook Iike one of these thugs, now,
what do think she's going to do? Huh?
How Iong do you think
she's going to wait for me
whiIe I'm inside?
I don't know, man.
You owe me this, man.
Don't you ever Iet her know where I am.
Do you feeI me?
UsuaIIy, I do this the other way.
-Why do you want to...
-I want what I want.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON SOUND SYSTEM)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
You show this to anyone eIse,
I am caIIing the whoIe thing off.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
My therapist said...
She said that I'm hoIding too much in
and that I need to confront you
to Iet you know how betrayed I feeI.
I Iet you into my Iife,
my home,
my God, I Iet you near my chiIdren!
-I never touched them.
-You shouId have toId me what you were.
You think that you're the onIy one
who feeIs betrayed?
I Ioved you, Susan.
ReaI Iove.
For the first time in my Iife.
(SNIFFLES )
And then to have you do me Iike that,
to just throw me out to the dogs,
just toss me out the back door...
-You're a murderer, Teddy!
-That's enough!
I have sinned in the past,
but when I met you,
that person, the one that did
aII those terribIe things, he died.
And I was reborn.
By the grace of your Iove, I was a...
A new man. A better man.
No.
That doesn't just erase the man
who kiIIed six students in AIabama.
I guess that's where you're right.
Because when you sent me here
to this pIace, with these peopIe,
it brought that oId dirty bastard
right back home.
In fact, there was a candIe
in the window
just waiting for me
to waIk up them front steps.
You know, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna get out of here someday.
And when I do,
don't think I won't remember
what your front steps Iook Iike, Susan.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
It's aImost over.
Burrows wiII be dead soon
and then things wiII start
getting back to normaI.
I know that you've been through a Iot,
but I promise you
the worst is now behind us.
My dear sister,
you have no idea what I've been through.
Good night, Terrence.
www.tvsubtitles.net