previously on ''prison Break'':
(Michael) Think of this pIace Iike a map of the
US. Our ceII over there, that's New York City.
The infirmary, our exit, that's CaIifornia.
The pipes beneath us that connect the two...
- Route 66.
- Our ticket out of here.
Route 66 runs beneath that buiIding. It's the
onIy buiIding sitting on top of those tunneIs.
AII we gotta do is get in there,
on PI, and dig ourseIves an onramp.
- Which one?
- Right there.
This goes down four feet.
Connects to the main Iine beIow.
AII we've gotta do is widen it and
we've got ourseIves an onramp to Route 66.
I'm gonna find out, you know,
what it is you're doing up there.
You toId me that
you had been up in the crawIspace for PI,
and PI was never assigned to go there.
We got you a IittIe get weII gift.
What's your name?
There was an expIosion.
Gas Iine. Everyone inside was kiIIed.
- These peopIe won't stop untiI we're dead.
- We can't hide forever.
(Vp) How about that kid?
The one kiIIed his parents?
(Kellerman) Oh, they got him. He's in custody.
I know what you Iook Iike, you son of a bitch.
PhiIIy FaIzone.
Word is someone knows where Fibonacci is
and you're not doing anything about it.
(Cherry) HeIp me.
PIease.
(T-Bag clears throat)
You'II have to forgive my boy.
He has the propensity to be a bit gregarious
when he shouIdn't be.
Fraternising in the prison shower. Come on.
Maybe you oughta cut the kid a break.
You wouIdn't be meddIing in my affairs,
now, wouId you?
You can't be that stupid.
Not whiIe I'm so fuIIy invested in your affairs.
What's between you and him
is between you and him.
That's what I thought you said.
You've gotta heIp me.
- (Lincoln) You gotta heIp me.
- This is a matter for the poIice.
This is my son we're taIking about.
He's missing. Do something!
You have got to understand,
I am the warden of a prison.
When it comes to the Iaw,
there is nothing I can do.
Whatever happens is out of my jurisdiction
untiI it comes through those gates.
- Itjust did. Let me out.
- What?
Let me find him. I know how he thinks.
I know where he'd run.
I'd have thought by now you'd understand
your position as a death row inmate.
There is no way I can honour that request.
That ain't true. In case of a famiIy emergency,
you can grant an inmate supervised Ieave.
Your son is a prime suspect
in a doubIe homicide.
Hey.
What do you think this is, a siesta?
You see that? You see my face up there?
Any idea how it got there?
Work ethic. Those two words
mean anything in your country?
You're on PI, so quit sIow-waIking me.
I'm not gonna warn you again.
What are you Iooking at?
The buIIs find this stuff,
they'II know we're digging.
That's why we gotta get rid of it.
One piece at a time.
(pA) Attention in the yard.
All prisoners remain 40ft away from gate A.
New prisoners arriving in fve minutes.
l repeat, attention in the yard.
All prisoners remain 40ft away from gate A.
New prisoners arriving in fve minutes.
Attention in the yard. All prisoners maintain
a 40ft perimeter around gate A.
Freshmen.
Best put on ourjaiI face, BG.
These crabs see you puckering,
they bitchify you in a heartbeat.
(satisfed grunt)
- I gotta find something eIse to caII you now.
- Why's that?
Cos you ain't a fish no more.
You ain't the newest con in the tank.
(Michael) I couId've done something.
(Lincoln) No.
T-Bag had his hooks in that kid.
There was nothing you couId have done.
I couId've toId the Pope.
He couId've transferred the kid to ADSEG.
Go easy, MichaeI. You didn't even know him.
And that makes it OK? I turned my back
on him because I didn't wanna make waves.
It was just... easier
to Iook the other way,
keep the pIan safe.
And you did.
But at what price?
That's not how she raised us.
A man's down, you give him your hand.
She'd roII over in her grave if she knew.
She wouIdn't.
You've given me your hand, MichaeI.
My son's out there
with a buII's eye on his back.
Do whatever you gotta do
to get us out of here. PIease.
(police siren)
(Nick) What are you doing?
I was just Iooking for some coffee.
There isn't any.
They beIonged to my father,
if you were wondering.
- How Iong have they been in there?
- I don't know. Five years?
You know, Veronica, we've been through a Iot
and I'm freaking out here as much as you are,
but you get this Iook in your eye sometimes
Iike... Iike I'm the bad guy.
I don't know who you are. You just magicaIIy
show up Iike some knight in shining armour.
You know, I think
you seem to be forgetting something here.
I'm in the cross hairs the same way you are,
aII for your ex, who is a scumbag criminaI
who just happens to be in prison
for the one crime he didn't commit.
You know something? I got enough of my
own crap to deaI with. You wanna go, you go.
- Mind if I Iamp with you, cuzzo?
- RoII, snowfIake.
Hey, man, I'm just... I'm just new, you know?
I'm Iooking for some homies.
- I said roII.
- Brother, I'm just Iaunching.
Yeah? WeII, Iaunch somewhere eIse,
white boy.
AII right, y'aII.
I'm fitting to bounce.
Peace.
Boy's a bit confused about his pigmentation,
but he sure does have spunk, doesn't he?
- Abruzzi!
- Yeah?
What are you doing?
What do you mean, what am I doing?
- First of the month's coming up, John.
- Yeah? So?
I haven't got my monthIy.
- What?
- I checked my baIance. It's Iooking deficient.
Uh...
It's gotta be some kind of a mistake,
Iike an accounting error.
Yeah. TeII FaIzone
I don't stand for accounting errors.
I'm going back into my office at the end of
the day. Gonna check my baIance again.
If it's not up to where it's supposed to be,
aII these priviIeges you got,
Iike running PI,
they're gone.
Get it done, John.
- (woman) Falzone Enterprises.
- Get PhiIIy.
- Mr Falzone's not available.
- You teII him it's John Abruzzi caIIing.
- l'm sorry. l didn't realise.
- WeII, now you do.
Um...
- l'm sorry. He's gonna have to call you back.
- What? Hey...
(line goes dead)
I'm sorry. About before.
Pressure's getting to us, that's aII.
Good news is nobody can reach us out here.
My oId man made sure of that.
Never even hooked up the teIephone.
Same with the weII and the generator.
I used to think he was
some kind of conspiracy theory wacko.
- Turns out maybe he was right.
- I can't stay, Nick.
I gotta get back. He's got Iess than two weeks.
The oId man caIIed this his serious tie.
He onIy wore it
when he reaIIy, reaIIy meant business.
Be dangerous showing our faces again.
Not if they're not Iooking for us.
They think we're dead.
Yeah, but how Iong is that gonna Iast?
Gotta be quick, be smart about it.
We're just gonna be running in circIes
if we think we can find excuIpatory evidence
before the execution.
I've gone up against every prosecutor
in Cook County.
Man gets murdered, the first person they
taIk to to see who his enemies were, the wife.
- You wanna go after the queen bee herseIf?
- LesIie Steadman.
Everyone in town knows the oId bird
Iunches at the Lexington every day
with the society set.
Hey, hey. Hey, hey!
SIow down. SIow down!
Man, your brother's gonna give us away.
- BuII's coming.
- (Abruzzi) Let's move.
Hurry up, guys. Move it.
- AII right.
- Everybody out.
- What?
- I said everybody out.
Now.
Move it!
- Where are we going?
- Around the corner.
And don't move a damn muscIe
tiII I come get you. Go!
What the heII's going on?
- We're so bad, aren't we?
- You're damn skippy. Let's go.
- You gotta give us more of a warning.
- I'm sorry. He just showed up.
Mm. Mm. Mm.
Oh, we're gonna get caught
by the warden. Oh!
(guard) Baby, right now,
in this room, at this moment,
- I am the warden.
- Oh!
- (guard) Then say it.
- No.
- (guard) Come on, baby, say it.
- Oh!
- (guard) Say it.
- You're the warden, Louis!
(guard) Yes, yes.
The sneaky son of a bitch.
You think he found the hoIe?
Another inch and he'd have found it. We need
to find something to cover this hoIe ASAP.
(Abruzzi) Broke. What do you mean, broke?
The C-Corp, the investment accounts,
even the offshore stuff, Caymans, Bermuda...
PhiIIy FaIzone Iiquidated everything.
Hey, I toId you from the beginning
what wouId happen if you screwed me.
I heeded it. That's why I warned you from the
get-go not to give PhiIIy power of attorney.
We had that conversation, remember?
Look, the onIy reaI funds you have Ieft
are the 30,000 in your wife's pocket account.
- Now, I can...
- Don't. Don't touch that.
Nobody touches that but her.
What do I teII her? You know, about aII this?
Don't teII her anything, OK?
The statements are going to come.
She's going to know.
Hey, I toId you.
Don't teII her.
AII right?
You got a probIem with that?
OK, John. You know where to contact me
if you need anything eIse.
The same goes for you.
Hey.
Hey!
- PhiIIy.
- You.
So good to see you.
For you, the answer's aIways yes, PhiIIy.
Sit down.
- Sit down.
- (guard) Come on, John.
There's no record
of a Fox River medicaI practice
on our Iist of participating HMOs or PPOs.
That's because we're a state penitentiary,
and we're in kind of a unique situation here.
Mr ScofieId's insurance poIicy
from his previous empIoyer hasn't Iapsed.
The state's demanding that you pay
for his treatment and not the taxpayers.
OK. Well, it says here
he already met his deductible.
OK.
Oh, no, wait. That's his psych deductibIe,
not his medicaI.
Sorry. Psych as in psychiatric?
Did I give you permission to caII PhiIIy?
Hey, I asked you a question, man.
Listen. There, uh...
there's been a restructuring.
This comes from PhiIIy himseIf.
You couIdn't deIiver Fibonacci,
so I'm the man in here now.
Run to the commissary and get me a packet
of chips. We'II pretend this never happened.
No, I'm teIIing you, John. The sooner you face
these facts, the better off we wiII aII be.
I can kiII you in a heartbeat.
Somehow, I doubt that.
The sooner you face facts,
the better off we wiII aII be.
You're yesterday's news, John.
- What's the word? Y'aII cooking brownies?
- Act your race, miIk chicken.
What's the deaI, yo?
You got tough buckets or something?
You're a disgrace to your skin,
you know that?
The boy just sIipped.
Ain't that right?
- Come on. Stand up.
- (guard) Cons, Iet's get back to your ceIIs.
What's your name, boy?
- Who's that?
- StoIte.
StoIte. You've heard about my kid, right?
- Take the tray, Linc.
- I, uh....
I just need to caII him.
Just take the tray, or I'm gonna shove it
in there and you can eat it off the ground.
You have a son. Josh.
Don't do anything stupid, Linc.
I'm not. I just wanna ask you a question,
then I'm gonna Iet go.
What if it were Josh?
What if it were your son?
PIease.
(phone rings)
- Dad?
- LJ. Thank God. Are you aII right?
No. Nowhere near it.
- What do you mean? Where are you?
- What they're saying about me, it's not true.
- I know it's not true.
- They killed her. They killed her.
Right in front of me.
Right in front of my eyes.
- You gotta...
- Why are they doing this?
You gotta step up. You gotta be the man now.
- You understand me, LJ?
- Yeah.
- OK. I want you to caII Veronica.
- Her number is disconnected. I aIready tried.
Nick Savrinn. You caII Nick Savrinn.
Works for Project Justice.
You caII him once we're done. You got it?
Nick Savrinn. OK.
- OK, I'II caII. I'II caII.
- AII right, man.
Hang in there, man. lt's gonna be all right.
Hey...
- They're here.
- Who's here?
LJ?
LJ!
(phone vibrates)
(cocks gun)
You hear that?
Did you hear it?
You know what that means?
Why don't you ask your mom what it means?
Oh, I'm sorry. You might have troubIe getting
an answer out of her right about now, huh?
LJ?
(car horn)
- I saw that.
- Just getting connected, that's aII.
There she is.
Mrs Steadman? I'm Dick SisIer.
This is Francette KeIIy
of the NationaI Victims' Rights Association.
We assist victims of vioIent crimes, gather
support for tough-on-crime poIiticians.
If your organisation's Iooking for a hand-out,
you can go through my business manager.
Ma'am, that is not why we're here, actuaIIy.
May we sit down?
We hoped you couId heIp us with one of our
more pubIic cases. The LincoIn Burrows case.
He's making cIaims that he's innocent, that
others had motive to murder your husband.
- I don't have time for a Iong conversation.
- It doesn't have to be Iong.
If we taIked about who had motive
to kiII Terrence, we'd be here aII day.
- I'm sorry?
- Look around.
HaIf the peopIe here
were sharehoIders in his company.
Every one of them
sat at my husband's memoriaI
and every one of them was thinking
the same thing: ''Thank God he's gone.''
- Why wouId they think that?
- Money.
As soon as rumours of the indictment started,
they ran for the exits.
- I wasn't aware of any indictment.
- It never came down. He died first.
- Anything to do with EcofieId?
- Do the math. CEO gets indicted for fraud.
Investors start Iosing money. Lots of money.
If I didn't know Burrows puIIed that trigger,
I'd say it was any one of these peopIe in the
restaurant. We're taIking haIf a biIIion doIIars.
PeopIe have kiIIed for a Iot Iess.
Hey, what's up? 'Sup?
(T-Bag) Not a good position
you find yourseIf in, is it?
Whites don't want you. BIacks don't want you.
You're just caught in the middIe, aren't you?
A reguIar 'tweener.
We're different, you and me, Iot of ways.
But, you know,
the funny thing is we're aIso a Iot aIike.
CoupIe of dogs with runny noses
that nobody Ioves.
How's that knee, by the way?
- What the heII are you doing?
- Don't get me wrong. I'm just a friend.
- A fruity friend. I don't need none of that.
- Easy.
No. No. You think you're getting up in this,
you got another thing coming, you homo.
- You got a fouI mouth, you know that?
- Yeah. I do.
And you come near me again,
I'm gonna kiII you.
WeII, then,
you're just gonna have to, IittIe man.
- (T-Bag) You sIeep with one eye open.
- Bring it on.
- Oh, I'm gonna bring it on in spades.
- (Michael) You oughta Ieave that kid aIone.
Maybe you are in no position
to be teIIing me my business. Hm?
That's what I thought.
I'm sure you can understand
my reIuctance to discuss past patients.
My understanding is that under HIPAA
we're aIIowed to share information
as Iong as it furthers the care of the patient.
I'm not accustomed to making
enquiries Iike this, but I...
I feeI Iike I can get through to him.
I can heIp him.
- I imagine he needs it in there.
- What did you treat him for?
MichaeI suffered from a coupIe of things.
One was a condition
caIIed Iow Iatent inhibition.
Sorry. I'm not famiIiar with the term.
PeopIe who suffer from Iow Iatent inhibition
see everyday things Iike you or I do,
Iike this Iamp.
But where we just process the image
of a Iamp, they process everything.
The stem, the buIb, the boIts,
even the washers inside.
Their brains are more open to incoming
stimuli in the surrounding environment.
Other peopIe's brains - yours and mine -
shut out the same information.
We have to do it in order to keep our sanity.
If someone with a Iow IQ
has Iow Iatent inhibition,
it aImost aIways resuIts in mentaI iIIness.
But if someone has a high IQ,
it aImost aIways resuIts in creative genius.
Do you think MichaeI's a genius?
WeII, I think that word's been derogated
in the media these days.
But in the cIassic sense of the word, yes, I do.
You... you said there was something eIse
you treated him for?
He came to me
with absoIuteIy no sense of seIf-worth.
The Ioss of both parents
very often does that to a chiId.
But with the Iow Iatent inhibition,
something interesting happened to MichaeI.
He became very attuned
to aII the suffering around him.
He couIdn't shut it out.
He became a rescuer,
one of those peopIe who are more concerned
with other peopIe's weIfare than their own.
I didn't know aII this about him.
Then maybe you don't know MichaeI ScofieId.
Yeah.
(T-Bag) # Oh, Tweener
# I'm coming
# Oh, Tweener
# I'm a-coming for you
# I'm coming
# Coming
# Is you ready? Are you ready?
# However you are, see, I'm here
# I'm coming for you
# Are you ready? Are you ready?
# I'm coming, I'm coming
# I'm a-coming, I'm a-coming, I'm coming
# I am coming
I checked my voicemaiI at work.
LincoIn's son LJ just Ieft me a message.
He's in troubIe.
(phone vibrates)
- HeIIo?
- LJ, it's Veronica. Where are you?
Oh, Veronica, I don't know.
You gotta come get me.
We can't, OK? We're not in Chicago.
You have to come to us.
Oh. AII right. Where's that?
Oh.
Oh. How the heII do they know where I am?
- (Veronica) What's going on?
- (LJ) How do they know where l am?
- LJ, LJ, I want you to Iisten to me.
- Everywhere I go, they're there.
I want you to Iisten to me, OK? I need you
to come to us. We're in Lake Mercer.
- Where's that?
- On the Iowa border.
There's a bus station. We'II meet you there.
- They're stiII aIive.
- The bird in the hand just became three.
- (Veronica) Keep your cellphone open.
- (Kellerman) Let's go.
- But the kid's right...
- Let's go.
- (LJ) OK.
- (Veronica) OK, what?
OK, I'II keep it open.
They're Ieaving. They're Ieaving.
LJ, I need to know that you hear me, OK?
Lake Mercer.
Lake Mercer. OK.
AII right, bye.
(glass smashes)
What the heII are you doing?
DeIivering yesterday's news.
(Gus screams)
Your bus Ieaves from depot six
in just a few minutes.
Thanks.
- Yo, man, get off me, bitch.
- Let's pants him.
I... wanted you to know that if you're Iooking
for someone to taIk to, you're not aIone.
It's part of my job to counseI inmates
and heIp them with their probIems.
I got things pretty weII figured out.
I sort of backed into
some information about you.
I hope you don't mind,
but there's a reason I became a doctor.
It's in my nature to want to heIp.
From what I understand,
it's in your nature too.
You did a Iot of good things before you were
in here. Community work, charity work.
What happened?
The man you're taIking about died
the moment I stepped inside these waIIs.
AII right.
(pA) Shuttle now arriving on platform one.
Shuttle departs in ten minutes.
Ladies and gentIemen,
United States Secret Service.
PIease remain caIm. Remain where you are.
(man) Watch your step, son.
Hey.
Come here.
It's OK.
They're Ieaving.
(phone beeps)
You're safe now, aII right?
You received communication
from your attorney.
PIease sign this document
certifying that I inspected it for contraband
without at any time
breaching attorney-cIient priviIege
by reading the materiaIs encIosed herein.
- What are you grinning about?
- I'm gonna be out in the reaI worId in a bit.
The fact that I'm gonna get me one fine piece
of taiI certainIy don't hurt either.
Nothing Iike taiI, eh, ScofieId?
(laughs)
- (screams) Son of a bitch!
- This ends right now.
Oh, you just screwed
some major Ieague pooch, pretty.
I'm gonna sing Iike a whoIe tree
fuII of birds now. Badge!
You wanna sing, then sing.
But you know what I think?
You don't have the guts.
You want out of here
just as much as the rest of us.
We got a probIem here?
No.
I, uh...
I thought we was missing some tooIs here.
My bad.
Get back to work.
Now.
You and I may be stuck together
in this IittIe dance, but I caII the shots.
First shot, that kid out there,
you don't touch him ever.
Do we understand each other?
We do.
(Bellick) Out of the way, JuIio.
Abruzzi.
You and me,
we're gonna have a conversation.
(Lincoln) How come he didn't faII through?
- What?
- I warned you.
I'II get it together.
You gotta give me more time.
You've had your time, John.
You tripping on something, AIice?
Yeah. That's what I thought.
Lamp it up in here again,
I'II be fixing to break some shop.
Uh-oh. We got a probIem.
BeIIick.
Boss. Boss. What's happening?
What are they doing?
- Fixing the break room.
- What are you taIking about? That's PI.
I run it.
Not any more, you don't.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Margaret Burke
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net