previously on ''prison Break'':
There's a whoIe Iot of reaI estate
in between here and the outside waIIs.
The infirmary's the weakest Iink
in the security chain.
These were seriousIy hard to get.
What you need 'em for?
None of your business.
If I'd known how this was gonna turn out,
I'd have gotten some crap job with the feds.
Keep taIking Iike that,
I'm gonna put a buIIet in your head.
- We gotta go.
- You're in troubIe, aren't you?
- (Hale) Veronica Donovan?
- Who is this?
I have information that wiII Iead
to the exoneration of LincoIn Burrows.
I gotta check the status in there.
- It's aII good.
- Then you won't mind me checking it out.
Get off of him! Get off. Get off.
- We Ieave tonight.
- MichaeI, we got a big probIem.
Argh! Argh!
- Back out.
- Of the escape?
Or die.
(Sara) Stay with me, John.
I need you to stay with me. Breathe.
Keep breathing.
You're gonna be OK. Keep breathing.
Stay with me, John.
You stay with me, John. You stay with me.
Stay with me.
AII right? Can you do that? Keep breathing.
You'II be OK. Stay with me.
AImost there. AImost there.
..be OK.
(man) Large Iaceration to the throat.
- He's Iost a Iot of bIood. He's hypovoIemic.
- (man) Got it.
- What's his bIood type?
- A neg!
His bIood pressure's too Iow.
He's definiteIy hypovoIemic.
- We gotta get him to Chicago.
- Chicago's a 20-minute fIight.
We gotta go, Doc.
And then there were six.
Far as I know, there's five.
Don't you ever step up to me Iike that again.
Who's the tough guy now, huh?
Warden, where's my brother?
He's in a Iot of troubIe, son.
You have to Iet me see him.
That's not a request
I can grant at the moment.
PIease.
We're 36 hours away from his execution.
He panicked. He got vioIent.
For the rest of his time at Fox River,
we're gonna keep him in ad seg,
for his safety and everybody eIse's.
I'm his brother.
I deserve to see him. It's my right.
It's not your right to see him...
untiI tomorrow...
at his execution.
I'm sorry, son.
The name is John Abruzzi.
A-b-r-u-z-z...
I don't care what protocoI is.
I just want to know if he's OK. HeIIo?
- HeIIo?
- (phone hangs up)
Co¨¾o.
The hospitaI won't give out any information.
Wonder what happened to him. Maybe them
Mafia chickens came home to roost after aII.
- We gotta put this on hoId.
- We're not putting nothing on hoId.
I don't think you heard me. UntiI
I get my brother out, no one's doing a thing.
God bIess Sink, but the man is gone.
You go to the tombs, you don't get out,
not untiI they strap you up.
If you think I'II Ieave my brother behind,
you have massiveIy underestimated me.
- ReaIIy?
- ReaIIy.
That ain't my fight.
I'm through that hoIe, pretty,
with or without you, next time I'm on PI.
We're not having this debate.
We oughta open the fIoor to everyone eIse,
see what they aII say.
We got a cIear shot. Every day we don't use
that hoIe is another day the screws can find it.
- The way is not finished.
- We're cIear to the infirmary.
That's aII we need.
Through that window,
over that wire, over that waII.
The two of you wiII never make it.
Oh, fish, it's notjust two.
If it's now or never, we gotta go.
Go with us.
You've done everything you couId.
They're grown men, MichaeI.
They can aII decide for themseIves.
- You son of a...
- Wait a minute!
- Hey! Who are you separating there?
- Hey, it's good, boss. Just pIaying around.
It's aII good.
There are two things
that everybody needs to get with.
First, hiIIbiIIy,
you have got to Iearn some respect.
The man here made everything possibIe.
And you, you're gonna have to get with
that we are doing this thing this afternoon
as soon as we get on PI.
So you're just gonna make a run for it
in the middIe of the day.
WeII, you gotta do
what you gotta do, huh, baby?
- You are gonna screw this whoIe thing up.
- (laughs)
That's not for you to decide any more.
Now, this train is Ieaving the station,
and I suggest you get on it.
Get on the train, fish.
Get on the train.
WeII, you know what, you sons of bitches?
I won't Iet you do it.
What you gonna do?
BIow the whistIe on your own escape?
He'II be back.
Those guys, they go before us tonight,
they use that hoIe, it's over.
COs wiII turn this whoIe pIace upside down
tiII they find it.
WeII, sounds Iike you're thinking about it.
I'd be Iying if I said I wasn't.
I want to be out of here yesterday.
I got a kid coming, man.
MichaeI, you can't get him out of there.
Can I say something?
I know you won't want to hear it, but...
they're strapping him up either way now.
Once he's gone,
you'II be stuck here for another five years.
If they trace the hoIe back to you,
they'II toss another dime.
That's 15 years, papi.
Of course, if I were you,
I wouIdn't Ieave my brother behind either.
Not to die Iike that, no.
Uh-uh.
Worst thing in the worId they can do to a man
is strap him to a chair Iike that.
- We're in business.
- What?
I just spoke to a friend who's a cIerk at the
superior court. I toId him about the informant.
If he gives any evidence to warrant a stay,
my friend wiII hear us out.
- We might be abIe to stop this.
- I gotta teII LincoIn.
Go to that prison, they'II be aII over you.
They've kept us on the run because if anyone
hears from us, we can do them damage.
Maybe it's time
we do the exact opposite - go big.
What do you mean, ''big''?
You mean media big?
We got aII the ammo we need.
There's a string of murders connected to this.
Are you ready to show your face again? Huh?
Are you ready for that?
It's the bottom of the ninth.
What eIse are we gonna do?
(girl) Hello?
- Hey. This is Daddy, baby girI.
- Daddy!
Daddy's on the phone.
- How are the cameIs?
- Oh, weII, the cameIs... the cameIs are fine.
- When do l get to see you?
- EarIier than I thought.
Daddy said he's coming home soon.
Hey, put Mommy on the phone.
Thank you, sweetie.
First Sergeant Benjamin MiIes FrankIin,
how are you?
Oh, baby. Just driving trucks, eating dates,
trying to keep the sand out of my eyes.
I saw on the news the other day
it was 110 in Kuwait.
- You must be meIting over there.
- You have no idea.
What's this about you coming home?
You're not getting your daughter's hopes up?
- You sitting down?
- Sure.
Your man is coming home this week.
This week? What are you taIking about?
They said it'd be another year.
The orders just came down the pipe.
And the heII if I care
where they came down from.
- All that matters is we'll see each other.
- When? When is this happening?
Thursday, Friday. I'm not sure yet.
Do you need me
to pick you up from the airport?
Oh, no. No, no.
The army's got that aII arranged.
You know, you just be waiting for me.
WeII, you know I got that down.
(man) Today, C-Note.
WouId you back up?
Hey, you know, comm is onIy Ietting me
use this Iinkup for a few more minutes.
- Is Darius there? I need to speak to him.
- Yeah, yeah. I'II go get him.
I Iove you.
I Iove you more.
(man) Yo.
Yeah, what's up, money?
Your sister out of the room?
She is now.
So, how is it out there, man?
Fox River aII that they say it is?
Oh, man, it ain't aII that. Not for Iong, anyway.
- What you mean by that?
- I need you to do something for me.
Yeah, aII right.
- You stiII drive that EscaIade?
- Is MichaeI Jackson stiII white?
Ha-ha, you gotjokes, son.
How many does it hoId?
OK.
OK what?
Let's do it.
What? You mean tonight?
What about Linc?
I need a razor bIade.
- A razor bIade ain't gonna get him out.
- Do you have one or not?
CarefuI, bro.
Ay, Cristo amado.
Thou shaIt not kiII!
..Ieadeth me beside the stiII waters,
restoreth my souI.
Leadeth me in the path
of righteousness for your sake.
Though I waIk through the vaIIey
of the shadow of death, I wiII fear no eviI,
for thou art with me.
Thou preparest a tabIe before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
SureIy goodness and mercy shaII foIIow me
aII the days of my Iife,
and I wiII dweII
in the house of the Lord forever.
- Amen.
- He does hear our prayers, the Lord...
- Yes.
..on behaIf of LincoIn.
- AII who seek forgiveness wiII be deIivered.
- Yes.
If your brother accepts the Lord,
he'II be free of this cage forever.
Yes.
I'II be avaiIabIe
through this whoIe thing if you need me.
Reverend.
Reverend, wouId you give this to my brother?
It'd mean a Iot to him,
knowing it came from me.
I wiII.
That was my mother's.
TeII her it's going
to save someone a Iot of pain.
You sure you know what you're doing?
It's in God's hands now.
You've been the cIean-up crew for me
the whoIe time I've been in here.
Toes, contusions, insuIin shots.
WeII, somebody's gotta do it.
WeII, I'm gratefuI.
You ever think, in another Iife...
- I won't be that woman, MichaeI.
- I wasn't asking you to be.
But it is something to wonder about.
What if?
Anyway, just wanted to make sure it was said.
Why do I feeI
Iike you're saying goodbye to me?
I don't know.
I guess in a pIace Iike this, you never know
which day is gonna be your Iast.
(door opens)
- Sara, we got a backup out here.
- OK.
You're set.
I...
I'm sorry about your brother.
Doctor...
Thank you.
This is it, bro.
Hey.
Good Iuck to both of us.
PI! Let's do it!
Came to your senses, did you?
You figure a magic way to get your brother
out of that hoIe and into the guards' room?
He's not gonna be there.
CouId you put the Iight on?
You OK?
What do you think, Rev?
I spoke with your brother today.
He's been praying for you.
He must be desperate.
What about you? Are you feeIing desperate?
No.
Just for everyone eIse.
The ones you Ieave behind.
The ones I never got to say goodbye to.
I can be with you
aII day tomorrow, you know.
Right up to the time.
Thank you.
He wanted me to give this to you.
MichaeI.
Thou shaIt not kiII!
- She's back in pIay.
- Good. Who's there with you?
- Tangren.
- What about HaIe?
Nope. MIA.
He shouId be there. What do you mean, MIA?
I think it's a fairIy concise term.
(dials number)
(phone rings)
Don't get it.
- What time's the fIight?
- 11. I gotta head up to WrigIeyviIIe.
I'II be back in a coupIe hours to coIIect you.
Pack everything.
Once we're out that door,
we won't come back.
- What are you gonna do?
- There's a Ietter I gotta deIiver.
(crowd) Thou shaIt not kiII!
You'II have to step away.
I'm Veronica Donovan.
I represent LincoIn Burrows.
- (woman) This isn't the time.
- You'II have to step aside.
I'm sorry, did you say
that you represent LincoIn Burrows?
- That's right.
- AngeIa West. I'm a producer with News Six.
So, Mr Pied Piper, what's the pIay?
We do what we aIways do -
pretend to be working, be modeI citizens,
tiII the time comes.
- And that'd be?
- Nine o'cIock.
You seem to be forgetting
that PI shuts down at five o'cIock.
WeII, we have to make sure
it doesn't, don't we?
Hammer.
Whoa! What the heII are you doing, man?
(water dripping)
- What the heII happened here?
- Messed up. Hit a pipe.
- ShouId've kiIIed the water before we started.
- ShouId've?
It's not that big a deaI.
We can fix it in the morning.
I don't think mouId
shouId be a probIem before then.
- MouId?
- ScofieId, shut up, man.
You shut up. What are you taIking about?
You get drywaII and insuIation soaked Iike
this, you run the risk of stachybotrys mouId.
Boss, that's just, Iike,
one time in a thousand, for reaI.
TeII you what.
You and aII your compa¨¾eros here
aren't stepping outside this door
untiI every damn moIecuIe of water
is out of this pIace.
- It's gonna take aII night.
- WeII, then it's gonna take aII night.
Don't catch a sniffIe.
Man.
(crowd) Free Burrows!
Free Burrows! Free Burrows!
- Great. A Iot of it checks out.
- (man) Put her on.
- If you don't mind, we'd Iike to put you on.
- That's why I'm here.
Great. HoIIy here wiII be asking the questions.
Just watch his hand, OK?
Peter, I'm with Veronica Donovan,
the Iawyer for LincoIn Burrows.
- You're petitioning for a stay, is that right?
- Yes.
- On what grounds?
- On the grounds that my cIient was framed.
Get specifics.
- Do you have any proof?
- There's a whoIe string of proof.
Murders - Leticia Barris,
a potentiaI excuIpatory witness,
Lisa Rix, the mother of LincoIn's chiId,
Bishop McMorrow,
who couId have petitioned for cIemency.
Someone's kiIIing these peopIe off?
Somebody's trying to hide what happened,
the truth about Terrence Steadman.
Is this specuIation, or is there
hard evidence to substantiate your cIaims?
- (Veronica) l have a source.
- Get a name.
- CouId you eIaborate?
- No.
Somebody on the inside
claims they can exonerate Lincoln,
that Terrence Steadman
wasn't in the car that night.
Someone's been taIking.
- Is there a reason you're on direct current?
- Sorry?
You know, AC/DC.
AIternating current, direct current.
DC's kinda yesterday's news
for this sort of thing.
You can kiII a man
with haIf the energy if you go AC.
OK. Let's see what we got.
You ready to run one?
(electricity crackles)
I think you better turn these Iights on.
Can't do it. Your cIient's being discipIined.
You're vioIating
his Eighth Amendment rights.
Either you turn those Iights on, or you'II
be the first defendant named in a Iawsuit.
You OK?
- LJ?
- He's good.
He's scared, but he's good.
- I found someone who's gonna taIk.
- Who?
I don't know,
but I'II meet him in a few hours.
- A few hours is cutting it cIose, V.
- We don't have any other choice.
You have to have faith, OK?
Nick's aIready primed the court
to hear our case.
Whatever MichaeI's doing,
he doesn't need to do it now.
- We'II beat this the right way.
- What if you're wrong?
- I'm not.
- What if you are?
You gotta trust me, OK?
Don't give up on me.
Promise?
- Didn't mean to scare you.
- It's aII right. PauI, how are you?
I'm good, I'm good.
- You?
- Oh. (laughs)
- Where you going?
- Vacation.
Bahamas.
- Packing kinda heaviIy for the Bahamas.
- You know women.
Yeah.
So, where's Danny?
- Running errands, I think.
- Errands, huh?
Where... where might those errands be?
- Lewis, you there?
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm here, Linc.
What time you got?
A IittIe after eight.
It's 8:15.
You OK?
No.
(groans)
(vomits)
(groaning) Oh, MichaeI,
what have you done to me?
(cries out)
Nine o'cIock, fish.
Showtime.
Let's go, man.
(Lincoln groans)
Tancredi Ieave yet?
I don't think so.
You better caII her.
See you on the other side.
WeII, everything teIIs me it's food poisoning,
which means you shouId
feeI better in a coupIe of hours,
but...
I wish I couId say that this wouId be enough
to forestaII the execution. It's not gonna be.
It's aII right.
I can stay with you if you want.
No.
It's fine. Thank you.
OK.
We got a Iot to taIk about
and not a Iot of time to do it.
Your boyfriend, he can stiII be saved.
Burrows was chosen a Iong time ago.
Hand-picked to be an assassin.
But he never puIIed the trigger.
Who did? Come on.
Who kiIIed Terrence Steadman?
- Nobody.
- What?
Terrence Steadman's stiII aIive.
There's three sheets of paper inside.
You'II find aII the names
you need are on them.
Everyone that started this whoIe thing,
from top to bottom.
You need to take two steps that way,
right now.
Behind the car. Get behind the car.
You want to stay aIive, do as I say. Now.
Your boys better be there, rughead.
They'II be there, cIeatis. Don't you worry.
This is crazy.
So, what are you doing here, Danny?
- Where's the Iawyer?
- I don't know what you're taIking about.
AIIison toId me.
I got it out of her.
- You didn't touch her?
- Why wouId I do that?
We're partners, right? We're on the same side.
No.
AIIison's fine. She's just...
You're gonna have to ask yourseIf
who you want to give up.
Your wife, or this Iawyer.
Just teII me where she is.
Is she here? Has she been?
What exactIy have you toId...
Don't do this.
- Give me your gun.
- I can't.
Yes, you can. I'm your superior.
I give you a command. You obey it.
Give me your gun.
- PauI, it's nothing. It's not...
- Don't. Back up.
It's...
It's amazing.
You got it aII on onIy... three pages.
You know what wouId happen
if this feII into the wrong hands?
You named me?
- Right there aIong with the rest of them?
- I got scared.
- You named me?
- PIease, man!
AIIison's due in one month.
PauI, you and me,
we-we've been friends since the academy.
You named me.
OK. Let's go.
Hey, hey, hey. Put that away, man.
What you doing? Put that away, man.
Hey, yo-yos.
This is a state penitentiary.
You can't park here.
You think we meant to park here?
Put your hands where I can see 'em.
I said put your hands where I can see 'em.
AII fixed.
What do you say you two hit the road?
You two hit the road right now,
or we're gonna have a probIem.
- You aII right?
- I'm good. Haven't been this good in years.
They repIaced it.
MichaeI?
He's there.
Son of a bitch!
Here, MichaeI. Use this.
Come on! You ready?
Shh!
(keys jingle)
Ready?
What? TaIk to me.
- It can't be done.
- (Sucre) What?
It's too thick.
I'm so sorry.
We're not getting out of here.
UnfortunateIy, pretty,
that ain't an option.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Sarah Johnston
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net