SCOFIELD: Previously on Prison Break:
SUCRE: What are you doing?
I'm trying to remember those bIueprints,
what we Iost to the burn.
Without them,
we'II never be abIe to navigate those pipes
beneath psych ward.
Then I need to know
where you got that burn. Right now.
Otherwise, your ass is going to soIitary.
I put my bIood into this...
How about you eIaborate on that?
How about you
stop with aII the questions?
You are a gIorified bodyguard, that's it.
Okay, I got it.
KELLERMAN: Put it down.
You're not a kiIIer.
Get out of the way.
You know, maybe they give you
those things for a reason.
Yeah. To keep me
in their invisibIe freaking handcuffs.
HeIIo, roomie.
You were right about my tattoo.
It is a path...
And I need you to remember
when you saw it, Haywire.
Who are you?
ScofieId. MichaeI ScofieId.
Doesn't ring a beII.
We met a whiIe ago in Gen pop. CeII 40.
-Gen pop?
-GeneraI popuIation.
Officer BeIIick assigned you to my ceII.
I have a tattoo, you drew it.
Haywire, do I Iook even
vagueIy famiIiar to you?
Are you the guy who stoIe my toothpaste?
Yes, yes. I stoIe your toothpaste.
So you do remember.
Candy man.
Mr. Patoshik.
-Mr. ScofieId.
-No, thank you.
Medication is mandatory.
It's just a miId sedative
prescribed by Dr. Tancredi. Come on.
Then I'II taIk to her directIy.
I'm feeIing better.
Oh, reaIIy? That's great. Now take the piII.
Take them. They're good.
I'm fine. Thank you.
Carter, couId you come here a sec?
-ScofieId went J-Cat?
-Sure did. I saw it coming, too.
I knew he was gonna crack
first time I saw him.
-So he's not coming back here?
-Doubt it.
They had him in the whack shack.
-What about Sucre?
-He's in ad seg. Why?
MiddIe ceII, middIe tier,
prime piece of reaI estate.
-You thinking what I'm thinking?
-Maybe.
We promise to keep it a singIe
for a coupIe of months, auction it off.
Make it happen.
I don't need medication.
SwaIIow it, or it's going in the rear door.
AII gone?
Nice.
You were right, Haywire.
I did steaI your toothpaste,
and you drew that tattoo from memory,
and I need you to do it again.
MiddIe ceII,
cooI in the summer, warm in the winter.
How much you asking?
-How much you got?
-$200.
-We got a deaI?
-DeaI.
Now get your ass out of here
and I'II put in the transfer.
Hey, man,
the toiIet's Ieaking.
Look, it's dripping.
I'II put in a work order.
It'II be repIaced in 24 hours.
You got it, boss.
-I heard you was moving some reaI estate.
-AIready been moved.
-Ain't that ScofieId's ceII?
-Not anymore.
CIose on 40!
(DOOR BUZZING)
C-NOTE: Is that your daughter?
My wife gave me this when she was born.
OutIiving your wife is bad enough.
OutIiving your daughter...
No man shouId have to endure that.
How Iong does she have?
HospitaI says a week, maybe two.
We got us a probIem.
Mojo's moving into ScofieId's ceII,
and that ain't aII.
He's bitching about the toiIet,
so Geary's putting in a work order.
-They move that toiIet...
-They find the hoIe.
We are aII screwed.
-How much Mojo promise?
-$200.
Oh, Gomer, now you see,
you had me scared there for a second.
-I hear you got a ceII.
-Not anymore.
And if you were smart,
you'd keep quiet about that.
-Hey, Iook, I'II doubIe what you're getting.
-I'm getting $250.
$500? Ain't a probIem.
I ain't taIking cigarettes
and extra chow Iine desserts here.
I'm taIking green paper
with dead white guys on it.
I said it ain't a probIem.
Come on.
-Where?
-It's a surprise.
-I don't wear a diaper.
-I never said you did.
Then what are you doing?
You got something in your teeth.
-What?
-Oh, yeah. Right there.
-I don't...
-It's right there in the back.
Come on.
-Why are you doing this?
-I am heIping you.
Remember what you used to caII
those IittIe piIIs?
''InvisibIe handcuffs.''
Handcuffs on your mind.
You hate them, remember?
You got a phone caII.
-Who is it?
-Your son. It's an emergency.
Oh, LJ, what were you thinking, kid?
l don"t care
what happens to me anymore, okay?
They won, They"ll always win,
I just wanted
to take one of them down with me.
Put Veronica back on.
LincoIn?
What are the charges?
Attempted murder.
He"s also being arraigned for the murder
of his mother and his stepfather,
-l guess bail is out of the question?
-ExactIy.
Anything you can do?
Right now, his onIy shot is
if we can get him tried as a minor.
But he needs to show some remorse,
I need to seII to the court
that he was just a scared kid.
But where his head's at right now,
he won't Iisten to me.
He'II Iisten to me. I need to see him.
LincoIn, there's no way.
He gets tried as an aduIt,
he may as weII sit in my Iap in the chair.
-You got to do something, Veronica,
-Okay.
Look, I'II petition the DOC,
but it's a miIIion-to-one shot
they"re gonna let you out to see him,
AII right.
Yo, Trumpets.
You aII gotta round up aII outstanding
debts that are due ASAP, aII right?
Do it right now?
Like yesterday, aII right?
-I'II put it out there.
-Good.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
Are you insane?
You are done, bodyguard.
LincoIn's son, a 16-year-oId pothead,
managed to track you down
and shoot you.
You are now
a witness in his criminaI investigation.
I can stiII do my job.
You are not to make a move on Burrows
under any circumstance.
We make that caII.
You know what, trixie?
There are actuaIIy higher agendas here.
Yes, there are,
and they don't beIong to you.
PauI KeIIerman no Ionger works
for the Secret Service.
You're just good oId Owen Kravecki
from now on.
Have I made myseIf cIear?
Hey.
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
I need you to focus.
I need you to remember what you drew.
ORDERLY: Haywire. Time for group.
Come on, buddy. Let's go.
There we go.
HAYWIRE: It's a path.
Yes. It is a path.
Let's go.
(MAN CHATTERING ON P.A.)
So, what's up, man?
Here's the thing. You got nothing coming.
AII your outstanding markers,
they're mine now.
Is that so?
You got a probIem with it,
go cry to your new crew,
T-Bag and the white boys.
Okay, so that's what this is aII about.
This is about staying true to your own.
WeII, you know what, man?
I can have tea
with the grand wizard of the KKK if I want,
and I stiII get my money.
-You got that, IittIe boy?
-No. We don't got that.
Now, out of respect
for what you once were,
I'm gonna Iet you waIk away.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(HAYWIRE RETCHING)
(GASPING)
You were right.
The piIIs don't Iet me see the pathway.
That's a pathway to heII.
No, it's not. It's just the opposite.
I remember.
(EX CLAIMING)
Looks Iike the Bank of Africa
wasn't aIIowing any withdrawaIs.
Look, we are gonna have to find
another way to get that money, okay?
WeII, then I reckon
it ain't too much of a probIem
for our friend here to rummage up,
ain't that so, D.B.?
A, I'm not D.B. Cooper,
and, B, there's no visitation today.
Which means that none of us can get
any money from the outside worId.
I guess that onIy Ieaves us
with one reaI option.
The kitchen game.
GambIing? And that's your soIution?
Son, trust me.
When I pIay cards, it ain't gambIing.
There's maybe five peopIe in this country
that can do what I do with a deck of cards.
So why are you just bringing this up now?
'Cause if Jesus, over there,
catches you sIeeving aces
in the kitchen game,
weII, Iet's just say
there are Iots of knives handy.
Of course,
you need 50 bucks just for the sit-in,
and since we don't have any money,
I'd say we're in a catch-doubIey-deuce.
You sit right here.
There you go. Take this.
And this.
Oh, no. It's gone.
That's why I need you to fix it.
That's why I need you to remember
what was there before.
Oh, this is bad. You can't break a path.
-Then it doesn't Iead anywhere.
-That's right.
That's why I need you to remember
what was there before it was broken.
I remember. I remember the demons.
Wait, no, maybe they were piIgrims.
They were pointing to the way,
and they were saying,
''This is the way, this is the way.''
I can't see it.
I can see it, but I can't see it.
I'II be right back.
Hey!
I need you to give Sucre a message.
TeII him I'm okay,
and that I'm trying to fiII in the bIanks.
He'II know what that means.
-You're trying to fiII in the bIanks?
-Just do it. PIease.
What the hell am l gonna do now?
You've been down in 13
as Iong as I can remember.
Why the sudden interest in moving?
Second-story units Iike this
don't come on the market too much.
I figure since I'm getting on in age,
maybe it's time I retired in comfort.
Open on 40!
(DOOR BUZZING)
Make it quick.
Hey, Bob ViIa, it's a ceII.
Quit kicking the tires and make a decision.
I'II give you 100 bucks for it.
You wasted my time.
Get the heII out of here.
Sorry, boss. I thought it was a good bid.
CIose on 40!
(DOOR BUZZING)
HeIIo, Benjamin.
Now, Iet me see,
minted in 19 and 72.
That's your buy-in.
The rest is up to you.
Hot damn.
-Keep waIking, peckerwood.
-Got the buy-in for the card game.
Go get our money, boy.
UnfortunateIy, you and I are gonna
have to be partners in this endeavor.
Oh, heII, no.
I don't pIay cards, I'm a dice man.
Look, aII you need to know is this,
every time I deaI,
you bet big and never foId.
See, if I'm winning every time I deaI,
I end up with a CoIombian necktie.
You know what I'm saying?
But if you're the one raking in aII the cash,
weII, I seriousIy doubt anyone wouId
ever think you and I are working together.
It's aII right, baby, yeah.
Excuse me.
I've been aII over town.
I can't find a charger for this.
-WeII, Iet me check.
-Thanks.
How you doing, Savrinn?
-Where's your girI?
-She's doing her job, aII right?
FiIing a petition down at the courts.
She'II be at my pIace in about an hour.
See, that was easy.
I shouIdn't have to chase you down
to get that information.
Why don't you just take a step back?
And why don't you remember
who you're taIking to, who I work for?
You need to keep
an eye on Veronica Donovan.
Not some of the time, aII of the time.
'Cause pretty soon,
we're gonna caII in our favor,
unIess you want to go back on our deaI.
-No.
-Good.
Be in touch.
Haywire.
Haywire, did you take your meds?
WeII, come on.
You got something in your teeth again.
You shouId be carefuI when you teII peopIe
to remember things, MichaeI.
Because I remember everything now.
I remember how you set me up!
How you smashed your own head
and had me sent back here.
I aIso remember this.
The pathway.
Your map.
Your escape.
Give me that.
Don't. Don't.
Now, do I tear this up
or do you teII me exactIy where
and when you're doing this?
-It starts in the basement.
-Okay.
This Iine Ieads
from the hatch in the coaI room,
to this pipe system here,
and that runs to the infirmary.
That's how we'II get out.
I just need to get out of psych ward
to set things up.
But three days after I'm gone,
I'II come back up through the basement
and get you out.
You're just teIIing me what I want to hear.
No, I'm not.
I need you to Iet me get us out of here.
I need you to trust me.
If you try to screw me over again
I'II kiII you.
-Hey.
-Hi.
-How did it go?
-FiIing the petition was easy,
getting it approved,
that's a whoIe 'nother story.
-You found the charger?
-Oh, yeah.
-Why didn't you pIug it in?
-I was just... Just thinking for a minute.
-About what?
-Nothing.
We're in business.
What is it?
His entire phone book is stiII in here,
322 numbers.
No open seats. Gotta wait.
-C-Note, crap or get off the pot.
-I'm thinking.
We ain't betting on CPT here, man.
Either you gonna see his bet
or you can go outside
and MiIIion Con March
or whatever your peopIe do.
Either way, get on with it, son.
I'm in.
Three bitches, bitches.
What you hoIding?
You teII me.
-FuII house.
-A fuII house?
That's a concept a Mexican shouId be
quite famiIiar with, eh, Jesus?
(CHUCKLING)
She said what?
She said, in unequivocaI terms,
that I was not to move on Burrows.
Whatever their agenda is with Burrows,
it is not the same as ours.
This whoIe business with his father,
it interferes with the one thing
that we set out to do in the first pIace.
Put LincoIn Burrows in the ground.
If he Iives,
you're the one that stands to Iose,
not the Company.
They get themseIves another candidate,
and you're the one
that suffers the brunt of it.
Then maybe it's time we broke ranks.
We do that,
they puII support for the campaign.
You know that, don't you?
That is, if they know, PauI.
(SNIFFING) SmeII that kitty.
Jacks or better, Trips to win.
Last hand.
I'm tired of Iosing aII my money today.
-How much you up?
-I don't know. $300.
-Does it hurt?
-What?
The horseshoe up your ass.
Rather be Iucky than good, ping-pong.
MisdeaI. Bury the card.
-Man, I don't care if you aII saw my card.
-Yeah, I bet you don't.
-Bury the card, young bIood.
-Hey, chiII, wrinkIes.
Ain't my fauIt saItine here
got a sIoppy deaI.
That there was just uncaIIed for.
Now, aII right. You know what?
I'II teII you what.
I'm gonna deaI another hand,
you gonna be such a baby about it.
On a misdeaI, you bury the card,
finish out the hand.
House ruIes.
-Warden.
-I have some good news for you, Linc.
Somehow, your Iawyer's
petition went through.
The Department of Corrections
is aIIowing you a one-hour visit
with your son.
I've never seen
one of these granted before, ever.
-Good Iawyers.
-No Iawyer's that good.
I'II make the traveI arrangements,
but this is not going to be
a ride in the country.
You're gonna be y-cuffed,
and the men are gonna be heaviIy armed.
-I don't want any probIems.
-There won't be, I just want to see my son.
I'II bet aII I got.
$82.
You better have some aces
shoved up there with that horseshoe,
or that pot's mine.
You in or out?
I'm in.
And I raise you $74.
-I said I onIy got $82 Ieft.
-WeII, then I guess you're out of Iuck.
-You never heard of a gentIeman's game?
-Yes, I have, but this ain't it.
You want to borrow some money?
Ask your boys.
But I'm in here to make money, bro.
You want weIfare,
you'd better vote Democrat.
If you know what's good for you,
you'II stay away from me in the yard.
(SIGHING)
You think you're smarter than me?
(ALARM BLARING)
No, no, no!
Okay, there's a pathway.
No, there's a pathway! There's a pathway!
Look, he's trying to escape!
He's trying to escape. This is his map!
-Haywire, I need you to come back!
-He set me up!
-Zap him !
-No! No!
There he is.
Hey, boss.
I think you dropped something, man.
That's haIf a G-note.
-So when do I move in?
-You don't.
What?
-Oh, come on, chief, now, we had a deaI.
-Renegotiation, the price is $700 now.
That ain't right. I just gave you $500.
What you gave me was a down payment.
If you can't come up with the rest, weII...
No, no, no! Wait, wait, wait. Just hoId on.
One minute, aII right?
Oh, man, he's trying to shake us down.
-I'm gonna need that watch.
-Not an option.
Look, wouId you rather be
Iooking at a picture of your daughter
or hoIding her in your arms
once you get outside?
Hey, Iook, man,
Father Time owed me a few bones.
He gave me this in trade.
That shouId be
more than enough to cover it.
Not bad.
Your probIem is somebody
aIready gave me $700 for the ceII,
so, you're S.O.L.
No! No! Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa !
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
wait a minute. Look.
So you're just gonna
take my money and waIk?
Yeah, weII, write to your congressman.
Oh, come on!
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
-Hey.
-Hi.
-They said you wanted to taIk to me.
-Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Good.
PIease.
Thanks.
I made you something.
It's an ashtray.
-I don't smoke.
-Yeah, I know.
But they onIy
Iet us make these and jeweIry,
and I didn't figure you
for the macaroni neckIace type.
It's very sweet.
How about we taIk
about how you're doing?
I think we both know I don't beIong here.
I don't remember much about that night,
but being Iocked up in ad seg,
something must've snapped.
What I'm trying to say is,
I think I've had enough of arts and crafts.
But that's your caII.
And the doctors here
do say that you've been acting fine.
The probIem is that
if you don't teII the Pope who burned you,
he's gonna Iock you back up in ad seg.
And after a coupIe days of that,
you're gonna be right back here.
MichaeI, I hate what happened to you,
and I hate that you're here.
But you have got to Iet me heIp you.
If you want to get out of psych ward,
and stay out,
you've got to teII the Pope
the truth about that burn.
Out with the oId, in with the new, cons.
I got a message from your ceIIie, bro.
He says he's okay
and he's trying to fiII in the bIanks.
Did he say he's trying,
or that he aIready got the bIanks fiIIed in?
Yo, man, I don't know.
I didn't write it down.
Okay. Now you gotta teII him
that I fiIIed in the hoIe.
Yeah, yeah, I'm done
with your IittIe secrets and messages, bro.
I saw ScofieId's back.
He's got a burn in the same spot
as the burn in that guard's shirt.
I don't know what you're doing
but I have an idea, huh?
And I'm through heIping you
untiI you teII me what's going on.
I can't, bro.
-Then good Iuck in the hoIe, jefe,
-No, no, no! Wait, wait.
LINCOLN: Manche.
-Who's that?
-That's Linc, bro.
-Linc the Sink?
-Yeah.
Come here.
I think we can work something out.
AII I can say is, before I get out of here,
Geary wiII pay. BeIieve that.
No one's getting out of here
if maintenance goes to
repIacing ScofieId's toiIet.
I got a way to heIp you
with your ScofieId probIem.
-What'd you say, sIim?
-I said I got a way to heIp you with...
-Who the heII said we had a probIem?
-It's cooI, man. ReIax.
LincoIn and Sucre toId me everything.
What in the heII did they teII you?
ExactIy, what did they teII you?
Everything. They said I can come with you,
you know, on earIy paroIe,
if I can heIp get the Fish out of psych.
What are we, the A train?
Everyone gets to ride with us?
Why don't you take a waIk,
before I give you a smack?
You got another soIution to our situation?
I didn't think so.
Me and my cuz and LincoIn
came up with something.
Now, it can work, but it's risky.
You ready to get out of
this aquarium, Fish?
Assure me I'II be protected.
(DOOR BUZZING)
MichaeI, you know me
weII enough by now.
Such assurances are not necessary.
With aII due respect, Warden,
if I had been protected in the first pIace,
none of this wouId have happened.
-A name.
-Geary.
Geary?
He shakes cons down for money,
anything he can get his hands on.
He knew I went to coIIege, so he must've...
He must've thought
I was rich or something.
Anyway, when I couIdn't pay up,
he heId me down with one arm,
and burned me with the other.
I don't know what he used,
but it was hot as heII.
What a surprise. Disconnected.
Two-hundred and fifty businesses,
72 residences, covering aII 50 states.
-London, Martinique, Jakarta, Dakar.
-AII the numbers out of service.
As soon as Quinn disappeared,
they must've
erased the paper traiI within days.
Is there anything they can't do?
My P.I. buddy in DC.
What if I send him aII this,
see if he can make
a connection between the numbers?
I'II teII him I need it ASAP.
-Thank you.
-Oh, it's no big deaI.
I'II just overnight him aII this stuff.
No. For everything.
For hanging in there, keeping me going.
-Thank you.
-Sure.
GEARY: Guy with a six ERA,
signs for four miI a year.
Sucks at his job, he stiII gets a raise.
You suck at your job.
You shouId ask the Pope for a raise.
Very funny.
Warden, what brings you
to our IittIe cIubhouse?
Hey, what gives?
Hey, that was a gift from my oId man.
Since when is your name CharIes
and your dad's name Ann?
This is a raiIroad. I didn't do nothing!
Don't Iook at me Iike I'm some con.
You're as crooked as scoIiosis.
I don't get caught.
When we get there,
I'II take you out of the y-cuffs
and put you in a four-piece.
-Got it?
-Got it, boss.
You pIay nice, I pIay nice.
-Understand?
-Got it.
She's here. I've got her.
(DOOR BUZZING)
GUARD: Scofield for re-admission
to Gen pop,
-WeIcome home.
-Thanks.
Never thought
I'd be so gIad to be back in my ceII.
Pope wanted me to give you this.
-What the heII are you staring at, anyway?
-Everything.
(HORN HONKING)
www.tvsubtitles.net