(man) previously on ''prison Break'':
- I didn't kiII that man.
- The evidence says you did.
I was set up.
Put down your weapon.
I find it incumbent
that you see the inside of a prison ceII.
- I'm Iooking for LincoIn Burrows.
- Man kiIIed the vice president's brother.
- Why do you want to see Burrows?
- He's my brother.
- I'm getting you out.
- It's impossibIe.
- Not if you designed the pIace.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
Better than that. I've got 'em on me.
I spoke to your mother.
- If you mean that guy at Fox River...
- He refuses to caII him his father.
Take the onIy thing Burrows has Ieft.
The chair isn't the only way
to take a man's life in prison.
(woman) And now scenes
from last week's episode.
ConstantIy coming up here for count won't
Iet me do what I need to do to get through.
The onIy way to stop count is a Iockdown.
You'd better get the inmates riled up.
AII right! That's it! Lockdown!
The anonymous caIIer
couIdn't have seen LincoIn.
- How do you know?
- Because the caII came from Washington DC.
This is BeIIick. Our wing has been breached.
Hooke's Law of eIasticity.
If we driII hoIes in strategic Iocations, we
compromise the waII's Ioad-carrying capacity.
- Take the cuffs off.
- A rookie CO.
- Get out of here, T-Bag.
- I think we can work something out.
No deaI.
- (governor) Where's my daughter?
- (warden) She's fine.
A guard assures us everything is fine.
We have everything under controI.
You'd better hope you do.
They're breaking out.
They're breaking...
Shh.
- We need a favour.
- Heavy hitters want this done.
Burrows is as good as dead.
You Iooking for ScofieId?
- Yeah, Turk.
- Come on.
Hey, yo! Stroke is about to get the doc.
Finish what we started.
No one touches the CO. No one.
(inmates shouting and yelling)
(pA) Attention all personnel.
Attention all personnel.
Secure the perimeter.
Remove private vehicles from all areas.
Attention. The area is on secure lockdown.
Let's go!
- Any word from the governor?
- Not yet, boss.
- BeIIick! Get those guys in Iine.
- Get 'em into formation.
- Going back in?
- Not yet.
We cut the water off about an hour ago.
The stink aIone shouId drive 'em out of there.
- You think that's gonna work?
- No, but it's protocoI.
And we're aII gonna do this by the book.
- It's the best chance we have.
- (inmate) Hey!
This is the warden.
What's happening in there?
We got some demands.
TeII them we need the air back on.
We need the AC.
We got a hostage - the guard.
We got a hostage - the new guard.
Find out who's in there.
They got Bob.
And the girI doctor. TeII him we got her.
- Why don't you do it?
- I don't wanna get shot.
And we got the girI doctor.
- The doctor?
- There's onIy one.
How the heII did that happen?
How did they get their hands on her?
- I thought she was safe in Sick Bay.
- We gotta get her out. We gotta go in now.
- We can't do it, sir.
- Why not?
It's not by the book.
Sir, I've got some updates for you.
HeIp!
ScofieId's in here?
Argh!
You sure he's in here?
Turk.
You ain't gonna use that.
You making up the ruIes now, ese?
- It's my house. You got a probIem?
- Yeah, I got a probIem. We aII do.
No probIem.
I swear to God. I'm not gonna say anything.
I didn't see anything.
That's right, badge. You didn't see nothing.
Wait. Don't Ieave.
Sorry. I'II be back.
Don't worry. I'II cover for you.
Don't worry, CO. AII right?
I'm not gonna hurt nobody.
I'm part of the team now.
HeIp a brother out. Drag that over.
That's the way. Mm-hm-hm-hm.
(banging)
PIease return to your seats
and fasten your seatbeIts.
We are making our finaI approach
into Washington DC.
We need to focus on the reaI question.
Who wanted Terrence Steadman dead?
The caII came from DC.
What does that teII you?
You gotta think past the government.
Anybody couId be here.
A business partner, a rivaI.
Before Steadman was kiIIed,
EcoFieId introduced
a prototype eIectric engine
at the techno conference.
$60 barreIs of oiI wouId be obsoIete
if that thing ever hit the mainstream.
CouId be oiI. OiI companies.
SuppIiers, consumers, everything in between.
Or the government of an oiI-based economy.
Like the United States.
- Can I take your soda?
- Sure. Thank you.
At any rate, we Iand, we meet my guy,
and even if we don't find the person
who tipped off the cops, we find his phone.
The paper traiI begins.
(shouting continues)
OnIy a matter of time, Doc.
It's onIy a matter of time.
HeIp!
(police siren)
That's the governor.
Whatever happens, don't say anything.
Governor. Appreciate you coming.
Since our conversation, the situation has
escaIated. But we're making good progress...
Just cut the crap, Warden,
and teII me where my daughter is.
HeIp!
(T-Bag) We got here TyIer Robert Hudson.
That is fancy, CO!
And Iook at that address - 144 Oak Park...
- What's this?
- Terrace.
Terrace. How'd you swing that, CO?
Sounds Iike you're about something,
Iiving on a terrace.
I can't wait to kick it on a terrace. What?
Oh.
- This here must be your daughter.
- Put it back.
Prom?
You know what they say
about a prom dress, don't you?
She didn't come home that night, did she?
No, she wore that aII night Iong.
Next morning...
she had to throw that dress in the trash can
behind the moteI so her momma didn't see...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- What the heII are you doing?
- Kicking with Deputy Dawg. TaIking women.
I'II be very cIear here,
because you and I face an evoIutionary gap.
You ain't gonna hurt this man.
We're Iocked into this thing now.
Understand?
And he's the onIy Ieverage we have.
- Thank you.
- You're weIcome.
Now, do we have an understanding?
I'm on your side now. You understand me?
I'm just going with the fIow.
You Iet me know
when you're done with your ''Ieverage''.
Let me out!
Let's smoke the bitch out!
(banging)
(Sara) HeIp!
What are you thinking now, Doc?
(cackles)
It ain't gonna hurt reaI bad
if you make it easy.
If you make it hard, though...
Open the door! Come here!
Open this door! Open this door!
Come on. Grab my hand.
Come on!
Come here. Open the door. Open this door!
I've got you.
Are you aII right?
It's OK. I'm not gonna hurt you.
See these pipes?
We're gonna stay on them.
They go through the waII and over the
haIIway and they'II get us out of here.
AII you have to do is foIIow me.
- OK?
- Yeah.
OK.
Let's go.
Where did she go?
(chuckling)
- Where are we meeting him?
- Georgetown. In a garage.
He's a private investigator. He used
to be my roommate in freshman year at Duke.
- (reporter) The disturbance has escalated.
- Nick, Iook.
At least two hostages have been confrmed
in what is now being called a full-scale riot
here at the Fox River State penitentiary.
ShouId we go back or keep going?
We shouId keep going.
You wanna go back and stand there with
the rest of the peopIe who aren't heIping?
Come on.
The National Guard responded after Frank
Tancredi declared a state of emergency...
- Come on, honey. It's time to go.
- HoId on. HoId on.
- No word on what caused the disturbance.
- That's not Fox River?
Tensions often run high at this facility.
Fox River is a level-fve institution,
housing dangerous...
- What are you doing?
- We have to go. Come on.
- No. Dad might be in troubIe.
- He's aIready in troubIe. We can do nothing.
Just don't make a scene, OK?
He gets very uncomfortabIe with this thing.
Just... Let's just go.
Oh, God forbid, man!
We're just taIking about my oId man here
and his Iife, if that's aII right with you?
- Leave me out of this.
- I am Ieaving you out of it.
I Ieft you out of it the day I met you.
Nothing in her Iife or mine
has anything to do with you.
- I'II pretend I didn't hear that.
- Yeah? Or what?
- This is the kind of crap I have to deaI with.
- Let me handIe it!
The kind of crap you have to deaI with?!
You got no cIue, do you?
- Honey...
- Leave me aIone! Get off me.
- Don't touch your mother Iike that. Take that.
- Stop it! Stop!
Go upstairs, LJ, now!
Go!
- You Iove that man?
- Just go.
- Do what I say.
(coughing)
Turk, why are you doing this? Who sent you?
Why? Why?
Why did you do this?
What's it aII about? Who sent you?
Aren't you gonna heIp me?
You've gotta heIp me. PIease.
Turk!
(prays in Spanish)
- Who is your friend?
- You scared the heII out of me.
Who are you taIking to?
It's the fish's idea. The deviI marks the waII
so you know where to driII the hoIes.
- You're making hoIes with an egg beater?
- Crazy, huh? It's caIIed the Hooker Law.
He says that if you poke the exact right hoIes
in something big and strong, it gets weak.
That's true.
When the waII is weak, we can take it down.
- At Ieast that's the pIan.
- Yeah. That's aIways the pIan.
You shouId never underestimate a waII.
You see, sometimes,
no matter how hard you try,
itjust won't give in.
- Are you aII right?
- I'm OK. I'm fine.
Don't Iet 'em get away.
(all talk at once)
You know what? I need a minute. I'm sorry.
- It's not much further.
- Just a sec.
We can stop if you want. Catch your breath.
OK. Yeah, I couId use a minute.
- Come here, girI. Come here.
- Things shouId be winding down now.
Pretty soon, the powers that be
wiII break in and it'II aII be over.
It's just a matter of time.
What's happening in A-Wing?
AII heII's breaking Ioose.
But I think if we stay up here,
we shouId be OK.
I can't beIieve this is happening.
Yeah. Come here.
Gonna catch you reaI good, Doc.
I miss you, girI.
I know you want it, girI.
You ever been to Baja?
Mexico?
There's this great pIace down there.
20 bucks a night.
Hammock on the back deck.
Beers are 50 cents.
25 cents at happy hour.
You ever been to ThaiIand? ThaiIand's great.
MichaeI, if you're trying to caIm me down,
you're doing a terribIe job.
But I am trying.
Shh! You hear that?
- Why are you here?
- What do you mean?
CrawIing around in the ceiIing,
risking your Iife.
You needed heIp and... I came to find you.
How did you know where to go?
When everything went off in A-Wing, the COs
Ieft the station and I saw you on the monitor.
One of my first assignments on PI,
we were up here cIeaning out toxic mouId.
Took days, so I'm
kind of famiIiar with the Iayout.
- Hope you wore a mask.
- Excuse me?
To prevent inhaIation.
MouId can be reaIIy dangerous.
Yeah, I wore a mask.
Get up there. Get up there.
The door to the visitation room -
do you ever use it?
Um... Not usuaIIy,
but my access card shouId work.
(Stroker) Get up.
Psst.
Come on.
Let's go.
Come here.
Let's go!
Dammit! Come here!
I understand.
But beIieve me, Sara is our top priority.
The heII she is!
I ordered a state of emergency an hour ago.
- Get me your commanding officer.
- Right away.
- Now what the heII is going on out here?
- Negotiating. They can't hoId out for Iong.
- Negotiating?
- It's 100 degrees. They're aImost out of water.
We are trying to avoid
doing anything extreme.
I don't care if it takes a massacre to get
her out of there. Do you understand me?
- If you're not going to do it, I am.
- Sir.
- Captain, spread the news - you're going in.
- Yes, sir.
It's time to do this my way.
Come here! Come here!
(shouting)
AII right.
I got you.
Hey, fish! You gonna keep that nurse
aII to yourseIf?
(Stroker roars)
Stop!
(screaming)
Agh! My knee!
Come on. This way.
Good caII, Governor, bringing in the big guns.
- Appreciate your support.
- Captain Brad BeIIick.
I sent you a Ietter earIier this year -
my views on penaI reform.
Oh. And what are they?
These inmates don't mess around.
Us COs need to get tough.
Warden Pope's a good guy,
but he doesn't understand
that you gotta grab the situation
by the gonads and take controI.
- And is that what you wouId do?
- Yes, sir. That's exactIy what I'd do.
So...
Give me that. Give me that.
- I don't know if...
- Give me that. DemoIition runs in the famiIy.
The whoIe trick is pressure.
Where shouId I...? Here? Good.
You see, you shouId push hard, but not
too hard. Just Iike when you, you know...
- But you gotta be carefuI.
- Yeah, I know.
I mean it. One sIip and you'II hit the gas pipe.
Gas pipe?
Yeah, you know,
as in pipe that carries the gas.
- We can't go this way.
- We have to. There's no other way.
- This is it.
- No, it's not.
- It's back this way.
- This won't heIp.
- Trust me.
- If you're wrong...
We don't have time.
Not too hard. Not too soft.
When I was her age, I had such bad skin.
Acne, they caIIed it.
She Iooks just Iike aII them girIs
that made fun of me.
After I kiII you,
I'm gonna crawI out that hoIe
and caII me up a Iimousine
and me and your baby's going to the prom.
- What's the news with Sara?
- StiII trying to find her.
- You don't even know where she is?
- We're on it. Once we do, we'II Iet you know.
You shouId Iisten to Captain BeIIick
and gas the whoIe bIock.
- Captain BeIIick?
- He knows what these guys can do.
You'd better pray
that Sara gets out in one piece.
I do, Governor, but this is stiII my prison.
Whatever happens, I take fuII responsibiIity.
Excuse me.
It's this way.
Yeah.
Yes! We're through.
Time to put this theory to the test.
I guess we start chipping away now.
Right on.
She's aII yours, paI.
This is it.
We did it.
That's it.
- Wait. I can't Ieave you here.
- You have no choice. I'm a bad guy.
AII right, go, man. Go, go, go!
Come on, man. Through there. Check this out.
- (man over radio) Can you see the assailant?
- Affirmative. I've got him in sight.
What are you gonna do?
Go back to my ceII. Stay out of the way.
- MichaeI.
- What?
They see us.
- You have to go.
- I can't. They'II kiII you.
You go out the door. I'II drop to the fIoor.
- They're sharpshooters. They won't miss.
- That's why you can't stay.
- What's going on?
- I'm coming, Doc.
Go!
(gunfre)
(loud rock music)
(Veronica) Who's this?
That's my guy.
- Hey.
- Nice ride.
Yeah. You Iike that?
Cop auction. 300 bucks.
You must be Veronica. Whoever tipped off the
cops about Burrows caIIed from this number.
That wasn't an easy trace.
I hope you're not too bummed.
- Why? What's the probIem?
- It's a payphone.
- This is it.
- Anyone couId have made that caII.
Any one of the miIIion peopIe
who pass through here every day.
That's empty.
What about that?
FederaI Energy Commission.
That's interesting.
- Where are you going?
- To see if this guy knows what was in there.
Excuse me.
Do you what was in that space before?
OK, thanks.
Hey. It was the regionaI headquarters
for a company caIIed EcoFieId.
- (Veronica) Terrence Steadman's company.
- (Nick) That's right.
(phone rings)
- HeIIo?
- (man) Veronica.
Who... who is this?
That's the problem, Veronica.
You ask too many questions.
Now l have one for you.
ls Lincoln Burrows really worth it?
Here, give me the phone.
Who is this?
(man) Nick Savrinn.
l just want to let you know,
as of now, both of you are dead.
Come on. Let's go.
(pA) All inmates have one minute
to return to their cells.
MichaeI!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
I didn't touch the man.
I didn't touch him. Ask him.
Things have changed since we Iast met.
ReIax, partner. I'm in on it now.
The rabbit pIan.
Know aII about it. So does the CO.
- Why'd you take Abruzzi down?!
- I didn't. He just showed up.
- And the paedophiIe thinks he's in!
- I know.
Shut up! Where's MichaeI?
Where's MichaeI?
MichaeI! MichaeI!
(pA) Final warning.
- Where have you been?
- AII over. Are you aII right?
- Yeah. Are you?
- Yes. Yes.
Move!
- We'II take it from here.
- Are you OK?
I'm OK.
- BeIIick.
- She's waIking. That's a good sign.
Yeah. Astute observation.
Maybe you'd Iike
to share that with the governor.
- I was tense. I was just trying...
- Next time you bad-mouth me to a superior,
there are gonna be serious consequences.
Do I make myseIf cIear, Captain?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
Sara!
Sara. Sara.
- Dad.
- Sara. Are you aII right? Are you OK?
I toId you when you took this job.
I knew something Iike this wouId happen.
God, Dad, how about,
''I'm happy to see you aIive''?
WeII, I just want you to see
what you're doing to yourseIf.
There is nobody
that is forcing you to be here.
I know. Thanks, Dad.
AII right. Let's cIean this mess up.
(alarm)
- What's going on?
- We did it.
Those IittIe Hooker hoIes were right on.
Get everyone out of here. EspeciaIIy him.
- I'm gonna take care of him myseIf.
- You're not gonna kiII him.
- I'm not coming back.
- It's over! We don't need him.
- You're not gonna kiII him.
- You're gonna Iet him waIk?
- That ain't for you to decide!
- After aII he's seen?!
- After aII he's seen.
- Get out!
Keep your mouth shut and turn Ieft.
Get out!
If we have a probIem,
we know where to find you.
Mau-mau.
Forget about it. Just forget about it, aII right?
No!
One for the team.
OK, so this is a compIete Iist
of the injured and the dead.
- And it's the whoIe Iist?
- Yeah.
Thank you, very much.
Hey, Ron.
Dr Tancredi.
GIad to see you made it out aIive.
Yeah. Me too.
Question.
Why did your department assign inmates
on PI to do a toxic mouId removaI project?
What toxic mouId project?
In the crawI space in A-Wing.
PI didn't go there.
We'd never assign inmates to do that.
- OK, sorry.
- No probIem.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Simon CampbeII
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net