SCOFIELD: Previously on Prison Break:
I want him under 24-hour surveiIIance.
I have to be there when they kiII this man.
The Ieast you couId do is review his case.
REYNOLDS: Terrence,
The thing I can't quite figure is
with the crap storm this thing's become
why they haven"t killed you,
Have at it.
Now, out of respect
for what you once were,
I'm going to Iet you waIk away.
Why don't you
just hand me that shank you're hoIding?
I'm not even sure why you need it.
Thank you.
Your keys, they were right over there
by your in-box.
WeII, you got a maintenance guy
waiting outside here,
says you want him to change the Iocks.
Want me to caII him off?
No, send him in.
It's your Iast chance, Tweener.
ScofieId and his whoIe PI crew,
they're escaping.
You know I can't Iet you Ieave here, boss.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(MAN CHATTERING ON PA)
Dogs. The numerous times
I've been apprehended
whiIe trying to eIude the authorities,
it's aIways because of the damn dogs.
Turns out you can run
from just about everything in your Iife
except your own particuIar stink.
Yeah, weII, some of us stink
more than others.
Kinte, you can smeII
Iike a bouquet of bonbons,
but unIess you get rid of your smeII
you might as weII
send a note to the poIice
with directions and some cab fare.
You know, Theodore's right, man.
We gotta scrub down our ceIIs.
-What about our bunks?
-PiIIows, sheets, everything.
Either get rid of your smeII or change it.
WeII, how much time we got?
-SCOFIELD: John?
-Three days.
That's the soonest I couId get us
into the guards' room for PI.
You think you'II have
the extra suits by then?
ProbabIy. They shouId be here tomorrow.
Good, so we're good to go.
AII we got Ieft is figuring out
how to get through that door
in the infirmary.
How to get Linc out of that box.
-And you can do that in three days?
-Three days shouId be pIenty of time.
We got to get out of here.
Now.
I don't know how he found it. He just did.
SUCRE: So the hoIe's just sitting there?
I covered it the best I couId,
but it's just a matter of time
before someone discovers
BeIIick's missing.
What do you mean BeIIick's missing?
Okay, okay, okay. Fox River is a big pIace.
Maybe they won't notice for a whiIe.
Nothing happens around here
without BeIIick's say so.
Somebody is gonna notice
that he's missing.
And when they do,
they're gonna cIose this pIace down
untiI they find him.
What are we gonna do?
As soon as it gets dark, we go.
-SUCRE: Tonight?
-Pretty, we ain't ready to escape tonight.
Escape aIready started.
It started
the minute BeIIick found that hoIe.
And it's gonna end the minute
they figure out that he's missing.
Then stay!
I'II be sure to read the papers
in the morning.
See how many years you got
when they reaIized
which crew was working in that room
and dug that hoIe.
So what's the pIay, man?
Do you think you can have
the pIane ready by tonight?
Sure.
-You had kitchen duty, right?
-Yeah.
What'd you use to scrub down the fIoors?
I don't know. I think it was some peroxide,
or something Iike that.
That'II work. Get as much as you can.
I'II work on getting us
that key to the infirmary.
The rest of you find whatever you can
to get rid of the scent in your ceIIs.
None of this matters
if we can't get in the guards' room.
We're gonna Ieave after dinner,
during tier time when the gates are open.
7:00, one by one, through my ceII.
Whoa, whoa. No, we were supposed
to go through the guards' room.
That was going to give us a head start,
hours before they even found out
we were missing.
We Ieave through your ceII,
we ain't got no Iead time.
-7:00. Count's at 8:00, that's onIy...
-Sixty minutes.
Sixty minutes to get over that waII
and as far away from here as possibIe.
They'II be right on our asses.
PATTERSON: Quit your taIking and start
your waIking. Ladies, yard time is over!
They aIready are.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
Come on, Iet's go. Hurry it up. SingIe fiIe.
You know, there's one thing
we didn't taIk about out there.
Your brother.
I mean, he's under 24-hour surveiIIance.
I'm just saying,
if you can't get to him by tonight,
we stiII have to go, you know that, right?
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
GUARD: Lock it down.
Hey, boss.
What do you want?
My brother's in Gen Pop.
He's got no cIue I was in an accident.
So?
WeII, is there any way
I can get a message to him?
Yeah. Put it in your wiII.
And you're sure aII those dots connect?
Okay. Thank you.
-Who was that?
-A friend of mine at the titIe company,
handIed a Iot of my firm's business.
She dug up an address
for that phone number in BIackfoot.
Where is it?
It's not the where that's interesting,
it's the how.
It turns out our IittIe pIace in Montana
was purchased for $2 miIIion
by an offshore hoIding corporation.
WeII, that's pretty standard
for a transaction that size, though, right?
Sure. OnIy this hoIding corporation
was bankroIIed by a trust.
A trust financed
by the estate of Terrence Steadman.
Looks Iike you and I
are going to BIackfoot, Montana.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
-Have you seen BeIIick today?
-No.
-Why?
-Mack was asking.
-I guess he ain't showed up yet.
-(CHUCKLING) He's probabIy just Iate.
BeIIick? I haven't beat that guy to work
in eight years.
ScofieId, this ain't Gibsons. Move.
They're aIready starting
to ask questions, man.
We're not gonna
make it out of here in seven hours
without them finding the answers.
How we coming with that peroxide?
I'm gonna need it
before we meet up for yard duty.
ProbabIy not tiII Iater.
You wanna teII me what you need it for?
Makkos, you going to be
eating them there BrusseIs sprouts?
No.
-You mind if I...
-Take them.
They smeII Iike crap.
Do they, now?
What's up?
-Yo, if you got...
-Tonight.
-What?
-Change of pIans.
-Why, did something happen?
-Just find Sucre.
He'II teII you
what you need to do to be ready.
-But what about the...
-Tonight.
MAN: What the heII's going on?
The President changed his mind.
We were given assurances
he wouId veto the energy biII.
Assurances can teII you everything
that a man is going to do
untiI he wakes up in the morning
and changes his mind.
-Then change it back.
-I don't think you understand.
-The President...
-Have you enjoyed our support?
-Yes.
-Good.
We certainIy wouIdn't want you
to take it for granted.
-Are you threatening me?
-Why? Do you feeI threatened?
CaroIine, we've aII been
through this before,
the ebbs and fIows of poIiticaI conscience,
but we've found at the end of the day
we get what we want.
It's simpIy a matter of who heIps us get it.
If you can't convince a doddering oId fooI
finishing up his second term
what the best thing is
for this country's economy,
perhaps you're not the kind of heIper
we're Iooking for.
Sara.
-I was thinking about something...
-Enough, MichaeI.
Enough with the Iies and the coincidences
and the stories, aII of it.
-It's not what you think.
-I know what you did.
The question is,
are you man enough to admit it?
The keys.
CongratuIations. Is that the first time
you've been honest with me?
-It's not...
-The second?
What are you after, MichaeI?
-Is it drugs? Is it needIes?
-Neither.
Then what?
PIease understand that I never meant...
I never wanted to invoIve you in this.
WeII, you've done a pretty poor job of that.
I came here to teII you something.
I'm getting my brother out of here.
Tonight.
And I need your heIp.
MichaeI, honestIy, for your own good,
don't say anything more.
You know he's innocent.
Do what you're taIking about
and he won't be.
But he'II stiII be aIive.
You understand that I'm required
to report everything you're teIIing me.
-Yes.
-Then why wouId you?
Because you're the onIy one that can heIp.
And because I know
you want to be part of the soIution.
Yeah, aiding and abetting
is not part of the soIution.
Neither is doing nothing
knowing what you know about his case.
How dare you put this on me.
I did what I couId.
I gave my father the information...
No offense to your father,
but the peopIe who are framing LincoIn,
Iet's just say they have
a higher security cIearance.
-So now it's a conspiracy?
-I didn't come here to have a debate.
-You're asking me to break the Iaw.
-I'm asking you to make a mistake.
Not hurt anyone, not steaI anything.
Just forget to Iock up.
Leave the door unIocked
when you Ieave tonight.
That's it.
PIease.
This is where you're breaking out of?
This room?
There are aIarm contacts
on the gIass surrounding the door.
Otherwise, I wouIdn't need you to...
I was part of your pIan.
-Was it aII an act?
-At first, yes.
I needed to be here.
-But then I wanted to be here with you.
-Right.
And it's kiIIing me to know
that you'II never beIieve that.
Whatever you may think of me,
this is about LincoIn.
Don't make him pay for my mistakes.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-MAN: Yeah?
-Hi, it's me.
There's been an acceIeration.
-How fast are we taIking about?
-Fast, Tonight,
Son of a bitch.
I think what you're trying to say is,
''No probIem''?
-Yeah, of course. It'II be taken care of.
-Good,
-The van?
-Waiting up Fitz Street, 200 yards,,,
Behind the oId miII?
Behind the oId miII, I got it.
One question, John.
Don't you want a bigger pIane?
You onIy got three seats.
I thought you said
there were seven or eight guys.
WeII, not everybody gonna have a ticket.
You gonna teII me who is?
The three of us stiII breathing.
Whatever airport's cIoser to BIackfoot.
AisIe, window, it doesn't matter,
just get us on the next fIight.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah, I'II hoId.
HeIIo?
Change of pIans.
We're going to need you to have
a girI at the airstrip tonight.
Tonight?
Was I not enunciating?
No, it's just that...
Look, things couId get messy.
So wear a smock.
Is that his nympho secretary?
Come on, man, Iike you wouIdn't hit that.
I don't know, Vegas, 2:00 a.m., maybe,
but if she didn't have such a big booty.
Man, the booty is the man's
biggest weakness.
I know I wouId've hit it.
You find a way to the infirmary yet?
I'm working on it.
(MAN CHATTERING ON PA)
-Yo, you seen BeIIick today?
-Not yet.
I need to taIk to him.
Do you know if he went somewheres?
Do I Iook Iike his mother?
The guy hasn't shown up yet.
You sure he ain't showed yet?
'Cause I thought I saw him here
this morning, man.
Tweener!
-Need a hand over here.
-Yeah, I'm on it.
-AII right?
-Fine.
It's just sore, that's aII.
You Iive to my age,
you'II know aII about it.
You know you got
a coupIe of foxes in your hen house, right?
-Who are we taIking about?
-The bastard and the born again.
They both want out of here.
They'II behave untiI then.
Think so?
I just picked this off of T-Bag yesterday.
If I wouId've been there 10 seconds Iater,
they'd have been serving Abruzzi
with red sauce over at the morgue.
I know you want to be shot caIIer
and everything, and that's cooI,
but you got to handIe things, man.
Are you picking up
what I'm putting down?
-Yeah.
-Look, this is it, man.
Ain't no do-overs this time.
Can't be no compIications.
We break out tonight,
or we ain't never getting out.
We got that paperwork in from the county.
-Sara?
-Yeah. Sorry.
-The paperwork from the county.
-Right. I got it.
Do me a favor,
couId you take care of that for me?
-I got to get out of here.
-Sure.
Thanks.
-Where are you going?
-Out.
Put your bIues on over your PI gear.
-What?
-Just do it.
You want to teII us why?
If we don't have time
to get the suits we need,
we're gonna have to make them.
Yo, what the heII are you doing, man?
We got company.
It's okay. He's coming with us.
Hey, whatever happened to,
''We got too many peopIe''?
When the pIan changed, so did the timing.
-I'II make sure we aII get through.
-WeII, for heaIth reasons,
information Iike that shouId be
disseminated a IittIe more pronto.
Uh-uh, Fish. One more person means
there's one more thing that can go wrong.
He is not coming.
-It's not up for discussion.
-The heII it ain't.
I owe him.
I don't owe you a damn thing.
WeII, you're gonna if we get naiIed
'cause you didn't wanna
cut down on the damn guest Iist.
Don't worry, it'II be fine.
Hey! HoId up, cons.
I saw some drops of bIood
on the fIoor of the PI Iocker room.
Now who's going to teII me
what's going on?
That'd be me, boss.
I did it whiIe I was Ioading
some equipment back into the shed.
You make sure and get that patched up.
WiII do.
Okay.
Move it!
Are you okay?
Okay enough
to make it out of here tonight,
I swear.
(INAUDIBLE)
Hey, SheIIy, this is... It's me.
Listen, I know I'm supposed
to caII you as my sponsor,
in case I have a...
Whoa !
Right.
I think we shouId break
a bottIe of champagne across its bow.
If you're intending to get this thing home
for your anniversary tonight,
-I wouIdn't recommend it.
-No.
Listen, I want you to know that I...
WeII, I feeI very fortunate to have met you.
Yeah. I'm guessing
not many structuraI engineers
make their way into Fox River.
No, no, I don't mean
because of your vocation.
I mean because
you're a decent young man,
and there are not many of those
who make their way into Fox River.
WeII, for what it's worth,
there are a few down there.
WeII, that's good to hear.
Listen, I know this goes without saying,
but if there's anything you need...
WeII, Iet's just say that I owe you one.
ActuaIIy,
there is one thing you can do for me.
LINCOLN: So this whoIe thing,
this whoIe time, it was never about me.
It was about Dad.
I can't beIieve it.
MichaeI. MichaeI!
-What?
-You got something you want to teII me?
Just toId you everything we knew
about Dad was a Iie,
and you bareIy bIinked.
We have to go. Tonight.
What are you taIking about?
BeIIick found the hoIe,
so either we go now or it's over.
MichaeI.
Look, I know it's gonna be tight,
but I can do this.
-MichaeI, stop it.
-The chains on your Iocks, they're...
-MichaeI! MichaeI!
-I can do this!
Listen to me!
-Go. You gotta go.
-Don't say that.
Look at me! You can't do this.
There's not enough time.
If you stay here,
they'II naiI you and you'II rot in here.
I'm not asking you, man, I'm teIIing you.
Leave me behind.
Go.
-What the heII you think you doing?
-Nothing, man.
You trying to run something
for those Wonder Breads
-you been running around with?
-No, it ain't even Iike that.
TeII me something, boy.
Is you stepping or is you fetching?
I thought I made myseIf cIear
when I said your punk ass
was no Ionger in business.
This ain't business, aII right?
This is personaI.
What you got there anyway,
some kind of cIeaner?
What you trying to cIean up,
Sergeant FrankIin?
(CRACKING)
(GRUNTING)
MAN ON TV: There"s breaking news report
with implications
in the race for the Presidency,
Political correspondent
Nancy Lu has the details,
Nancy,
NANCY: And rumors coming out
of Vice President Reynolds" camp
detail a preliminary short list
of running mates
should she, as expected,
win her party"s nomination,
Perhaps the biggest surprise
is the inclusion of lllinois governor
Frank Tancredi,
His consideration
is attributed to his reputation
for being tough on crime,
And some point to his recent refusal
to grant clemency to Lincoln Burrows,
the murderer
of the Vice President"s brother,
which was welcomed
with deep appreciation
from within the Oval Office,
Thanks, Nancy,
Locally, a jackknifed big rig,,,
-What the heII are you doing, John?
-Lord's work.
The Lord wants you to spread horse crap
aII over your mattress?
It's not in our pIace to question his wiII.
Are we cIear?
GUARD: Hey, hey, hey! Let's cut the noise.
Open on 88!
-Yo, what's that?
-Avocado's gear.
He's getting out of the infirmary tonight.
Tonight?
So you got pIenty of time
to bake him a cake.
Hey, I heard you were asking Patterson
about BeIIick.
Said you thought you saw him
this morning?
Yeah. I was.
No, it was yesterday.
That's when I saw him.
You sure?
Yeah.
You know, time just sort of bIends
together up in here.
AII right.
CIose on 88!
SUCRE: What am I supposed
to do with this?
Pour it in the toiIet.
You had C-Note steaI some peroxide
from the kitchen
so we can cIean the toiIet?
We got to get aII of us
in the psych ward tonight
to access the pipes.
A bunch of cons wearing their prison bIues
wouId stick out Iike a sore thumb.
But the inmates in the psych ward
aII wear...
White.
-Peroxide acts as a bIeach.
-CamoufIage.
Just a few more hours now.
Looks Iike we got everything we need.
Everything except your brother.
You worry about the suits.
I'II worry about Linc.
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
-CouId you give us a coupIe of minutes?
-Of course, Mr. President.
-You probabIy know why I'm here.
-If I were a betting man,
I have a pretty good idea
where I'd Iay my chips.
The energy biII, Richard.
Why did you change your mind?
You've been saying for months
it's so fuII of pork,
the damn thing's ready to squeaI,
-and now aII of a...
-Yes, the biII is fIawed,
but it's better than doing nothing.
And, frankIy, I find it a IittIe curious
that you're here,
teIIing me to veto a biII
you voted in favor of.
You're on the way out.
Some of us need to think ahead.
ActuaIIy, I've been doing
some thinking ahead as weII, CaroIine,
specificaIIy, about my endorsement.
-What?
-I'm considering making a switch,
throwing my weight
behind Senator ChaIIis.
-You can't do that.
-Can't I?
CaroIine, you are everything
that's wrong with poIitics.
You vote not to IegisIate change,
but to profit.
You run not to make a difference,
but to make demands.
You put me on your ticket
not because I share your views,
but because I didn't share your gender.
So don't take the moraI high ground.
We aII know how this game is pIayed.
-Richard, pIease, I...
-Good day, CaroIine.
Richard! Richard!
You know what I got my wife
for our anniversary?
-What?
-A scarf.
WeII, this is a big one for me.
I had to do something speciaI.
Okay, Iet's get this thing down to the car.
-We'II do it aII together on three.
-AII right.
-Ready? One.
-Ready.
Two. Three.
Oh, no! Oh, no!
Put it down, put it down, put it down.
AII right, get ScofieId up here right away!
It's working.
AII right, get them out and get them dry.
We got to get them on under our cIothes
before tier time,
which is in 45 minutes.
-You think everyone eIse wiII be ready?
-We don't have a choice.
As soon as the gate's open, we go.
And we're gonna need every second.
Open on 40.
-ScofieId, Pope needs to see you, ASAP.
-Now?
-What for?
-A bar mitzvah. Let's go.
-It's 6:15, bro. You can't...
-Now!
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
Hey, pretty, tick-tock.
(CHATTERING)
Excuse me a minute.
(SIGHING) Sara, to what
do I owe the pIeasure?
I guess to congratuIations.
Can't beIieve I had to hear about it
on the news.
Oh, the VP thing. WeII, that's just taIk.
-Is it?
-Yeah.
What was it your mother used to say?
''It's aIways nice
to be invited to the dance,
''even if you don't have the right shoes.''
Yeah. She aIso used to say,
''Your father's a Iying bastard,''
but I figured
that was just the booze taIking.
You know,
it's aIways nice to see you, Sara.
Is there something that you needed?
-Or did you just come by to...
-Just teII me something.
Did you Iook at the information I gave you
from LincoIn Burrows' attorneys?
Sweetheart, move on.
The man's attorneys had a window
to present new evidence, they didn't.
Now that window is cIosed.
I just need to know,
did you Iook at the information?
-Come on, Sara.
-Answer me.
I swear,
working at Fox River has changed you.
You're aIways saying
you want to make a difference?
At that pIace? It's too Iate.
You shouId be a teacher,
so that you can get to these peopIe
-before they become...
-Did you Iook at the information?
I didn't need to.
I supported the findings of the court.
If you have a probIem with the verdict,
go after them.
But before you do,
I suggest you Iook at the guy's rap sheet
and ask yourseIf
if the worId wiII be a better pIace
with LincoIn Burrows waIking the streets.
Just teII me one thing.
Did they promise you the vice presidency
before or after
you signed his death warrant?
I wiII not discuss moraIity
with an addict and a thief.
You want to taIk reaIity, Sara?
How many times did I use my infIuence
to keep you
and one of your junkie boyfriends
out of jaiI?
How many? Was it three, four times?
I swear, Sara, it's funny, you know?
You have no troubIe whatsoever
with me bending the Iaw,
especiaIIy when it's bent in your direction.
Grow up.
PATTERSON: You taIk to that Tweener kid?
Yeah, he says he got his days mixed up,
but I don't know.
-What?
-Just something about the way he said it.
Oh, come on, man,
BeIIick's just taking a personaI.
-I don't want to get the guy busted.
-And if he's not?
I'm just saying, it's 6:30,
and no one's heard from the guy.
We got to teII Pope.
Okay. I'II teII him.
VERONICA: Did you caII
a cab for the airport?
No, not yet.
Why not?
Come on, the fIight Ieaves in an hour.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm starting to think
that us going to Montana
might not be a good move.
What are you taIking about?
What if you are right
and the smoking gun is in that house?
You think they're just gonna
Iet us waIk in there
and make a citizen's arrest?
Look, Nick,
I don't know what your deaI is IateIy,
but I'm getting on that pIane
with or without you.
I can't Iet you do that.
AII this time you were one of them?
Who's puIIing your Ieash, Nick?
Steadman? KeIIerman?
Look at me.
I want you to remember my face
when you do
whatever the heII it is you're gonna do.
Look at me!
You're a coward.
-ScofieId's outside, sir.
-Okay.
I want you to try every number we have
for Brad BeIIick.
Try his home first.
His mother usuaIIy answers.
Mrs. BeIIick? Hi.
One moment, pIease.
I have Warden Pope here for you.
Mrs. BeIIick?
No cause for aIarm, no, no. We just...
We haven't seen him,
and we were wondering
if he might be home under the weather.
So Brad caIIed you
when he puIIed in this morning?
And he said he was here?
Okay, weII, thank you, Mrs. BeIIick.
We'II keep you posted. I'm sure he's fine.
Radio Mack.
Have him check the parking Iot
for BeIIick's truck.
If he finds it,
have him caII me immediateIy.
457.
This is base. What's your 20?
MARICRUZ: I'm pregnant, Fernando.
I'm gonna have your son.
But aII I know is, is I'm reaIIy scared.
I'm reaIIy scared to do this aIone.
MAN: John, it's never too Iate.
If you'II agree
to accept Christ into your heart
and turn from your sin,
he wiII forgive you
and save you in eternity.
I'II give you Fibonacci
when the time is right.
The time is right now.
No, the time is right when you and I
are both standing outside those waIIs.
I'm gonna get out of here someday,
and when I do,
don't think I won't remember
what your front steps Iook Iike.
C-NOTE: I'm being shipped back off.
How many times I got to say it?
You onIy got one thing I need.
POPE: l"ve got some bad news, Charles,
Your daughter"s got esophageal cancer,
and she wants to see you
while there"s still time,
-How Iong does she have?
-HospitaI says a week.
(GASPING)
(GROANING)
POPE: l read somewhere
where the actual Taj Mahal
appears pink in the morning,
milky white in the evening
and golden when the moon shines,
The changes, they say,
depict the different emotions of a woman,
WeII, I can teII you something,
if we don't get this thing fixed tonight,
I don't wanna know what kind of emotion
my wife is gonna have
if I waIk through that door empty-handed.
It's strange. I mean, it just gave way.
We Iifted it up,
and the support beam snapped.
-What's this?
-The support.
And the one that hoIds up that beam.
You took it?
I'm sorry.
But I needed to get back in here.
-I don't understand. Why wouId you...
-I'm breaking out.
And you're gonna make sure
my brother goes with me.
www.tvsubtitles.net