previously:
- I didn't kiII that man.
- The evidence says you did.
- I was set up.
- Put down your weapon.
I find it incumbent
you see the inside of a prison ceII.
- I'm Iooking for LincoIn Burrows.
- He kiIIed the vice president's brother.
- Why you wanna see Burrows?
- He's my brother.
- I'm getting you out.
- That's impossibIe.
Not if you designed the pIace.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
- Better than that.
I've got 'em on me.
- You find out who's trying to bury him.
- Nobody is.
The evidence was cooked.
- A Iawyer's poking around.
- Anyone that's a threat is expendabIe.
ScofieId, found you a new ceIIie.
Haywire, get in here.
- Someone found Fibonacci.
- Who was this someone?
Where is Fibonacci?
I give you that information, I'm a dead man.
Joey.
On your feet.
What time is it?
- Get up.
- What's going on?
Let's go, LincoIn. On your feet.
- BeIIick.
- Come on, move it.
BeIIick. BeIIick. No! BeIIick!
BeIIick!
BeIIick! Where are you taking...
BeIIick! No!
No! BeIIick, no! No! I got a month Ieft!
PIease, no, BeIIick!
BeIIick, no. BeIIick, pIease, no!
No, I got a month Ieft! PIease!
No, BeIIick...
PIease, BeIIick...
Make your peace, LincoIn.
Let's get on with it.
(door slams)
(man) Open 40.
CIose 40.
Haywire, you ever thought of breaking out?
- What the heII wouId I do out there?
- Not be here.
HaIfway houses. Psych visits.
Meds. Checking in with the PO.
Urine tests. Keeping ajob.
No. Why'd you ask?
This guy was taIking about it in the yard.
I didn't know what to say.
TeII Officer BeIIick.
He'II make Iife easier for you if...
If what?
- Your tattoos.
- What about them?
What are they of? No, no, no,
what are they? Like, some kind of...
- They're just tattoos.
- (guard) Candy time, Haywire.
They think I have schizo-affective disorder
with bipoIar tendencies.
Think you got it?
Whatever.
I take the piIIs
to keep the quacks off my back.
Bye, now.
Get outta the way.
You know, maybe they give you
those things for a reason.
Yeah. To keep me duII.
To keep me
in their invisibIe freaking handcuffs.
SeriousIy. Those tattoos, they're beautifuI.
You mind if I, you know,
Iook at the whoIe thing?
I do, actuaIIy.
Why?
(guard) Yo. Stand cIear.
Does there need to be a reason?
Sucre.
I'm not even taIking to you, man.
(Abruzzi) What's the probIem?
- Nothing I can't handIe.
- WeII, I knew there was a probIem.
I couId teII by Iooking at you
from across the yard.
Guys, didn't I say there was a probIem?
So what's the probIem?
- You're Iooking at it.
- What, Haywire?
Yup. He's my new ceII mate.
- That's a probIem.
- He doesn't sIeep.
- So when do you dig?
- I don't.
Hey, you and I are in bed now.
You made me a promise. You said
that we were gonna get out of here.
You renege now, and I'm gonna cut you.
So you better take care of your business.
Or I wiII take care of you.
Have a nice day.
It's reaIIy coming together, isn't it?
- Yup.
- You think it'II be done in time?
WeII, I figure we stiII have the interior aIcoves
and piIasters to do, which is no smaII task.
But, yes. I think so.
Listen, I have to say I reaIIy appreciate
aII the effort that you put into this.
I wish there was some way I couId,
you know, pay you, or something.
There is one thing you couId do for me.
- My ceII mate.
- The inimitabIe CharIes Patoshik. Haywire.
- Then you know.
- HoId it right there.
Officer BeIIick is in charge of ceII transfers.
You're gonna have to taIk to him about that.
I tried. But he seems to think
we're a good match.
- Has he threatened you?
- Who? Haywire or BeIIick?
UnfortunateIy, unIess there's
some evidence of vioIence
or sexuaI predation between ceII mates,
those kinds of requests
faII on deaf ears around here.
Prison system's a IittIe too crowded
for requests based on personaIity.
- It's not exactIy SandaIs out there.
- (knock at door)
Warden, sorry. Your wife is here.
What? She's not supposed
to be here tiII four o'cIock.
Becky, do not Iet her come in here
under any circumstances.
She's not supposed to see this
untiI our anniversary. I'II be right out.
Hi, sweetheart. You're earIy.
- Let's go eat.
- You're acting funny.
- I am?
- What's going on in there?
- Just going over some fiIes.
- Becky said you were in a meeting.
This isn't ToIedo aII over again, is it?
ToIedo? How can you say that?
- Then you won't mind if I Iook.
- Uh, Judy...
Warden, I'm not gonna be abIe to cooperate.
I'd get kiIIed if I did.
Johnson's stiII deciding.
Then you and I are done.
You shouId have just toId me.
WeII, you know how anxious I get
when you come around the inmates.
Becky, have a guard
escort Johnson back to his ceII.
I'II deaI with him Iater.
Come on, Iet's eat.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm your attorney.
I'm representing you now.
Hm.
If that's aII right with you.
- Last time I saw you, you caIIed me a Iiar.
- Things have changed.
I beIieve you now.
I got in touch with
Crab Simmons' ex-girIfriend, Leticia.
She corroborated your story.
- WiII she testify?
- She's missing.
I don't know.
I think the Secret Service got to her.
- Secret Service?
- They've been poking around.
They show up, she disappears.
What do you think?
Oh, man.
I didn't reaIise it was that high up, you know?
Do you know what we're up against?
I know it's a Iot more
than either of us can handIe on our own.
- Project Justice.
- Why have I heard of them?
They handIe death penaIty cases.
There's a guy, Ben Forsik.
I sent him copies of everything.
You couId teII him what you found.
Maybe it'II be enough to bring him on board.
OK.
So, uh, how's Sebastian?
What do you mean?
WeII, you being here.
I mean, is he cooI with it?
I haven't taIked to him.
The, um...
The engagement's off.
Oh.
Sorry.
You couId at Ieast say that Iike you mean it.
I do.
God, you aIways were a Iousy Iiar.
Yeah.
I better get to Project Justice.
Veronica.
Thank you. I didn't have a whoIe Iot Ieft.
You can thank me when I get you out of here.
(door buzzes)
Baby, it's me. Are you there?
HeIIo? Are you there?
Hey. If she is,
she obviousIy don't want to taIk to you.
It's Wednesday, babe.
You were gonna come around today, right?
Look, I gotta hang up now.
I gotta go back in the bIock, but...
you're gonna be here today, right?
I'm your man, baby, and I Iove you.
I do.
It's a pattern.
- What did you say?
- Your tattoo. It's a pattern.
You're seeing things.
Putting him in with Haywire is a Iow bIow.
What? The shrinks cIeared Haywire
for re-entry into Gen Pop.
- He's so doped up on meds he's Iike a kitten.
- A kitten who murdered both his parents.
With respect, sir,
if you give ScofieId preferentiaI treatment,
it'II undermine your credibiIity.
I know you got a soft spot for the guy
because he's got brains
and he's heIping you with that contraption,
but the guy's a vioIent criminaI.
He deserves punishment
as much as the rest of these guys.
You know that I'm Iess interested
in punishment than I am in rehabiIitation.
And sticking him in with Haywire
is not rehabiIitation in my book.
You deIegated authority
over Gen Pop to me, boss.
- I know I did.
- You gotta Iet me do my job or pass it on.
Now, Brian, go easy.
There's a reason I'm giving you
more and more responsibiIity.
When I retire,
I'm recommending you to take my pIace.
Don't make me regret it.
AII I'm saying is, take another Iook at the
ScofieId situation. I trust yourjudgment.
Yes, sir.
HoId up. This is supposed to be
an open visitation. Why we doing it here?
Ask your visitor.
What are you doing here? Where's Maricruz?
- She's not gonna be coming any more.
- Is she hurt?
No, no, she's fine, she's fine.
She's just, uh...
She's with me now.
She's with you now? It's ajoke, right?
No, she made a decision, man.
She decided she needed stabiIity.
- Is she gonna get that from you?
- You can think what you want about me but...
I'm not the one who's in prison.
I actuaIIy can do something for her.
She wanted me to taIk to you first
in case you got mad...
Hijo de tu madre, jte voy a matar!
As¨ª sea lo ultimo que hagas.
jDesgraciado! jTe voy a matar!
You just proved my point.
You're a con.
And that's aII you'II ever be.
Make it quick.
Yeah. He's right in here.
Take a waIk, Choppy.
ScofieId.
You're in a restricted area.
I'm doing yard work for PI.
We need some fertiIiser.
Then why are you in the masonry section?
Oh, by the way, how's the foot?
Don't ever go around me to the Pope again.
Now, move.
You know what, Haywire?
I don't think we're gonna work out.
And since I was here first,
I think you shouId go.
I crapped myseIf once in junior high.
During PE, we were pIaying badminton,
and I knew I had to waIk past a bunch of the
other students to get back to the Iocker room,
and so I just started waIking.
And I tried to make fun of it,
you know, before anyone eIse did.
So I turned around behind me,
and I said, ''Look, I have a taiI.''
I just shared a secret with you.
- Now it's your turn.
- You want to know what the tattoos mean?
- Yeah.
- Nothing.
(Abruzzi) Hey, fish.
Making any progress?
With SIeeping Beauty back there?
Or with the digging?
- Either.
- No.
- But I know what to do.
- Oh, yeah?
ProbIem is,
you don't got the stugots to do it.
(guard) Abruzzi, Iet's go.
See ya.
Yeah? ReaIIy?
WeII, teII the crazy son of a bitch I said hi.
- Wrap it up.
- How's Aunt Ruth? She out of hospitaI?
- HoId on, Ma.
Bite me.
OK. We got a probIem now, man.
Let's handIe it then.
That's what I thought.
(phone rings)
- HeIIo?
- Maricruz? It's me.
What's going on?
What's the deaI with you and Hector?
- When were you gonna teII me?
- What?
That Rita SaIda¨¾a's been visiting you.
- Yeah. Hector told me.
Hector toId you. Of course he toId you.
Baby, that guy is a snake. He's a Iiar.
- Why wouId he Iie?
- Why would he lie?
Because he's been trying to get into your
pants since the minute we started dating.
You know what? I don't know what to beIieve.
Me, mami. BeIieve me.
Yeah, while l wait by the phone twice a week.
Baby, where is this coming from?
I don't know.
Look, there's just so many things.
Yesterday I went to Teresa's house,
and I saw her baby.
Is that what this is about?
Your cIock is ticking?
WeII, I am gonna be 30 in a few years.
You're 25. You want to get pregnant?
Let's get pregnant right now.
I can't get pregnant untiI I'm married.
We're gonna get married. In 16 months.
Yeah, weII, Hector says
that if something goes wrong in there,
you couId serve your fuII sentence.
I can't wait ten years.
l can't wait ten years, baby.
I'm gonna be out in 16 months.
Te lo prometo, mi amor.
But what if something does happen, huh?
Baby, I can't wait that Iong.
I can't.
I'm sorry, I gotta go.
HeIIo? Baby, wait... HeIIo?
Even if Leticia turned up,
her testimony wouId be worthIess.
By and Iarge, mostjunkies with
criminaI records don't shine on the stand.
I just found aII this out
in the past coupIe days.
I'm confident I can find out more
now that I'm devoting aII my time to the case.
The agent who came to visit when Leticia
was in your office, what did he want?
Nick, pIease. You've got to understand,
unIess there's new information for us,
we've aIready reviewed
Mr Burrows' case thoroughIy.
Do you have any new evidence?
- No, but I...
- But.
That is what you're teIIing us, right?
I need to cIarify here.
Yes. That is what I'm teIIing you.
But, Mr Forsik, you don't need to point out
what I don't have. I'm weII aware of that.
I'm asking for your heIp. I don't think a man
shouId be kiIIed for something he didn't do.
That's what it says
on your mission statement in the Iobby.
- We get many requests for representation.
- I'm sure you do...
And I have to decide which cases we're going
to devote our Iimited resources to.
I wiII do aII of the Iegwork, Mr Forsik,
but with no experience
in death penaIty cases,
I'm just asking you
to point me in the right direction.
PIease.
I'm sorry.
We just don't have the manpower.
Thank you for your time.
She's just Ieaving now.
It'II take her a haIf-hour
to get across town in this traffic.
We're not gonna need nearIy that much time.
I've turned up quite a bit aIready.
Hey. Hey, have you seen my toothpaste?
- It was right here.
- I haven't seen it.
- I aIways put it in the same pIace.
- I'm sure it'II turn up.
(guard) Lights out in ten minutes.
The tattoos - there's a maze.
- Get away from me.
- I need to see 'em.
You gotta show 'em to me.
It's puIIing me in.
I said, get away from me.
OK.
He's got a maze on his skin.
Man's got a maze on his skin.
Why? Why wouId he do that? Why?
Why wouId he put a maze on his skin?
Um...
I don't know.
- How are your contacts in chemicaI Iockup?
- Depends who's asking.
I need a bottIe of drain Iine root controI,
sooner than Iater.
You got weeds growing in your ceII?
Just one.
(man) Looking for me?
I wanted to ask some questions
about the LincoIn Burrows case.
- Yeah?
- I'm Veronica Donovan.
I'm representing LincoIn on his appeaI.
What about it?
You were the first one to LincoIn's
apartment the night of the murder.
Right.
I'd reaIIy appreciate it if you couId
just teII me exactIy what you saw.
Dispatch caIIed. Burrows was seen running
from the garage where they found Steadman.
So we went over to Burrows' pIace.
We spread out, l took the bathroom. l saw
your client washing out the bloody pants.
PoIice! Hands up.
I don't need to teII you
it was Steadman's bIood.
In the report you typed up, you said
you saw LincoIn in the bathroom. That's aII.
Later, you testified that you saw him
washing the pants. Which one is it?
- Does it matter?
- Did you see him washing the pants or not?
Yes. He stood up, turned around,
his hands were aII wet, Iooking guiIty as heII.
Your testimony factored into his conviction.
You know that, right?
You know, Iady, if you got any other
questions, just go through the department.
Ms Donovan?
I didn't mean to scare you.
- What are you doing here?
- Nick Savrinn, with Project Justice.
I know who you are,
but what are you doing here?
Look, my boss may not think
LincoIn's case is worth Iooking into, but I do.
There's a quicker way
to take care of your probIem.
There's smarter ways, too.
(guard) Lights out in ten minutes.
Hey, Iights out in ten minutes.
What stood out was that most death penaIty
cases take ten years to exhaust aII appeaIs.
LincoIn got there in three.
So for it to be expedited, there had
to have been some poIiticaI infIuence?
Steadman was the vice-president's brother.
It's not hard to beIieve.
How? They got to every judge
that rejected his appeaI?
It doesn't take ajudge.
AII it takes is a IittIe speciaI attention
from one of his cIerks.
But how LincoIn got fast-tracked
doesn't interest me. It's why.
If he was set up, then why?
I think the answer to that
might Iie in the victim.
What do we know? He was a CEO of EcoFieId,
right? He was pushing aIternative energy.
Successfully pushing aIternative energy.
OiI companies, the Saudis,
even our government -
a Iot of peopIe stood to benefit
with Steadman out of the picture.
Why did you wait tiII now
to take up this case?
I thought he did it, Iike everybody eIse.
I just hope it's not too Iate.
It very weII may be.
You need to prepare yourseIf for that.
What about you?
Why death penaIty work?
My father did 15 years
for a crime he didn't commit.
I know that when the government gets you in
their cross hairs, you stand very IittIe chance.
That's why.
Now, do you want my heIp?
- I want in.
- Too Iate.
I'II do anything.
These hands are digging machines.
I'II get you to China.
I'II dig Iike a psychotic rodent if I have to.
Fish, I gotta be back in.
As of right now, there is no in.
Van Gogh over there is my new ceII mate.
But you're gonna get rid of him.
- I'II do what's necessary.
- You're my boy.
- So how you gonna do it?
- Let's just put it this way.
Someone's gonna get hurt.
(phone ringing)
(woman) How did we miss this?
ScofieId's father was out of the picture by the
time he was born. Took his mother's name.
AII right. ScofieId had no priors
and a fuII-time job as an engineer?
- (man) Correct.
- Then he goes and robs a bank,
discharging a gun in the process,
so in sentencing he couId
manoeuvre his way to Fox River,
where his brother's
scheduled to die in less than a month.
- Obviously, something's up.
- With aII due respect,
brothers are incarcerated together aII over.
It may just be a coincidence.
(woman) Move on the younger brother.
Do it pre-emptiveIy, before anything rises up,
bites any of us in the ass.
It's a pathway.
Where does it Iead?
Where are you taking me?
What? Are you nuts?
Officer! I need an officer!
What the heII's the probIem down here?
What the... Son of a bitch.
Open up on 40.
He's got the pathway on his body.
It Ieads somewhere.
- Back off, Haywire.
- Now, Iook.
Look at his tattoos. It's a pathway.
I said back off.
You want a hot shot?
I'm teIIing you, Iook... Argh!
Back off, man.
- Let's go. Get him out of here.
- It Ieads to heII! It Ieads to heII!
It's a pathway to heII!
He's taking us aII to heII!
(door slides opens)
So, the gang's aII back together again.
WeII, ain't that sweII?
I toId you
not to go around me with the Pope.
But you just keep making waves, don't you?
- Good to be back, man.
- Good to have you back.
So, when do we get started?
- Good afternoon, Mr ScofieId.
- HeIIo.
How are you feeIing today?
ReaI good.
What happened?
Uh...
Caught an eIbow pIaying basketbaII.
Uh-huh.
- Mind if I take a Iook?
- By aII means.
You know you're gonna get kiIIed
in here, right? If you're not carefuI.
I'II make you a bet.
When I get out of here, aIive,
I'II take you to dinner.
Lunch. Cup of coffee.
MichaeI, this charm act
couId be exactIy what's getting you
into troubIe out in the yard.
Lean forward.
AII right. You went to the parking garage,
Terence Steadman is aIready dead.
- That's right.
- You saw that, you ran? Took the gun?
- Dumped the gun.
- Where?
- Storm drain. Van Buren and WeIIs.
- Nobody ever found it.
What did you do after that?
Go back to your apartment?
Yeah.
l was freaking out,
trying to fgure out what had happened.
Then l saw the bloody pants in the tub.
The cops, they busted in
a minute after I got there.
The pants, with Steadman's bIood on them.
First cop on the scene says
he saw you washing them in the tub.
He's Iying. My hands were wet
after spIashing water on my face.
PoIice! Let's see the hands! Hands up!
I never touched those pants.
Which brings us back to the gun,
the one you dumped.
It was pIanted.
OnIy way it couId have got there.
- BaIIistics matched it to a sIug...
- The gun was pIanted. Just Iike the pants.
Your fingerprints were aII over the gun.
Bo.
- Who's Bo?
- He's the guy who arranged everything.
He had me come round the night before,
try a few guns, see which one felt right.
That was the setup. One of those
must have been the murder weapon.
That's how they got my fingerprints
on the gun. Had to be.
AII right. So this Bo, he coerces you
into doing this, aII to cIear a $90,000 debt?
He was gonna kiII my son.
- WeII?
- Lot of ''I didn't do it'', don't count for much.
The tape that shows LincoIn
puIIing the trigger. You got it?
- Yeah.
- If LincoIn's teIIing the truth, the tape's Iying.
I think we shouId have a Iook,
decide for ourseIves.
You're cIear.
If the chemicaIs can eat
through the iron pipes,
how come they can't eat
through the tube?
When the chemicaIs are combined,
they become a corrosive.
- You studied chemistry or something?
- Not in schooI.
But what you're doing up there
in the infirmary,
what's it gotta do with this here?
Getting through this waII
is just the beginning.
There's a whoIe Iot of reaI estate
in between here and the outside waIIs.
The infirmary's
the cIosest buiIding to those waIIs.
And the weakest Iink in the security chain.
CooI.
I think I've removed enough grout
to bust through.
I'm gonna need you to make some noise.
# Como una promesa, eres t¨±.
Como una ma¨¾ana...
Is that the best you can do?
Have some faith, papi. Have some faith.
# Como una sonrisa, eres t¨±
- (man) Shut up!
- # Eres t¨±, as¨ª...
- (angry shouts and commotion)
- # Eres t¨±
# Mi esperanza, eres t¨±, eres t¨±
- (klaxon)
- # As¨ª, eres t¨±
# Eres t¨±
# Como el agua de mi fuente
(screaming) # Eres t¨±
# Eres t¨±
- # Eres...
- (klaxon)
Not one more word. Next inmate
that opens his mouth goes in the hoIe.
(whispers) We're good.
You OK?
Work.
- It's fine.
- (doorbell)
I got it.
- Everything aII right?
- CouIdn't be better.
You want to come in?
We just sat down to eat.
No. I just wanted to stop by
to teII you in person.
- ProbIem soIved.
- What's this?
That is a transfer request. MichaeI ScofieId
is getting shipped out tomorrow.
Have a good night.
Visiontext SubtitIes: PauI Burns
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net