previously on ''prison Break'':
We're through the hard part.
Another 18 inches, we'II hit that pipe.
We'II be there by Friday.
Now, we got a heII of a Iot
to taIk about, don't we?
- This guy says he's on the job in here.
- Concrete is my speciaIity.
OK, boss. Sign him up.
Whites don't want you, bIacks don't want you.
You're just caught in the middIe, aren't you?
A reguIar tweener.
- HeIIo?
- It's me. It's time.
Yes.
Why are you so cynicaI?
I think there's cynicism
and then there's reaIism.
And there's optimism. Hope. Faith.
Thank you for trying to make me smiIe.
Not today.
(Michael) You never know.
You want the Cooper story?
I can't give it to you.
Cos I'm not him.
The Iawyers, they're stiII running around.
Same thing goes for the kid.
You gotta hand the reins over to me. Now.
First of aII...
You and your partner
are off the job untiI further notice.
(alarm beeps)
(turns on tap)
- (Michael) That one.
- (man) Nice choice.
PIatinum. Brushed.
- 6.25?
- 6.25.
She's a Iucky woman.
Yes.
She is.
- You kept it.
- Kept what?
- The fIower.
- I'm a pack rat. I never throw anything out.
Yeah. AII this cIutter, it's overwheIming.
- You shouId see my apartment.
- Whoa.
Haven't even had our first date yet,
and you're aIready inviting me in.
- I thought you were a nice girI.
- MichaeI, we aII know nice girIs finish Iast.
So where do you finish?
That depends on where I start.
Deep breath.
ExhaIe.
InhaIe.
Sara, we're backing up out here.
Right. I'm sorry.
I'm gonna get your shot.
This is not what I signed on for.
What do you want us to do?
Wave the white fIag?
- I just want to get LincoIn off death row.
- LincoIn?
Vice President ReynoIds funneIIed miIIions
of doIIars into her brother's company.
That money was fiItered into smaII accounts
that made smaII donations to her campaign,
setting her up to be
the Ieader of the Free WorId.
This doesn't end
with us stopping an execution.
(Veronica) For me it does.
OK. Let's rotate.
Sergeant Sodomy, you're up next.
Yo.
- Come on.
- I don't know about y'aII, but...
This room is getting
a IittIe too dark for me to dig.
Are you teIIing me that there's a hoIe
in Fox River that you don't want to get into?
Hey. No one gets hurt.
Hey, you know, I got a question.
Now, how come FusiIIi over here
ain't grabbing a shoveI?
I handIe arrangements on the outside.
ReaIIy? What is that?
Transport, paper, what?
ExactIy. Makes me manager.
- And that makes us just Iabour, right?
- Mm-hm. Now you're getting it.
You know, management better keep
a cIose eye on the conditions up in here.
Or the Iabour's IiabIe to go on strike.
- Get back to work.
- Whoa, CO coming.
(Sucre) Hurry, you guys.
Come on, cover it up.
Put that back up there.
ScofieId. Move it.
It's time for your conjugaI.
Your wife is here.
So you're Mrs ScofieId?
Ever done this before?
Had a conjugaI, I mean.
(woman) No.
Don't worry,
I'm just trying to make conversation.
CIear.
She Iook famiIiar to you?
No, Captain.
I know her from somewhere.
You came.
Of course.
- How've you been?
- Fine. I found ajob.
Good. I'm gIad.
Is it awfuI, being here?
Remember the first pIace you stayed?
That hoteI, by the airport?
OnIy difference is $69 and the free shampoo.
AIways the brave face.
You're stiII wearing it.
Every day.
I worry about you.
Don't.
Is there anything eIse that I can do?
Just what we agreed on.
I was so nervous when they were checking.
One question.
Why wouId you need a credit card in prison?
The riot didn't change anything.
Have you seen the budget cuts?
- Another 10¡ã/¡£ from heaIthcare.
- And 35 from prevention.
He's the governor, but aIso your father.
Maybe he thinks if he cuts enough,
they can't afford you.
(Michael) Thank you.
You understand this is standard procedure
foIIowing a conjugaI, right?
Never can be too carefuI.
AII right. Bend over.
You have a good time
in the romper room with that Euro?
Whatever you say, boss.
- She come around here before?
- First time.
You sure? Cos damn
if I don't recognise her from somewhere.
Maybe she visits some other con.
KiIIing two birds with one bone.
- Catching my drift?
- I wouIdn't know.
AII right. He's cIear, Captain.
Make sure you take a shower, ScofieId. You
never know what some women can give you.
# Swing Iow, sweet chariot
# Coming for to carry me home
# Swing Iow
You know this one, don't you?
# Sweet chariot
# Coming for to carry me home
Come on, gimme something.
I thought you was a musicaI peopIe.
You know, your parents
must be so proud of you, man.
Hitting the traiIer park trifecta.
You're a racist, a paedophiIe, and stupid.
You know, it vexes me that I'm made out
to be the bad guy in the room.
Y'aII ain't here
for steaIing GirI Scout cookies.
None of us murdered
any GirI Scouts in the process.
MichaeI's coming back from the boneyard.
AIone, aIone.
I teII you aII about me,
you don't teII me you're married?
Later.
(C-Note) Rough day, huh, ScofieId?
WhiIe the rest of us
are in here sIinging concrete,
you got some IittIe girI in
to pIay on your rusty trombone, huh?
Man's got a point.
Itjust doesn't seem equitabIe, Iike.
- Shut up and dig, T-Bag.
- (Abruzzi) What the idiots want to know is,
whiIe we're digging this hoIe,
what are you doing?
I'm going shopping.
(Sucre) We're good.
AII cIear.
Credit card? The buIIs catch you with that,
they'II be so far up your doggy door...
Don't worry.
They won't be catching me with one.
- How you so sure?
- Because...
I don't have a credit card.
(thud)
- Nick?
- (knocking)
(Quinn) HeIp! PIease...
- PIease, I had an accident, my car is totaIIed.
- (knocking)
Is there anybody there?
- We can'tjust ignore him.
- The heII we can't.
(Quinn) HeIp me. PIease!
HeIp me, pIease.
Ow! God!
- (Nick) What happened?
- I must've dozed off.
I've been driving for 12 hours.
- ShouId I get some water from the weII?
- No, the weII's dried up.
I think there's a medicaI kit over here.
No one's going anywhere.
- AII right. Say goodbye to Junior.
- (muffled yell)
(muffled cry)
You know how many pints of bIood
the human body has?
The answer is ten. Ten pints.
How many you think Prince Charming
over there on the fIoor has Ieft?
Eight, going on seven?
I'm gonna take him out to the woodshed,
have a IittIe taIk.
In the meantime,
I want you to chew on this.
You teII me everything about the Burrows
case, and who eIse you've toId about it,
and there's a chance that I might Iet you go
in time to get Mr Savrinn to a doctor.
You decide whose Iife is more vaIuabIe.
The guy waiting to die on death row, or the
guy wishing he'd die out in the woodshed.
One suit, black.
One pair of socks, black.
One pair of shoes. Shoelaces.
One small tape recorder.
One gold watch.
You ever stayed at a fancy hoteI, LJ?
You Ieave your room in the morning,
it's a mess.
Wet dirty toweIs on the bathroom fIoor, Iast
night's room service stinking to high heaven.
Then, you come back at night, it's aII gone.
Fresh toweIs, sheets,
candy on the piIIow.
It's just the best feeIing in the whoIe worId.
Cos someone eIse cIeaned up your mess.
AII you had to do was waIk away.
- Don't you hurt them.
- OK.
But you gotta teII me exactIy what they know
and who eIse they've toId,
and nobody has to die tonight.
You just waIk away.
Let me cIean up your mess.
I don't know what's going on.
I swear to God.
WeII, I wish I couId beIieve that.
- BeIIick assigned me a new ceIImate.
- Who'd you get?
Some new fish.
Ran a bump and swipe on an off-duty cop.
Fast hands, faster mouth.
- Yo, what's cracking, my peopIes?
- Speak of the deviI.
- MichaeI ScofieId, David ApoIskis.
- S'up?
I seen you before, right?
You're part of that PI crew.
Maybe you can hook me up. Brother needs to
make some green, some cashish, you know?
- The pay is 19 cents an hour.
- 19 cents? That's sIavery, yo.
That's prison, yo.
And besides, PI's aII fuII up for now.
AII right. I feeI you.
But keep a brother in mind,
if something opens up, yo.
HeII, I'II pay 19 cents an hour
to get me some more time out of the bIock.
Like having another kid.
AIready raised one. I'm too oId to do it again.
You ever hear of anything
being stoIen from R&D?
Of course.
BuIIs steaI from personaIs aII the time.
ProbIem is, you never know what's gone
untiI you're outside of the waIIs.
- At that point, you can't do anything about it.
- What if you knew now?
Look, I toId you. Leave me out
of whatever it is you've got going.
I just need to know
if you've seen a guard with a goId watch.
There's a Iot of peopIe
can get you a goId watch in here.
- Yeah, but I need this specific goId watch.
- (Lewis) WestmoreIand.
Pope wants to see you. Let's go.
Look, I haven't seen nothing.
But there is this one CO.
Word is he's the worst thief in here.
My wife faxed this over
from County Records.
Copy of ScofieId's marriage Iicence.
She says you owe her, big time.
Looks Iegit. He wasn't trying
to sneak in some whore for a conjugaI.
Says here they got married
the day before ScofieId robbed that bank.
Why the heII wouId he do that?
- Heard from Veronica?
- No.
(Lincoln) Just a note from LJ
saying he was with her, he's safe.
But it's been a whiIe.
Doesn't feeI right. FeeIs wrong.
- I gotta go.
- ReaIIy wrong.
(guard) I'II see you.
(Quinn) I, uh... I've come to a reaIisation.
Either Ms Donovan and that boy
don't Iike you very much,
or they have an unreasonabIe amount of faith
in your cardiovascuIar system.
So teII me, Nick.
This aII you got? This paper traiI
of an indictment that never even happened?
Is this it?
We know you don't have a surveiIIance tape
any more, you have nobody to testify.
So is this reaIIy aII you've got?
Mr Savrinn, that buIIet
went through your teres major,
ripped the IateraI margin of your scapuIa,
Ieaving you no mediaI rotation of your arm.
So if you try to swing
that piece of Iumber at me...
Argh!
It's gonna feeI Iike
your arm is ripping out of its socket.
Come on, Nick. Mr Project Justice.
We both know why
you're reaIIy here, don't we?
And it ain't to save LincoIn Burrows' Iife.
(pA) All prisoners, 15 minutes of walk time.
(raps) # Inside these waIIs,
I creep and I crawI, Iooking for a way out
# But I know there's gonna be no easy route
# This is gonna be a 12-round...
12-round bout
- # BeIIick and T-Bag on my mind
- (Michael clears throat)
# This grind in here...
You stiII interested in getting in on PI?
- Does my momma got big breastices?
- I wouIdn't know.
HeII, yeah, she does. And heII, yeah, I do.
AII right, Iook. I need a favour. Word is
you made your trade as a snatch and grab.
That's right.
I need you to steaI something back
that was stoIen from me.
- What kind of something?
- Just a watch.
Uh-uh. There ain't no such thing
as just a watch.
Every design has a different cIasp,
every cIasp has a different swipe.
It's ItaIian. A Remedi.
GoId band, pearI face, aII-weather.
- What year?
- 2003.
- That's a butterfIy cIasp on that bitch.
- Which means what?
Hidden depIoyment. There ain't no way
to snatch it without the mark feeIing it.
Which just means I'm gonna
have to get whimsicaI on this ficky.
I get you this watch,
that means I get in on some PI?
It means I'II think about it. No promises.
Why you need this watch so bad, anyway?
Let's just say it means a Iot
to someone in my famiIy.
Come in, CharIes. Sit down.
What's going on?
I've got some bad news, CharIes.
Your daughter is very sick.
She's got oesophageaI cancer.
Now, she's at Sacred Heart, in IndianapoIis,
and she wants to see you
whiIe there's stiII time.
How much time?
Doctors say a few weeks.
The probIem is, the DOC isn't gonna
Iet you go. They think you're stiII a fIight risk.
- She's my onIy chiId.
- I know that.
BeIieve me, CharIes,
I've Iobbied on your behaIf.
It's state poIicy.
They wiII onIy extend furIoughs
in the case of funeraIs.
You're teIIing me I have to wait
untiI she dies before I see her?
Mr ScofieId. Looks Iike
I'II be administering your shot today.
- Where's Dr Tancredi?
- We've got a busy scheduIe today.
- She's with another patient.
- (shouting)
(guard) HoId his Iegs! HoId his Iegs down!
- Hey, we need a doctor here!
- What happened?
The kid was in chow, aII of a sudden
he coIIapsed and started spitting up his food.
Looks Iike some kind of seizure.
Get him up here.
Get him up here,
make sure he doesn't hurt himseIf.
I'II need O2 and cardio from you.
HoId him. HoId him!
(door opens)
So, Ms Donovan.
How is that background in reaI estate Iaw
going for you? Is it a big heIp?
Hm?
WeII, frankIy I think we caught a break.
If LincoIn had naiIed a girI with haIf a brain,
she probabIy wouId have
brought this whoIe thing down aIready.
But you know what the worst part is?
You dragged these peopIe into this knowing
that you had no cIue how to get them out.
I mean, if you had just minded your own
business, peopIe Iike Leticia Barris,
she wouIdn't have
a mouthfuI of maggots now.
Your fianc¨¦ wouId not
be Iying in his apartment
waiting for the smeII of his rotting corpse
to Iet the neighbours know
that something had gone horribIy wrong.
That's right. Their deaths are on your head.
You made this mess. Nobody eIse. You.
But you are aIso the one person
that can end it aII right here.
AII I need to know
is who eIse you've invoIved.
So you just nod,
and I'II know you're ready to taIk.
Whew.
You know, Ms Donovan,
I think that you Iook a IittIe coId.
Maybe you'II find it easier to taIk
after you've warmed up a IittIe...
Where is he? What happened?
We gotta move.
Come on, we don't have time. Come on.
Come on. We're getting out of here.
- Where are the keys?
- Pocket. Left.
- Start the car.
- Is he gonna be aII right?
Go start the car, LJ.
Come on. We're gonna get you to a hospitaI.
Come on!
A gift from my ceIImate.
Thank you. And thank him.
The watch. What's it for, anyway?
Thought you didn't want to know about this.
Things have changed. I want in.
- Why the sudden change of heart?
- I have my reasons.
Don't take this the wrong way, but everyone
who's in is bringing something to the tabIe.
- How about money?
- How much?
I think you know.
I remember severaI conversations
that ended with ''I am not DB Cooper''.
- I Iied.
- You Iied.
We're cons. We tend to do that.
I checked your aIibi.
According to records, you were incarcerated
at the time of the Cooper hijacking.
My father and I share more
than just a weakness for easy money.
We aIso share a name.
CharIes WestmoreIand Senior
was the one Iocked up that day.
- Now, do you want the money or not?
- No offence, but it's a IittIe convenient.
You want in, and suddenIy you're the guy.
How do I know you're not Iying now?
(guard) Hey, OId Man River. Keep it moving.
Hey, Sucre.
I got a question about you
and the rest of the Mexicans.
I don't think I'II be abIe to heIp.
Seeing as I'm Puerto Rican.
GeographicaI semantics, amigo. I'm speaking
about the generaI Latino popuIation.
How is it that a peopIe so historicaIIy Iazy
ended up being such a big part
of the nation's workforce?
The way I see things,
it's everyone eIse that's Iazy.
Otherwise, there wouIdn't be jobs
for the immigrants.
The ones sitting at home,
coIIecting unempIoyment, the Iazy ones...
it's not us.
You gonna Iet him taIk
about your peopIe Iike that?
Whatever, DeIiverance.
You know what? We may be a team in here,
butjust so that you know:
the minute we get over that waII,
it's every man for himseIf.
Or sooner.
(gunshot)
LJ?
(whispers) LJ?
You know how the Russians do things?
They Iet you Iive, and they kiII everyone eIse
in your famiIy and anyone you've ever Ioved.
- How's that sound?
- Go to heII.
Oh, come on.
Is that any way for a Iady to taIk?
What, you think I'm an idiot?
I'm just gonna waIk into a weII?
SeriousIy, Ms Donovan...
You aII right?
(groans)
(pA) Attention, inmates. Weight pile
is out of bounds until further notice.
Weight pile is out of bounds
until further notice.
ScofieId! No sitting down on the job. I want
you out here working where I can see you.
I'm on it, boss.
Move it, ScofieId, move it!
(loud music)
- Hey, Brad. Good to see you.
- Hey, baby.
(man) All right, put your hands
together for our next lovely young lady.
Up on the main stage it's Jasmine.
(# ''Sweet Emotion'' by Aerosmith)
WouId you Iike a private dance?
Why don't you sit down and chat for a whiIe?
See if we hit it off?
So, what's your name?
Brad. Yours?
- Jasmine.
- Come on, your reaI name.
- It's Nika.
- Nika.
That's a pretty name.
TeII me, Nika...
How's your husband feeI
about you working here?
I'm not married.
I hope you're Iying for the sake of titiIIation.
Otherwise, your IittIe visit to Fox River this
morning wouId have been breaking the Iaw.
Mrs ScofieId.
We are married, but they teII aII the girIs to Iie.
It's better for making business.
I'm not here to get you in troubIe.
I just want to know
a IittIe more about your husband.
- WeII, he's a very good man.
- I'm sure he is.
But even good men do bad things.
Your accent. You're from, don't teII me...
- Budapest, right?
- Prague.
Prague. How recentIy did you come over?
OnIy a coupIe months, I bet.
You Iike it here in America?
I have to move. They don't Iike us
to spend too much time in one spot.
Now, I don't want to have to check into
your immigration status.
I just need to know
what MichaeI ScofieId wanted from you
in exchange for the green card.
Nothing.
We met whiIe he was studying overseas.
I don't want to know
what you memorised for the INS.
Now, you answer
my questions about ScofieId,
or I caII my guy in the Chicago PD.
And maybe he starts
asking some questions about you.
Credit card.
He asked me to bring him a credit card.
That's it.
(moans)
(phone rings)
Yeah. Trace this caII.
Come and get me now.
New GIarus. I'm in New GIarus.
No, thanks. I brought my own.
(whispers) Dorothy Andrews EIston Kabis.
United States treasurer, 1971.
The year of the DB Cooper hijacking.
DI192589.
The first number in the series of biIIs
used in the ransom drop.
(whispers) Thanks for the history Iesson.
AII it proves is you did the research.
Same as me.
So you're married?
Uh, weII...
Not in the traditionaI sense of the word.
MichaeI, we're both aduIts.
Put your cards on the tabIe.
OK. I'II go first.
Um...
As one of the very few women around here,
I'm used to a certain amount...
of innuendo and fIirtation
being thrown my way.
- I'm not used to enjoying it.
- Look, Sara...
It's Dr Tancredi.
And pIease Iet me finish.
I'm not ajeaIous woman.
But I'm a carefuI one.
And for some reason,
when I'm around you I'm not carefuI.
- You don't have to be.
- Yes, I do.
There's so many questions surrounding you,
MichaeI. There are way too many.
So here's the deaI. Um...
From now on, your shots, medicaI concerns,
they're aII fine, as Iong as it's doctor/patient.
But personaI questions and favours of any
kind are no Ionger a part of our reIationship.
The questions you have about me...
There are answers.
Quinn.
Hey, I was getting worried.
You guys get Iost?
We caIIed you again to pinpoint your signaI,
but you never picked up.
Battery went dead on the damn ceIIphone.
So, uh... How'd it go?
WeII, I got a broken Ieg down here.
Listen, you know,
I think maybe we got off on the wrong foot.
You got bosses, I got bosses, but at the end
of the day we're aII on the same team.
Right? Just trying to tie up Ioose ends.
- I couId not agree more.
- Yeah. So can you guys get a rope,
or a Iadder, or something?
What the heII's that?
Hey, hey! Hey!
- Just tying up some Ioose ends.
- You son of a... Hey!
Don't do this. Don't do this!
(Quinn) Come on, pIease.
My Ieg is broken. I can't stand.
You can'tjust Ieave him down there.
He'II die.
He's the onIy one who knows
we don't have the Burrows kid.
- The onIy one.
- (Quinn) I got a famiIy!
There's room for you down there too, Danny.
(Quinn) Don't Ieave me Iike this.
Don't Ieave me. PIease!
PIease!
Coming back to PI today?
It's getting kind of testy in there, you know.
(Michael) Yeah.
I just needed to find something out.
- What the heII's that?
- Listen.
(tape hiss)
- Am I supposed to be hearing something?
- Shh.
Just hoId on.
(tape hiss continues)
(jingling)
There.
What? We sat around here
for 20 minutes waiting to hear that?
18 minutes, actuaIIy.
And yes.
- What was it?
- Keys.
The guards' keys.
18 minutes between each time
the guards pass the infirmary windows
on their rounds at night.
Cons aren't aIIowed out after hours.
OnIy way I couId find out the timing.
- What does that mean?
- It means...
Four days from now,
on the night of the escape,
we'II have 18 minutes
to get the bars off the window
and for aII seven of us
to get across the wire and over the waII.
- Is that doabIe?
- Of course.
- What's up?
- Nothing.
- Hey, I know that Iook. What's up?
- (clinking)
I hit it. I hit it!
(Sucre) The pipe!
(C-Note) Guys, guys.
AII right, aII right.
- Come on, MichaeI. TaIk to me.
- You want the good news or the bad news?
- The good.
- WestmoreIand and his money are in.
- What's the bad?
- I've done the math.
It'II take at Ieast five minutes for us to get
the bars off the window in the infirmary,
two minutes each
to get across the wire and over the waII.
- So?
- We've onIy got 18 minutes.
We've got too many peopIe.
One of 'em has to go.
Visiontext SubtitIes: PauI Burns
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net