MALE NARRATOR:
Previously on Prison Break:
I'm through.
See you on the other side.
It can't be done.
We're not getting out of here.
There's onIy one person
who can reaIIy stop this execution.
WouId you taIk to your father for me?
I'm the Iast person in the worId
that my father Iistens to.
The Governor has reviewed your case.
He's not granting cIemency.
Let's proceed.
I came in here a man.
Give me the strength
to waIk out of here a man.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Doctor, you can Ieave now.
It's him.
MichaeI.
What's he saying?
MichaeI, turn around.
It's him.
What do you think he's saying?
MichaeI, turn around.
(PHONE BEEPING)
-What's going on?
-I don't know.
What's happening?
What the heII's going on in there?
I can't teII you how sorry I am
that you've had to go through aII of this.
LincoIn.
What happened in there?
Judge KessIer caIIed.
The execution's been deIayed.
What do you mean deIayed?
ApparentIy, some new evidence
has come to Iight.
-What evidence?
-I don't understand.
How Iong do we have? One day, two days?
That's aII the information
I have at the moment. I'm sorry.
I'II give you a minute.
You okay?
I need to know how much time we have.
I'II go and see the judge and find out.
You're with MichaeI. You'II be okay.
-Did you see him?
-Who?
-The guy in the viewing room.
-No.
It was Dad.
It was him. I know it was.
That's not possibIe, Linc.
It is possibIe. I saw him.
I don't know how you couId have.
There were onIy haIf a dozen peopIe
in that room.
Me, Veronica and a bunch of reporters.
-He wasn't there.
-You don't know that.
I do. I wouId have recognized him.
You don't remember what he Iooks Iike.
I do.
This is a man who took off,
what, 30 years ago?
Why wouId he come back now,
at the very Iast minute?
(SIGHING)
I don't know.
REYNOLDS: Why is he stiII aIive?
It appears that some information
was anonymousIy sIipped to the judge.
AnonymousIy?
It was your fat IittIe friend, HaIe.
-If you had taken care of him sooner...
-It wasn't HaIe.
How do you know that?
If HaIe had given Veronica Donovan
anything that couId have
gotten a stay of execution,
I think she wouId have brought it up
when she made her argument in court.
It didn't come from him.
WeII, who eIse on your end knows?
Who eIse on your end knows?
Why aII the finger-pointing at us?
Are you sure that the Ieak didn't come
from your end? From the company?
Hey, we are aII
on the same team, remember?
AbsoIuteIy.
Just find the Ieak and pIug it.
Thank you, ma'am.
One more thing.
The next time you're in my office,
I expect you to stand
when you're addressing me.
AbsoIuteIy.
AII I can teII is
I was working Iate in chambers,
I Ieft at 1 1 :00,
and there it was, right under my door.
One is Terrence Steadman's
autopsy report.
In it, his appendix is noted
as present and unremarkabIe.
The other paper is an operative report
from when Mr. Steadman
was 12 years oId.
The procedure was an appendectomy.
That's impossibIe. Let me see this.
I want the conviction overturned
and LincoIn Burrows
immediateIy reIeased from custody.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, not so fast.
These records haven't even been certified.
The hospitaI can teII you.
The hospitaI does not keep records
going back that far. I checked.
So as far as we know,
these documents couId be a hoax
from some anti-death penaIty advocate
or, dare I say it, defense counseI.
Oh, pIease. You're preposterous.
Let's just aII
take a deep breath here, okay?
I don't know what these papers mean
and for that reason,
I'd Iike to err on the side of caution.
I'm going to deIay the execution
for two weeks.
That shouId give us more than enough
time to exhume the body.
Exhume the body.
Your Honor, aII due respect,
that is a drastic measure.
It's aIso the onIy way we're going to know
if that body in the ground
is reaIIy Terrence Steadman.
GUARD: (ON P.A. SYSTEM)
Recreation hour will be over in 10,,,
SCOFIELD: So that's not
Steadman that was buried?
VERONICA: We don"t know,
lf it isn"t, Lincoln"s free,
lf it is, we"re right back where we started,
Take care of yourself, Michael,
So, that body, what if it's him?
WeII, I'm not going to sit around hoping.
What does that mean?
It means we get back to work.
God, I was hoping you wouId say that.
They're digging up the body, huh?
To be honest, I've never been
in a situation Iike this before.
If nothing eIse, you can be gIad
that you've got peopIe who'II go
to extreme Iengths to get you out of here.
No kidding.
Warden,
at the execution,
there was a man in the viewing room.
Just wondering if you or anyone
in the prison had spoken to him.
WeII, according to this,
those present were your brother,
his attorney and three reporters,
two women and a man.
The man, who was he?
He was from The Headline Press,
WiIIiam PraII.
You know him?
No.
Guard.
HoId it steady, pIease.
What exactIy are you Iooking for
in aII that ink?
A new way out of here.
-You don't know those pIans by now?
-No.
Memorizing it wouId be Iike
memorizing the phone book.
Yeah, but why not just tat up Route 66?
Contingencies.
Contingencies?
-You saying you found another way?
-Maybe.
What do you mean, maybe?
There's aIways been another way,
but it's suicide.
(MEN CHATTERING)
Man, I'm so coId my hands are stinging.
You know what they say
about weather in the Midwest,
if you don't Iike it, wait an hour.
We're stiII going out through the infirmary
and we're stiII going to do it
from the guards' room.
It's just the in-between
that's gonna have to change.
Now wait a minute.
Why are you changing the pIan, man?
We're aIready through that room
beneath the infirmary.
That's aII we gotta do is get through
that pipe and we're home free.
There's a reason they repIaced it
with a 12-inch pipe, Darwin.
PeopIe can't get through it.
The onIy way we're getting
into that infirmary is from beneath.
We're going to have to find another way.
The psych ward?
It's the onIy buiIding that shares
a subsurface Iine with the infirmary.
You teIIing me,
to get to the infirmary
we gotta go through the whack shack?
UnIess you got a better idea.
And there's a subsurface Iine
that runs from the guards' room
to the psych ward?
Sort of.
Oh, whoa, whoa.
What do you mean ''sort of''?
We can go into that hoIe
in the guards' room.
About 40 yards up Route 66, there's
a grate and that'II get us haIfway there.
-And what about the rest of the way?
-We gotta do it above ground.
Oh, so it's just a bunch of cons
taking a stroII in the middIe of the night
for aII the guards to see?
Yep.
You're right. It is suicide.
This grate that you're taIking about,
it's hidden, right, partner?
-The COs can't see it.
-Not exactIy.
-WeII, where is it?
-You're standing on it.
Oh, heII no.
When we come up out of
that ground there, that tower there,
that tower there,
that tower behind me is gonna see us.
We'II be Iike ducks in a shooting range.
You feeI me?
Hurry it up, cons.
Your pIan sucks, snowfIake.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
I gotta go back into the waIIs tonight.
Why?
I gotta get over to psych ward,
famiIiarize myseIf with the pipes beneath,
make sure we can get through.
I don't know, MichaeI.
C-Note's got a point.
We come up in the middIe of that yard,
we're sitting ducks.
I know.
(SIGHING)
I might have an idea.
My famiIy and I are more than dismayed
by Judge KessIer's decision
to aIIow the exhumation of my brother.
This stunt
by Lincoln Burrows" defense counsel
is an affront and an insult
to the memory of my brother,
a good man who tried
to make positive change in this country,
This is being done in the name
of trying to reIease
a convicted kiIIer from prison.
Steadman asked for a green buriaI.
No embaIming, biodegradabIe coffin.
It's very environmentaIIy aware.
Or smart, if you don't want the body
to be identified.
We haven't hung in months
and now you want a favor?
You know I Iove you, cuz,
but that's a big ask.
-I gotta say no.
-You can't say no.
Whatever.
If my mom, or worse, your mom knows
I did anything in here
to get you in troubIe, forget it.
I'm in prison, pendejo,
-How much troubIe can I get into?
-A Iot.
You owe me.
Like heII I do. It's your turn, not mine.
Miss Mangini's broken window.
The Terrado sisters?
Your brother's ''Iost'' EI Camino.
The church coIIection basket.
The donkey.
Yo.
We took an oath, bro.
Don't make me break it.
BURROWS: Come on, Linc,
we want to catch batting practice,
Let's hurry. Take my hand.
-Great seats, huh?
-Yeah.
See Number 1 1 over there?
Keep your eye on him. Watch him cIoseIy.
You got it?
Where is it?
Oh, he's cooI.
You get caught with this, they'II kiII you.
Hey, and I need this back by morning.
They'II know if something Iike that
is missing.
And, cuz, now you owe me.
(SIGHING)
Hey, you dropped something.
-Does that say ''Iraq''?
-Thanks.
(MEN CHATTERING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Let's Iook busy.
What the heII?
Oh, shoot.
Damn, bro, what did you do?
It's the cement we dug up.
My God, you cons are sIower
than a speIIing bee fuII of stutterers.
You aII think you can sIow-waIk this job?
PIay grab-ass in here?
Drag it out for months?
Get to work.
You got it, boss.
How about it, eight baII?
Get to work.
Oh, you know, boss, my Ieg feII asIeep.
You disobeying me, convict?
The man said get to work.
What the heII is your probIem, oId head?
My probIem is young con punks who
don't know how things work around here.
Construction's a sweet gig.
You wanna cIean toiIets, be my guest.
Otherwise, grab a hammer.
AII right.
StiII got some piss and vinegar
in those oId veins, huh, CharIes?
I Iike it.
CIose one, huh?
Oh, man.
What are we gonna do with this?
It was OIe Miss, right? OIe Miss?
-Nah, it was a Midwestern schooI.
-Iowa.
No, not Iowa. HoId on a sec.
Hey, BagweII.
Hey, do you know what schooI
Art SchIichter pIayed for?
Not reaIIy sure there, boss.
I reaIIy ain't much of a footbaII guy, boss.
Too much vioIence.
Come on, you know the guy
I'm taIking about.
Art SchIichter, the quarterback,
got naiIed for gambIing.
No, doesn't reaIIy ring a beII.
Bet if I asked you what his ass Iooked Iike,
you'd remember.
Hey, maybe someone
in the brain trust knows.
StoIte, come on, man,
Iet's grab some Iunch.
HoId on, I just want to figure this out.
It's driving me crazy.
Ohio State!
That's right. He was a Buckeye.
(DOOR BANGING SHUT)
You're not compIeteIy worthIess, after aII.
How's your stomach?
Any more vomiting?
Just nauseous. Must be the nerves.
That's understandabIe, considering.
-I can give you something for it.
-No, that's fine.
AII right.
You Iet me know
if there's anything you need.
-Can I ask you a question, Doc?
-Yeah. What?
With aII that went down yesterday,
head pounding, heart racing,
couId that cause me
to see something that wasn't there?
Yeah. Yeah, anxiety attacks are often
accompanied by
fIashes of Iight, bIack spots...
No, no, no.
I saw someone in the viewing room.
-There were peopIe there.
-This person couIdn't have been there.
Yeah, LincoIn, you've heard of,
post-traumatic stress disorder, right?
Yeah.
I'm gonna caII you a prime candidate.
I don't think a Iot of peopIe
have been through what you just did.
So if you thought you saw someone,
it's possibIe that it was your subconscious
giving you what you wanted,
whoever it was that
you wanted to be there with you
in that moment to comfort you.
Who was it you thought you saw?
Thanks, Doc. Thank you.
Sure thing.
Seen a Iot of rackets in my time,
but if you're doing what I think
you're doing with those postcards,
yours definiteIy takes the cake.
Yeah, how about
saving the smaII taIk, oId head,
'cause you and I
ain't got nothing in common.
What do you do?
Write them here
and then send them to a paI in Iraq
and have him maiI them your wife's way?
You know, why don't you
just shut your word hoIe?
'Cause you don't know nothing
about my racket.
A con pretending
he ain't in the hoIe to his famiIy.
I seen that once or twice.
But Iraq?
Yeah, you the one to taIk.
Dede, is that your wife or your kid?
Now you Iisten,
I don't even want you
to say her name in this prison.
You feeI me?
A daughter.
DefiniteIy a daughter.
-Yeah, what do you know?
-'Cause I got one myseIf.
You know,
after you break outside these waIIs,
that's the first pIace
they're gonna Iook for you.
FamiIy.
Now why is it you think
that I'm that dumb
that I wouId go directIy there?
'Cause that's exactIy the first pIace
I'm gonna go.
Turns out maybe we got
something in common after aII.
See Number 1 1 over there?
Keep your eye on him. Watch him cIoseIy.
Mid-IeveI reIiever at best.
But he's aIways working at it.
That's why he's your oId man's
favorite pIayer. Work ethic.
WiIIiam PraII.
You know him?
The pipe system
beneath the psych ward is...
WeII, it's compIex.
Be reaI easy to get Iost.
-How compIex can it be?
-Very.
When they buiIt this pIace in 1858,
the pipes were Iead.
A century Iater,
they discovered Iead was a heaIth risk
so they went to copper.
They never removed the Iead pipes.
Cost too much.
There's thousands of yards
of the stuff stiII down there.
And then a few years ago,
they switched to industriaI pIastic.
Again, it was cheaper
just to Iay it over the oId stuff.
If I make a wrong turn down there tonight,
I won't make it back by count.
WeII, you won't make
the wrong turn, right?
(PANTING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
(BUZZER BUZZING)
I don't beIieve my eyes.
One of the bIues
actuaIIy coming into psych ward.
I gotta hit the head
and I didn't want to waIk
aII the way back to A-wing.
-Mind if I use your faciIities?
-Yeah, be my guest.
I don't know why you guys
are so scared of the whack shack.
I mean, between the kiIIers
and the crazies, I'II take the crazies.
Because if a crazy steps out of Iine,
aII I gotta do is shoot him with 40 cc's
of ''shut your trap'' and it's beddy-bye.
So, which way is the bathroom?
Down the haII,
through the door, make a right.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
(CREAKING)
(DOOR BUZZING)
Hey, bIue. What you doing down here?
Hey.
I was just Iooking for the bathroom.
Down here?
Yeah. You said down the haII,
through the door and to the Ieft.
No, I said through the door
and make a right.
My bad.
Have a good night.
BIue! HoId up!
Don't you stiII gotta take a Ieak?
Yeah. Which way was that again?
With decomposition this extensive,
the most accurate identification tooI
is dentaI records.
We made an imprint
of the deceased's teeth
and compared them to the
dentaI records of Terrence Steadman.
-And?
-They were a perfect match.
Thank you, Doctor.
That can't be Terrence Steadman.
If you Iike, you can bring in
a forensic examiner of your own choosing
to examine the body.
But I can teII you now,
they'II come to the same concIusion
that I have.
Thank you.
I hope you're proud of this.
You've gotten your pound of fIesh.
Are you done now?
Or wouId you Iike
to hurt my famiIy some more?
Come on. Come on.
(SIGHING)
(GRUNTS )
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
GUARD: (ON RADIO) Hey, Mack, you there?
Yeah.
What"s your 20?
I gotta stop by maintenance reaI quick.
I'II be up in a minute.
(SIZZLING)
(COUGHING)
(CLANGING)
You okay?
-I'm burned.
-Oh, God.
AII right, heIp me take this off.
-No, it's Iike, burned to your skin.
-Take it off.
Are you kidding me? I can't.
It's meIted into your skin.
If the guards catch me wearing this,
I'm a dead man.
-Bro, it's just not...
-Do it.
PIease do it.
Ready?
One, two...
(SCOFIELD SCREAMING)
-MichaeI, it's Sara. How are you feeIing?
-Groggy.
It's the anesthesia.
Why did I have anesthesia?
We had to perform a procedure.
So, you got so sick
of ScofieId's smart mouth
that you decided
to deep fry him, is that it?
-I didn't do anything to him, I swear.
-Let's review.
A Iocked ceII.
Two inmates.
One gets branded
Iike a South Dakota steer.
You think we shouId
caII MatIock in on this one?
Who's MatIock?
Fernando, you're onIy going
to make things more difficuIt
if you don't cooperate.
I toId you I didn't burn him.
-I found him Iike that.
-You found him Iike that.
He was acting kind of weird
when we Iined up for finaI count.
He was sweating, you know?
But he's not a big taIker anyway,
so I didn't think much of it.
MiddIe of the night, I get up, you know,
to shake hands with the president,
and there he is, face down on the fIoor.
My ass.
Ask him yourseIf
when the doc's done with him.
I didn't touch him.
(SCOFIELD GROANING)
PainkiIIers?
How bad is it?
I'd take the piIIs.
Do I get to see it?
No, bandage stays on for now.
Take your piIIs.
Your ceIImate do this to you?
Sucre?
No.
Who did?
This is the part where I don't answer you.
AII right.
I'II have you sent back to your ceII.
AII yours.
Hey, Katie, it's me.
Listen, can you come up to my office
for a second?
I got something I wanna show you.
What the heII am I gonna do now?
I'm a dead man.
I'm sorry, cuz. It was an accident.
BuII's gonna see this and fIip his Iid.
Hey, sIim ! You got my uni ready?
There's been a bit of a probIem, boss.
-What the heII is this?
-I Ieft the iron on it too Iong.
You are as stupid as you are fat,
do you know that, D-cups?
My new shirt's coming out of your kick.
-You're gonna teII me right now.
-TeII you what?
What the heII you got going on
that's got you burning up guard suits?
Trust me, primo,
The Iess you know, the better.
(DOOR BUZZING)
Any news?
No. No, not yet.
Testing takes a coupIe of days.
What do you remember of Dad?
Your dad? I didn't know him.
Your mom said some pretty horribIe stuff
about him when we were growing up.
I think I saw him when I was in the chair.
LincoIn.
It was him. I know it was.
How wouId you know?
You haven't seen his face in 30 years.
-The name that was used, WiIIie PraII.
-So?
It's the name of this guy
who threw for Chicago back in the day.
Dad and me were reaIIy into him
but I'd forgotten aII about him.
It's reaIIy weird.
Been having these dreams, memories,
things I guess I suppressed when he Ieft.
But...
This man who came to the execution,
how do you know he used that name?
Pope toId me.
Was that before
or after you had the dream?
Look, I'm sorry, okay?
I don't mean to chaIIenge
what you're saying,
but your dad's been MIA
aImost your entire Iife.
I know what I saw, V.
I know what I saw.
(SIGHING)
This is the security camera footage
of the courthouse
from the night that Judge KessIer
got those documents.
Now, check out this guy.
He is very skiIIed.
He moves casuaIIy enough
to avoid suspicion.
You see how he shifts his hat
when he turns corners to hide his face?
He knows exactIy
where those cameras are.
Wait. Right there.
See that refIection? Rewind it. Rewind it.
Right. Can you bIow that up?
-Son of a bitch.
-What?
I know that guy.
What is it?
It was fused into MichaeI ScofieId's skin.
I removed it
during the d¨¦bridement procedure.
And what about it?
WeII, this fabric doesn't come
from a standard issue prison uniform.
-Where'd it come from then?
-As far as I can teII, a guard's uniform.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
Open on 40!
GUARD: 40 open!
CIose 40!
40 cIosed!
How you feeIing?
What's wrong?
The bIueprints,
the ones we need to get
from the psych ward to the infirmary,
our map out of here,
they're gone.
www.tvsubtitles.net