(man) previously on ''prison Break'':
It's the onIy buiIding on top of those tunneIs.
AII we gotta do is get in there, on PI,
and dig ourseIves an on-ramp.
I'm gonna find out, you know,
what it is you're doing up there.
If we taIked about who had motive
to kiII Terrence, we'd be here aII day.
- To do with EcoFieId?
- Do the math. CEO gets indicted for fraud.
Investors start Iosing money. Lots of money.
- CaII Nick Savrinn. Works for Project Justice.
- They're here.
(Linc) Who's here? LJ? LJ!
- You gotta come get me.
- We can't, we're not in Chicago. Come to us.
- First of the month's coming up, John.
- Yeah. So?
I checked my baIance.
It's Iooking deficient.
ApparentIy Fibonacci's
coming up for air again.
If he testifies at that hearing
a Iot of peopIe are going down,
incIuding me.
Listen. There, uh...
there's been a restructuring.
This comes from philly himself.
So l'm the man in here now.
What the heII are you doin'? Aargh!
(Michael) Uh-oh. We got a problem.
BeIIick? What's going on?
That's PI. I run it.
Not any more, you don't.
BeIIick.
- Hey, boss.
- Check that voIume, inmate.
We've been doing business too Iong.
We can fix this thing, right?
Let's get something cIear. You and I haven't
done crap. FaIzone's the one payin' me.
He's just an enveIope. You've been
doing business with me face to face.
You think I Iike getting piss thrown at me?
Spit on?
Other chumps might do it for 40 grand a year
and the IittIe uniform, but I'm not that dumb.
FaIzone's enveIope is the onIy reason
I come through that fence every day.
And it's the onIy reason
I'm gonna keep coming through that fence
untiI I have enough money
to buy a house on Lake Gray.
I'm thinking earIy retirement, John.
And you're interfering with that.
Hey, boss. Just give me some time and I can
match whatever FaIzone's paying you.
You're out of business. Get used to it.
Hey, boss. Boss!
They're gonna find it. The Ionger they're
in there, the sooner they're gonna find it.
Then we gotta get back in there.
- I'm gonna say something crazy to you now.
- Surprise, surprise.
- I don't give a damn about that Fibonacci.
- You're right. That is crazy.
Because I got bigger things to think about,
Iike survivaI.
You see, I'm kinda short on friends in here,
in case you haven't noticed.
I need to get out, right now.
WhiIe I've stiII got my Iife.
Then why are we taIking about Fibonacci?
The onIy way I can get that room back
is if I can prove to FaIzone I'm stiII worthy,
that I've stiII got what it takes. Yeah?
And the onIy way I can do that
is if I can give him Fibonacci.
Interesting.
You see, this is not
a me-versus-you thing any more. This is us.
An us thing, aII right? It's us for the escape.
Is it? Or is this about you getting back
in good with the Mob again?
That Iife is over for me, fish.
I mean, they cIipped my wings.
They want me to rot in here,
so I got no aIIegiance to them any more.
And yet you stiII want to do them a favour.
FaIzone is desperate.
See, if Fibonacci testifies
in front of the Congress next month,
FaIzone's gonna go down in fIames.
But if we give him Fibonacci,
he wiII give us anything.
Anything. IncIuding that very speciaI room.
What do you say, fish?
''And the Lord said unto Satan,
'Hast thou considered my servant Job?'''
'''That there is none Iike him in the earth.
A perfect and an upright man.'''
'''One that fears God and shuns eviI.'''
- Give him up.
- They'II kiII him.
- Maybe he deserves it.
- That's just it. He doesn't.
Who is this guy? You toId me he was Mafia.
He was working for the Mafia.
He just didn't know it.
Otto Fibonacci is... He's just Iike you.
An innocent man,
caught in the wrong pIace at the wrong time.
(man) What are you doing?
You know I didn't steaI from you, John.
(Michael) He was management
at one of Abruzzi's warehouses.
Just a normal guy-
working class, religious.
Hey, Nicky. Nicky, Nicky, Nicky. Sh.
What did I teII you about taIking?
(Mickey) John, pIease.
Johnny, pIease! No!
(Michael) Somebody that couldn't
turn his back on murder.
He realised that Abruzzi and Falzone,
the men he worked for, were killers.
He had the key to their dealings
that could put them away for life.
And now he's in witness protection for life.
The judge asked why he was coming forward
with this information.
He said it was because
he thought it was the right thing to do.
What's the right thing to do now, MichaeI?
I don't know.
But if I don't give him up,
this whoIe thing's over.
What you're teIIing me is if... if I'm to Iive...
A good man has to die.
(phone rings)
- KeIIerman.
- (woman) You're where we discussed?
Yes. I'm stiII not exactIy sure
why we're here, but...
- A friend of mine shouId be aIong shortIy.
- A friend?
Just to see where you are with things.
We're cIear on where we are.
Everything's under controI.
Nothing wiII affect tomorrow,
if you're worried.
l'm not worried about tomorrow.
My friend is a problem solver, that's all.
He's there at your disposaI if you need him.
Do me a favour,
make him feeI Iike part of the team, hm?
TaIk soon.
- What?
- She's bringing someone in.
- What does that mean?
- Something in her tone changed.
You think she knows about the kid?
We don't know that.
We shouIdn't have toId her we had the kid.
What is it you don't understand? We teII her
that kid got away, we are not here now.
- I swear to God, it gets deeper and deeper.
- What is that supposed to mean?
It means, if I'd have known
how this was gonna turn out,
I'd have got some crap job with the feds.
Pushed penciIs.
Drank coffee aII day Iong behind a desk.
God, that sounds good.
Keep taIking Iike that, I'm gonna be forced
to put a buIIet in your head.
As for her friend, whoever that is,
we find out what he wants,
we pIay nice, we deaI with it accordingIy.
MichaeI, you better see this.
(whistles) Jersey! Are you putting
that carpet in the guards' room?
Yeah, I think so.
- When?
- We gotta tear up the oId stuff first.
As soon as we're done with that.
Tonight, tomorrow maybe.
They're gonna find it, bro.
They're gonna find the hoIe.
We gotta do something.
Linc. Chow.
- What's this?
- It's for, you know...
your Iast meaI.
Write down what you want.
Linc, you gotta write something down.
I ain't gotta do nothin'.
If you don't fiII it out, aII they're gonna
give you is what's on chow for that day.
- So?
- You don't want that for your Iast meaI, man.
Hm?
In case you think of something.
Hey, Eyetie.
Something you need there, rug head?
Yeah, ajob, man.
Why don't you hit the DQ down the street?
We're not hiring.
I'II put a hundred in your kick every month.
You wanna pay me to work?
I've been in the kitchen for eight months.
I scrub one more tray, I'm gonna go j cat.
Hey! FioreIIo, how about it?
Yeah, yeah.
150.
Sign me up, then, baby.
I was thinking about what you said -
that it's not a me-versus-you thing,
it's an us thing.
- That's right.
- How far are you wiIIing to go with that?
- As far as I have to.
- Then set up a meeting with FaIzone.
I wanna taIk to him directIy.
FaIzone doesn't taIk to guys Iike you directIy.
If he wants Fibonacci, he's gonna have to.
No, no. No, you heard me right.
(Falzone) This kid is gonna give up
Fibonacci? Sure?
I'm definite. OnIy one thing,
he wants to meet with you directIy.
(Falzone) Son of a bitch.
You actually did something right. That's good.
Guess l'll have to call off those guys
l hired to shank you.
- That was a joke, John.
- Funny.
Good. l'll come out there this afternoon.
And, John, if l come all the way out there
and this turns out to be a waste of my time,
l'm gonna castrate you.
l hope you understand that.
- Be well, my friend.
- I Iove you too.
He's coming.
Don't mess this up.
(phone rings)
- HeIIo?
- It's me.
I know. I saw ''Inmate'' on the caIIer ID.
Remember when I said
I might be caIIing you on Fibonacci?
- Yes.
- Well... it's time.
- You seem distracted.
- Got a Iot on my mind, I guess.
Yeah?
Have anything to do with
the peopIe who took these toes?
- Nice fIowers.
- Right.
- Do we have an admirer?
- They're from my father.
Ah.
- What's the occasion?
- It's my birthday.
- Today?
- Mm-hm.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
OK.
Huh.
Nothing. Birthday's aren't usuaIIy
a sore subject, that's aII.
UnIess the ceIebrant is feeIing her age,
which I don't see how you couId be.
I'm 29 years oId, MichaeI.
I'm not feeIing my age.
It's just, out of those 29 birthdays,
my father has managed to see me
on preciseIy six of them.
So, I get fIowers instead.
FIowers that end up dead
and in the trash a week Iater.
- That sounded bitter, huh?
- Kind of.
It's not a big deaI.
You are aII set. I wiII see you tomorrow.
OK.
I'm sorry you feeI that way.
About the fIowers, I mean.
- Hey, I want these in the other room.
- I got it, boss.
Hey, chiII, IiIy white. I got it.
Come on,
I know you're around here somewhere.
(floor creaks)
- (Nick) He's not doing weII, is he?
- (Veronica) He just Iost his mother.
Ten days from now, he Ioses his father.
(Nick) How are you hoIding up?
You know, I...
I sort of get
what you're going through here, LJ.
No disrespect, but I don't know that you do.
No, with my dad,
I was in the same spot when I was your age.
He was in prison,
and Iike your dad, he was innocent.
What happened?
I mean, you know, at the end.
What I hope happens here -
he got exonerated.
- What did they say he did?
- A Iot of bad things.
They weren't true, and we proved that.
Every day. Every day was a Iost cause,
but we kept fighting.
I mean, what eIse are you gonna do when you
Iove somebody? Let them go out Iike that?
So you fight. You keep fighting.
You never give up.
We're gonna beat this thing.
OK?
- HeIIo.
You were expecting me?
A mutuaI friend arranged it.
- Yes.
- You mind if I...?
PIease.
Hey, how are...
(whistles)
- (Kellerman) I'm sorry, I didn't get your name.
- Quinn.
Mr Quinn,
mind teIIing us what we're doing here?
You can probabIy teII just by Iooking at me,
I'm not a wave-making sort.
Just think of me as a supervisor
who's here to make sure things are under
controI as we approach... the big event.
I wasn't aware that things were out of controI.
WeII, you'd be the one that wouId know,
wouIdn't you?
WeII, the reason I'm here is because
there's a discrepancy between what you know
and what you have said to the vice president.
The Iawyers you tried to bIow up
are stiII heaIthy as thoroughbreds.
You know it, I know it.
Same thing goes with the kid,
who you were siIIy enough to teII the oId Iady
that you were actuaIIy in possession of.
Everything that I'm saying
is boiIing down to this.
You gotta hand the reins over to me now,
so that I can save your ass.
First of aII...
No! No.
See, now you made me make a wave.
You and your partner are off the job
untiI further notice.
It doesn't come from me
or from the White House -
it comes from the company. You understand?
Your proximaI and middIe phaIanx are
broken. Ice it for 45 minutes then spIint it.
That's what a doctor wouId teII you to do,
so you don't need to go see one.
EcoFieId's SEC fiIings.
Steadman was murdered so information
from his indictment wouIdn't be pubIic.
Sure, but we have no way of knowing
what they were trying to cover up.
Steadman's wife said there were
hundreds of miIIions of doIIars at stake.
So I figure we foIIow the money
and see where it takes us.
109 miIIion, 212 miIIion.
Over haIf a biIIion doIIars I've found so far
in federaI grants to EcoFieId
for aIternative fueI research.
- That is a heII of a Iot.
- But for what?
Not onIy did the company
never make a profit,
as far as I can teII, they never made anything.
No fueI saIes, no patents,
no findings, nothing.
So EcoFieId was a sham. It was a cover.
The question is, for what?
(buzzer)
PhiIIy.
Sit down, kid.
So...
Fibonacci - how'd you find him?
I did my homework.
You get eIIipticaI with me
for one more second and I wiII canceI you.
- You understand me?
- Give it up, fish.
Before someone's transferred to the marshaIs
and pIaced in protection,
they're guarded by a IocaI sheriff
from the county where the triaI wiII take pIace.
(phone rings)
- Sheriff SoIomon, pIease.
- (woman) please hold.
Andrew Solomon here.
(Michael) lf the sheriff was available,
he wasn't the one guarding Fibonacci.
- (woman) putnam County Sheriff's Office.
- Yeah, is Sheriff Pronzo there?
l'm sorry. Sheriff pronzo's on vacation.
- ReaIIy?
- Yes, sir.
There are onIy four sheriffs in the county.
Since Pronzo was the onIy one not in his
office, and his wife and kids were at home,
I knew the onIy vacation
he was taking was with Fibonacci.
Watching him
tiII they couId put him in protection.
Thing is, sometimes it takes weeks
for the marshaIs to set up a new identity,
so some IocaI sheriff is stuck
in the middIe of nowhere with Fibonacci.
He gets IoneIy and caIIs home - a Iot.
l called the phone company,
said l was pronzo and l'd lost my bill.
l asked for another copy.
Mrs pronzo was receiving dozens of calls
from an area code a long way from Chicago.
I went onIine,
reverse-traced the number, and voiI¨¤:
there was Fibonacci's exact Iocation.
- How do you know he's stiII there?
- I have someone Iooking after him.
- Watching from afar, in case he moves.
- Mm-hm.
- This is about money, isn't it?
- You're an astute man.
- What?
- Your friend here is trying to extort me.
Not extortion, insurance.
I pIan on being out of here one day.
I don't think my new r¨¦sum¨¦
is gonna cut it in most pIaces.
- How much?
- 200,000.
- I'm gonna kiII you.
- Quid pro quo.
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
WeII, I'II give you some quid pro quo.
(Michael) Where did you get this?
Who took this?
Since you took it upon yourseIf to have
peopIe watch our interests on the outside,
we took it upon ourseIves
to have some peopIe watching yours.
So who's it gonna be?
Fibonacci or your pretty IittIe girIfriend there?
Yeah, you shouId be carefuI with who
visits you in here, fish. These waIIs have eyes.
If you touch her,
I'II kiII you myseIf.
One, that is an empty threat.
You are Iess than a gnat to me.
And two,
aII you gotta do is give me the address
and we avoid aII this meIodrama aItogether.
The address, you gnat.
Now.
Promise me...
promise me it'II be quick and painIess.
- Do you beIieve this guy?
- Promise me.
If the next thing that comes out
of your mouth is not that address,
there's gonna be a Iot of pain...
in a Iot of pIaces.
Canada.
345 HamiIton Avenue,
Thunder Bay, Ontario.
Get outta here.
Nice work, John.
I guess the demise of John Abruzzi
was greatIy exaggerated.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
CouId you do me a favour
and fix this BeIIick thing for me?
Yeah, consider it done.
Thank you. And PhiIIy.
Before you puII the trigger,
Iook that son of a bitch in his eyes
and teII him John Abruzzi said goodbye.
OK.
''In the race toward worIdwide peace
and prosperity, America wiII set the pace.''
''Race''? Rat race, arms race...
Can you think of a word
with a worse connotation?
Fix it.
(Kellerman) Did you send me a baby-sitter?
- This is not the time or the pIace.
- This is the time and the pIace.
Don't take that tone.
Remember who you are taIking to.
I am vice president of this country.
No, actuaIIy you're CaroIine ReynoIds
from Montgomery, IIIinois.
I know exactIy who you are.
Come with me.
Just...
There is something you need to understand.
If you had done yourjob,
I never wouId've had to ask for Quinn.
And there's something
you need to understand.
You woke a sIeeping beast
when you caIIed these guys in.
They have a bigger agenda than us and get
nasty quick if things don't go their way.
So now no one is safe -
not you, not me.
Let's not overreact. I mean, I know everyone
is nervous about tomorrow. I understand that.
But the one thing both of us have to
remember is that we are in this together, OK?
AII I'm saying is these guys are into this thing
now, and there's no going back.
That's bad news for everyone.
Sebastian BaIfour?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I'm Nestor PoIIack.
Midwestern Life and CasuaIty.
I'm aIready covered. Thanks.
- No, I'm here to discuss Veronica Donovan.
- What about her?
We've been trying to track her down with
respect to the damage from the expIosion.
- ExpIosion?
- You didn't know. Oh, I'm sorry.
It's just that her records,
they Iist you as her fianc¨¦, so I assumed...
- HoId on. Is Veronica OK?
- WeII, there has been a fataIity.
But the medicaI examiners haven't been abIe
to identify the remains with any certainty,
so Veronica couId be OK, we just can't
find her. We were hoping you couId heIp.
Rozz.
Reese.
Burrows.
BIueberry pancakes, huh?
AII right, man. You got it.
BIueberry pancakes.
(beeping)
(Falzone) 341...
345.
This is it.
AII right, that's it, kids.
Time for bed. Give me a kiss.
Are you OK down there?
Night-night.
AII right, sweetheart. Give me a kiss.
- The kids are down.
- Thanks.
Tonight we send a message, gentIemen.
We are gonna hurt him and his famiIy
the way he hurt ours.
- Oh, honey.
- Yeah?
- Can you change the timer on the sprinkIer?
- OK.
- Love you.
- Love you too.
(siren)
(man) Freeze!
PoIice! Drop your weapons!
Drop it!
Down!
Hi, it's John. You wanted to taIk to me?
(Maggio) Yeah. You hear the news?
Falzone got popped last night, up in Canada.
lnternational gun charges, parole violation...
He's in deep.
- You threw away your fIowers.
- Like I said, they don't Iast.
I don't think they're dead yet.
I don't Iike getting attached to things
if I know they won't Iast.
- There you go.
- Why are you so cynicaI?
- I think there's cynicism and there's reaIism.
- And there's optimism. Hope, faith.
Coming from an eight-toed guy
Iocked in a penitentiary?
Toes are overrated.
Thank you for trying to make me smiIe.
Not today.
- You never know.
- We're aII set.
You and I have a Iot to taIk about,
don't we, fish?
Seems PhiIIy FaIzone
ran into some probIem up in Canada
just because of the information you gave him.
- What kind of troubIe?
- InternationaI gun charges, paroIe vioIation.
He's gonna go away for a Iong time.
How do you feeI about that?
Pretty darn good.
- And what about PI?
- We got that back too.
FaIzone paid BeIIick yesterday,
so we're good. For now.
- It aII worked out.
- Sure did.
NiceIy done. You're a heII of an actor.
Thank you.
This heIped. It's nice.
Nice shot.
Where did you take it?
It's LincoIn's from back in the day.
A camping trip or something.
- So when do we get back in that room?
- Right away.
- WeII, Iet's get to it.
- Yeah.
Oh, there's one more thing.
You are gonna give me Fibonacci
once we're outside these waIIs, right?
Of course.
Thank you.
And I think I'II keep this,
as insurance.
- (Linc) Juice?
- Why can't we have breakfast every day?
You shouId have breakfast every day, LJ.
It's an important meaI.
No, why can't I have breakfast with
you every day?
Nothing wouId make me happier.
But your mommy and me,
we don't Iive together any more.
Why?
WeII, uh...
sometimes that happens
with mommies and daddies.
But you know what?
You're the Iuckiest boy in the worId,
because your mommy Ioves you very much
and I Iove you very much.
I teII you what, how about every Sunday
we have our own speciaI breakfast?
- Just you and me. Yeah?
- Yeah.
- LittIe bit or a handfuI?
- HandfuI.
HandfuI.
Here we go.
Take a waIk.
Anyone eIse want to waIk with him?
Yeah.
- This is my game.
- Looks Iike our friend got his throne back.
Looks Iike it.
Something teIIs me
we may have you to thank for that.
- You don't want to know.
- Right.
Stretch your Iegs, oId head.
Now, we got a heII of a Iot
to taIk about, don't we?
I got nothing to say.
You think you can pIay me, snowfIake?
Cos you got coIIege?
Big-schooI Iearning, huh?
WeII, Iet me schooI you.
Darwin wins inside these waIIs.
Not Einstein, Darwin.
(guard) Yard time's over, Iadies.
Let's Iine it up.
I'm not done with you, fish.
You never even got started.
AII right.
We're through the hard part.
Another 18 inches, we'II hit that pipe.
- We'II be there by Friday.
- Friday?
- Better start making traveI arrangements.
- Maricruz, here I come.
- (Abruzzi) Sardinia.
- Where are we going?
- Panama.
Panama. Darien Gap, south of the canaI.
No roads, no eIectricity, no cops.
Nothing but white sand beaches
and ice-coId beer.
- WeII, that's nice, but what about our Iives?
- WeII, we'II open a scuba shop.
- Hey, I don't dive.
- Neither do I.
We'II have pIenty of time to Iearn.
BuIIs.
This con says he's on ajob in here.
- I don't think so.
- You heard the paisano. Move your ass.
CO, hoId on one second.
Now, are you sure about that?
Are you sure you can't use an extra hand?
You know anything about construction?
Concrete is my speciaIty. Can you dig it?
OK, boss. Sign him up.
You got it.
Now it Iooks Iike Darwin wins after aII,
eh, fish?
I have a Iot of dots,
but no way to connect them.
- Nobody's getting rich.
- What about sharehoIders?
Profits were aII converted back to shares.
Looks Iike they subcontracted out
some research -
it's pennies in the scheme of things.
Nobody got earIy retirement.
But you can't hide $500 miIIion
by moving a few decimaI points.
ln a move anticipated by many, Reynolds
announced she is running for the presidency.
She made the announcement
from her hometown of Montgomery.
The move toward worldwide peace
and prosperity is a marathon, not a sprint,
but l assure you,
America will be setting the pace.
$0.5 biIIion doesn't disappear.
You couId run a smaII country with that.
The vice president is reported to have
the largest campaign war chest in history.
lt is so large, in fact,
prognosticators are already casting her
as the favourite in the presidential race.
Maybe not a smaII country.
Maybe this one.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Jo CIarke
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net