SCOFIELD: Previously on Prison Break:
Hey, John, you know,
actuaIIy about Jesus,
say hi to him for me, wiII you?
It's him.
-Did you see him?
-Who?
-The guy in the viewing room.
-No.
It was Dad.
-Where's your girI?
-She'II be at my pIace in about an hour.
Pretty soon, we're gonna caII in our favor.
Have at it.
Boss!
POPE: The Department of Corrections
is allowing you a one-hour visit
with your son,
l"ll make the travel arrangements,
but l don"t want any problems,
(HORN HONKING)
(GROANING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(CLEARS THROAT) You know,
I used to have a Great Dane, big and IoyaI.
But when she was 12, she got cancer,
so we had to put her down.
And you'd think it wouId be this
big, dramatic event, but,
it was very peacefuI.
(SHUSHING)
One minute she was breathing,
the next she wasn't.
Hey!
Everything okay? Need me to caII 91 1?
No, no, I got it.
That engine's smoking pretty bad,
Iooks Iike it couId go up any second.
We'II be okay, actuaIIy.
-You think?
-Yeah.
-AII right, if you say so.
-Fine. I think it's going to be fine.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
MAN ON PA: Fernando Sucre
released from Ad Seg,
Cuz!
You're out.
It's good to see you, buddy.
You aII can sign each other's
yearbooks Iater. Where are we at?
The map is compIete. I got what I needed.
-Then we're ready.
-AImost.
I know which pipes we need to take
beneath Psych Ward now.
Which means our way to the Infirmary
is cIear.
With our new route, we're gonna come
up on the far end of that buiIding.
Which means we gotta waIk down
30 feet of haIIway to get to
the doctor's office, our exit point.
Which means there"s only one piece left
to this whole thing,
The key to that room.
No sweat. That's aII we gotta do is
run a bump and grab on a CO
Iike we did Iast time,
grab the keys, make a copy.
It's not that easy.
OnIy the medicaI staff have those keys.
How're you fixing
on getting it then, pretty?
CarefuIIy.
No more surprises this time, right?
Right.
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
(PRAYING)
-HeIIo, John.
-MichaeI.
How are you?
Any day above ground is a bIessing.
Thanks be to God.
Do you mind? PIease.
Thank you.
Lot of rumors going around.
Yeah.
I'm gIad you're back.
I'm surprised you're stiII here.
I thought you'd be gone by now.
WeII, we had a few setbacks.
StiII pIanning on it?
That depends.
How does the idea of escaping
sit with the new you?
Oh, the oId sinner
who was confined to these waIIs,
he's dead.
The new souI deserves to be free.
WeII, the oId sinner was gonna have
a jet ready for us.
Is the new souI gonna be abIe
to puII that off?
Noah had his Ark, did he not?
Let's pray.
I'm gonna need a bIade.
Pronto.
-Hit and run?
-Yes, sir.
-And Burrows is gone?
-That's right.
-The officers?
-Two are dead, one is in criticaI.
Do you reaIize what the media's gonna
say when they get ahoId of this?
We'II get him back, sir.
40 years in corrections, and this is
how they're gonna remember me.
This is Kane County.
Sheriff BaIIard's a good friend of mine.
-He hasn't said a word to anyone yet.
-Yeah, weII...
Give us four, five hours, we'II find him.
If I don't report this
to the D.O.C. right now...
They don't have to know.
You've aIways been
a by-the-book guy, boss,
but this time,
the book's gonna get us aII fired.
Find him.
The records of every phone caII
made to and from every contact
in Quinn's ceII phone.
WeII, we have our haystack.
Any idea what the needIe might Iook Iike?
There must be thousands of caIIs here.
But to who? To where?
You know, it's gonna take us forever
to go through aII of these.
And what if these have nothing to do
with LincoIn and Steadman, huh?
What if we're just burning time?
We're just that
much cIoser to the execution.
What's going on with you, Nick?
I mean, it's aImost Iike you want to quit.
I don't want to quit.
Then Iet's get to it.
Dr. Tancredi wiII be right in.
-Morning.
How're you feeIing today?
-Better.
-Good.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
We got checkpoints up at 171 by Lemont,
at Sage Bridge and at the river going
towards RomeoviIIe.
According to our witness over there,
this new perp was driving an '06 Mustang,
bIack, dark bIue, maybe.
We're not gonna be abIe
to sit on this thing very Iong, Brad.
This is me, Nate. I need this.
AII right. You go back to Fox River.
I'II be in constant contact.
You mind if I...
How're you doing, Mr...
-Roy Hawkings.
-Hi.
Where are you going?
I'd Iike to get going if I couId.
I'm Iate for a meeting in Aurora.
-Where you coming from?
-Chicago.
Kind of an indirect route to get to Aurora.
I'm not from around here.
2006 Mustang, bIack. No ID on the pIates.
If any of you get so much as a whiff
of anything,
I want to know about it immediateIy.
Makes two of us, paI.
What do you want from me, MichaeI?
Sara...
I need you to do something for me.
What?
Wait for me.
It won't aIways be Iike this.
In this room, in this pIace.
UntiI then, I can't.
We can't.
Damn it.
I can't.
And I gotta go.
MAN: Doors closing!
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
Hey, squirt.
Avocado.
How many times I gotta say it?
You address me formaI-Iike.
-Mr. BaIIs-Johnson.
-That's better.
I think maybe you and I
can work something out.
-ReaIIy?
-Check it, I got this homie on the outside
and he can put a hundie into your
commissary account each month.
It was nice of you to think of me Iike that,
but you onIy got one thing I need.
I need you to get something for me.
Do your bump and swipe thing.
-Like I did with the watch?
-ExactIy.
Yeah, that did me a Iot of good.
Guards found out and they stuck me into
a ceII with Avocado.
So if you want something gIommed,
you need to do something for me.
KiII that son of a bitch.
That's not something I can do.
Screw Honus Wagner.
What was that?
This kid in my neighborhood,
his dad had a basebaII card coIIection.
So I figured, you know, I'd swipe it.
I couId get some party cash, you know?
And there was one card in there.
A 1910 Honus Wagner.
Doesn't mean nothing to me, you know.
Hoops is my sport.
This card, it was worth $300,000.
So they sIapped me with grand Iarceny.
That's why I'm here.
That's why I'm sitting on a nickeI
getting turned out Iike a IittIe bitch.
A basebaII card.
(KEYS JINGLING)
Dad?
What are you doing here?
As soon as I heard they granted you
a visit with your son,
I knew they'd make a move on you.
I mean what are you doing here?
I've got a car about 20 miIes from here.
We'II switch out. After that,
gonna make sure you disappear.
Then this business wiII just be
between me and them.
Can you move?
What are you taIking about?
They're after me, not you.
It's not as simpIe as that, trust me.
I worked for them.
You worked for them?
You're an aIcohoIic...
Is that what you remember
or is that what you were toId?
Why'd you Ieave?
I took a position with a group
of muItinationaIs we caII The Company.
They caII every shot this country takes,
what Iaws to pass, what judges
to appoint, what wars to fight.
Thing is, if you wanted to rise in the ranks
Iike I did,
you had to commit to Ieaving
everything you know behind.
Because then you start to get access
to the reaI information.
Information peopIe wouId do
a Iot of things to get their hands on,
-Iike harm your famiIy.
-You expect me to beIieve that?
Why didn't you reach out to us?
Why didn't you caII us?
I regretted it every day,
but I didn't have a choice.
LincoIn, the day I Ieft The Company,
I took aII that information with me.
That's why they're doing this to you.
AII of it, to stop me.
You have to trust me.
NIKA: Then you"ll have to tell me
what"s going on,
l can"t do that,
Then I can't heIp.
Look, I did what you ask. Green card
for credit card, that was the deaI.
Then, we'II make a new deaI.
-MichaeI, if somebody find out...
-Believe me,
-I'II be in more troubIe than you wiII.
-l know,
and this is why I won't heIp you.
Look, Nika, I promise you...
Look, I don't know what's going on.
I don't know why you're in there,
but if there's one thing those guys
that brought me here taught me,
is that if you fight, if you struggIe,
you onIy make things worse.
Stop fighting, MichaeI.
-Just think about it, okay?
-I'm sorry.
There it is again, the 406 number.
It's on every Iisting.
406.
Yeah, there's
over 200 businesses, another 100
residences in 17 different countries.
-And they're aII caIIing the same number.
-406.
Montana.
-Can you check the prefixes?
-This doesn't make sense.
AII these peopIe from aII over the
worId are caIIing this pIace
in the middIe of nowhere with a
popuIation of 42.
BIackfoot, Montana.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I thought you understood, Terrence.
If you wanna taIk, we set up a meeting,
at home, in person.
I saw the Iatest tracking.
Your poIIs are headed south.
Maybe the Burrows thing is finally starting
to gain some traction with the swings.
It couId hurt.
-Goodbye, Terrence.
-You said it was aImost over.
It is.
Are we taIking about LincoIn Burrows
or your candidacy?
The onIy reason that you are stiII aIive
-is because l won"t let them kill you,
-Yeah.
I'm pretty cIear on that.
But the thing I can't quite figure is,
with the crap storm this thing's become,
why they haven't kiIIed you.
(SIGHING)
Figure out how you're gonna
get the key to the Infirmary yet?
Not quite.
You working a game on her, or what?
I don't know.
Hey man! Get out of my way!
I've had time to think.
Not that you tried to kiII me,
but about how Jesus saved me.
I didn't come here, Theodore,
to infIict any more pain.
Take my hand
so we can put this behind us. PIease.
Show me the paIm of your other hand.
Don't insuIt me. After aII that you've done,
the Ieast I ask is that you don't insuIt me.
Does not a warm hand
feeI better than a coId shank?
You got a point there, John. Yeah.
Truce?
You got it. Truce.
Son of a bitch.
It's been two and a haIf hours
and you're teIIing me that
sheriff has got nothing?
I'm teIIing you the roads are bIocked off.
That Mustang's got to be somewhere
within those 10 square miIes.
AII right, Iisten,
you got two hours to find him.
After that, I have got to taIk to the press.
Hey, but there's an escaped kiIIer
outside our waIIs
and there are some things
that are more important than career.
Now you find him !
STOLTE: Hey, Captain.
I don't have time.
He says he reaIIy needs to taIk.
You have something for me
or do you need something?
'Cause if it's the Iatter,
you just wasted my time.
That ceIIie you stuck me with, Avocado...
Do you have something or do you need
something? Last time I'm gonna ask.
I'm asking you
to just, pIease, get me out of that ceII.
Boss, pIease. Boss!
Let's go.
(BED CREAKING)
You need to start reIaxing.
It'II hurt a Iot Iess.
-Can we go on your bunk?
-Sure, squirt.
Let me make it
a wee bit more comfortabIe.
Now we're taIking.
(BIRDS CAWING)
-Are you the doctor from the prison?
-Yeah. Can, I...
Do you know a prisoner
named MichaeI ScofieId?
I do.
-You're his wife, right?
-I need to taIk to you.
I think MichaeI has got himseIf
in some troubIe.
And I think he's pIanning on doing
something dangerous to get out of it.
Thanks.
-So what is it that you...
-MichaeI has a deep need to heIp peopIe.
So I've come to understand.
That's actuaIIy how we met.
There were these men
that brought me here.
ToId me I'd have good job,
but that was just a Iie.
They were going to seII me.
And untiI they did, I...
MichaeI paid them off for my freedom.
And not to keep me for himseIf,
Iike I've heard from other girIs,
but to give me an opportunity.
He's a good man.
Yes, he is.
Nika, I wanna do
whatever I can to heIp MichaeI.
To do that, I need you to teII me
what it is you think he's mixed up in.
-I think this is a mistake.
-No, no, it's not at aII.
-If you can just teII me what it is...
-PIease, just keep an eye on him.
God, I'm sorry. Thanks.
Listen, couId I just have a contact number
for you in case I see something wrong.
I don't think that's a good idea.
PIease don't teII him that we met.
I... I...
Something I don't get.
How couId kiIIing me stop you?
'Cause I'm the one who Ieaked
the information about EcofieId.
They couId've covered up the scandaI
a thousand different ways,
but they chose to fake
Terrence Steadman's death.
And they chose you
'cause they knew it wouId fIush me out.
They knew that any man with a son
on death row who was innocent
wouId have to come forward.
But you didn't.
We had a cause, Linc.
We have a cause.
Their wars can be averted
and miIIions of Iives can be saved.
So you were wiIIing to sacrifice one.
Yeah.
At Ieast I thought.
But I couIdn't watch you die.
You know what you've done?
The mother of my chiId is dead.
-I know.
-Do you?
Then I'm guessing you know
MichaeI's in Fox River
-and LJ's rotting in some jaiI.
-I know aII of it.
-If you think for a second...
-You don't have a choice right now.
This is aII on you. AII of it.
Yeah, I know. That's why I'm here.
'Cause there's stiII a chance
we can make it right.
That man in there
is our transportation out of here,
which means that, you go after him,
and that messes with my chances
of me seeing my famiIy.
So I ain't gonna Iet that happen.
So why don't you just hand me
that shank you're hoIding, huh?
Good.
-Hey, Sara.
-Hey, Rick.
You aII right?
Yeah. I can't find my keys.
WouId you Iet me in?
Oh, sure.
-I'm surprised to see you here.
-That makes both of us.
Look.
You were right and I'm sorry.
I shouId never have gotten you
invoIved in this.
-Oh, it's okay.
-No, it's not.
If anyone knew what I asked...
I'm not even sure why I did it.
Thank you.
Now we're even.
-You didn't owe me anything.
-Yes, I did.
I owed you everything,
but that's over now.
Goodbye.
The Iady doctor, she cares for you.
BeIIick. It's the sheriff.
I think he's got something.
Go, for BeIIick.
We just got a caII from Steve
Schimek up at the junkyard.
-Our Mustang is on the premises,
-BELLICK: He seen Burrows?
Yep, l got a couple of units
five, 10 minutes away, tops,
Good, I'm right behind you.
Here. You ready to traveI?
PIace is gonna be crawIing with cops.
You know that, right?
There's an unimproved road
down by the river.
There's a chance
they haven't bIocked it off yet.
We got troubIe.
Come on. Through here.
Come on.
Hey!
Get out of here.
Go.
Turn around.
BeIIick!
BeIIick, don't shoot! Don't shoot!
-AII right on your knees!
-Right there! Right there!
On your knees! Hands up! Let's see them !
Take him down!
Get down! Get down!
You thought you'd go
for a IittIe stroII, did you?
SUCRE: Did you hear about Avocado?
Got his salchicha sIiced.
-How?
-Tweener.
But Avocado's saying
it got caught on the frame
whiIe he was hopping
down off his bunk, yeah.
Why did he Iie?
He doesn't want Tweener to go to
the SHU 'cause he can't get him in there.
AII I have to say is, as soon as
Avocado gets out of the infirmary,
Tweener is a dead man.
How's that key coming?
What about your car?
You know, sometimes...
I just checked.
Your apartment?
No, 'cause I had them this morning.
WeII, then, they gotta be here.
Just retrace your steps.
When did you first notice they were gone?
When I came back from Iunch...
Hey, Kev, I need to take a Iook
at that visitation Iog.
Thanks.
MichaeI?
I need to know where he is.
-Who?
-Fibonacci.
You see, my conversion requires
that I not onIy seek forgiveness,
but provide forgiveness,
even to my greatest transgressors.
Don't Iook at me Iike that,
Iike I'm the same oId man I used to be.
I'm not.
Trust me,
I need to reach out to
Fibonacci, so we can heaI.
That's a good story, but the answer is no.
I understand.
I'II be patient.
(PHONE RINGING)
-NICK: Hello,
-Hey, you're officiaIIy now on standby.
And you'II have her there.
Do you understand?
-Yeah. I'II do my best.
-Hey, I said, do you understand?
-Yeah. Loud and cIear.
-Good,
Goose Park airstrip.
You can find it on a map, As soon as l call,
you have that bitch there
ready and waiting.
Hey.
You stiII want me to swipe the thing
you were asking about?
'Cause I'm having
a going-out-of-business saIe.
Why don't you get yourseIf to Ad Seg?
For that to happen, I'd have to admit
what I did to Avocado.
That'd get me what, 20 years?
I'm dead no matter what.
There may be another way out of here.
Yeah, in a body bag.
I need to know if I can trust you.
I'm as straight up as they come,
you know?
No, I mean reaIIy trust you.
-Hey.
-Hi.
-How are you?
-I'm fine. You?
Fine.
Can I have your hand, pIease?
-Here they are.
-Here what are?
Your keys,
they were right over there by your inbox.
WeII, you got a maintenance guy
waiting outside here,
says you wanted him to change the Iocks.
Want me to caII him off?
No, send him in.
Is it okay if I...
Yeah. We're about done here.
Is there something wrong?
No.
UnIess you want to taIk about
what happened this morning.
I think I have a pretty good idea.
We're done here.
(MAN CHATTERING ON PA)
I want him under 24-hour surveiIIance.
-He doesn't sneeze without my knowing it.
-What the heII for? What did I do?
Someone tried to kiII me.
Finding you in a junkyard eight miIes
from here makes me think different.
Who was your accompIice?
-What accompIice?
-24-hour surveiIIance.
(HUMMING)
Boss.
I heard Avocado
cut his hose on your bunk.
Must have been some serious gymnastics
going on.
I got something for you this time, Boss,
but I want guaranteed protection
from Avocado,
-and I want time cut off my bid.
-Anything eIse?
CoupIe of big-canned whores
avaiIabIe to you 24/7?
BeIieve me, what I got is worth it.
So, are you gonna step up or what?
This is your Iast chance, Tweener.
You bIow smoke again, they'II be
scraping you off the heeI of my boot.
ScofieId and his whoIe PI crew,
they're escaping.
www.tvsubtitles.net