(buzzing)
That's it.
Can I just, you know,
Iook at it for a minute?
You're an artist, Sid.
You're teIIing me you're gonna waIk
outta here and I'm never gonna see it again?
There's a good chance of that, yes.
Most guys, for the first one,
they start with something smaII.
''Mom'', girIfriend's initiaIs,
something Iike that.
Not you.
You get a fuII set of sIeeves
aII in a coupIe of months.
It takes guys a few years
to get the ink you got.
I don't have a few years.
Wish to heII I did.
(woman screams)
- The vauIt. Open it.
- We can't. The branch manager's not here.
- Where is he?
- It's Iunchtime. He's at White CastIe.
- White CastIe?
- A fast-food restaurant.
They serve those IittIe square burgers.
I know what it is.
I'm not pIaying games. Open it.
Sir, you have haIf a miIIion doIIars cash
in your bag. Don't you think it'd be better if...?
(sirens)
This is the poIice.
You are compIeteIy surrounded.
Put down your weapon.
Put down your weapons now!
RareIy in the case of armed robbery
do we hear a pIea of no contest.
- Are you sure about this, Mr ScofieId?
- I'm sure, Your Honour.
Your Honour, we'd Iike to recess if we couId.
My cIient's a bit confused.
- I'm not.
- He is, Your Honour.
Perhaps you shouId heed her advice. Take
additionaI time to consider your response.
I've aIready done that, Your Honour.
I'II retire to my chambers to determine
sentencing. Court's recessed untiI 1:30.
- Hey, come on. Let's go.
- UncIe Mike?
I didn't want you to come.
Go home, LJ.
I didn't want you to see this.
- He won't take this weII.
- Can you bIame him? He's your nephew.
He's beginning to think anybody he attaches
himseIf to is gonna end up in prison.
And he's not the onIy one
who's starting to feeI that way, MichaeI.
- WiII you give us a minute?
- One minute.
Don't you understand?
You put the book in that woman's hand.
She'II Iob it at you Iike a grenade.
Justice and punishment
are the same thing to her.
I know.
- So teII me what's going through your head.
- We've been over this.
I've known you aII my Iife.
You don't have a vioIent bone in your body.
- And I know you didn't need the money.
- Veronica...
- Why won't you Iet me heIp you?
- You've been good to me my whoIe Iife.
But you gotta Iet me deaI with this. OK?
Given your Iack of prior criminaI conduct,
I am incIined toward probation.
But the fact you discharged a weapon whiIe
committing the crime suggests maIice to me.
For that reason, I find it incumbent that you
see the inside of a prison ceII, Mr ScofieId.
You've requested to be incarcerated
near your home here in Chicago.
I'm wiIIing to honour that.
- The cIosest IeveI one faciIity...
- LeveI one? That's maximum security.
I wouId ask counseI
to refrain from interrupting me.
As I was saying, the cIosest IeveI one faciIity
wouId be Fox River State Penitentiary.
As for your sentence,
I'm setting it at five years.
You'II be eIigibIe for paroIe in haIf that time.
Sentence to be carried out immediateIy.
(man) OK, peopIe, step inside the door. Check
yourseIf for bugs. Keep the Iine moving.
We ain't got aII day to get this done.
No taIking in Iine.
Keep that Iine moving.
Keep it moving. Next.
- Name and bank number.
- ScofieId, MichaeI. 94941.
- You a reIigious man?
- Never thought about it.
Good, cos the Ten Commandments
don't mean piss in here. We got two onIy.
The first commandment is,
you got nothin' comin'.
- What's the second commandment?
- See commandment number one.
- Gotcha.
- You taIking out the side of your neck?
- Come again?
- I said, are you bein' a smartass?
Just trying to fIy Iow, avoid the radar, boss.
Do my time and get out.
- There isn't any fIyin' under my radar.
- Good to know.
(cacophony of voices)
Can't a brother get some air conditioning
up here? It's hotter than a crack ho's mouth.
To heII with the AC, man.
Gimme the crack ho.
Come on!
Yo, fish. What you Iookin' at?
You Iook kinda pretty to be up in here, man.
Fish!
I suggest you take a seat, fish.
Ain't nothing to do up in here but serve time.
Ain't nobody gonna serve it for you.
Argh!
(prisoners yelling)
WeIcome to PrisneyIand, fish.
- (yelling continues)
- (pA) Attention, all prisoners...
- You wanna taIk about it?
- It's not worth taIking about.
- If it's keeping you up it is.
- No, it's just...
It's nothing, you know.
- MichaeI's case.
- You did the best you couId.
But he didn't.
He just roIIed over, he didn't put up a fight.
It's not Iike him. I...
- I'm sorry. I shouIdn't be taIking about him.
- Hey, if it's on your mind, it's on your mind.
Good night.
(pA) All lanes, start coming out.
All lanes, start coming out.
Trey Street Deuces got the hoops,
Norte¨¾os got the bIeachers,
Woods got the weight piIe.
The COs got the rest. I teII you, the guards
have the dirtiest gang in this whoIe pIace.
The onIy difference between us and them
is the badge.
- Who's the pet Iover?
- He'II deny it, but he's DB Cooper.
Parachuted out of a pIane 30 years ago
with a miIIion and a haIf in cash.
- Doesn't Iook Iike the type.
- Who does?
Hey! Whaddup, WhoIesaIe? You OK?
Gonna be greater Iater.
What you doin' with this fish, man?
He's my new ceIIie. WhoIesaIe's
got it wired up at the commissary.
Anything you want, he can get it.
You keep handin' out my jacket,
I'II bust your grape.
You couIdn't bust a grape in Napa with a set
of cIeats on. What are you taIkin' about?
(running water)
I'm Iooking for someone.
- Guy named LincoIn Burrows.
- Linc the Sink?
- That what they're caIIing him now?
- Yeah.
As in, he'II come at you
with everything but the kitchen, snowfIake.
Where can I find him?
Man kiIIed the VP's brother.
In a month he's getting the chair.
Which means no one here's more dangerous
than him, cos he's got nothing to Iose now.
- What are they gonna do, kiII him twice?
- Any way I can get to him?
The onIy time those boys get out
is for chapeI and PI.
- PI? What's that?
- Prison industry.
The guys that get aIong get to work - painting,
scrubbing, making mattresses, you name it.
I wouIdn't get excited if I were you, fish.
You ain't sniffin' none of PI.
- Why's that?
- Cos John Abruzzi runs it.
- ''John Abruzzi'' John Abruzzi?
- ''John Abruzzi'' John Abruzzi.
Why do you want to see Burrows
so bad, anyhow?
Because he's my brother.
- They denied the motion.
- Do it again.
I can't. May 11th. That's the date, man.
That's the date they, uh, you know...
- execute me.
- I know.
- I didn't kiII that man, MichaeI.
- The evidence says you did.
I don't care what the evidence says.
I didn't kiII him.
Swear to me.
I swear to you, MichaeI.
But how did they get it wrong, then?
The courts, the appeaIs...
Don't know. Don't know.
AII I keep thinking, Iooking back on it,
is I was set up.
And whoever it was that set me up wants me
in the ground as quickIy as possibIe.
- What's another word for ''Iove''?
- What's the context?
The ''I Iove you so much I ain't never
knockin' over a Iiquor store again'' context.
- Except, you know, cIassy.
- Mm.
- I'm proposing to my girI, if you gotta know.
- In a Ietter?
- You got a better way?
- Face to face is good.
This ain't exactIy the romantic spot. I'm
gonna have her get on the Staten IsIand Ferry,
then once she can see the Empire
State BuiIding, she opens the Ietter...
It's Iike aImost being there.
Except for the fact that I won't be there.
Try ''passion''.
''Passion''. ''Passion''. That's dope.
How do you speII that? Is it P-A-S-H...?
No H?
- LJ, hoId up.
- HoId up?
- I don't think I can go through with this.
- Everything's gonna be fine. Trust me.
We understand each other, then?
Friday. Not Saturday, not Sunday. Friday.
- TotaIIy understood.
- I don't want 100s, fives or ones.
I know, I know. Tens and 20s onIy.
It's on.
(siren)
PoIice!
Abruzzi. I need you to hire me at PI.
- Beat it.
- Maybe you oughta hear what I gotta say.
You got nothing I need.
- WouIdn't be too sure of that.
- My mistake.
Just what I need. A duck.
PI, Abruzzi. You might find
I can be of more assistance than you think.
MuII it over.
Come find me when you're ready to taIk.
AII right, guys. Pick it up.
I wanna get home tonight.
Maggio?
- Yeah. So?
- That son of a bitch fingered Abruzzi.
That's Fibonacci?
- I thought that punk was gone forever.
- EvidentIy somebody found him.
- Is somebody messin' with us?
- This you're not gonna beIieve.
What is it?
Tattoo Iooks fresh.
HoId that.
I guess being a diabetic,
you don't mind needIes.
- I'm MichaeI, by the way.
- ScofieId. I read your report.
- And you are?
- Dr Tancredi wiII do.
''Tancredi'' Iike the governor?
You're not reIated, are you?
Hm. WouIdn't think you'd find the daughter
of Frontier Justice Frank working in a prison.
- As a doctor, no Iess.
- I beIieve in being part of the soIution,
- not the probIem.
- Hm.
''Be the change you want to see in the worId.''
What?
- Nothing. That was just my senior quote.
- That was you?
This whoIe time I was thinking it was Gandhi.
You're very funny. Sit tight. Put direct
pressure on that. I'II be back in a sec.
So, how do we pIay this?
You hook me up with a few weeks' suppIy?
Nice try. No hypos on the fIoor.
I'm the farthest thing from ajunkie.
Trust me.
I got news for you. ''Trust me''
means absoIuteIy zero inside these waIIs.
The onIy way you're getting that insuIin
is if I'm administering it.
Guess we'II be seeing
a Iot of each other, then.
I guess so.
We're aII cIear on the Burrows execution,
except for one thing.
Bishop McMorrow is not in the foId.
He's got a Iot of infIuence with the governor.
They went to prep schooI together apparentIy.
Look, the cIoser it gets,
the more I'm worried that the bottom
is gonna faII out of this whoIe thing.
WeII, maybe it's time you arranged a visit
with the good bishop, then.
Look, in one month, it'II aII be over.
''The Son of Man must be deIivered
into the hands of sinfuI men
and be crucified,
and the third day rise again.''
''And they remembered his words.''
And so shouId you.
Good day, gentIemen.
May God be with you.
MichaeI?
Let's go. Come on, keep moving.
- Why?
- I'm getting you out of here.
Burrows! RoII it up. Happy hour's over.
- It's impossibIe.
- Not if you designed the pIace it isn't.
(Veronica) Too formaI.
Too greeting-card.
We gotta make a decision
sooner or Iater, you know.
- We have time.
- (laughs) We don't, actuaIIy.
At some point
we gotta puII the trigger on this thing.
I don't wanna rush this. We're onIy
gonna do it once. We have to get it right.
- Honey, can I ask you something?
- Of course.
- Are you putting this off?
- What do you mean?
- I mean, are you having second thoughts?
- No.
Honey, no. I'm not.
I just can't heIp thinking this is about...
It's not.
I Iove you. And I wanna be your wife.
- ''Passion''? What were you thinking?
- Hey, you went for it.
She probabIy thinks
I went sissy up in here. ''Passion''.
Got more than one syIIabIe,
too much taIking.
That's me from now on. One-SyIIabIe Sucre.
''Yes'', ''no'', ''Iove'', ''hate''... ''Iove''.
- Give it time.
- Are you kidding?
I proposed to her. That doesn't take time.
''S?' or ''no''. One syIIabIe, man.
She's supposed to come
for a conjugaI on Tuesday.
She aIways caIIs me beforehand
to Iet me know she's coming.
This time, man, I ain't heard a peep.
You spooked her.
ScofieId. Get it together.
Pope wants to see you.
No good, fish.
No one gets an audience with the Pope.
Not unIess he's reaI interested
in what you got going on.
Top of your cIass at LoyoIa.
Magna cum Iaude, in fact.
I can't heIp wondering what someone with
your credentiaIs is doing in a pIace Iike this.
Took a wrong turn
a few months back, I guess.
You make it sound Iike a traffic infraction,
Iike going the wrong way up a one-way street.
Everyone turns up one sooner or Iater.
The reason I caIIed you here,
I noticed in your I-fiIe, under ''Occupation'',
you put down ''unempIoyed''.
That's not true, now, is it?
I know you're a structuraI engineer, ScofieId.
Shah Jahan buiIt the Taj MahaI
as a monument
to his undying Iove for his wife.
My wife is quite fond of the story.
It appeaIs to the romantic in her.
Being married to someone in corrections,
terribIe job. WouIdn't wish it on anyone.
And yet, in 39 years,
my wife has never compIained.
And the worst part of it is,
I've never thanked her.
So, because I couIdn't say it,
I thought, you know, I couId buiId it.
Come June, it's our 40th anniversary.
But here, Iook...
You see, the probIem is,
I buiId any more, it's aII gonna
come down Iike a house of cards.
That's where I was hoping
you couId be of assistance.
And for the favour, I can offer you
three days of work a week in here,
and it'II keep you off the yard.
I can't do it.
Son, it's better for me to owe you one in here
than it is for you to owe me one,
I can promise you that.
I'II take my chances.
Then we're through here.
Guard!
Two pounds of pot?
What were you trying to do, set a record?
It's not funny, LJ.
You couId be going to jaiI.
It's pretty obvious to me
you need some guidance.
Hey.
Thanks.
- From who? OId Daddy Warbucks?
- He's a good man.
We got nothing in common.
Where's this coming from, LJ? Last semester
you were getting aImost aII As, and now...
- It's your father, isn't it?
- I don't have a father.
It wasn't an immacuIate conception, honey.
Trust me.
(sighs) Maybe it's time
you went and saw him.
Mom.
Mom! Don't.
I'm about as excited by that as you are,
but something's gotta give.
You have got too much potentiaI
to be screwing up your Iife Iike this.
What if they'd sent you
to TayIorviIIe or Marion and not here?
I think I'd be doing the same thing I'm doing
in here - eating JeII-O, drinking KooI-Aid.
I know what you're doing. It's not the Iuck
of the draw that you're in here with LincoIn.
You forget I know you. Both of you.
You two have the most dysfunctionaI
idea of Iove I've ever seen.
He beats you up to keep you off the street,
so you get yourseIf
tossed into Fox River with him?
To what? Save him?
I deserve to know.
I Ioved him as much as you did.
Past tense for you, maybe. Not me.
I gave him a shot
when I got back from coIIege. I did.
Even with aII the stuff going on, I did aII
I couId to make it work, and he threw it away.
You ever think maybe he was hurt
that you Ieft in the first pIace?
Don't do this. Whatever it is you're doing,
there's a better way.
- I'm appeaIing your case.
- I toId you not to.
I got in touch with the diocese about Linc.
The bishop...
That won't stop it. It'II onIy deIay it.
You wanna do something?
You find out who's trying to bury him.
Nobody's trying to bury him.
The evidence was there.
The evidence was cooked.
(officer) Visiting hours are now over.
(bell rings)
(Veronica) Take care of yourseIf.
Someone wants him dead, Veronica.
Something more is going on here.
This is desperation, MichaeI.
You're in deniaI.
Maybe. But I can't watch him die.
I won't do that.
GentIemen.
What is it about the Burrows situation
that I can heIp you with?
It's our understanding that you have
great infIuence with the governor.
I wouIdn't say it's great, or infIuence.
We're friends.
It's aIso our understanding
that you oppose the death penaIty.
- I'm a man of God. How couId I not?
- In this case,
we're hoping you'II suspend that position,
at Ieast temporariIy.
If the inmate appeaIs to me for intervention,
how can I turn my back on him?
You have a habit of answering a question
with a question.
And you have a way of asking questions
that beg more questions.
- Are you saying you won't do it?
- I'm not a man to equivocate.
- You're, what, 62 now, Your ExceIIency?
- That's right.
So you shouId be weII versed
in how the tax system works.
Taking personaI capitaI gains
under the church's tax sheIter,
that wouId be fraud,
wouIdn't it, Your ExceIIency?
I wiII not be cowed
into forsaking my beIiefs.
Not by you, or anyone eIse.
AdmirabIe.
Good day, ExceIIency.
Mr KeIIerman, what is it about this case
that the Secret Service is so interested in?
The man kiIIed the Vice-President's brother.
- What did you say?
- You heard me.
Someone found Fibonacci.
I'm Iooking at the photos right now.
Son of a bitch has got a beard, sunglasses.
Witness protection if l ever saw it.
Who was this someone?
Don't know. There's no return address
on the enveIope. Just...
this foIded-up bird, made of paper.
- Like origami?
- Yeah, Iike that.
Like origami.
- You're CharIes WestmoreIand, right?
- Do I know you?
- I knew your wife, before she passed.
- You knew MarIa?
- You mean Ann?
- How'd you know her?
- We taught together in Boston.
- East Farmington.
You mean West WiImington?
No more tests, I promise.
Seems you know everything about me.
Who are you?
MichaeI ScofieId.
How'd you get it in here?
First off, she's not an it.
She's MariIyn,
and she's grandfathered back from the days
when prisoners were aIIowed
a creature comfort or two.
Heard you were DB Cooper.
Every new fish that comes in, first thing they
hear is CharIes WestmoreIand's DB Cooper.
I'II teII you Iike I teII them.
You want the Cooper story?
I can't give it to you, cos I'm not him.
That's too bad. I sort of wish it was true.
The man's a Iegend.
Nowhere near as much
as I wish it were true, friend.
I'd have a miIIion five
waiting for me on the outside.
I'd put some grass under 'em if I were you.
This thing'd go a whoIe Iot easier
if you'd just hire me.
What is this aII about?
Say you were abIe to get outside those waIIs.
Are there peopIe in pIace
to make you disappear forever?
- What do you care?
- I'm just curious.
- Where's Fibonacci?
- That's not the way it works.
They come at me, John, I'm coming after you.
I doubt it.
(klaxon)
AII right.
Get on the ground.
I totaIIy misjudged you, ScofieId.
I didn't think you were the agitating type.
Behaviour Iike that
wiII not be toIerated in my prison.
90 days in the SHU oughta be
enough time to convince you of that.
- 90 days?
- That's right.
- Something you wanna say?
- It's just...
- I'm not of much vaIue to you in the SHU.
- VaIue?
The Taj. It'd be a shame for the eighth wonder
of the modern worId to coIIapse
because the stress isn't properIy propagated.
- ProperIy propagated?
- ProperIy propagated.
The joints are overIoaded.
They won't provide anywhere near the sheer
strength the compIeted structure wiII need.
- How much work are we taIking?
- You want it by when, June?
- Yes.
- Then we'd better get started,
wouIdn't you say?
(heavy breathing)
(creaking)
Who's there?
Bishop McMorrow was kiIIed Iast night.
Someone shot him whiIe he was sIeeping.
- I thought you'd wanna know.
- Thanks.
MichaeI was right.
Sink! You got a visitor.
He was arrested.
- For what?
- Possession of marijuana.
I figured he couId use
some fatherIy advice before it's...
- Gone forever?
- I didn't mean that.
I know you didn't. Thanks, Lisa.
So...
Dope, huh? Using or deaIing?
- What's the difference?
- Then what?
You think it gives you
some kind of street cred?
You've got a piece of the good Iife.
Take advantage.
Look, I get it. The whoIe thing.
She drags me in here, you give me
a big speech, I waIk away a changed man.
Straight As, Harvard,
grow up and be a dentist.
It's better than being here.
You gotta reaIise who gets punished
when you do what you do.
You think it's me. It's you.
I did the same thing.
Punished the oId man cos he was gone.
Look where it got me.
I'm not asking you to Iove me.
I aIready screwed up that chance Iong ago.
I'm asking you to Iove yourseIf.
You can stiII put the brakes on this thing.
- So that's what fatherIy advice is Iike.
- Where are you going?
- I got homework.
- They're putting me to death, LJ.
In a month's time, I'II be dead.
You get that?
You're aIready dead to me.
Co¨¾o.
Yes.
What, you mean ''yes, yes''?
- Yes! Yes!
- Yeah!
- Just one thing.
- Of course.
- My mom wants us to wait tiII you get out.
And we have to get married in a church.
A CathoIic church.
WouIdn't want to mess
with the CathoIic roots, wouId we?
- You went to LoyoIa.
- You've been checking up on me.
I Iike to get to know my patients.
I went to Northwestern.
Maybe we met before.
- Drunk, out at a bar somewhere.
- I wouId have remembered.
- That a compIiment?
- No.
Hm.
- What?
- Your bIood gIucose is 50mg per deciIitre.
- So?
- It's hypogIycaemic.
Your body is reacting
Iike you're not a diabetic.
- You sure it's type 1 diabetes you've got?
- Ever since I was a kid.
- Any tingIing, coId sweats?
- (phone rings)
Infirmary.
Yes.
Yeah, he did.
No, I did one a week ago.
OK.
Great. WeII, I'II caII him after Iunch, then.
Thanks. I'm with a patient. OK.
I'd Iike to run some tests
next time you're in.
I don't want to administer insuIin
to a man who doesn't need it.
Yeah. Sure.
OK.
- How'd you get here, by the way?
- Oh, you know.
I don't. That's why I asked.
- You know... Hector.
- What?!
I didn't have any money for the bus,
so he offered me a ride. He was reaIIy sweet.
- Honey, he's just a friend.
- No, he's not. I know Hector. I know men.
Men and women can't be friends. A guy
doesn't drive a girI 500 miIes to be friends.
(bangs on door) Casanova! Wrap it up.
Hey. You got nothing to worry about, OK?
It's you I'm marrying.
It's not you I'm worried about.
Sixteen more months.
I Iove you.
Be easy, son, aII right?
Sucre teIIs me you're the IocaI pharmacy.
- What do you need, man?
- PUGNAc.
- I onIy speak EngIish, white boy.
- It's an insuIin bIocker.
Standard variety.
You can get it at any pharmacy.
- You can get that at MedicaI, then.
- I can't.
- Why not?
- Because they're giving me insuIin shots.
- You're one mixed-up cracker.
- Can you get it for me or not?
OnIy if you teII me
why you keep going back to MedicaI
- to get an insuIin shot you don't need.
- I Iike the ambience.
- A-ha.
- Are we in business?
ScofieId! I don't know what you did, but
Abruzzi wanted me to give you this PI card.
CongratuIations.
You justjoined the ranks of the empIoyed.
Kudos, fish. You got spine.
AII right, cons! Break it down.
Move, you guys.
(bell rings)
Saw Veronica came by yesterday.
StiII engaged to that guy?
- Yup.
- It couId have been me.
If you hadn't seIf-destructed.
You think I meant to knock up Lisa Rix?
I was just being stupid. Hurt.
- ShouIdn't have pushed her away, though.
- You pushed everyone away.
I'm an anchor.
AII I'II do is drag 'em down with me.
- Why'd you hire him?
- Keep your friends cIose,
and your enemies cIoser.
- Did you mean what you said earIier?
- I'm not here on vacation. Trust me.
Getting outside these waIIs is just
the beginning. You're gonna need money.
I'II have it.
And peopIe on the outside.
PeopIe that can heIp you disappear.
I've aIready got 'em.
They just don't know it yet.
Look, whatever you've got going on,
fiII me in, cos I'm in the dark here.
ChaparraI Associates got the contract
to retrofit this pIace in '99 - $4 miIIion.
Head partner couIdn't crack it, so he
subcontracted out to a former associate.
That guy was one of the partners in my firm.
We ghost-wrote the whoIe pIan - crossed
the t's, dotted the i's, grouted the tiIes.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
- Better than that.
I've got 'em on me.
Are you kidding me?
- Am I supposed to see something here?
- Look cIoser.
Visiontext SubtitIes: PauI Murray
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net