previously on ''prison Break'':
- I didn't kiII that man.
- The evidence says you did.
I was set up.
Put down your weapon.
I find it incumbent
that you see the inside of a prison ceII.
- I'm Iooking for LincoIn Burrows.
- Man kiIIed the vice president's brother.
- Why do you want to see Burrows?
- He's my brother.
- I'm getting you out.
- It's impossibIe.
- Not if you designed the pIace.
- You've seen the bIueprints.
Better than that. I've got 'em on me.
- There's a lawyer poking around.
- Ms Donovan? I didn't mean to scare you.
- It's gone.
- Does anyone eIse have a key to this pIace?
You were here.
I waIked over to the cabinet and I...
Got an issue with our IittIe friend over there?
Yeah. Maybe it's time
I Iit up that Ieather once and for aII, huh?
- What happened?
- Don't make me Iie to you.
- You heard the news?
- No. What?
- They're brothers.
- Who?
Burrows and ScofieId.
MichaeI ScofieId?
I'm going into the waIIs,
see if I can access the roof.
Take the onIy thing Burrows has Ieft.
The chair isn't the onIy way
to take a man's Iife in prison.
Just a few more rides.
Then you have to wrap it up.
Wow. Adam's getting bigger. Ten.
Not here.
We need a favour.
- I've been out of the Iife for years.
- I know.
ProbIem is, no one's gonna beIieve that
if I take the heroin in my pocket
and put it in the gIove box of the reasonabIy
priced minivan you got over there.
I wiII cuff you. I wiII drag you
out of here in front of everyone.
What do you need?
(president) What America needs
is an environmentally friendly,
logistically feasible
and economically responsible
alternative fuel source.
(phone rings)
(Veronica on answerphone) Leave a message
and l'll call you back. Thanks.
lt's Wendy. l know you wanted to work
with no distractions, so don't pick up.
l just wanted to let you know that
Nick Savrinn left six messages for you...
- What did you teII him?
- What you said to say- you were in a meeting.
If he comes by tomorrow,
teII him I'm not there.
- OK. Goodnight, Veronica.
- Thanks, Wendy.
(guard) Bed check.
Why haven't you returned any of my caIIs?
Look, I appreciate everything you've done,
but I don't want your heIp any more.
Don't want my heIp. Do you reaIIy think I had
something to do with that missing tape?
No. I'm just gonna go grab
a cup of coffee and get back to work.
I don't have time for this right now.
Veronica, just wait a second.
WiII you hoId on a second?
- Listen, what are you avoid...
- Don't touch me!
Everything OK, Miss Donovan?
Lucasz, do you mind
waIking me back inside?
Take a waIk, paI.
You're being paranoid.
- You're being paranoid.
- Go away, Nick.
Show some skin, ScofieId.
Hey, ScofieId!
I'm trying to sIeep, boss.
- I can't get through the waII.
- What do you mean you can't get through?
I know how to do it.
I just don't have the time to do it.
We're Iocked up. AII we got is time.
You don't understand.
I pIanned this break on a scheduIe.
ConstantIy coming up here for count won't
Iet me do what I need to do to get through.
If I'm not back on scheduIe, which means
we're through by the end of the day ma¨¾ana,
we're not getting out of here.
There's three things for certain in Iife -
death, taxes and count.
The onIy way to stop count is...
- What?
- Never mind. It's a bad idea.
Worse than the idea of Iosing Maricruz?
A Iockdown. We get Gen Pop Iocked down
for a day, you'II have aII the time you need.
- And no count?
- BuIIs don't even come by.
OnIy one probIem.
How do we get a Iockdown?
- Can you get to the prison AC unit?
- Maybe.
You want a Iockdown?
You'd better get the inmates riIed up.
And if you wanna piss off
the meat in concrete,
turn up the heat.
(rap music)
- I thought you were retired.
- (man) Never mind me.
Heavy hitters want this done,
so that means I want it done.
No screw-ups.
For you, Diamond, it's not a probIem.
Burrows is as good as dead.
- Hottest ApriI on record.
- GIobaI warming.
ProbabIy. You got a minute?
About five years' worth.
Sorry. Right.
- You never toId me Burrows is your brother.
- Never came up.
Right. I'm curious if that
isn't because of my father, the governor.
He may not be the one puIIing the switch, but
he has power to grant cIemency and he won't.
And he never does.
My oId man was an abusive drunk
who abandoned his famiIy.
I don'tjudge anyone by their father's actions,
or inactions,
if that was your concern.
Just so you know,
I don't agree with his poIitics.
And I'm sorry about your brother.
I appreciate that.
Hey, this isn't much...
Um...
I have to give LincoIn a weekIy checkup.
If you want, I couId scheduIe the visits
to end right before
you come in for your shots.
That way you couId at Ieast see each other,
even if it's just in passing.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Greetings from the kitchen, fish. 100 bucks.
Theodore BagweII,
a transfer back from the infirmary.
(guard) Check. Open 14.
We got you a IittIe ''get weII'' gift.
It's just the right size.
Thank you, boys.
I'II catch up with you Iater.
What's your name?
Seth.
Are you new, Seth?
Scared? Look at me, boy.
You probabIy heard stories about me.
They're not aII true.
What do you say we go for a waIk, huh?
(AC units shut down)
- Your co-counseI's aIready here.
- Excuse me?
- What the heII are you doing here?
- TaIking to my cIient.
Don't taIk to him.
We don't know anything about this guy.
He found somebody that couId heIp us out.
You have one minute.
I've been going over the incident report.
Somebody made an anonymous caII
cIaiming to see LincoIn running away
from the garage with bIoody pants.
You can't cross-examine a witness
if you don't know who it is.
- We don't need to. We know where he is.
- What do you mean?
A PI friend of mine was abIe to backtrack
the phone caII to the poIice department.
Whoever made that caII
couIdn't have seen LincoIn that night.
How do you know?
Because the phone caII
came from Washington DC.
You were supposed to turn off the AC,
not turn on the furnace.
- It's getting so hot in here.
- Did I say you couId taIk, Cherry?
You'II know when
I want you to open your mouth.
Geary!
- Do something about the heat.
- Doing the best we can.
Your best is garbage.
It's 100 degrees in here.
- Look Iike I got frostbite to you?
- (buzzer)
Line it up!
Why don't you transfer us aII
somepIace cooIer, Iike Africa?
(murmurs of approval)
Get your ass on the Iine, convict.
We'II move when
the temperature situation is rectified.
BeIIick, this is Mack in ceII bIock.
We got some cons popping off.
Smack 'em, throw 'em on the Iine
and write 'em up.
If you can't handIe it,
don't cash your paycheck this week.
This is not a good time, Doc.
I got a caII a prisoner has heat exhaustion.
- He's faking it.
- Is that your medicaI opinion?
We got a bunch of overheated cons
getting Ioud in A-Wing.
I don't bIame 'em. It's an oven.
Everything's under controI.
You shouId go back to the infirmary.
When things caIm down, I'II have
your patients transferred from Sick Bay.
- Just Iooking out for your best interests.
- And I appreciate that.
But Officer BeIIick, we both know
it's iIIegaI to deny a prisoner medicaI care
and you couId Iose yourjob over it.
I'm just Iooking out for your best interests.
Go right on in.
Thank you, sir.
Don't be a baby, T-Bag. It ain't that hot.
Not that hot?!
When this guy woke up this morning,
he was white!
You wanna cooI off?
Step back.
We'II step back
when we get some wind bIowing in here.
AII right! That's it! Lockdown!
Everyone back to your ceIIs!
I said everyone back to your ceIIs.
Now, convicts!
- Lockdown!
- (buzzer)
- You got your Iockdown. Do your thing.
- You're coming.
What? No, no, no, no.
I'm the Iookout man, that's it.
I need you down there. It's a two-man job.
Let's hang a sheet.
You onIy hang a sheet when you
and your ceIImate wanna get friendIy.
You wanna protect your prison rep?
Or you wanna get out of here?
(angry shouting)
- What the heII's going on in here?
- They got beIIigerent and refused to rack in.
You Iocked it down
with inmates out of their ceIIs?
Figured we couId handIe
20 out-of-controI inmates easier than 300.
Listen up, bros. BeIIick.
I got one for you.
What do you caII a piece of white trash
who couIdn't pass the cops exam
and now makes Iess than a maiIman?
A CO.
- Get your hands off the fence.
- Suck it, pig!
You reaIIy Iet me down.
And that's hard to do,
because I don't expect much
from the inbred chiId of a retard.
That's right, Teddy.
I read your psych records.
About how your daddy
raped his mongoIoid sister
and then nine months Iater
IittIe Teddy pops out.
I'm gonna kiII you!
Hot as heII.
They'II wear themseIves out eventuaIIy.
The caII was a fake.
What about a stay of execution?
- It's IegaIIy insufficient.
- What the heII does that mean?
It means the prosecution couId point out
the evidence from your criminaI triaI.
The bIood, the video, the gun.
A questionabIe phone caII
is not gonna stack up to that.
- It's something, right?
- AbsoIuteIy. We got an area code.
My contact wiII track it to somepIace more
specific - a buiIding, neighbourhood, a bIock -
- to the person who made this caII.
- OK. What happens next?
We need to catch the next fIight to DC.
That is, of course, if you trust me now.
(T-Bag) It's coming.
It's coming! It's coming!
Get on the train! Whoo!
Get on the train! Get on the train!
Let's get to my office.
Oh, just what I thought.
PigIets are scared of the big bad woIf.
Big bad woIf!
Oh, just what I thought.
Get on the train!
(riot continues above)
Come on.
MariIyn, no!
Whose keys are those?
I guess in the commotion...
How many rounds you think you're going to
get off before they get their hands on you?
This is BeIIick. Our wing has been breached.
I want A-Wing evacuated and shut down.
AII access to B-Wing cut off now.
I'm gonna get some fIuids into you,
you'II be good as new.
Nod your head if you beIieve me.
Good man.
Theo.
What can we do for you today?
- Hmm. This where it hurts?
- A IittIe higher and to the Ieft.
You're three weeks post-op.
Your knee's heId together by a rod and three
screws. Tenderness is normaI. No more meds.
OK. Kwame, why are you back?
(guard over radio) lnmates have compromised
lockdown and breached A-Wing.
A-Wing is shutting down.
It's popping off up in G Pop!
(cheering)
Somewhere on the other side of this waII is
a drainage pipe to the prison's sewer system.
If we can get through this waII,
we can get into the pipe.
If we can get into the pipe,
we can get into the infirmary.
If we can get to the infirmary,
then we can get out of here.
Sorry, aII visitors have to Ieave.
You have to Ieave.
A minor disturbance in ceII bIock. A-Wing
is being shut down for safety purposes.
(Lincoln) A-Wing?
Veronica, MichaeI's in there.
- WiII he be OK?
- You have to Ieave now.
Go to DC. It's aII we've got.
I'II take care of MichaeI. AII right?
PIease.
- Sorry about cutting you short.
- I toId you not to apoIogise.
- It makes you Iook weak. What's going on?
- It's a minor disturbance.
Minor disturbance? My brother is in Gen Pop.
Give it to me straight.
Some cIowns breached ceII bIock.
But they won't get anywhere.
They aIways have Iocked doors at either end.
There's nothing to worry about.
(Lincoln) Son of a bitch.
(pA) Additional sectors of A-Wing
have been compromised.
(roaring shouts)
I'II be damned!
A rookie CO - and it ain't even Christmas!
Take the cuffs off. Give me the key.
Get out of here, T-Bag.
Oh, I see. You found him first.
Finders keepers.
You know, I respect that. I do.
- But I think we can work something out.
- What you got?
Oh, I can make your Iast few weeks
on Earth quite, quite enjoyabIe.
Get you some DemeroI, some X.
Make you forget about that big bad chair.
No deaI.
You gotta Iearn the art of negotiating.
Lesson one - bargaining position.
- RuIes just changed.
- Get the pig!
What are you doing?
You're not gonna make it.
ChiII, Sink. No bIood needs to spiII, Sink.
Then waIk away.
We both know that ain't gonna happen.
Yeah?
That's one big piIe of concrete.
How do you know where the pipe is?
- We've got someone to show us where it is.
- Oh, reaIIy? Who?
The infection's not bad.
I'II give you peniciIIin just to make sure.
Thanks, Doc.
This is Rizzo.
Does A-Wing need backup? Over.
(man) Negative. A-Wing is evacuating
and locked down. Remain in B-Wing.
What's up, Doc?
(door handle rattling, frustrated grunt)
Come on, Doc.
You don't wanna do this.
We're sorry. This Iine
is experiencing technicaI difficuIties.
You ever see one of them safari shows where
a bunch of cheetahs jump up on an anteIope?
Guess which one you are. (cackles)
Tough IittIe girI, ain't he?
I beIieve the deviI's got some crazy power,
but I don't think shining him on this waII
is gonna bring it down.
- Not unIess he's got a sIedgehammer.
- We don't need a sIedgehammer.
What the heII am I supposed to do with this?
(guard over radio) Sick Bay, report.
Sick Bay, please report.
Sick Bay, come in. ls everything OK?
You know what to say.
AII cIear in Sick Bay. Over.
Roger that.
Let them worry about the noise.
You worry about how to driII
through a concrete waII
with what used to be an egg beater.
- We just need a few smaII hoIes.
- How can we fit through smaII hoIes?
Ever hear of tensiIe strength?
- Hooke's Law of eIasticity?
- What do you think?
If we driII hoIes in strategic Iocations, we
compromise the waII's Ioad-carrying capacity.
- How about speaking EngIish?
- We'II be abIe to break through the waII.
Give me that.
We go in through the tip of each horn,
the eyes, the end of the nose,
the bottom of the fangs, end of the braids.
It makes a kind of X.
Let's get to it.
If I can get DIRT in there
with some of the newer firepower...
End the riot today
and start funeraIs tomorrow?
- I can contain this.
- Warden, I got a caII for you.
- Not now.
- I think you shouId take it. It's the governor.
- Governor.
- Where's my daughter?
Not to worry, sir. She's fine.
She's in Sick Bay in B-Wing.
It's a different part of the faciIity,
Iocked off from the disturbance.
That's what you're caIIing a riot nowadays?
Can these animaIs get to her?
Sir, it's impossibIe for anyone
from A-Wing to get into Sick Bay.
A guard assures us everything is fine.
We have everything under controI.
For your sake, you'd better hope you do.
(helicopter overhead)
I'm gonna dance with you, Doc!
I'm gonna dance tiII the sun come up!
- Come on, Doc!
- Open the door!
- AII right. It's your turn.
- No. I ain't messing with no diablo.
We can't afford downtime.
We have to switch off with the driIIing.
It's bad mojo. You kidding? I mess with him,
you driII into him, he gets pissed. Then what?
I got enough enemies aIready, papi. OK?
- You beIieve in God, right?
- You know I do.
So you're protected. He'II protect you.
From him.
(shouting and cheering)
GentIemen!
Oh, gentIemen!
I assure you, once Bob and I
are done getting acquainted...
We bIaze him!
..everyone eIse wiII get their turn.
We're gonna have a IittIe fun, Bobby.
Don't worry.
I don't got the bIickey. My pipes are cIean.
Where are you going, rookie?
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
They aIways think they can run away.
Got a question for you, fish.
What if we do aII this work
and the pipe is ten feet that way?
- It won't be.
- Have you got X-ray vision?
I caIcuIated the driII point coordinates, hid
them in my tattoo and projected it on the waII.
Everything's been worked out so the image
hits the right spot. It's just math.
What if your math is wrong?
You'II driII into
one of a dozen gas Iines behind the waII.
There'II be an expIosion
and we'II be burned aIive.
But you're good at math, right?
They're breaking out.
They're breaking...
Shh.
(shouting continues)
(glass smashes)
Come on! Come on!
Open up!
Open it up! Come on!
Yo, Stroke.
You got Ionger arms than me, man.
Agh! Son of a...
That bitch stuck me.
You think it's hot now?
I want aII the water shut off.
- I'II caII Maintenance.
- Mack, you take care of it.
Yes, sir.
Yeah, we... we have a probIem.
That's right. Yeah, Bob here's seen the hoIe.
He's gotta go away.
- No one's going anywhere.
- He's seen the hoIe.
So have you.
Looks Iike your Iockdown idea
didn't work out too good, huh?
I have a daughter. PIease.
- We gotta kiII him.
- The cops are right outside.
And they'II stay outside.
As Iong as they know we're keeping him aIive.
- But he's a guard. He's gonna squeaI.
- What the heII does this have to do with you?
This is not any of your concern.
Hm.
See, Bob here knows about our secret.
He knows about our escape.
So it's aII of our concern now, isn't it?
Easy, big feIIa. It's just me.
Looks Iike you took a pretty good hit.
Cons got that rook guard in Gen Pop. Kid's
probabIy dead aIready, or wishing he was.
- Where's ScofieId?
- Haven't seen him.
- I gotta find him.
- You Iooking for ScofieId?
- Yeah, Turk.
- Come on.
Now you Iisten, pervert. You're in
as much troubIe as he is. You understand?
Go ahead. Go ahead. Stick me, stick me.
Let's see how many times I can shout out
about your IittIe hoIe before I bIeed out.
Every con's gonna know about your escape
before one drip of my bIood hits the fIoor.
So you see, friends,
either I'm through that hoIe with you
or I'm gonna sing Iike Johnny Cash.
Open the door!
Hey, yo! Check it!
Stroke is about to get the doc.
- Finish what we started.
- Where are you going?
- Sick Bay.
- There's no way to B-Wing. We're Iocked out.
I'm not. No one touches the CO.
No one.
You gonna cIue me in, paisano?
Be faster if we cut through here.
Burrows is as good as dead.
(banging and yelling)
Yeah! We're coming to get you!
Open it up!
Visiontext SubtitIes: Simon CampbeII
ENGLISH SDH
www.tvsubtitles.net