Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Shared by http://DJJ.HOME.SAPO.PT/
Previously on Prison Break:
Sona's a one-way street.
What goes in
never comes out.
Since the riots of last year they left here us to rot.
They figured we would just destourselves,
but instead we've thrived.
How about we work together,you know,help each other out?
You're on your own.
Get me out of this! Yowant tYoknow
where she is,find a way
to get me out of this!
Maricruz... Maricruz.
We can assist you should you ever decide,
say,to break out of here.
This conversation's over.
We're trying to dohis the easy way
Think you can do me a favor?
We have a lot to discuss,Lincoln.
Specifically,your brother.
How are we coming with the transfer?
You got to stay. What are you talking about?
Dad,I'm so sorry.
They got me and Sara.
You got a week to find this Whistler guy.
Otherwise,they,uh,both die.
Where you from up there,bro?
Chicago.
Michael Jordan.
Yeah.
You meet him?
It's a big city.
Oh,yeah,big city.
Thanks for saving me a spot.
Hey!
Ejected!
You ever have sex with blond cheerleader?
Yeah,sure.
You're the man,bro.
How long's the water been out?
Since riots last year.
Government blame us.
They say,"Screw you,you break it."
No water.
Gracias.
Real quick.
There's an inmate here named James Whistler.
I'm looking for him.
Welcome to club.
Everybody looking for him.
Why's that?
He killed the mayor of Panama City's son.
In bar fight.
Mayor not happy.
Hey,hey.
So where is he now?
Disappear.
Some say he might even escape.
Hey. Hey!
"I don't have no money.
I don't have no money," that's all I hear from you,
you know that?
But then I see you with this,huh?
Life must be good,eh?
Look,I'm-I'm hungry,okay?
You worry about me being hungry.
Hey,hey,hey,hey,come on.
Come on!
But you eat all the time.
Okay,I can see you up there.
Hequilo!
There's gonna be more water.
When?!
I said there will be more water.
Later,bro.
Go.
Spare a little?
I need some information.
Absolutely.
You slipped this note in my pocket yesterday.
Why?
My memory's a little foggy on account of this thirst.
Yeah,it's starting to come back to me now.
A little more agua there.
The note.
This guy gave me some rat meat in exchange for putting that
in your pocket and the pocket of the guy you were set to fight.
Why?
He's nuts,that's why.
Anybody who can live down in those sewers
doesn't have all his faculties.
Where in the sewers?
Whistler!
Whistler.
My name is Michael Scofield.
I was sent to get you out of here.
I'm going to assume they told you I was coming.
Or that someone was coming.
Whistler.
Last chance.
I'm not coming down here again.
You're here to get me out of Sona.
Are you surprised?
It's just that it's gonna be a bit difficult
getting me out of this hole.
Seeing as if I go above ground
and another inmate spots me,
I'm a dead man.
-TThere's a,there's a slight misunderstanding
that I have with the mayor...
You know what? It's none of my business.
I'll come back and get you when the time is right.
I may not make it that long.
That's your problem,my friend.
I've got problems of my own.
So you work for these people?
The ones that want me out of Sona.
Lookjust stay put.
As loI'll be back.knows you're here,y Why do they want me
out of here so badlyso can you at least tell me that?
Is this the part where you etend re innocent?
Just a pawn in all this?
If they told you anything about me before you came here,
you'd know that to be true.
I just want to know what they want with me.
Stay put.
In an effort to save some time,I'm gonna have
to insist that we just
skip right past all the threats I know
you're prepared to layout.
Should anything happen to Sara to LJ,
you will scour the Earth and hunte down
and rip my heart from my chest
and bup,bup,bup.
I absolutely know how you feel,
as would I,okay?
So that's done.
On to business.
Did you brother get the message?
Good. You and I will meet here every day.
I'll want a full report of the prior day's progress.
When I call your cell phone,answer.
Don't ask me stupid questions.
Don't waste my time.
Get a plan together.
Execute it.
LJ and Sara will be traded for Whistler.
Are we clear?
I want a picture of my son and Sara to prove they're alive.
OX Fine. I can do that,next.
Why us?
I'll answer that question
so we can put it to bed and you can focus on your work.
There's a political spotlight on Whistler
due to the nature of his crime.
Ras,bribes,what have you,
are not an option.
We have to go in through  door,so to speak.
This can't be done in a week.
You have a week. That's it.
Are we clear?
What's your name?
Susan B. Anthony.
I'm assuming you weren't
born by immaculate conception.
You're right,Lincoln.
Family trees being what they are,
moms,dads,brothers,sisters.
Anything happens to my son or Sara,
I'm not coming after you,Susan.
Get to work.
His man knocks over the water!
Now,didn't you see how Lechero just walked away?!
He doesn't care about us!
He doesn't give a damn!
Living like a king up there!
(speaking gibberish)
Come out,what are you,afraid?!
Come on!
Lechero,come out!
Por favor.
Por favor. Vete.
Vete,perro.
Why you so interested about that guy down there?
No reason.
Then why you whispering,college boy?
Why don't you lower your voice already?
What's in it for me? I'm sorry.
Do you have any other friends in here besides me?
I'm it.
Friends don't t friends go hungry and thirsty All right.
All right. and damn near half-naked.
I said "all right;" I'll take care of it! When?
When I can.
What's the big deal?
Why's he hiding?
Who's he hiding from?
Mayor get message to Lechero
saying if Whistler guy gets killed here in Sona,
whoever kills him gets to go to court,
gets to see a judge.
Judge friendly with mayor.
Kill him,and-and
then you get to get out of here and be free?
That's what Lechero say.
This'll stay between me and you.
If your friend wanted you to know,why didn't he tell you?
'Cause... 'cause you and I are friends now.
Unless you want to be enemies.
Fries.
Good. Me,too.
Sucre?
Sucre,get me out of here,please.
Where's Maricruz?
Yeah.
Yeah,Maricruz-- she's good,she's okay,
but-but I'm not telling you anything
until you get me out of here.
Tell me where she is right now!
You shoot me,you'll end up inside this hellhole.
WA I'm done.
I don't care anymore.
I can only guess she's dead by now,
so you're dying with her. (gun cocks)
I never had her!
At that house in Mexico,
I chased your aunt and Maricruz off.
I told them I'd lock 'em up
for accessory if they didn't hightail it.
I swear to God.
And the crucifix?
I ripped it off
Maricruz before she ran.
There was no phone in that dump,so I knew you wouldn't
be able to call from t road to...
to make sure I wasn't lying.
I-I conned you.
So...
She's picking grapes.
I have no idea.
Now,just lower the barrel.
Put the gun down.
Now,I came clean with you and helped you out,
right,buddy?
Soou got to return the favor.
Call my mom in Joliet-- Edna Bellick.
She's listed. Sucre?
I never la a hand on Maricruz.
I would never do that!
Sucre,help me,please!
Sucre,help me!
Help me!
Hey.
You find Whistler?
Yeah.
What's his story?
I don't know,and maybe
it's better that way,huh?
I just got
to get him out of here,right?
Come on,man,come on.
We got to keep moving,we got to keep moving.
What's the next play?
Whistler got a note out
on a dead body yesterday.
I don't know what it means or who it's for.
But we need all the leverage we can get,
and,uh...
I need some money.
ne'sver brok out leale wi a  thisweeko pl i
so...
u tell theseple,veit is thatook Sara
and  nhew...
you tellm I get it,
and m going  do everytng I can.
I'm going to break this guy out of here,
or I'm going to die trying.
And if it's the latter,
then that should count for something,rightg,
That's got to count for something.
You tell them that.
I will.
Tell them.
I'd trade places with you in a second.
I know.
Whistler?
You're not safe here.
I can take you someplace that is.
Fhmhm
Sucre?
Linc!
What are you doing here?
Michael's locked up.
For what?
I don't know.
I'm sorting it through.
(sighs)
I could use
your help.
We're in a... we're
in a bad spot.
UhI feel for you, man, b I
to my cousin Peteye Mariuz.I st talked
d he told me
e's back or in Chicago.
Hey, youe still wanted
in Chicago, remember?
I'll figure meing out.
All right.
If you changyour
mind, I'm staying at
the Plaza del Sol.
I won't. I'm-I'm out
of here, bro.
I'm going to go see my girl.
Listen to me. The innocent
people in your life--
you got to keep them innocent--
if that means walking away
from them, that's what
you got to do.
Good luck, Linc.
VERSAILLES  1989  V,MADRID
Banco de Versailles,
por favor.
Have we had our laughs
with him yet?
(Wyatt shouting in distance)
He's useless, man.
You want to get rid of him?
Huh? Then you cut
the mango. Huh?
You caused me
a big, big problem
out there today!
You understand that?
Now there's
no more water.
They'll live.
(distant shouting)
Oh, yeah?
They'll live?
Yeah? Well,
you tell them that, then.
WYATT:
Hey, come out,
Your Majesty.
Teodoro!
WYATT:
Are you scared of...
There's ter here.
Give each man a little, hey?
onc
WYATT:
Thngs ve tir
ads choppe
Hey, Lechero!
Don't worry about us!
We're fine!
He may have rulethe streets
out there,
but inere,
's just
like !like us.
Come out
What, are
Co and look at maid?
me on!
Lecher come t.
The Ameran in hisunderwea-
T-Bag.
Boy, you're going
to be drinking your own urine
before you get any of this.
I just need to speak
to Seor Lechero, please?
Why don't you do yourself
a favor-- scamper.
But I got something.
Oh, yeah.
You got yourself
the untouchable status.
Get myself killed just talking
to your mangy ass.
Andale.
But I got information.
Good information.
Are you out of
your mind, huh?
Hey! Hey! Hey!
He's got info.
Pick a... pick a kneecap, huh?
BELLICK:
I got information!
I just want food and clothing.
Patron, please.
Hold on. Hold on!
This better be
informative.
Or it's your kneecap next.
This morning, before that whole,
uh, water thing,
I, I heard you
and the lads talking
about that Whistler character,
how no one's found him.
Well...
I just want food and clothing...
Just tell him, idiot!
BELLICK:
There's a guy hiding
down in the sewers.
I-I figure he's hiding
from you, right,
because you run
this place, right?
And so I figured you'd want
to know everything
goes on here,
so...
Fine, shut up.
It just might be Whistler,
si, patron?
Si?
Is he Australian?
Yeah.
Yeah!
Courtesy of the Lechero's
munificence.
All right, now, y'all need
to back up a tad now.
Hey.
How long you been
in Sona?
McGRADY:
Three years.
How old are you?
Seventeen.
And as far as you know,
no one's ever broken out
of this place except,
uh... except maybe
this Whistler guy?
You Americans ask a
lot of questions.
(softly):
Oh, no.
What's wrong?
Come on.
Please.
Come on!
I have a family.
S-So do I.
Come on.
Stop!
Stop, okay?
Just...
he is come on with me
Just back up,
Michael. Just...
You don't actually think
that killing somebody
is going to help you getut
of here, do you?
That does seem pretty strange,
doesn't it?
But this is
a really strange place,
one I want to get out of.
Then I'll help you.
I'll testify for you,
whatever it takes.
Wow.
Wow, look at that halo
that just appeared
above your head.
It's amazing.
I don't have a choice, Alex...
What'd you tell me
yesterday?
What did you tell me
Huh? "You're on your own, Alex."
Back up. Back up!
You...
you don't want this.
Let me help you, Alex. A
WYATT:
Hey, your majesty!
You got
to shut him up.
I need this bolson
to call me back.
I need to talk
to you.
Don't ever
walk in here
thout being called!
I'm sorry.
But it's worth the breach
in etiquette.
Is it now?
I thought you could use my help.
There are ways I can be
of assistance.
不知道说什么  自己听
Whistler don't mean
nothing to me, man.
I have five consecutive life
sentences-- I ain't coming out
of Sona no time soon.
And why should I deprive
other men of chance at freedom?
Huh?
I need you to trust me.
Oh.
Trust you?
I don't know you good enough,
brother.
Teodoro.
Si, patron?
Can I trust this bobo?
He's a snake.
He stabbed me
in the back every chance he got.
A whst a m t back.
ner hear
such a creature before.
We got to op this!
Just give me two more minutes.
Leave now!
Leave!
WYATT:
Crumbs!
That's what you're giving us!
Your crumbs!
Hey, Lechero,
how's your
television?
(laughing):
How's your whore?ho
Come on,
what are you scared of?
Hey.
I need some, uh,
some moonshine.
Moonshine?
Or some alcol.
Booze.
Booze, yeah.
I need it now.
A liter or a gallon--
whatever you can get
your hands on.
It's not good time
for party, bro.
Bring it to me
in my cell.
Vera Vera
The women's been waiting for you
Thank you
Vera Madrid
I hope you haven't been waiting long
Sofia Lugo
I'm James Whistler's girlfriend
You're a signatory on his account
Wait here
he's beautiful
Thank you
My girlfriend's pregnant
Oh  congratulations
I'm going...
Can i help you?
No thank you .I'm good
Cause it looked like you needed something
No
I'm just waiting for the bus
Vamonos.
Come on, Whistler.
Whistler, stop!
Stop!
What are you...
Whistler...
Just come up
top with me.
You got
a better chance coming up
with me.
At least you can plead your case
to Lechero.
Just get...
Go to hell.
Just...
His best batch,
he say.
It's fine.
I'm going to need
some plastic bags.
You didn't get it for to party,
did you?
Plastic bags,
as many as you can get.
I'll make it worth your while,
I e.
This is it?
That's it
If you could just sign for it
Gracias.
Yospk EYeah.Excuse m
We've me
I mean I saw you
yestenaay at, uh,
Yeah.
You know, uh,
you could lose the whole
grieving widow thing.
You're Whistler's
girl, right?
I'm sorry, I have
to be somewhere.
I've got, uh, I got to
do something, all right?
Do what?
Give me that back
or I'll call
the police.
You're not going to
call the police.
Why does he want this?
I don't know.
He's just a fisherman.
A fisherman?
Well, tell your fisherman
friend...
tell your fisherman friend
Scof 's brother just have this
Why won't you people just leave him
alone?!
You think we want to
be forced into this?
You think we want
to be here, lady?
Forced into what?
What are you talking about?
All right,
hold this.
Hold it.
Watch the hallway
for me.
I'm friends with
everybody here, bro.
That's how I keep alive.
You and I are friends, right?
Yeah, but looks like
you got enemies.
What I did for you,
getting you those
things...
No one will ever know.
ALL (chanting):
Lechero! Lechero!
Stand up, stand up.
Stand up.
(coughing)
Come on.
Back up! Back up.
You can have him,
but two of you will die
in the process.
You first? You first. I'll wrap
this right around your head.
Move. Move!
CROWD (chanting):
Lechero!
Lechero! Lechero!
Enough!
Let me go down there.
Let me cut just one throat.
Just one.
They'll quiet down, man.
T-BAG:
And then regroup later
with a real reason
to come after you.
Shut your mouth.
LECHERO:
He's right,Sammy.
Lechero! Lechero!
Lechero!
So, what we going
to d
We just going
to sit up here,
hope they run
out of rocks?
Lechero!
LECHERO:
We have a
problem.
MAN:
What is it?
Ran out of water.
So, you mean
you've got a problem.
Look, there was
an accident here.
The tank tip over.
My men need water, man.
I'll see if I can get the water
truck there day after tomorrow.
No, I need water now!
I guess it's too bad
there's no guards
in there anymore with you, huh?
You could
hostages, have a riot,
make demands.
Day aftertomorrow.
Lechero...!
You call me and you raise
youroice at me like that
again, you're not going
to see water for two weeks.
Hmm? Entendido?
he got Whisler
LECHERO:
Enough!
Now, I'll decide this!
You'll decide nothing.
You can't
deliver, Lechero.
You're done here.
t
Now what?
What do we do?
You've been outbid.
Wait. What are
you talking about?
What are you ta...?
What are you
talking...?
That's, uh, very useful.
Very useful.
And Whistler's clear?
Yeah.
Clear as the blue sky, brother.
MARICRUZ:
Hello?
Baby, it's me.
Oh, my God.
Oh, I... I've been so scared,
I've been praying
every day.
I did, too, babe.
I just thank God you're okay.
Petey called me
after he had talked to you,
and he said that you might
)  coming back here?
That's what I told him.
Yeah.
You have to be so careful.
Baby,
I've been thinking, and, um,
the only thing that I...
about right now
is that isu
t and e ba are oy.
That's all that matters to me.
I'm not coming back.
It's not because
I don't love you, because
you know I do--
I love you more...
I love you more than anything,
but... all I do
is bring you down.
I'm no good for you.
That's not true,
that's not true.
Oh, it is, it is, it is, and...
sometimes the only way
to protect the people
that you love
is... is by staying away
from them.
One day when i get my life together
however long that takes--
I'll find you.
I'll find you, and, uh,
and I'll make you
and our baby proud.
Te lo prometo.
Te lo prometo, mi amor.
I wish we could go back.
I would give anything
to go back.
I wish that, too.
I wish that, too, baby.
I love you so much, baby.
I love you, too, baby.
Good-bye.
(quietly):
Bye.
You know, they told
me that your brother
got all the brains,
but I didn't realize
you were this stupid.
What do you want, Susan?
No sooner do I tell you
to stick to the plan,
than you go and hassle
Whistler's girlfriend.
You need to quit
playing Sherlock Holmes
and leave her alone.
Why?
'Cause I said so.
w about that?
All right.
How about you beat it,
so I can get to work?
I will
as soon as you give me
what you took from her.
I took nothing from her.
I got a gallon
of bleach, a tarp and a hacksaw
in the trunk of my car.
One hour, tops--
you're off the face
of the earth.
It's just a bird guide.
I am not going to ask you again.
Toss it.
Tomorrow-- bar.
Progress report.
I will be waiting.
Sot's water you want.
Here's your water.
Thank you.
So, how are we
getting out of here?
I have no idea.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
www.tvsubtitles.net