Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Shared by http://DJJ.HOME.SAPO.PT/
Previously on Prison Break.
I just want to go.
It's okay.
MAHONE:
What special talents
do you have
that the Company
might make the decision
that you are worth more
to them alive than dead?
Be careful, Alex.
- Were you able to find my book?
- Yeah.
But there was this guy.
He took it.
He said to tell you
that Scofield's
brother has it now.
MICHAEL:
You have to break them out
of there.
LJ!
Sara!
SUSAN B.:
You're never going to try
anything like that again.
But just to make sure,
I left you a little something
in the garage.
What's so interesting out there,
other than our freedom?
Vine's alive, so the fence
is dead. No current.
WHISTLER:
Yeah? Everyone in here knows
that fence doesn't work,
and it doesn't mean
a bloody thing,
because there are soldiers
out there
that'll shoot you dead before
you get within 30 yards of it.
Well, I guess I got a lot
of work to do, don't I?
Listen, mate, I get
what you're doing with my book.
They hold your girlfriend,
you hold what they want.
Countering needs.
Churchill 101.
Soon those bastards
are going to ask me
what progress I've made in
figuring out what they want,
and I'm going to say nil, 'cause
Lincoln Burrows has the book.
You know what?
Threatening the brother
of the guy who's supposed
to get you out of here
might not be the smartest move.
I'm not threatening--
we're on the same team.
But if we play games
with that book,
people who want me out of here
will take action against us all.
"I never worry about action,
only inaction."
Churchill 101.
Now, like I said,
I got a lot of work to do.
Linc, you alright?
I'm sorry, man.
Just all this stuff--
it's starting to get to me.
You know?
Listen, our situation could
change very, very soon.
The grave digger for the prison.
I need you to reach out to him.
And tell him what?
It's all written down.
But we got to
get started now.
What are you
not telling me?
All these people
that have been hurt
because of me.
You know, it's...
I'm so sorry, Michael.
They did this, not you.
Okay?
It's not your fault.
(sighs)
Just get to the grave digger.
I feel like we're
running out of time.
Sara...
www.opensubtitles.org
Prison Break
Season 03 Episode 04
I am just a soldier
in this war, Lincoln,
just like you.
I did not want
to do that.
Can you even comprehend
the intimacy
of the mechanics of what
I had to do to that woman?
It's horrible!
Now, if you and your brother
are done playing games,
LJ will be fine.
If not, the last thing
I want to do
is start mailing pieces
of him to you.
But if you push me,
and not even that far, I will.
I'll do anything you want.
Just don't hurt my son.
That's really up to you.
I know the past few days
have been hard,
for me, as well.
If you want to talk about it,
I know
what this pain feels like.
I just want to get
your boy out of Sona
and get my son back.
Michael's got a plan.
I need details.
We need to
bring someone
who works at the prison
onto the team.
- Who?
- The grave digger.
Get it done.
Lincoln, I'm going
to need that book.
The Company did handwriting
analysis on the one you gave me,
and yours hasn't changed
since high school.
Just soldiers, Linc.
Different armies,
but soldiers just the same.
Nice.
I was the best
in my school.
All-girls?
(Laughs)
Kiss my ass,bro.
20 bucks says
you can't do that again.
- Bet.
- Wait.
Adjust for wind.
Shut up.
Just a bit outside.
Hey, bro, you know I don't have
that kind of verde lying around.
It's going to
take a while.
Well, the thing is,
I don't have a while.
- So, unless...
- No, no more favors.
All right.
Can I borrow
that cross of yours?
- I'll take it in trade.
- My dad gave me this.
Besides, it's not
even real gold.
That's why I need it.
Look, I'll give it back, okay?
It's just for awhile.
Come on.I got to go.
This time,
I want to know why.
It's light again.
Someone's getting fat off
of everything I built
while I rot in here.
MARY:
Don't get upset, Patrón.
I only have
a few more hours.
Let's be nice.
This motherless bitch.
Alex?
(Gasps)
You just get here?
Yes.
Listen,
I've been thinking
about our little talk,
and, uh, you're in.
I'm in.
Okay.
- Just like that?
- Right.
I really don't have a choice,
do I?
What's the plan?
I'm working on it.
Meanwhile,
I could use your help.
What do you need?
A black felt-tipped pen.
- A pen?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- Some documents
that need altering.
I'll explain it to you later,
but right now, I need that pen.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
And I'll tell you
what else I need.
I need you to get
your act together.
I need you to bring yourself
under control, because
you're attracting attention,
and that, we don't need.
I'm under control.
Of course you are.
MAN:
This is what happens when
a system is overloaded.
See? Look.
- Son of a...
- Power is out.
Fix it.
I'm a truck driver.
Hey, Alex.
Hey, glad I found ya.
Just wanted to see how
- you're holding up in here.
- Just dandy.
Yeah, well, I've been having
a tough time of it myself.
And I was figuring, it
shouldn't be that way
for us, seeing as how
we're the only lawmen here
in Taco Hell.
Hey, whoa,
hang on a second there, Alex.
You and me--
we were a team
on the outside,
remember?
I was your dog, and
I still got a lot
of bark left in me.
I'm busy, Brad.
What do you want?
You and Scofield-- you're
up to something, right?
You can tell me, one
badge to another.
I can help.
Do you have a black
felt-tipped pen?
Not on me.
Then you can't help me.
I know.
You know what?
I know you're trying
to escape from here
with that man, Scofield.
- Sweetheart...
- Please, don't lie to me.
Lincoln Burrows, he
told me everything.
There are some very powerful
people that want me out of here.
- And they want those
brothers to get me out.
- Why?
I'm not sure.
Has something to do
with a charter I did in Seattle.
What I do know
is their end game
is exactly the same as ours, and
that's me out of this hellhole.
And once that happens,
you and I will
disappear... forever.
But I don't want
to involve you in this mess.
I want to help.
That's way too dangerous.
I'm not asking
your permission, James.
I'm telling you.
I can do this on my own,
or you can tell
me what you know
and we can work it
through together.
I don't understand everything
that's going on,
but these brothers,
they're obviously trying
to find out what
they can about me.
Let's see what we can
discover about them.
Find out what their plan is,
see what they're all about.
They're trying to get you out,
and you don't trust them?
I don't trust any of these guys.
And you shouldn't, either.
If you insist
on getting into this,
promise me you'll be careful.
Because God
knows I will die
if anything happens to you.
Hey.
MAHONE: Michael.
Here.
I said I need a
black felt-tipped pen.
That's black.
It's not what I need.
Keep looking.
He's playing you.
Do not trust him.
Your amigo, the American.
He's a builder,
an engineer, no?
He's no amigo
of mine, boss.
And trust me,
you do not want
to get under the covers
with that...
Is he or is he not an engineer?
Well, yeah, but...
Scofield.
Yeah?
What do you know
about the electricity?
Only that we don't
have any right now.
Let me tell you something.
This phone keeps all the food
coming to the gate.
It keeps my business running,
it keeps Sona running.
Electricity die,
phone die.
- Phone die, we die.
- We die or you die?
Boy, you have enough
education, but you're
not being smart.
Now, I come to you,
that is an opportunity.
Be wise and
take advantage.
Now, can you fix the electricity
just like you
fixed the water?
It's not that simple.
The water pipes
are inside the prison.
The electrical lines are
probably running underground
along an exterior wall,
which means
they're out there somewhere
in no-man's-land.
So, you can fix the power?
Last I checked, they shoot
prisoners who go out there.
So I'm thinking
the answer is "No".
You listen to me,
and you listen closely,
water boy.
Like it or not,
soldiers or not,
You're going out
into no-man's-land.
MICHAEL:
It's a suicide mission.
LECHERO:
I'll make some calls.
- And you're going to
keep me safe?
- As best I can.
I don't think
I can do this.
No, no, no, no, no.
You will help me with this.
Look, I will do
something for you.
I'll get you a new pillow,
goose-feather like mine,
or a small TV.
All right.
Get me that.
- Why?
- It's the first one to get
sunlight in the morning.
You get me that cell,
I'll get you electricity.
Hey, Linc.
Look, bro, um, I'm going to be
out of your way real soon.
I saw these flyers for
migrant workers in Colombia.
It's coffee bean season,
and they're letting
Panamanians in,
so I figure,
with a good ID, I can pass.
Bus leaves today, okay?
All right, well, before you
get out of here, man, I...
I'm meeting someone,
and I need a translator.
Linc, uh... I appreciate
everything you've done...
It'll just be a couple hours.
Just a couple hours,
that's it.
When I was 15, my cousin told me
about a job that only lasts
a few hours and, uh,
I got three months in juvie.
I can't do this without you.
I'm in Panama,
I don't speak the language...
And I can't miss that bus.
I'm going to make money
and send it home.
Underground or not,
I'm going to be a dad, Linc,
and you out of all people
should understand that.
(Knock at door)
I spoke to James.
He confirmed what you told me
about the escape.
You and I,
we both have people in there
we care about.
Please... let me help you.
Your Spanish as good
as your English?
LECHERO:
Yes, Colonel.
I just have one favor to ask.
It's just outside
of the gate.
You, you can bring your men.
The phone is dying.
Make him one.
This is it?
Not everyone has it yet.
We let credit go a week,
and there is still time.
The money's in your
veins, addicto.
No, patrón. I don't use anymore.
I swear to you.
I swear to you
Chin up,
pal o' mine, Chin up.
Sí, Colonel.
Yes, thank you, Colonel.
We'll be right there.
Come with me.
Excuse me.
Do you, um...
Do you have a-a, a pen?
Pen. Pen. Not, um...
Not... not the brush
but the pen. Pen. Pen.
No,  pintura.
Yeah, yeah, pintura. Yeah.
He's leaving you.
He's leaving you,
he'll be gone,
and you'll be stuck
in this maze... forever.
Thank you for arranging
this for us, Colonel.
I'm getting something
out of this as well,
I assure you.
You know you can fix
this electric problem?
I won't know for sure
until we can start digging,
but yes, I think so.
My men will
shoot you in the
back of the head
if you so much as
look at the fence, eh?
And you, patrón, if
anything goes wrong.
it will not only be
his life that is lost.
You have my word on that.
No worries, Colonel.
I'll keep this boy in line.
I'll dig.
I don't need your help.
Hey, come on, now,
don't be proud.
I heard you talking
just yesterday.
Talking to Mahone.
You know, about how
us Americans should
stick together.
So I help you now,
and I'm sure you'll
help me down the
road, right, Mikey?
What is it,
a '66 or a '67?
-Perdon
-Your car.
El quiere saber
el ano.
Este aqui
Pues, es un '66.
Yes mi preciosa.
'66.
Uh-huh.
What is it, 325 horses?
SOFIA:
Caballos de fuerza
375.
Perdon a me, señorita.
Mm-hmm.
- What's he saying?
- He recognizes me, but
he doesn't realize
it was at the prison.
Ask him does he want
to make enough cash
to get this car cherry
by next week?
He knows we're not
talking about cars.
That's right.
BELLICK:
Come on, Scofield, I know
you're getting out of here.
I heard it all about
you and the limey.
I'm just fixing the
electricity, Boss.
Yeah, right, and I'm just
single 'cause I'm choosy.
Don't make me tell
anyone what I know.
What is it you think you know?
Somebody called "The Company"
wanted you in here
to work with that
Whistler guy.
- Am I warm?
- What's the Company?
What do they want
with Whistler?
I don't know, but you do.
Doesn't sound like you
know much after all.
I don't need to know
how to change a diaper
to know when it
stinks to high hell.
You're doing something
here, Scofield.
You're right. I am.
I'm fixing the electricity.
Now, you wanted to help dig?
Dig.
Hey, this is it.
I assume we're doing more than
just than playing electrician.
Don't worry.
We're exactly
where we need to be.
Heat's getting to me, Scofield.
It's quitting time.
You mind telling me why he's
even out here with us?
He knows something's up.
How the hell does he know that?
Let's just say I have
a bit of a rep.
From Fox River?
I know who you are, mate.
Figured it out just lately.
Finally made sense
why they pick you
of all people to send here.
No worries.
It's in my interest to keep
your little secret.
But Bellick?
Can't be trusted.
I can handle Bellick.
He's not in on this.
Okay, good.
But Mahone is.
Mahone?
He's looking about as stable
as a three-legged chair,
and he's escaping with us?
No, he just thinks he is.
He needs his meds.
Without them,
he'll self destruct.
It's just a matter of time.
And if he doesn't?
I'll string him along,
tell him what he wants to hear,
and then I'll
cut him loose.
How do I know you're not going
to do the same thing to me?
You don't.
You need a hook-up,
my friend?
No.
Take your time.
I don't hard sell.
My product speaks
for itself.
Outside, I took something.
It's a prescription
drug called Varatril,
and I was
wondering if you...
This ain't no farmacia.
But what I got
right here...
it's better than
anything your doctor
gave you back
in the States.
That's tar.
Just take a taste,
algo pequenito.
You know, keep it in check.
I don't have any
money right now.
Then I don't have any drugs.
But there are a few
ways for a man
to make a few dollars in Sona thou...
servicing
the needs of others--
not something I'm into...
You think I'm a punk?!
I'm just helping you
get well, friend, just
helping you get well.
Señor Lechero?
Señor Lechero.
What do you want?
Look, I know you're a busy man,
but I wanted to tell ya,
I don't know exactly
what he's doing,
- but Michael Scofield's
taking you for a ride.
- No, cerdo,
I don't think so.
Listen, I heard him talking
about escape yesterday--
about breaking outta here.
- It's he's talking
about escape,
why are you here telling me and
you're not going with him, eh?
I would if he'd let me,
but he's already cut me out.
He says he's square,
but I know
the son of a bitch
is up to something.
So I figured,
if I ain't running,
I might as well tell you
and make my time in here
a little bit easier.
Every man fantasizes
about escaping from Sona.
Yeah, but they aren't all
in no-man's-land with shovels.
I'm gave him the shovels.
Get him out.
I gave him shovels too,
and guys to work with,
just like you.
I worked in the prison
he broke out of.
He said he was
doing me a favor--
fixing damage
from a fire he started.
And you know what I got?
Hog-tied and left in a pipe
under my own prison.
There's nothing he can do.
The soldiers
are watching him.
That's what I thought,
until he tunneled out
of my guard's room.
He's buried something
in a junction box out there
and covered it with dirt--
I saw him.
Go see for yourself.
If I'm lyin', I'm dyin'.
Trouble keeps finding you
here in Sona, doesn't it?
Let's take a walk, eh?
There are rumors about
that you are trying to trick me.
I'm just doing what I'm told.
Oh? Let's hope for your sake
that's true.
Hmm?!
But just to make sure,
Let's go on out
to no-man's-land
and see what you
buried in there.
Just wanna make sure my men
are doing a good job for the colonel.
Get in there.
Open it.
Move the dirt.
Now!
It's duct tape.
To fix the frayed wires.
That's why the power
was so inconsistent.
I didn't want the tape
to come loose,
so I packed it
down with dirt.
(chuckles)
Beautiful.
Where are you going?
I got to turn the main
power switch back on.
I had to turn it off, so we could
work on the wire safely.
I'Il come with you.
It's just a switch.
I can handle it myself.
You can... but you won't.
Hey, water boy,
it's back here.
I don't need the chain,
just the cross.
It's the perfect size
and it's not real gold,
so it won't
conduct current.
Keep the
circuit open--
no power even when
the main switch
is turned on.
Tahe cross out...
Sona lights up again.
Lechero find out you messed
with his electric...
you're dead.
That's why he can't
ever find out.
Now, don't make
me come get you.
SAMMY:
Nobody back there
can help you.
Uh, it's...
It's some kind of mistake.
It should be working.
The only mistake I made
was trusting you.
Sammy.
Transformer delay.
It's an old prison.
Now, if you
don't mind...
I'd like to move
into my new cell.
Thank you for your
words before, blanco.
Working for Lechero,
not an easy field
to plow, comprende?
Oh, yeah, yeah, I comprend.
You and me, we're
amigos, Nieves.
When Lechero is in
a better mood,
I'm going to put in
a good word, help you,
How you say,
"Move up the ladder"
I appreciate
it, compadre,  but I
was always taught
that God helps those
that help themselves.
Vaya con Dios.
LINCOLN:
$15,000...
- Why?
- Because that's what he wanted.
Relax. I'll get you
the money.
- And I will meet you there.
- Okay.
How are you holding up?
I just want to get this done.
Good.
Stay here.
SOFIA:
- I'm coming with you.
- Stay here.
- You expect me to stay
here and wait?
- I don't care what you do.
- You don't care?
Who the hell are you
to say you don't care?
You're not the only one
affected by this.
Yeah, I know;
that's the problem.
But you will still just run off
and do whatever you want?
What kind of a man are
you that just...
They killed Sara
and put her head in a box!
And they've got my son!
Oh, Linc, I'm.... I'm sorry.
You still here?
Hey, Lechero wants
to talk to you.
I was just about to get
a little trim.
Lechero said I was looking
all bhuttu!
It'll wait.
(T-Bag stammering)
Did you know
about this?
(Panting): No.
Did you know
anything about this?!
Me? No! No! Nieves...
Nieves--
we was friends, man.
That's right!
If you knew he was using
and didn't tell me...
his death is on your head.
Patrón, patrón, patrón...
I don't know nothing
about drugs.
I don't. I don't.
I mean, hell, I...
I tried me some reefer
when I was 12,
I almost coughed up a lung.
Good.
That's good.
Teodoro.
There appears to be
an opening on my crew.
McGrady, here's
your cross back.
And, uh... Thank you.
You're a real smart guy.
What the hell are
you doing in prison?
Here.
It's perfect.
How did you get it?
It's what
you wanted, right?
Yeah.
Good work.
So what's the next step?
Uh... we wait.
And, I'll keep you posted.
You know what
you need to do.
MICHAEL:
What do you think?
think you fixed
electricity for a reason
but it can't have been
to make that fence sizzle
like the third bloody rail.
Unless you want
to make the colonel happy.
Actually, it's in both
of our best interests
to make that fence
as deadly as possible.
Now all we have
to do is wait for my
brother to come through
with the grave digger.
He wants more.
You said $15,000.
You said $15,000!
No, no, no!
What the hell
are you doing?!
- We need him!
- He will sell us
out to the cops
after he takes
as much as he
can from us.
LINCOLN/GRAVE DIGGER:
No!
He's packing up to go.
Kill him.
He's going to betray you.
T-BAG:
Good news, Agent Mahone!
Due to the untimely
demise of Señor Juan Nieves,
I have now been promoted Manager
in charge of Retail distribution
and Customer liaison.
Get away from me.
All in due time.
Now, I'm not your momma,
and I ain't one
to wipe other's noses,
but let's just say
you've looked better.
I want nothing
from you.
But sure seems
you need something.
On the arm.
No strings attached.
Get your head
straight, Alex.
SAMMY:
Come on in, man.
Come watch
the match. Come.
Oh, yeah. You guys call this
football down here, right?
Very good, very good.
It's World Cup-- football
without the silly hats
you wear in America,
where they all jump
on top each other
like a bunch of batty boys.
(laughs)
Have a seat.
Come.
Teodoro.
Café
The only thing
I hate more than a rat
is a rat with
bad information.
Yeah, look, I'm sorry
about all that,
but my information was good.
It's just that Scofield
is a tricky bastard.
He'll try something again.
You'll see.
Wait! Wait a minute!
Wait a minute!
Come on, you guys.
What are you doing to me?
Come on! I gave you
good information!
Scofield's planning to escape!
I'm telling you!
He's a smart bastard!
Come on, you guys. Come on.
What are you doing?
No. No.
SAMMY:
Shh. Shh. Shh...
No! No.
Look, I gave you
good information.
Oh!
You said something
this morning about,
"If I'm lyin', I'm dyin'."
Just be thankful
I don't hold you to that.
Come on,
Agwe....
Help me here, man!
Come on.
Bagwell!
You left this in your old cell.
Thanks, Alex.
You're welcome.
It's funny that you
could forget something
as important as this is.
Well, I'm glad
you found it for me.
Yeah.
Oh. Oh, look.
You are breathing only
by my grace, Michael.
Now, you remember
the next time that
you're going to send me
on a goose chase.
- Okay?
- I didn't.
No, no. You did.
And you think
you can manipulate me,
just like you did to Sucre...
and Tweener
and Haywire.
I'm not your errand boy.
I'm going to go with you
when you escape,
and if you think,
in any way...
that you'll leave me,
I will put this piece
of metal right in that
very small space
right between your eyes.
I will.
How's LJ? How's Sara?
They told me they're fine.
Listen, uh,
the grave digger
is gone.
What do you mean,
he's gone?
Linc, we can't
do this without him.
We know, we know, that's
why we went to his supervisor--
the guy who approves
any hires for that job.
Turns out he could
use some cash.
Oye, man.
Mail call.
"You're running out of time"
This is how we're
getting out?
Yes.
With a little help
from an old friend.
What is that?
"Kesslivol."
It's a chemical
that kills the odors
caused by
decomposing bodies.
And, when heated to
a certain degree...
...it eats through steel.
www.opensubtitles.org
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
www.tvsubtitles.net