WHIP: Hey!
(whistle blowing)
Hey!
Hey, yo,
where we headed?
Marseille.
WHIP: Marseilles.
Marseilles.
JACOB:
I own you, Scofield.
I know everything about you.
Even your most mundane actions,
like the zoo.
What's with you and the zoo?
MICHAEL:
I go there to think.
JACOB:
18 times in the past month?
A lot of thinking.
I was figuring out how to get
your guy out
of Barranquilla.
Hmm.
Turns out he's not just
a rebel leader--
he's a murderous sociopath.
That's the only way
to make omelets.
I need to know more
about our targets.
If I'm facilitating escapes,
we can't have surprises.
Be proud. You and me,
we're changing the world.
Doesn't make it right.
Don't act like you're suddenly
a fan of the status quo, okay?
The system, it's slow,
stupid, and doomed to fail.
That's why you had to bust your
brother out in the first place.
New ink since the
last time I saw you.
Working on a new plan?
No. No new plan.
Just get tired of looking
at empty skin.
Uh-huh.
You know, it was those tats
at Fox River
that caught my eye
in the first place.
I had to know everything
about the man
who wore his plans
on his skin.
In plain sight
yet so mysterious.
The key to real power
is to disappear.
Hi, Professor Ness.
Hello, Claudia.
Yeah, the secret to real power
is to never betray
your intentions,
to wear nothing
on your sleeve.
And to never
let anyone
see your face.
(trilling)
(click)
Come on in.
Next time I'm sitting
in solitary,
I'll think of you in here,
running the world
in air-conditioned comfort.
JACOB: I've spent my
time in the field.
You all set for Myanmar?
It's only a few weeks off.
That's why I'm here.
I want to bring
someone on board.
Oh, really?
The prison camp at Sittwe
is a two-man job.
I've been watching this guy.
He'll be useful.
Watching him? You in charge
of recruiting now?
Trust me.
The last thing I was to do
is suck someone else into this.
He'll have my back
and he'll speed things up,
increase our odds.
(sighs)
Not exactly
a distinguished career.
He's held up well in prison.
He's got a mean streak.
And he grew up without a family.
It means he can be manipulated.
If you're planning
something,
I'll always be
a step ahead of you.
You know that.
I can see everything
in your eyes.
It's what's behind the eyes
that counts,
Professor.
Hmm.
So you're gonna
wait a year
for me to find my
way out of Sittwe?
Or are you gonna
get me a partner,
so we get on with the business
of changing the world?
Done.
(gulls calling)
I need some food.
(phone chimes)
I'm with you.
Linc, it's Sara.
She's back in New York.
LINCOLN:
Are she and Mike okay?
That's what I'm trying
to find out.
What is it, Michael?
Something's wrong.
Yes, you will.
(muffled shouting)
♪ ♪
I got to get back
to the States.
Slow down.
You're Kaniel
Outis, remember?
You're on every no-fly
list in the world.
Jacob's done something to Sara.
Maybe Mike, too.
How do you know?
That text.
She referred to our son
as Junior.
We agreed we'd
never call him that.
He's baiting
you, Michael.
It worked.
(birds chirping)
Hey, buddy.
Where's Mom?
Oh. I, uh,
dropped her off at work
while you were at school.
That is quite
a pirate ship.
Although it would be
a little hard
to sail with the mast
that far forward.
Your ship might tip over.
The mast has
to be there.
It's not just a ship--
it's a treasure map.
(chuckles)
What do you mean?
It's for Jimmy.
We hide Legos for each other.
I always find his.
He doesn't always find mine.
Wait a second,
how is this drawing a map?
This is the park.
That's the
playground.
And this is the sidewalk.
Impressive.
You put a code
in the drawing.
So, okay,
where did you hide the Legos?
These cannons
are pools at the park.
But there's an extra one,
in the sand.
That's where I buried
the Legos.
Well done, Mike.
Well done.
I've tried everyone. I'm out
of resources in the States.
All my contacts. People who
can go and check on them,
make sure they're okay.
Linc, I got to get home.
I can't spend another two weeks
on a cargo ship.
He's got my
wife and kid.
There may be another way.
You told me about the last
seven years of your life.
Haven't told you about mine.
After Sara got exonerated,
she left Panama.
Me and Sofia stayed behind
and opened a dive shop.
We broke up,
and everything went to hell.
You weren't there to stop me,
so before I knew it,
I was in the old hood,
doing odd jobs.
Odd jobs meaning what?
Moving things from point A
to point B.
For Luca Abruzzi.
John Abruzzi's son.
Yeah.
I just wanted some quick
cash to kick-start my life.
They told me not to
look in the boxes.
But I looked in the boxes.
The amount of fentanyl they're
smuggling out of Europe--
tens of thousands of
pills in every box--
it's just killing people.
So I dumped a box in a Dumpster,
100 grand's worth.
Now you're in hock
to Abruzzi's son.
Yeah. He wants to kill me.
But maybe it's a way to get back
to the States real fast.
LUCA:
You got balls, Burrows.
You actually think
I want to help you?
What if I can get you the $100K?
(scoffs) $100K?
How are you gonna
come up with that--
crawling around
the back alleys of Chicago?
I'm not in Chicago.
I'm in Marseilles.
(chuckles) Marseilles?
Yeah.
I've been working
on a couple deals. I got $100K
in my hand. But I
want off the hook.
Sure you do. How about you get
over here and hand it to me?
That's why I'm calling.
I need to sneak into the States
invisible, like your pills.
Those flights you got
coming out of Europe--
the fentanyl flights--
I need a few seats.
(sighs)
I'll tell you what.
I'll make a few calls.
'Cause either I'm gonna see you
and get that money,
or I'm gonna see you,
and you're gonna get something
a whole lot worse.
(beep)
I can't believe
I'm doing this to myself again.
Difference is this time
you're not alone.
(birds screeching)
God, these things
are disgusting.
What they call 'em again?
Boudin noir.
Not sure what's in them.
I don't think your French is
as good as you think it is.
Yo, be happy
you're not eating snails.
(indistinct chatter)
Hey.
Do you think
they noticed?
Let's not take any chances.
Guys.
Your faces were on the news.
WHIP:
Somebody sees you,
this thing is over.
We got to move, papi.
We got to go.
(phone dinging)
Hold. Luca.
If you can get to Lyon
by midnight,
I can get you on a flight.
I got a warehouse in New York.
You're coming to me.
We'll be there.
Can't decide whether I want you
to have that money
or not, Burrows.
Killing you might be
a lot more satisfying.
JACOB:
Now we know they survived the
strike in the Mediterranean.
We can be pretty sure
he's coming back to Ithaca.
I need some clarification.
Why would he come back here...
to the States
when he's more wanted here
than anywhere else in the world?
Of course.
(clears throat)
Because of them.
He had a life
before he worked for me,
a name-- Michael Scofield.
A family.
And when he went away,
I ended up looking after them.
Ended up... falling for them.
Well...
He wants to kill me.
He thinks I stole his life,
ruined him, which speaks
to his dissociative mind.
I mean, he's a murderer,
a turncoat, a terrorist.
But we'll use it.
I'll be the bait if I have to.
So we can go about taking him
down once and for all.
He's not just gonna
stroll in here.
He's too clever for that.
That's why we got someone
even more clever.
Thoreau?
Guy's a pencil neck.
A pencil neck with insight
into Scofield's plan.
So you, in turn,
can be the hammer.
(door opens)
NELSON:
Screen-grab
of the Skype transmission
he sent from the desert.
He routed the image
through a server
to this BlueHawaii guy,
but it could have been
secretly subrouted
to another, yet
unknown, recipient to use
the information encoded in it.
Information?
It's actually incredible.
Encrypted in the Arabic, the
images are all sorts of stuff.
Apparently,
mundane as hell.
Visiting hours for zoos,
links to defunct message boards
on the Internet.
What message boards?
Truesnuff.com,
Hunterspycamporn.com,
both of which carry... this.
Images of the Harlan
Gaines murder.
What's the bastard doing
rubbing that in our faces?
Of all the things
to encrypt, why that?
What's that get you?
Stegaonographically, a lot.
Steganography is the practice
of concealing information
in the code that
makes up digital files.
Russians do it,
Chinese, everybody.
He's probably thinking
if anyone sees this,
this'll be as far
as they'll look.
But I'm already going inside the
image, breaking down the data
that comprises it.
This is making my head spin.
Point is we put big data,
AI on this,
we can crunch any codes
hidden in there pretty quickly.
And that's what I'm doing.
Nice work, but the truth is,
if I've done my job,
he may reveal his intentions
to us first.
(sighs)
Because I've got him
so far off his game now,
he'll start
to play his cards too early...
Teddy.
"But in return,
you must take a life."
JACOB: ...show us
what the tattoos mean
even before the computers will,
and all the people
he'll be enlisting
for the fight.
You have to call
this pay phone
in France.
(woman speaking French
over P.A. system)
Wait. Chicago?
I thought I was going with you.
Not until you find out
why you're my whip-hand.
I have to go to Chicago
to find that out?
Safe travels.
In the grandiosity of his plan,
he'll lose sight
of the simplest details.
The phone he texted me with
was located in Lyon,
France last night.
It was turned off in an airport
terminal at 11:51 p.m...
...20 minutes before a direct
flight to New York where
you'll be waiting for him
to put this game
to bed for good.
WOMAN (over P.A.):
Flight 290 to Miami, Florida
will now depart from gate B24.
He just powered back up.
(chiming)
We got him.
Look out!
Back of the plane.
Uh, excuse me!
Excuse me.
You're not allowed...
(phone chirping)
Looks like
the game's still going.
♪ ♪
It's impressive
how you get these drugs
in the country
just by bribing small-time
airport officials.
I'm guessing
you got about
five million bucks worth
of fentanyl in here.
So what?
You and your brother here
are gonna lecture me?
We were actually
debating on whether
I should give you the 100K
or not.
He says it's blood money.
I agree.
How about you just
shut up and pay me, Burrows?
I don't have it.
Grab his guys, bring 'em
to the back and shoot 'em.
I don't think you want to add
murder to your arrest warrant.
Wait.
Arrest warrant?
That guy out there
is a DEA informant.
We have him in our pocket.
He owes us. He's
got three vans
full of agents
that are waiting for his call.
They're gonna rain down on you
and your pills.
Unless you forgive
my brother's debt.
Then our informant
won't make the call.
Have your brother fighting
your battles, do you?
No.
Why don't you tell your guys
to drop the guns,
and you and I can have it out?
What do you say, Luca?
Scare that guy off.
Bring these guys
to the back.
They make a move,
he makes a call.
Yeah? I think you're bluffing.
I warned you.
We got company.
(engines revving)
(tires squealing)
MICHAEL:
You shoot us, there's
dozens of witnesses now.
Let's go.
(engines revving,
tires squealing)
(tires squealing)
All they had to see
were DEA hats and SUVs,
and they were gone.
Famous Michael Scofield.
Sheba. Thank you
for everything.
You have no idea how happy
I am to see you back home.
We're not home yet.
All right, so what's next?
How do we get
this son of a bitch?
We don't do anything.
Your part is over.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Tricking Abruzzi's
kid is one thing.
Poseidon-- he knows your face.
Been tracking you
since you went to Yemen.
You've been a warrior,
and I owe you.
But your face is a liability
now to you and your family.
I don't want you
to risk that.
They may know his face,
but they don't know mine.
It's the punch you don't see
coming that knocks you out.
That's my Sheba.
You take care
of her, all right?
I take care of him, you mean.
(laughs)
I love you, brother.
Love you, too.
Be safe,
okay?
You, too.
Bye.
All right.
Well...
when you need me again,
you know where to find me.
(birds singing)
We'll transport her
at 1600 hours.
Lay low until then.
Thank you.
Hey?
That doesn't bother you--
what you just saw in there?
Down in the basement
with his wife, the woman
he says he fell for?
Stop.
I'm done with 21-Void
after this.
After we get Scofield... Outis--
whatever his name is--
I'm done.
That's all I ever wanted,
to get Gaines' killer, but
what he's got
going on in there--
that's not normal.
It's personal.
Something sicker.
There's no leaving 21-Void, Van.
You know that.
He hired us because
we are the best.
We can do
whatever we want.
And if we want to
disappear after this...
we can disappear.
There's no getting out.
If you think
that way...
then you're a prisoner, too.
MAN: The guy at the gate
said the vehicles split
five minutes after
they got here.
Five minutes?
Something ain't right.
The product is still here.
Come on.
It was all staged.
Clever.
But Burrows is gonna die for it.
I don't know
how we're gonna find him.
He's in the wind.
Maybe not.
EZ Pass transponders.
Santora's got a guy
at transit authority.
I bet you he can us what roads
they've been taking and when.
Then it's up to us
to comb the neighborhoods,
find the vehicles,
and put a bullet in that
son of a bitch once and for all.
MAN (over PA): Please keep your
baggage with you at all times.
Unattended baggage is a
security risk and may result...
I got a weird request.
If I give you some coordinates,
can you take me to 'em?
See what I can do.
No.
Unless this cab's got pontoons,
ain't gonna happen.
These coordinates are in the
middle of Lake Michigan.
This is it.
LINCOLN:
No lights.
I don't think
they're here, Michael.
Unless that's what
he wants us to think.
Come on.
Get ready to get us out of here
as fast as you can.
SHEBA: Linc.
Be careful.
Thanks.
What's wrong?
That's why Sara never responded.
I wasn't allowed
to contact anyone,
but she was my wife.
I reached out to her in a way
I thought only she would know.
But he knew my ways, too.
♪ ♪
(lock clicks)
Nothing.
What are you doing?
That's not
Sara, Michael.
He doesn't know I know that.
That's the right answer.
She's alive.
He must be right there with her.
I'm gonna set a meeting.
And what, you're just gonna
show up and show your face?
Yes.
That means Poseidon
has to show his face, too.
And the endgame begins.
It's high noon, boss.
I'm not seeing him.
And you shouldn't.
He's waiting for us
to push the first piece
out onto the board.
Which would be me?
Maybe not.
Black SUV.
Something I can help you with?
Car service. I'm here to
pick up a lady and child.
They got another ride.
Hit the road.
Are you sure?
Mark the black SUV.
No need. They were just here
to make you show your face.
Walk away, please. Now.
Okay, act the tiniest bit
flustered.
Now repeat these words back
to me loud enough to be heard:
"They didn't show.
I'm coming back to you now."
They didn't show.
I'm coming back to you now.
Now we have a game.
He's already revealed
his brother, his biggest piece.
Soon he'll have to
show his face. Trailer,
please take him down.
What the...
I lost him.
Hey.
Can you hear me?
Damn it.
No signal.
What are you doing here?
I lost reception in the garage.
Damn it, you fell right into it.
Now they've got
a mark on us.
Black sedan.
He's heading west.
Please!
Please, don't shoot.
You okay?
So that's what the dog
who's destroying my country
looks like.
(phone rings)
Talk to me.
LINCOLN:
Michael, we found the car.
We're on the corner of Third
and Washington by an alley.
Get here now.
He had Sara with him
but we couldn't see her.
What do you mean
you couldn't see her?
SHEBA:
There's no way we could have.
Oh, my God. Sara.
There was no one
in the backseat?
No, the windows
were blacked out--
we couldn't see.
What's that?
My son did this.
He's good.
There might be
something here.
It's a ship.
A pirate ship
with three pirates--
man, woman and a boy.
That's me, Sara and... Mike.
What do you
think that is?
It's a...
it's a many-headed hydra
reaching up to attack.
Think it's Jacob?
Must be.
This is a message.
You're telling me
Mikey's left something
encoded in that?
Yeah. Yeah, it's encoded in him.
He's got my DNA.
He didn't even know
you were coming.
Sara must have told him.
I don't know.
She must have told him
I was coming.
There's definitely
something here. Definitely.
What is it?
It's one of Luca's guys.
SHEBA:
What?
How the hell did
he track us here?
I don't know.
All I know is all the chickens
are coming home to roost
at the worst possible time.
We got to go.
Linc?
I got it.
This ship, this galleon.
The body of water it's on.
I looked at the map.
There's a lake,
a lake shaped exactly like it,
up in the Finger Lakes district.
"Long lake."
This X
would be on the east shore
of that lake.
He's telling us where he is.
I'm trying to figure out if you
lost your mind or not.
There's only one way
to find out.
Uh-uh.
What?
You're going back
to Buffalo.
What?!
I want you to be with your
family, look after the refugees.
Linc, I'm a part
of this fight, too...
What was that?
It's good-bye.
I could never forgive myself
if something happened to you.
Can I help you?
Yeah.
Can I rent a boat?
I want to take one
out on the lake.
(sighs)
Been thinkin'.
God...
I been thinking.
'Cause a hard bargain's
been presented to me,
and I'm considering something
that's-that's gonna seem like
the old Theodore Bagwell.
T-Bag. (chuckles)
And if that's indeed
what's coming...
...it won't be the work
of a cold-blooded man.
And it won't be for sin...
...or for hate.
If there's blood on my hands,
know this, world...
...it'll be for love.
♪ ♪
How you doing, buddy?
I'm sick of the lake house.
I want to go home.
I know. I know.
(sighs) We'll go home soon.
Don't worry.
Is Mom okay?
She's, uh...
she's a little
under the weather.
She's just resting.
Everything will be fine, kiddo.
Everything will be back
to normal soon enough, okay?
♪ ♪
Michael, go get him.
And I'll be ready.
Thanks, man,
that was fun.
Yeah, anytime.
Yeah, great. Thank you.
What kind of honorific is Whip?
Who's asking?
A man drawn into this
by destiny.
Okay. How about
you take off?
I don't exactly cotton to
strange men coming up to me
in the middle of
the night, you know?
Only one person calls me
Whip-- you ain't him.
Nobody calls you that.
Man who gave me this hand.
Nobody.
Kaniel Outis.
Or for those of us
who know him,
Michael Scofield.
Who are you?
We all got handles, don't we?
Outis. T-Bag. Whip.
But you're Dave Martin,
aren't you?
How'd you know that?
Huh?
You better start
talking, old man.
You don't want
to tangle with this.
Neither do you.
(grunts)
All your answers are
right in here, all right?
West Virginia honky-tonk,
1991, pretty waitress,
bunch of personal business
between us after closing,
and then I git, 'cause Johnny
Law's breathing down my neck.
Lacking a forwarding address,
I never heard from her again.
What are you trying to tell me?
Scofield was looking
for a partner, combing prisons,
looking for someone
who could handle himself.
And with your
innate ability to thrive,
rising to the top
in even the worst of cages,
you reminded him
of a certain someone.
And so he did
a little research.
Wanted to know
what we all want to know.
Did you learn it...
or was it ingrained in you?
(shuddering breath)
It was ingrained in you, son.
You got it from me.
(panting)
♪ ♪
(phone rings)
Linc, he's here.
My son.
Thank God.
Hold on.
Hold up.
I think Jacob's coming back.
I can't believe
I'm seeing my son.
Something's wrong.
Sara's here, but...
something's wrong.
Don't do anything.
He's coming back.
I'm going in.
LINCOLN:
It's not Jacob.
You're clear.
Get your family. Get your son.
Burrows!
(grunts)
(whispering):
Hi, Mike.
You know who I am?
I got your map.
I'm gonna get you
and your mother out of here.
I... I didn't draw a map.
Is someone in there
with your mom?
It's not...
We need to run.
(gunshot)
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
www.tvsubtitles.net