REPORTER: The fighting in Yemen
intensified today
as ISIL forces
get ever nearer to the capitol.
The rebels, who have the stated
intent of taking over
the country and establishing
a radical caliphate,
are also bent on freeing
their leader,
Abu Ramal, who was captured by
the government five years ago.
Ramal is known for his extreme
views and practices,
from using young girls
as sex slaves,
to a medieval brand of justice
that includes public beheadings
and executions in the street.
Ramal is currently
being held in Yemen's
most notorious penitentiary,
Ogygia Prison.
Psst.
(whispers):
This is it.
Whip, get up here.
MAN:
Is it happening?
You are not going
to leave us, are you?
If the rebels take
the city, we're dead.
MICHAEL: You've told us that
a thousand times, Sid. You're
a broken record. Is it clear?
SID:
Okay, it's clear.
Whip. Come on.
Lights go out...
(grunts) ...you follow.
Come on.
WHIP: Would have made it
so much easier
if it was just you and me like
it was on all the other ones.
Nothing is easy
on this one.
Yeah, tell
me about it.
One minute.
(distant explosions rumbling)
(sighs)
Board spans the gap.
Okay.
Blanket covers the wire.
(gasps)
Now it's about
those lights going out.
He didn't flash it
24 hours before.
That's supposed
to be the signal.
Have faith.
Seven straight nights?
No signal, no lights
getting turned out?
Those strikes are
getting closer, too.
(distant explosion)
Those lights aren't going out.
Lights aren't
going out.
Got to go back.
Maybe make a run for it.
Too much ground to cover.
They'll shoot us down
before we make the gap.
What's the plan then?
Give up and die?
I can't wait
another four years.
It was supposed to be one week.
Poseidon has left
us here to die.
We still got
one card left to play.
I didn't want to play it,
but it's already in motion.
(explosion rumbles)
Let's go.
C-
Apparently, Kaniel Outis
was thrown into Ogygia
for crimes
against the government.
Shortly after, he was captured
trying to escape, and
thrown into solitary.
They just released him
into gen pop recently.
Call him Michael, will you?
But why didn't he acknowledge us
when he saw us?
(soft scraping on floor)
Stop!
LINCOLN:
Get back here!
Kid was spying on us.
Yeah.
And he left something
under the doormat.
♪ ♪
This is Michael's handwriting.
Swan was his calling card.
He's reaching out to us.
But why is he being
so mysterious?
Back in the day, he never
talked to you straight, as in
not in code?
He's worried about someone
intercepting his message.
Yeah, but what does it mean?
I don't know, but
we're supposed to know.
Sheik of Light.
That sounds like a guy
on a mountain peak
communing with God.
Yeah, we got to get help.
We're out of help.
Sheba.
She's thinks I'm
abetting a terrorist.
Well, then you have
to convince her that you're not.
SHEBA:
You have got to leave, Papa.
I will not run away.
The government
is being targeted.
You are being targeted.
I'm a no one.
You are government to them.
You don't understand
being a Yemeni.
(panting)
You would run away when
she needs you the most?
I understand that we are no good
to this country dead.
Papa, there will come a time.
We go abroad,
regroup
with an exile government.
With what money, girl?
It would cost
two years' salary.
I'd rather die with my face to
the enemy than to run away.
Papa...
(sighs)
(knocking at door)
Hey.
SHEBA: I suggest you leave
this country as quickly
as you can.
What's he doing here?
My friend needs your help.
I gave him my help.
You didn't tell me he was
working with the enemy.
This man you claim
is your brother,
Kaniel Outis,
worked with the rebels.
His name's Michael Scofield.
I don't care!
Not Kaniel Outis!
There's nothing you can
say to me that will
make me help you, okay?
Is that right?
This enough to get your family
out of the country?
Deliver me this first.
(school bell ringing)
Ready, love?
(phone chimes)
MIKE:
What's that?
It's, uh... it's
something your
Uncle Lincoln sent.
Here.
I don't want to go.
I want to stay with you.
You got to go to school.
And I'm gonna be right
here when the bell rings.
Okay? You walk
down those steps,
you hop straight
into the car. Yeah?
I love you.
Make it a great day.
LINCOLN (on video):
I got the note.
(gasps)
I got the note, Michael.
We're here
to get you out of here.
MICHAEL:
Look, my name isn't Michael,
and I don't know who you are.
I'm sorry.
(phone rings)
Hey.
JACOB:
You know I'm a noted economist?
I mean, that's what it says
in the paper.
"Noted Economist
Attacked in Home." (laughs)
I didn't even know
economists made the news.
That's the first and last time,
hopefully.
(laughs) I've been trying
to piece this thing together.
You remember
those government guys,
those think tank guys,
trying to pick my brain
about game theory,
how they could use it
for foreign policy?
Yeah, you bored the hell
out of 'em, right?
Yeah, okay, but I mean,
did I hear something
I shouldn't have?
I don't know. Did you?
Like who shot JFK?
(laughs)
I am trying to be serious here.
No, you're doped up
on painkillers
and you're thinking too much.
I promise
this has nothing to do with you.
You rest. I'm going to, um...
I'm gonna run some errands,
and then I'm gonna
come visit you, okay?
Okay. Love you.
Love you, too.
Okay, no problem. Thanks.
Hi. I, uh, I called earlier
about a missing U.S. citizen
in the Middle East.
Yes. I'm Henry Kishida.
Let me walk you
to the director's office.
It's an unusual
situation,
which you can appreciate,
since your husband
is declared legally dead,
and the person that
you're referring to
goes by another name.
KELLERMAN: I'll take it
from here, Henry.
How are you, Sara?
Kellerman?
I'll leave you two be. Let me
know if you need anything, sir.
Mm-hmm.
Sorry, how did I
end up with you again?
You asked
for the State Department's help.
I wanted the State Department,
not you.
Yeah, you've lived
so many lives, I don't
know who you are.
That'd be a consistent theme
for you, wouldn't it, given that
you were married to a man
who never existed?
What is that
supposed to mean?
It means you should come in
and let me enlighten you
to all things
Michael Scofield...
Or should I say Kaniel Outis?
You shouldn't drink
bottled water-- the dioxins,
the BPAs in there...
I'm touched by your concern.
Have a seat.
Good, thank you.
You know, Sara...
(clears throat)
...you and I have...
a checkered past.
But I am evermore
a boring guy now, and...
mellowed by life,
trust me.
If you have something
you want to tell me
about Michael,
I'd sure love to hear it.
Okay. When your call came in
and Kishida processed it...
well, let's just say
there are certain keywords
that get our system buzzing
pretty quickly.
Kaniel Outis...
Actually, can't stand it
watching you drink
out of that.
Hey, Kishida?
Could you bring Sara a glass
for her water, please?
Thank you.
Kaniel Outis...
is a known terrorist,
ties to ISIL,
wanted in the killing
of a senior CIA official.
Michael's no killer.
You see,
that's the problem.
Because Kaniel Outis is.
Thank you.
KISHIDA:
You're welcome.
And...
this is Kaniel Outis.
That's ridiculous.
KELLERMAN:
The record here at State says
that... that's
Kaniel Outis's face.
Okay,
but you and I both know
who Michael Scofield was.
No, that's just a memory.
The official record-- history--
it says otherwise now.
Now, that's scary, to think
who could be behind that.
Because only somebody
very formidable
would be capable
of officially turning
one man into another.
It would take a genius...
like Michael.
You're insinuating
that he did this?
He disappeared,
just quit on his life?
I want answers just like you do.
Who's capable of this?
Only a handful of people
in the world.
Sara? Sara!
I figure we got
a day, maybe two,
tops, to get out
of this hole.
(explosion)
At that point,
either the shelling gets us...
or ISIL does.
Does any of this
faze you at all?
The fact that we're
gonna die in here?
We're not gonna die.
We're still getting out.
All of us.
How's that? The roof?
The roof ain't happening.
The roof is happening.
We don't have time to come up
with another escape plan.
So you are nervous.
Great, now I know
I'm in deep crap.
I'm only doing this
for the money.
Don't think you and I
are suddenly good.
You just deliver
me the sheik.
The sheiks are
well away from here.
High desert.
And I've never
heard of one
being referred to
as Sheik of Light.
Which means it's
probably a code.
She knows your brother.
This tape--
it's the only thing
that doesn't belong.
Your brother speaks
in riddles,
does he?
Maybe it's Braille
or, uh, Morse.
Or just numbers.
(speaking Arabic)
I think it's a phone number.
(line ringing)
Voice mail.
Mohammad El-Tunis.
Director of Electrical Works
in Sana'a.
Director of Electrical Works.
"Sheik of Light."
C-
the time to see us.
Where is everybody?
SECURITY GUARD: They are fleeing
ahead of the advance.
We have been trying
to reach him.
All we know is that
he went to the suburbs
to try to find
his daughter.
Do you have an address for her?
We tried calling her,
but no answer.
Address is here.
You are not going to try
to find him, are you?
God be with you, then.
Circled the address.
Good luck.
You're coming with us.
If you think I'm going
into the suburbs,
you're crazy.
What's wrong with the suburbs?
The suburbs
are out there.
The front line of the war.
Nice knowing you,
Benjamin.
I hope next time
it's under
better circumstances.
Pay up.
You have to get us
past the checkpoint.
Two Americans-- we'll never
make it without you.
I am not getting myself killed.
Pay up.
Deliver the sheik.
Then you get your money.
(mutters in Arabic)
Get in.
(phone rings)
Yes?
KELLERMAN: You should check
your e-mail, Sara.
What am I looking at?
Footage captured by
a hunter four years ago.
One of those motion sensor
devices you hang on trees,
takes intermittent
photos of prey.
Hunter comes out one morning,
finds these images.
This is the killing
I was telling you about.
The victim's Harlan Gaines,
Deputy Chief of the CIA.
And the killer...
well, you can see,
it's who we call
Michael Scofield,
or Kaniel Outis, or...
This is exactly what they
did to Lincoln.
And then there's the blood
evidence the next day.
Kaniel or Michael or whatever
gets on a flight to Yemen.
We all most nail him
when he lands.
He gets away.
His luggage doesn't,
and Gaines' blood is all
over the clothes inside.
The evidence is overwhelming.
Whatever name
you want to call him,
Michael's a murderer, Sara.
Hey.
Are you all right?
You all right?
Oh, this old thing?
Yeah, I'm doing fine.
What's going on?
I need your advice.
It's probably something
you're not gonna
want to talk about.
I could really use
your clarity right now.
It's about Michael.
(cell doors closing)
♪ I've paid my dues ♪
♪ I've done my sentence ♪
WHIP: Still want to know how
he got that in here.
Hugging naked
with the guards.
Got to be, right?
♪ But I've come through ♪
What the hell is that?
"We are the Champions."
♪ We are the champions ♪
You get stuck in a Porta-Potty
like this, you go Queen?
I mean, where are the girls
riding the washing
machines, right?
Look at my screen again,
this goes in your eye.
You know, the world
never ceases to amaze.
You get stuck in a
Middle Eastern prison,
the biggest S.O.B. is a Korean.
He's in withdrawal.
♪ 'Cause we are the champions ♪
♪ Of the world... ♪
MICHAEL: You know,
he's the biggest collector
of Queen paraphernalia
in the world.
They say his house in Seoul
is a shrine to Freddy Mercury.
And he got in here how?
Identity theft.
Apparently he used to
sit on his couch,
hack high net worth accounts
all over the world.
Turned it into a collection
of Hummers, helicopters
and, apparently,
Freddy Mercury's ashes.
WHIP: Wait, you mean like
his burnt-up body?
The story is Freddy's cremated,
but his ashes go missing.
To this day no one knows
where they are.
Ja admitted to me once
when he was high he bought them.
Two million bucks.
He's got Queen's lead singer
in his family room.
How exactly do you
know all this?
I asked him.
He's a real mensch when
he's not in withdrawal.
I didn't know
you talked to him.
Amazing.
Just when I think
I know your game, I don't.
You know my game, Whip.
See, right there, "Whip."
I don't even know
why you call me that.
Because you're my whip hand.
My ace in the hole.
Yeah, sure, okay.
JACOB: See, in game theory,
it serves you to be two-faced.
Be everyone's friend
till the moment you're not.
You make them love you so much
that when they're up against it,
their loyalty
will make them act
against their own
best interests.
That's game theory.
A cold, rational
focus on winning.
Even if it's at
everyone else's expense.
What I'm trying to understand
is what he stands to gain.
Leaving his family,
and-and the new identity.
According to the little you've
told me, he was different.
Always an agenda, right?
Yeah.
I mean, he apparently loved you.
Of course he loved you.
How could he not?
But he also wanted you
to open that door
in the prison for him.
I mean, true game theory,
everything, everyone
is a contingency.
You meet people,
you bring them into your life
and you keep them percolating
until the moment
you need to manipulate the
relationship to your advantage.
I'm not judging, you know?
That's not my thing.
I know.
You know me. But...
...schema as deep
and as calculating
as that can, in the end,
spin a man off into madness.
He might initially think
smaller evils are okay
in the service
of a greater good.
Like breaking Lincoln out
of prison.
But the dance of good and evil
could become jumbled,
and the manipulation
itself becomes
the most important thing.
Becomes about winning
rather than whether the game
should be won at all.
I don't think I've seen you
this scared before.
They say, for Ramadan, as an act
of forgiveness,
they're going to release
all prisoners from
solitary over there
back into general
population.
Worst of the worst.
ISIL fanatics.
Abu Ramal.
They're going to kill me,
you know.
Government
gave me 20 years
for homosexuality.
But the monsters in there,
Ramal and his men,
won't let me live 20 minutes.
Please tell me
you still plan
on getting us out of here.
You were responsible
for killing the lights,
and then your Sheik of Light
went missing
at exactly
the wrong time.
I don't know what
happened to him.
Maybe I can find another way.
There is something
you could do.
Give me a piece
of that gum.
Piece of gum is going
to get us out of prison?
It'll start the process.
Sometimes, my friend, I
can't tell which is bigger,
your plans
or your lies.
I take that personally,
you calling me a liar.
And I'm gonna show you,
just like the butterfly's wings,
this piece of gum is gonna start
a sequence of events
that will finish
on the other side of the world.
♪ ♪
(whispers):
Battery, please.
Prison lighter.
Whip, I need your socks.
Sid, water can.
How we doing
out there?
We're all good. Quick though.
Okay.
Hey.
You sure about this?
There's no time left.
The city's
about to collapse.
Desperate times
call for desperate measures.
(gasps)
(grunts)
Ah! Got it.
Come on, come on, come on.
(yells)
WHIP:
Go, go, go.
Guards!
We got a sick
one in here.
What is this?
He's burning up, he
needs the infirmary.
Please.
SHEBA:
This is it.
Limit of government
control.
Anything after this
is ISIL territory.
Stop.
Let me
do the talking.
(speaking Arabic)
(soldier speaking in Arabic)
He's says us being
Westerners, a woman...
we go inside, we
are not coming back.
They're not
letting us through.
Tell him I bet $500 bucks
we'll make it back in one piece.
He doesn't have
$500 to bet.
It doesn't matter.
We don't make it back,
he keeps it.
(speaking Arabic)
He says we have a death wish.
Fine.
The city used to be beautiful,
alive.
Look what they've done
to it.
They're putting up portraits
of Abu Ramal.
He's only gotten
more powerful
since he got locked up
in Ogygia.
LINCOLN:
God help us if he gets out.
SHEBA:
ISIL.
We're gonna get stopped.
Get down.
Down now.
Cover up.
Halt!
Can't believe this.
I know him.
Identification, please.
You.
Reza.
It's Abu Amir now.
What are you doing in
the suburbs, Sheba?
Took a wrong turn.
You got your hair covered up.
That's good.
Finally find God?
Not your God.
There is only one God.
We're gonna take
the city, you know.
You be nice...
maybe I'll make a
good woman of you.
Forgive the devil in you.
Why don't I just
turn around now?
We forgive each other.
Forget each other ever existed.
Beauty is not so
easily forgotten.
YASSER:
Lover boy!
We have to go.
Government's moving in
at Aksa Park.
Cut her loose.
(yells in Arabic)
Get the hell off
our territory.
(engine starts)
They are gone.
We have to hurry.
We're lucky he didn't
kill me right then.
Why?
SHEBA:
Maybe I'll tell you one day.
(groaning)
(automatic gunfire outside)
They're destroying our city.
Your ISIL friends
are destroying our city.
And you come in here
wanting help.
Just give me a little something.
Is there a doctor here?
I'm burning up.
You should have
thought about that
when you supplied guns to them,
assassinated
good men.
Those charges were
a misunderstanding.
Oh, Allah.
Kaniel Outis says
it was
a misunderstanding.
Was it also
a misunderstanding
when you tried to escape
the moment
you got into this prison? Hmm?
(groans)
An honest man doesn't
try to escape.
He asks for a lawyer.
But you,
you tried to escape
the very first week.
I'd have left you in solitary
forever if it was up to me.
(yells)
(whipping continues)
(grunts)
(Michael groans)
(door opens)
(medicine cabinet opens)
(Michael grunts)
(engine idling)
(engine turns off)
The address
at the end of the block.
Rebels...
right in front
of the house.
LINCOLN:
Son of a bitch.
Anything easy
in this country?
The question is:
is the sheik even inside?
Only one way to find out.
SHEBA:
They find us up here,
there's no
explaining ourselves.
We're all dead.
(grunts)
(grunting)
(muttering)
Shh, shh, shh.
Quiet.
You... You are not ISIL?
No. But you're
Mohammad El-Tunis, I take it?
There are still people
in the neighborhood.
We are from the city center.
We are here to get you out.
Not without my daughter.
We can bring her. Where is she?
She's out there.
Where?
In the basement of the
schoolyard, across the street.
Pinned since ISIL arrived.
I came to get her out.
And I got pinned, too.
C-
but I think we might've
just got pinned as well.
(soldiers shouting)
♪ ♪
You okay?
(grunts)
You look like you could use
a few sharp edges
knocked off your world.
You don't look so good yourself.
(inhales, exhales)
Say what you want about Yemen,
they're not shy
about prescriptions.
It's the good stuff.
Morphine derivative.
I need access to your cell phone
and a credit card number.
Why?
I want to order a pizza.
(shouting in Arabic)
There's a back door,
toward the schoolhouse.
Come on.
LINCOLN:
Too late.
Go to the rooftops.
C-
over the Rover.
We'll never get to it.
I can get
in that pickup,
make a ruckus on my way out.
Any luck,
they'll be all over me.
Then you got a clean shot
to the Rover.
(slamming on door)
Go. Go!
I'm not leaving
without my daughter.
You don't know
what ISIL will do to her
for educating those girls.
I'll get her out, I promise.
(grunting)
LINCOLN: Go!
MOHAMMED: Okay! Okay.
(speaking in Arabic)
(horn blaring)
(shouting in Arabic)
Your father sent me.
I'm getting you out of here.
Come on! Come on!
(engine starts)
LINCOLN:
Get down! Stay down!
(gunshots)
He's got to make it.
You know you got to make it.
Come on.
There he is! There he is!
Yeah, baby!
Oh, no. This isn't good.
This isn't good.
(shouting in Arabic)
SHEBA:
This government checkpoint.
They'll think we're suicide
bombers. We have to stop.
C-
Are you out of your mind?
Don't shoot at us!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
The gunman.
Hit the gunman!
LINCOLN:
Stay down!
(speaks in Arabic)
(laughing)
(sobbing)
(speaks Arabic)
Forgive me, uh...
Their parents
have been killed.
I'm trying to figure out
how I can help them.
They can stay here for now.
As long as you tell me
who you know in Ogygia
and why they want
you so bad.
(sighs) I'm a man
with, uh...
troublesome children.
They're beautiful.
But perhaps too modern
for this country.
My daughter tries
to educate girls.
And my son,
he falls in love
with another man.
They gave him 20 years
in Ogygia Prison.
I went to visit him
a few weeks ago.
He said maybe
there is a way out.
A way I could help.
A man is not a man
if he would let his family die.
You agreed to help him.
How?
He said if I could
arrange a blackout,
he... he knew someone
who could get him out.
An American?
I don't know.
I-I was supposed to
do this a week ago,
but then this happened
with my daughter.
Thank God you found us.
There's still
time to do it.
They're waiting for you
in there.
Then I have to go now.
He said I was
to give a signal
exactly 24 hours
before the blackout.
I will pulse
the power grid twice.
This city
may not have 24 hours in it.
(school bell rings)
TEACHER:
Bye, guys.
Bye.
God knows I'm no perfect
judge of character,
but Michael?
(chuckles)
If any of what they're
saying is true...
So there's more
to find out, Sara.
I mean, the important thing is
that you are gonna survive this,
however it turns out.
Mm-hmm.
And we're here for you. Okay?
Let's go.
Thank you.
Call me, okay?
Yeah.
Hey, can I just scoop
Mike real quick?
All the kids have been released.
You don't have him?
Mike?
I'll go this way.
Okay, yeah.
Mike?
Hey, hey, have you seen Mike?
Mike!
(panting):
There...
What are you doing?
You scared me.
I was looking
for where the man went.
What man, baby?
The man that gave me this.
The pizza man.
The pizza man?
(whispering):
Michael.
What are you into?
ISIL is getting
closer by the hour.
And the rebels
in here know it.
When they take over,
they'll kill all of us.
Infidels, the sinners,
the foreigners.
Praise Allah.
Someone found my father.
Means the escape is on.
24 hours from now.
(door opens)
But this may be too late.
Ramadan has begun.
The guards are releasing
the prisoners.
Abu Ramal and his men,
they'll kill me.
And you.
♪ ♪
Good to finally
see you free, brother.
We're not free yet.
You've found
a way out for us?
Yes. Tomorrow night.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
www.tvsubtitles.net