This is an overview. That's just the
beginning of what's on here.
You honor your side of the agreement, and I will
do the unveiling at the conference tomorrow.
I thought we were working with these people.
So did I.
Damn well almost got our asses
handed to us getting these.
These things are for tomorrow.
I want Scylla today!
Vincent Sandinsky.
Let's go.
What are you going to do?
I warned you not to come, Michael.
Well, it's not over, not by a long shot.
Christina Rose Scofield, that
name mean anything to you?
No.
Yes.
How badly do you want him, mom?
Michael, listen to me.
That's not an answer.
I'll be in touch.
I get the ass-Kicking of a lifetime and
you come back empty-Handed?
- What?
- Linc and Michael's mother-
She's got Scylla here in Miami.
Fuel the jet.
We're going to Miami.
The guy knows something.
I don't know what else I
can do to help you guys.
Please let me go.
I won't say a word to anyone about this.
Never heard of the name Christina Scofield?
I told you, no.
Never?
Never.
Yeah.
That guy you picked up at the airport.
There's something you should know.
What do you mean?
He's not some innocent victim, Linc.
He and Christina have been exchanging
E- Mails, phone calls, you name it.
They've got some kind of plan. I
just haven't figured it out yet.
Thanks.
So what are you going to do with him, Linc?
Leave town, Michael.
Linc?
Where's Scylla?
- No.
- Where's Scylla?!
You ready?
Almost. Is that Sandinsky's phone?
Yeah.
Good luck.
Thanks, I may need it.
It's Michael again on Sandinsky's phone.
I thought he turned it off.
Well, now it's on. Track it.
Michael?
Hello, Christina.
I hope you're ready to talk.
Let's start with Vincent Sandinsky.
Vincent Sandinsky the scientist?
He, uh, he's an old friend of mine.
A bit of a bore, don't you think?
But who cares about him?
I'd rather talk about you.
I'd rather meet you face to face.
Unless you're bringing me
Scylla, I'm not interested.
No Scylla, no meeting.
That's all I can offer.
What do you hope to accomplish?
I need your answer in ten minutes, and
that's the last time I'm calling back.
And found him.
He's in an industrial park in el portal.
Right up the coast.
All right, let's go.
You're lying, you're lying.
I don't work for the Company, six
words that never prove true.
Come on, man, this is over, look around!
What are you doing here?
- I swear I don't know anything, I don't know anything.
- What are you doing here?
I don't know what he's talking about.
I am here for a conference, that's all,
I don't know who told you otherwise.
I do, and Michael's also full of crap.
He's got no reason to lie.
Actually, he does, Michael's leading
us off the scent, so he can get in...
He doesn't want Christina to have
Scylla any more than we do.
It's not the first time he's lied to us.
Where is it?
- No.
- Linc.
Come on, Linc, he can't talk if he's dead.
You got three seconds.
- No.
- BURROWS!
Put the gun down.
Vincent and I need to talk.
Vincent? Yeah.
We had a deal.
New deal.
I'm taking charge.
Vincent and i are old friends.
Where'd you find him?
At an airstrip.
He's got something to do with Scylla.
Good.
Then you can help me find
it, can't you, Vincent?
And you can help me find Christina Scofield.
Dr. Sandinsky has been a Company operative
since... How long's it been, Vincent?
21 years.
21 years of service.
Scientist, statistician,
expert field combatant.
What brought you to Miami?
Does that help?
She invited me, okay? She invited me.
- Who?
- Christina Scofield.
I'm working with her.
Oh, that brings you full circle,
doesn't it, burrows?
But you knew that already.
When were you planning on telling me
that your mother was behind all this?
We just found out.
But bottom line is, you knew.
All of you!
On your knees.
You heard him, get down.
Oh, not you.
I don't need to make deals with
men who can't do their jobs.
If Bagwell is the only one
who is competent here,
- What? Are you serious?
- He'll do it alone.
Who do you think found this guy?
Where's Scylla?
I don't know.
I don't.
She doesn't tell me where she keeps it,
but I do know where she's staying.
A place called edgewater tower, room 1099.
You have today.
One day.
You're wasting time, burrows.
You tipped him off.
No, Bagwell.
You stay here.
Yeah, Theodore. He needs you.
But you'd better stay away from us.
This is where Michael's
signal is coming from?
Yeah.
Be careful.
Just stay here.
Check it out.
Let's go! Let's go.
He's leaving.
Come on, he can't be that far away.
Go.
Out.
Let's go.
All right.
Where is it?
You don't really expect me
to answer that, do you?
Actually, I do. Because
your life depends on it,
And considering your track record, I think it's safe to
assume that you're always looking out for number one.
I've waited 25 years for
this moment, Michael.
There's no way I can say
everything I want to say.
Why should I let you?
Because I'm your mother.
That's something you can't change.
It's something you can't take away.
It's nice to meet you, Sara.
In some ways, Michael's
done very well for himself.
In other ways, I'm not so sure.
Lincoln has led you down a dark path.
I make my own decisions.
You break Lincoln out of prison and he
goes to work for general Krantz.
And he has his reasons.
But if you're looking for some kind of common
ground between us, maybe that's it.
I don't want to see Lincoln working
for the Company, either.
At least you've stopped
making excuses for him.
I stopped making judgments.
Something I couldn't afford.
But that was a long time ago, and
that's not why we're here.
No.
You're right.
None of us wants to see Scylla
go back to the Company.
So, if we can put the past behind us,
maybe we can work something out.
Like what?
Like a deal.
"A deal"?
All right, you tell me where Scylla is,
and we'll work out the details later.
We'll go 50-50.
A mother-Son operation?
Maybe.
But first, Scylla.
Please, Michael, I know better.
We're very similar.
I know what it's like to look at the big
picture, see all the little moving parts...
How much easier it is to
think after the surgery.
I know you.
That's why you'll never be able to manipulate
me like you do the rest of the world.
You're running out of time.
All right, there's no one back here!
Well, they were here, but of course,
there's nobody here now.
'Cause that's what happens.
You know, this whole thing...
It's just...
It's just... crap!
We're always one move behind,
every step of the way.
Yeah, and it's gonna get worse now
that Bagwell is breathing down our backs.
How do you make that kind of mistake, huh?
And let that inbred get anywhere near us.
No, no, no, the first mistake
was working for Krantz.
Okay, that was the first mistake. What do you
think's going to happen now that he's in town
And he has his goons calling the shots?
What's going to happen now?
Yeah, I should've known better
than to get anywhere near this.
All right, you know what?
We should go. Let's go.
No, we can't go, because
you saw the photos, right?
You saw the photos, so you know
what he's going to do with them.
We should have known what
he was going to do with them!
That's what we should've...
Just calm down.
You know what, the deal is over.
You know it, I know it. Everybody knows it.
We're not getting out of here!
We're going to take a walk right to the gallows,
or somebody else is going to stab us in the back!
I did that walk and I survived.
Even if we win, do we win?
You don't believe that, do you?
Look, I'm going to do what I got to do.
If you don't want to roll
with me, that's fine.
- What is that?
- Rental receipt, a silver minivan.
What is this?
What do you know about this?
We found a whole box of
them down in little Cuba.
Guns, too.
What do you know about this?
She wanted me speak there.
About Scylla?
She said she'd give me the script
beforehand, that's all I know.
She said her interest
was purely scientific.
Her interest was financial.
She came to me about a
year ago with an idea.
Rather than build our organization with
Scylla as the permanent cornerstone,
She wanted to use the technology
to make a quick profit.
If certain events occurred, various nations might
feel the need for a more modern defense system,
And they'd come to us for the answers.
Solar weaponry.
Water desalinisation.
Now, what do you know about all this?
I told you all I know.
Well, I thought it was a crazy idea.
Plan of an amateur.
But I figured she'd be angry.
She wasn't allowed to hold a card.
Now, what was that?
I think it's more than that.
Really?
What did she tell you?
I know how the Company operates.
Shell corporations like Ecofield,
rampant misuse of funds.
You're literally sitting on a gold mine.
But your leadership only benefits you and
your friends ten generations in the future.
And you would like to see
the Company implode?
I want to see something happen.
You think too small.
Laos?
We'll all be dead before that pays off.
Uh, "laos", sir?
don't trouble yourself.
Burrows?
I got a question for your friend.
What is it?
Ask him what the letters "dmb" mean.
Do the letters "dmb" mean anything to you?
I'm sorry.
I thought you understood me.
She said her place is on the
same block as dade-Miami bank.
- Did you hear that?
- I got it.
He'd better be telling the truth.
See what else the doctor knows.
No... what's Christina's plan?
I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe we should've...
Maybe we should've followed
her or something.
Sit down for me.
How about I talk to her?
I might have some perspective.
She didn't leave me when I was six.
Okay.
I'm sorry we had to meet this way, Sara.
I'm sorry we had to meet at all.
Michael's been through a lot in the last year and
at some point, it's going to be too much for him.
Michael can handle it. He's never
known a life without change.
Oh, you say that like you know him.
Oh, I do.
Better than you.
I don't see how that's possible.
Well, you will when your child's born.
See, I wasn't sure at first, but
you do have that drawn look.
And I see the way you protect
yourself when you sense danger.
You don't even know you're
doing it. It's instinct.
And what is it you know
about maternal instinct?
I've tried to be a mother.
- Even to Lincoln.
- How can you say that?
You left them without so
much as an explanation.
But if Michael would listen...
You know what? You can stop.
You can't justify what you did.
Michael doesn't know you're
pregnant, does he?
What happened?
I got nothing.
Hello, joyce.
How are you? My name is
Don Self, Homeland Security.
don't worry, there's nothing the matter.
I'm just here doing a favor for my friend.
See, his mother passed away yesterday.
Okay, and her last will and testament
is in one of your security boxes.
It's actually box 6468.
Is he authorized to access it?
See, that's the problem. He's not.
But we're willing to fill
out all the paperwork...
I'm sorry. Only authorized individuals
are allowed to access safe deposit...
Listen, lady, I need to get in
that box. Where's your boss?
Sir? Sir, can I help you?
I need to get in my mom's safe deposit box.
Do you have a court order? Dmb
policy prevents anyone...
Here's the policy. Okay, I need
to open box 6468. Right now.
- Name's Don Self, Homeland Security.
Excuse me, mr. Frank?
Number 6468 was accessed a minute ago.
He just left. It was the guy
with the silver suitcase.
There he is. Hey, that looks like
the guy from the Ambassy.
Mr. Banerjee, how are you?
I'm trying to reach Christina hampton.
She's in a meeting right now.
If I don't talk to her before
5:00, the deal is off.
This is my final offer.
You're going to take me to Scylla,
And then you can walk.
No questions.
No one tells the general.
You can live the rest of your life like this
never happened, but Scylla is mine.
Lincoln would never let that happen.
He doesn't have to know.
Even as children, you couldn't agree.
You fought about everything.
The two of you couldn't be more different.
But you know that, don't you, Michael?
This isn't about Lincoln.
You have blue eyes, he has green.
He played with trucks.
You took apart the television set.
And I don't need to point out the
difference in IQ or temperament.
You know what I'm getting
at,don't you, Michael?
I don't have any idea what
you're talking about.
You've always known it deep in your heart.
You just had no one to confirm it.
Lincoln...
Isn't your brother.
It's true.
I should have told you before,
But you always looked up to him,
And I had no idea things
would happen like this.
You don't know what you're saying.
Have you ever seen pictures
of Lincoln as a baby?
- Yes.
- No.
There aren't any.
Your father didn't adopt him until
he was three years old.
His parents worked for the Company.
They were killed in an explosion in manila.
Aldo brought him home the next day.
He felt it was his duty.
He didn't ask me how I felt.
I- I never bonded with him
like mother and son.
He was always so angry.
Understandably so...
He was too young to remember his mother,
But he always knew something was missing.
I can't believe you're playing this card.
I'm sorry, Michael.
But I felt differently about you.
And you could tell.
That's why you always felt guilty.
Why you were always throwing
yourself over the cliff
After Lincoln was already
dead at the bottom.
It's why you went to prison
and pissed your life away.
You don't know why I did the things I did!
You weren't there!
Who knows what you could have accomplished.
But you always felt like you had
to make less of yourself
To make Lincoln look less
pathetic in comparison.
Lincoln was more of a brother to me
Than you were ever a mother.
You left.
He stayed.
He fed me.
Kept me off the streets.
Put me through school.
How?
By getting in trouble over and over
again, just like he is right now.
What do you mean, right now? Where is he?
He's out looking for Scylla,
and he's not going to find it.
Maybe you should call him and tell him.
Unless there's too much
bad blood between you.
Or no blood.
Who's the guy in the hood?
Is it miael?
Oh, just relax.
Where is he?
All right, keep up with him, come on.
I am. Just shut up.
It's not that I don't want to help you.
It's just that I hate to see you
go running after him again.
- Michael.
- Come here!
- Michael...
- Come here.
Michael!
Where is he?
Okay.
You want to go running after him,
Flush your life down the
toilet once and for all?
Go ahead!
Where is he?
Why don't you tell me where he is, or
I'll kill you myself, I swear to God!
I'll kill you myself.
Michael!
Michael.
Come on!
Tell me!
Where is he?
Where is Lincoln?
Fine.
There's an energy conference at the
Panda Bay hotel in about an hour.
He'll be there. That's the truth.
I'm sorry.
I'M... I dot know what to think.
Go. Go, go go.
Go find him.
I got her. Go.
If she gives you any trouble...
I know. Just...
Go.
You have surpassed
expectations, Bagwell.
You're much more than an informant.
I multitask.
Well, if things go as well as expected here,
You'll be rewarded accordingly.
As a special liaison to the Company?
Yes.
What exactly does that entail?
Well, that would be up to you.
Most Company operatives choose
their own career path,
Though I can't say what would suit you.
What do sexual predators from
Alabama typically do,
Uh, aside from the obvious?
Those days are behind me, general.
What I lack in formal education,
I more than make up for in
natural skills and curiosity.
And as you've seen, my
loyalty knows no bounds.
Then you shouldn't have any
difficulty passing your final exam.
Now, you didn't expect that a
few phone calls on the sly
Would set you up for life, d you?
No, sir.
I'm ready for anything.
Good. Then prepare for this.
When burrows brings Scylla back to us,
I will fly it safely back to los angeles,
And you will be the one to
put a bullet in his brain.
Sara?
What's going on in there?
What do you want?
Oh, please, keep that open.
Why?
So you can lob more accusations
and assumptions out at me?
I haven't made any.
Lincoln is adopted.
And you're pregnant.
You don't deny it, do you?
You should tell him.
He'd be happy, even under the circumstances.
It really isn't any of your business.
I'm sorry.
Sometimes in-Laws overstep
their bounds, but...
You know, when it comes right down to it,
I am the only mother any of
you will ever have, so...
You shouldn't throw that away so easily.
Yeah, you know, the
only thing I get from you
Is a great example of the
mother I don't want to be.
Sara?
It doesn't have to be like this.
Yeah, it does.
That was your decision a long time ago.
Sara, can I just give you
one piece of advice?
Stay out of the bars.
- That's good advice.
- I have friends in AA.
They're only alcoholics.
I can only imagine what it's like for you,
Trying to stay off the smack.
It's morphine.
Hospital-Grade morphine.
Christina Scofield will not be
leaving Miami tonight.
I want eyes at every airport and gas
station between here and Atlanta.
And I want the names of everyone
attending that conference.
I thought you might be asking that question,
so I called the front desk of the hotel.
Said I was from the newspaper.
Excuse the spelling.
These are all scientists.
I told you.
Those are the speakers. The names
below are "special guests".
Sounded like bigwigs from
all over the world.
"Frederich, Carlotto, Linarte, Ban...
" "Banerjee"?
Naveen Banerjee?
Who is that?
The son of prime minister Nandu Banerjee.
He has a known interest in
solar weapons technology.
This will all be over by the end of the day.
Come on, Linc, where are you?
It's Linc.
- You know what to do. - Linc, it's me.
Call me when you can. We got to talk.
Mahone!
This way!
Christina.
don't move.
Or I'll kill you both.
Where is he?
Where did he go?
There.
- Where is he?
- Right there, right there.
Lincoln, stop!
Why?
Wait, wait.
That's the hotel.
The energy conference.
That's right- It's today.
The silver van.
The rental van.
They want us here.
Something's up.
What the hell is going on?
Downey.
It's for a getaway.
Lincoln, no!
Where are you?
Running. Burrows is on my ass.
Are you okay?
I was worried you didn't get away.
This whole thing could go to hell.
I'm fine. I'm right on time.
See you soon.
Down.
Good girl.
He'll never forgive you for this,
and neither will his brother.
Soon, this will all be behind us.
Maybe I can meet my grandson one day.
Nomaash kaar.
My apologies, Naveen.
Where have you been?
I was told that you would call.
I got hung up on a few
details for this evening.
You spoke with downey?
It did very little to reassure me.
I need to speak to dr. Sandinsky.
Oh, you haven't heard?
Dr. Sandinsky had a family emergency.
His wife was in a terrible accident.
I spoke with him this morning.
He took a private jet out this afternoon.
It's very late to be making
these decisions now.
Yes, but you've come all this way.
You are prepared to give
your speech, aren't you?
Fine.
But in light of the fact
That I did not speak with the
doctor, I'll amend my offer.
$1 million in exploratory research.
The rest will follow in the weeks to come.
That's very generous, Naveen.
History will thank you.
Your country will thank you.
See you soon.
May I have your attention, please?
We're about to begin.
Thank you. Welcome to Miami beach.
And thank you for attending the
first global conference of its kind,
Where great minds will meet to
explore our energy future.
The importance of finding new ways to power
our world should not be underestimated.
It's running.
They rented this in Linc's name.
Okay. Look at this.
These passports.
It's us.
It's a setup.
For what?
It's a setup!
Thank you.
It's 5:00.
If burrows doesn't call in the next
five minutes, you're going downtown.
General, you should see this.
In the city of Miami.
Today, the venue will
be the Panda Bay hotel,
Where security it high in light
of the important guests.
This includes Naveen Banerjee, son of
prime minister Nandu Banerjee,
Who is scheduled to be the
event's keynote speaker.
Banerjee's fragile political position
May leave him vulnerable to
criticism on the world stage.
- He has aggressively sought to place his ideas
- Christina's plan.
What she needed to profit from Scylla.
An incident that'll domino
into global warfare.
...in the search for new forms of greener
energy like sun and wind and how this idea
Krantz.
You're out.
It's over now.
No!
You do it.
Do it!
Hey!
You need a pass!
At this point in our history, solar power
accounts for less than one-Tenth
Of one percent of the total
power generated in our world.
And in the next ten years, that number
should increase to ten percent,
But it's still not enough.
We must strive to seek new alternatives
So that we can break this
cycle of oil dependence.
We cannot do that without your help.
So that's why we're here today:
To explore our new energy future,
And envision a new tomorrow.
Now, our first guest is an
author and an entrepreneur.
As well as having a notable heritage,
He has spoken to audiences across the world.
Please welcome, Naveen Banerjee.
Thank you, thank you.
Good evening, my friends.
It is my pleasure to be here with you
today in this beautiful city of sunlight.
Throughout the United States,
I find there to be great interest
In the changing way that
we all power our world.
Many times I have been approached...
No!
With a proposal to reinvent the wheel.
New resources...
No!
Michael!
Linc!
We've got to go.
She set the whole thing up.
Do you have it?
Right here.
How'd it go?
The van was there with the passports.
I just got off the phone with
our contact at the bank,
And they've got clean video of burrows
trying to access the box.
He must have trashed the hotel room.
His hands were all over the shells.
You see Michael?
He was there on my way out.
Lincoln's right back where he started.
It's too bad about Michael I know you, uh...
Shut up and drive.
www.tvsubtitles.net