LOS ANGELES.CALIFORNIA
they ran the projection
you asked for, general.
you're clear. Go ahead.
CHICAGO,ILLINOIS
There's been a complication.
Burrows and scofield have
been transferred to...
I read the newspapers.
You don't have to tell me
what's in the headlines.
The exact penitentiary where
they're being held is undisclosed.
But you can guarantee it'll be federal.
Supermax.
No more updates.
Call me when they're dead.
Welcome to los angeles.
As it turns out, men
who have escaped not one,
but two penitentiaries, are
considered a bit of a flight risk.
So we need to know where you are
and what you're doing at all times.
Theses are gps ankle monitors.
Now step up, take one and put it on.
I ain't wearing that.
Let's make this clear: I'm your ally,
but more importantly, I'm your boss.
Which means if this fails-- it's my ass on
the line as much, if not more, than yours,
so from this point on, if I ask
you to do something, you do it.
If I ask you to say
something, you say it.
And if I ask you to put on a
monitor-- you put on a monitor.
As far as the general
public is concerned,
you're being contained in a supermax
facility somewhere in the united states.
So to avoid any messy explanations
and stay off the company's radar--
you need to keep your heads
down and your ears open.
We've provided cell phones,
clothing, and toiletries--
all the basic necessities
to get you up and running.
Hey, uh, you-you patted these guys
down before you let them in, right?
'Cause I can't be getting
shanked or shivved.
Who's this?
This is roland glenn.
He'll be assisting you.
We've already got our team.
No, scofield, see, this is my team,
and roland's working off a
sentence just like the rest of you.
In fact, with the amount of security
that's gonna be around scylla,
roland's expertise will be a necessity.
So, if no more questions, let's
get to work on finding scylla.
What about that second step?
What about the break-in?
You let me worry about step two, okay?
You just worry about finding scylla.
I've got an idea where to start.
That's excellent, alexander.
See, there's a man who's thinking.
All right, let's let
these men get to work.
Good luck. To all of us.
Yeah, since I was here first I think I'll just go
ahead and grab that S.S. Bedroom, if that's cool.
- Sara...
- yeah?
You take the bunk.
You know, when this is, when this is all
done-- you and me, we're gonna settle up.
All right, obviously, there's
a lot of history in this room.
That's a given.
But it we're gonna pull this
off, it's gonna take all of us.
We got to work together.
So if anyone has a
problem, get it out now.
You want to clear the
air with someone...
now's the time.
All right. Let's get to work.
Whistler's assignment was to drop
off this, this, this data card--
th-this 'scylla' to
a company executive.
Someone he referred
to as "the cardholder."
And his job was to-to protect it.
To... keep it safe.
Now, I didn't see who he was,
but I got a look at his driver.
His driver?
You want to sketch this guy's face and match
it up to 10 million people in los angeles?
Well, that's just great.
I saw more than just the guy's face.
All the drivers were hanging around, talking
shop, but this guy, he was standing by himself.
Legs apart, hands behind his back,
at rest-- he's former military.
His car rides a little
lower than the rest of 'em.
Probably signifies private security.
Weighed down by bulletproof siding.
His suit,
his suit--
you don't buy a suit like that on a cop's
salary or pulling weekend gigs as a driver.
That means he's full-time.
He's highly paid.
You ask our friend mr.
Self to run tax records
on the 45- to 55-year-old white males in
los angeles drawing a military pension,
and taking six figures from
a private security company,
and you narrow your field
from 10 million till about 50.
And then I can pick
the guy out from there.
Find the driver, you
find the cardholder.
MEXICAN DESERT 60...........
We haven't ate or
drank anything for days.
Oh, I don't want to die out here.
We ain't gonna die, sancho.
- we ain't gonna die.
- Okay.
We just gotta find what's
called a compass cactus.
Due to the fact it always
leans toward the south.
Inside there's delicious fruit
which'll fill our bellies.
Plus, we find out which way is south, we're
gonna find out which way is north. ¿Comprende?
tell you what. Why don't we,
uh, rest here for a while, huh?
Travel at night when it's cooler.
That sounds good.
What are we gonna do when we get there?
To san diego.
You mean after michael pays for
the vile he's transgressed upon me?
I'm still trying to figure that out.
Nice to work with homeland.
The fbi would take days
to gather this intel.
Well, the fbi should'a hired me 'cause I could've
gotten whatever info you wanted in 25 minutes tops.
You some kind of hacker?
I design silicon lithography
for personal gain.
He's an identity thief.
He's a douche.
Hey, why don't you sit in the corner
and we'll get you when we need you.
This is him. That's the driver.
Now what?
Well, he takes us to the cardholder,
and the cardholder takes us to scylla.
You could have left me there, in jail.
Could have or should have?
Maybe both.
- Are you thanking me, alex?
- I don't know.
Don't bother. You're here because we
needed you. Not because we wanted you.
That's him. That's the guy.
What's that, private security?
It's like a fortress.
Slow down. Slow down.
This thing we gotta get, it's in there?
Motion sensors, alarm
systems, armed guards.
In and out of that place
without anybody knowing.
You better have one
hell of a plan, michael.
So, basically, there's no freaking
way to break in to the place.
Not quickly. Not without being seen.
What about the neighbors, uh, somewhere we
can be staged from, you know, go under and up?
Closest neighbor is
here, across the street.
And even that would take weeks.
The government's story about us being
held in a supermax will only last so long.
What does that mean?
I mean, then what if
somebody finds out we're not.
What if we don't have
to be in the house?
If the card-- this scylla-- is so important
maybe the guy is carrying it on him.
Well, according to public records, the
owner of the estate's name is stuart tuxhorn,
and he's a ceo of a
company called spectroleum.
Heavy hitter like that's
gonna have security 24-7.
And we gotta get this thing without
anyone knowing it's gone, right?
So even if he's got it on
him, how do we get it off him?
You don't steal the card. You copy it.
Oh, now you're interested
in what I gotta say, right?
Copying it will make it harder.
Not only do you have to steal
it, you have to return it, genius.
Only if you don't got me, hombre.
What's that?
This is the reason I got busted.
Oh, you stole the cell phone?
Oh, yeah, yeah, no, I'm lookin' at federal
time 'cause I stole a cell phone-- seriously?
I invented this so that
I don't have to steal.
It looks like a cell phone but it's
really like a digital black hole.
Wireless hard drive that swallows up any
electronic data within ten feet of it.
Like what?
Like the account info of anyone at
starbucks with a latte and a laptop.
Like the pin number of any
credit card used at a gas pump.
I can walk out of here and get the identities and
financial statements of ten people in ten minutes,
on a slow day, with one hand on my junk.
And the information embedded in scylla?
If we can get close enough...
it's ours.
Prison
Break Season04 Episode02
is this number... acceptable to you?
10,000 people?
- Yes.
- Good.
Now that you're on board, we
can issue the op-order today.
He's on his way.
all right, hold on.
Sara, it's me.
Everybody's on.
Now, while I'm monitoring the device,
I'm not gonna be able to see
exactly what data's being copied.
But, like downloading quality
porn from the internet,
progress bar's gonna tell me
when it's time to rock and roll.
How long do they need to stay in range?
Encrypted data like this is
gonna take at least two minutes.
Here he comes. Sucre, you're on.
good luck.
easy.
Sir, would you mind stepping
away from the vehicle?
Talk to me, roland.
I got nothing, man.
Last time I had this little action, I was
dry humping my way through fifth grade.
Calm down.
sir... sir...
step away from the vehicle!
Okay, bro, just relax-- we
don't have to get all excited.
You speak english now.
Only a little, but, uh...
- how about now?
- Nada.
Try to get closer to them.
If he was any closer,
he'd be in the car.
I get your little act, pedro.
Hit the brakes, let the rich guy pay
for damage you don't intend to fix.
Just give the man some
money so we can leave.
congratulations.
He was there-- I think tuxhorn was
in the car. So did we get it or not?
Nope. Nothing.
Can I help you?
So how did you find me?
I never lost you.
The, uh, the new nose
threw me a bit, but...
what do you want, don?
I got customers.
Look, back in the days, when
you worked with the company...
well, for the company.
I did economic forecasts
of their operations.
- I mean, I wasn't one of the guys...
- but you had access.
Come on-- the last
time I helped you,
the only thing I got out of it was
plastic surgery and a $100,000 pay cut.
You know, so either you buy one
of these exceptional family cars,
with above average gas mileage,
or you leave me the hell alone.
I know about scylla.
And I'm going after it.
You know, I knew you were crazy.
I didn't know you were stupid, too.
Well, let's just say I was
able to get my hands on it.
It's my understanding that scylla could only
be used if it's plugged into a decoder box
that's hidden in one of the
company facilities. Am I right?
You know, I wish I
could help, but I can'T.
No, you are helping, jasper.
Just a matter of whether you do it before or
after I shame you in front of your coworkers here.
Tell me where the company
keeps the box, jasper.
Could be anywhere; I don't know.
Somebody does. Right?
Somebody that you might have access to.
You know, if you go down this road,
your government job won't protect you.
Then I better not get caught, right?
If I don't find something to eat
soon, I don't know what I'm gonna do.
We're not gonna make it.
No, we got to, we got to
just keep talking, sancho.
Keep our brains focused on something other
than our empty bellies and our dry mouths, okay?
Come on. Let's start with,
uh, your-your favorite color.
hell you doing?
I'm hungry, teddy.
Why should the both of us die out here when
one of us could help the other one survive?
You don't want to do this.
Please. I'll make it quick.
I promise!
Sancho.
Sancho!
Why'd you have to go
and do something so...
So tuxhorn doesn't keep the card on him.
It must be in there.
look, there's no way we're getting
in that house without being seen.
I know.
Well, if the card's in
there, how we gonna copy it?
We're not.
She's gonna do it for us.
What you reading?
"There is no fighting her.
"No power can fight her.
All that avails is flight."
That's homer.
That's from the odyssey.
Is this from my father's folder?
Yeah. And it explains why
scylla sounded so familiar.
If I'm not mistaken, it's
from that chapter in the book
where odysseus is told he has to
confront a monster known as scylla.
Wonder why he wrote this down.
I could be wrong, but I believe odysseus is
told that in order to continue on his path,
to pass scylla, it'll require
the sacrifice of six of his men.
His only other alternative
is to abandon his path.
And he chooses to make the sacrifice.
Well, that's a hell of a choice.
One I'm not sure I'm comfortable making.
Sara, um, about tomorrow--
the plan, the housekeeper...
if you're not up to it...
no, no, I am.
CHICAGO,ILLINOIS
Tell me, is claudia
mauricio a good roommate?
A good person?
I hope she feels the same about you.
oh, shelby, you wouldn't
believe the traffic on the...
you'll want to be quiet now, claudia.
There are levels of clearance at the department
of corrections that are simply not available,
even for friends as connected as mine.
So, listen carefully, if you even
remotely value your friend's life.
You're going to use your security code to
access the records for prisoner transfers
and tell me where they sent michael
scofield and lincoln burrows.
Can I take that for you?
- Thanks.
- Sure.
That's a great bag. Can I
ask you where you got it?
It was a gift from my boss,
so I don't really know; sorry.
Sure.
- Thanks.
- There you go.
I, uh... I can never find a good bag.
I'm a teacher, and I have books
and grading materials and...
I should probably go ahead and just
invest in a wagon one of these days.
Yeah, that's why I love this
bag. It has so many pockets.
Do you mind if I take a look?
- Oh, no.
- Thanks.
ah, thank god, thank god.
You all right, mister?
Yeah, my damn truck blew
a gasket a few miles back.
I've been, uh, hoofing it ever since.
Where you headed?
San diego.
Hell, we can give you
a ride, if you'd like.
Hey, what's wrong, man?
Eat some bad mexican?
Something like that.
Same as yesterday, right on schedule.
I hope to hell she's still
got that thing in her purse.
tuxhorn residence.
Hello, I'm from the alarm company.
We've been receiving some, uh,
strange signals from your property.
We'd like you to check
the windows, please.
Make sure all the
contacts are still active.
All the windows?
Yes, ma'am. Every room in the house.
Okay, hold on.
Does she still have the bag?
Yeah.
she's got it.
I'm picking up all kinds
of gak from the house,man.
Small stuff,maybe a digital
camera,an mp3 player.
Nothing of the size of what
we're looking for,though.
Keep her moving.
So far,so good,ma'am.
Uh,please move on to the next room.
How we doing?
Still don't got it.
If the card's in there,it'd
be in some kind of...
a safe.
Office.
Ma'am,our system is
showing that thealfunction
is coming from a room that's
designated as,uh,an office or a den.
You mean the library?
Mister doesn't like me going in there.
Well,I think he'd like it
even less if you went home
without properly setting the
alarm first,don't you think?
All right,I'll check.
We got something.
The card?
Oh,yeah.File's so big it
can't be anything else.
Now you just gotta keep her there for
two minutes while it finishes the burn.
Stall her,we need two minutes.
Ma'am,I think we found
the source of our problem--
if you could just stay
at that particular window
and hold it closed while we reset
the system,that should do it.
Talk to me,roland.
It's almost there,almost,almost.
Come on,come on,come on,come on.Come on.
Come on.
- Got it.
- Got it
All right,ma'am,thank
you so much for your help.
All we need to do now,man,is just...
whoa,whoa,whoa,whoa,she's
heading back inside.
What for?
I don't know.
Oh,no.
No,we're good.
She's out.
Hey,stop it!
Wait here.
I actually had to slow
down not to catch you.
I think I pulled a groin.
It's not in the bag.
It's not here.
How could it not be in here?
The device,it's not
here-- give me it.
son of a bitch.
Twenty-six...
Twenty-seven...
Go ahead.
Before burrows and scofield were
allegedlly transferred to arlington,
someone posted their bail.
I need to know who.
I'm showing a bruce bennett,former
aid to governor frank tancredi.
You think it fell out?
We looked everywhere.
You think we got the thing copied?
Like I said,I can't read the content
without downloading the device,but...
unless this tuxhorn's got,like,a
50,000-hour tivo,then,yeah,I think we got it.
Doesn't matter if we got
it if we can't find it.
Where the hell is it?
It's still inside the house.
That's why the maid went back inside.
She must have found it,assumed it belonged
to her boss,and then she left it behind.
Well,then guess
what,fellas,it's game over.
You know how many months it took
me to make that thing,michael?
What,you just think I can whip
up another e in a couple seconds?
Losing it is not the problem.
If they find it,that's the problem.
If they find out someone was
after that card,we're done.
What do you mean,done?What
does that mean?
Does that mean we're
gonna go back to prison?
Are they gonna kill us?
- What the hell does that mean?
- Shut up!
It means we're going in to get it.
Maybe if we had a few days,we could
figure out a way to pull this off,
but I gather we don't
have that kind of time.
Yeah,you gather right.
Look,if you want us to get that device
out of there,you gotta throw us a bone,
give us some extra help.
What you're asking for requires
involving additional people,
which,given the covert nature
of this operation,I cannot do.
Then you're asking for the impossible.
No,what I'm asking
for is competence,okay?
I'm not the one who put the entire
mission in the hands of a damn maid.
Look,if the company finds that
copy of scylla before we do,
that's it,michael,that's ball game.
They're gonna find out who was behind
it,and they're going to ghost us.
All of us.
Are you okay?
yeah.
I'm fine.
Look,I didn't choose you to do
this because I had you in custody.
I chose you to do this because
I believed you could pull it off.
Yeah,well,a lot of people have believed
in me in the last few months,agent self.
Not all of them are alive today.
Can you get me back the device or not?
All right,this is what we got.
The housekeeper saw the device
as she was leaving the house.
Then she disappears back
inside for 15 seconds.
So,we know,wherever it is,it's
somewhere close to the door.
So,15 seconds,that's all
we have to buy ourselves.
Listen,I'm not sure how close
we're gonna get to this house,
let alone inside of it,but
let's say that we do.
The alarm they got installed in
this house is triggered 1.2 seconds
after broken contact
in any door or window.
Which would immediately send
the private security guards
with their 47 guns
rushing into the property.
And after 30 seconds,the alarm company
will dispatch vehicles to the property.
Three to four,depending on availability.
After confirmation of a break-in,
they'll dispatch additional vehicles to
seal off any and all exits from the property.
I don't know about this,michael.
It's getting pretty clear why they
hired a bunch of cons to do this job.
It's not because they
wanted it off the books.
It's because we're expdable.
Who's gonna care if a bunch
of crooks wind up dead?
It's suicide.
I'm gonna keep looking
and see what I can find.
Thuote from the odyssey.
What about it?
I can't shake that line.
"All that avails is flight."
What if flight is our
onlyly option,linc?
What if our father-- after everything
he discovered about the company-- what...
what if that's what he finally realized?
You know,uh,the one thing I remember
most about dad was the back of his head.
Always walking out the front door.
Always running from something.
Mom,us,himself.
But the one thing he never ran away from
was his belief that the
company needed to be taken down.
And we got an opportunity to do that.
Then this is our fight,not theirs.
Man,this...
this ain't fox river.
These guys chose to be here.
Remember that.
They got a choice.
Almost.
Ready?
Go.
Go.come on.
let's go.
Where's it coming from?
It's across the street.
Come on.
go.
Just something across the street.
We got a team checking it out now.
You can go back inside,sir.
must be out of town.
Daddy,is everything okay?
Alex...
thanks,jim.
Alex!
Let's go.
go!
Don't turn around,
unless you'd like to experience a great deal
of pain over an even greater length of time.
You-you know, just-just
take whatever you want here.
The only thing I want from you, bruce,
is the answer to a simple question:
Where are michael scofield and lincoln burrows?
I only know what-what I read in the papers and...
three days ago, there were 105 inmates
in the supermax wing of
the U.S. Penitentiary in livingston, texas,
where the brothers were allegedly sent.
There are still 105 inmates there,
and no one has been released during that time.
Someone is playing a shell game, bruce.
I'm just trying to find out who.
I have no criminal jurisdiction over...
I know you bailed them out.
I know you've been in contact with sara tancredi.
I swear to you, I-I have no idea where they are.
I guess we'll see about that.
good luck, teddy.
Who needs luck when you got
friends like you fellas, huh?
hey, you mind if I take this
old newspaper of yours with me?
No problem. Sorry to hear about your friend, dude.
it's all right.
He had a full life.
Later, teddy.
SanDiego.PC Line.B12.36-24-36
Pacific Coach Lines
There you go.
Thirty-six, twenty-four, thirty-six.
Gate Corporation
LA
Did you get it?
Let's make sure we got what we wanted.
- Linc.
- Yeah.
- Don't let that thing out of your sight.
- All right.
We're halfway there.
All we got to do is that little b and e,
and- we're out of here.
Reminds me, I need to get ahold of self,
see when we can get started.
So what are you gonna do when all this is over?
That's a good question.
Brother, whatever this scylla thing is,
it is a monster of a code.
sara,
I was gonna come down here and ask if you wanted
to talk some more about what happened in panama,
but, um, I think I already
know what you're gonna say.
How's that?
Because you're a little like me.
Because you're gonna say you're fine,
that you can handle it.
So, um, I'll just leave it at this.
I'm here.
Whenever you want to talk, I'm here.
Thank you.
You know that the only thing that
kept me alive when I was being held
was the thought of being with you.
But I also knew that if anything happened
to me, you were gonna blame yourself,
and you would spend the rest of your life
puniing yourself for it, and...
I can't bear the thought of that.
So can we make a deal right now that we're even,
and just wipe the slate clean
and no guilt and no responsibility?
If we're gonna be together, I don't want
it to be out of a sense of obligation.
Or-or even that we should be,
because of what we've been through. I-I...
I just want to start over.
Start over.
Okay. But, uh, does that mean
I have to divorce my wife?
because you're still married
to a russian stripper.
Well, "a": I've been a little busy,
and "b": I'm pretty sure she was czech.
Hey, michael.
What's wrong?
- Whatever it is, it ain't it.
- I don't understand.
- I thought you said we copied the card.
- No, we did.
But according to the encryption code...
okay, how do I make this clear?
If-if scylla was like a pizza,
all we got's a slice.
- So where's the rest of the data?
- I don't know.
I don't know. I mean...
I mean, I don't know how we didn't see this coming.
I mean, it-it makes perfect sensE.
It's like the nuclear launch codes.
You don't give all that information
to just one person.
How many do you give it to?
Okay, that quote your father held onto-
in the odyssey, scylla is a six-headed monster
that requires a sacrifice of
six soldiers in order to pass.
So scylla isn't one card,
it's six.
What does that mean?
How we gonna find five more of these things?
Michael! Michael!
I'm busy.
I don't care what she looks like.
Three tablespoons of water, one of honey.
Nothing more.
If she knows something about anything
that's going on, I'm going to find it.
Rise and shine, bitch.
Breakfast.
Michael?
You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
All this security makes you wonder
what the company's hiding.
Only way to know for sure is to
find those five other cards, see for ourselves.
- Think we'll have enough time?
- Yeah.
We'll, uh... we'll be fine.
Prison Break
Season 4 Episode 2
www.tvsubtitles.net