Previously on prison break.
what do you want with scylla?
Same thing you want:
Bring down the company.
We need the pages.
Are we partners?
Partners.
So your brother told me
about your nosebleeds.
I'm fine.
You don't look fine.
Sorry.
Consider this a warning.
linc,pull back!
It's a trap!
You all right?
Damn,you're hit!
All right,all right.
You'll get your shot,now back off!
This is an attempt on my card.
How do you want to proceed?
I want it moved.
Move scylla.
Now!
Now,tell the general you killed us.
Otherwise,my hand,it
ain't going to get tired.
I just hope your mouth gets tired.
That's funny.
Come on,buddy,come on.
Enough already,come on,linc.
Believe me now?
Beating him isn't going to work,lincoln.
You tried your way.
We want general krantz to
think wyatt took us out.
You don't think a trained military veteran
is going to hear the fear in his voice?
They're going to know he was coerced.
I hear you,linc,but he can't
make the call if he's unconscious.
However we do it,we better get
what we need from wyatt soon,
because mahone ain't going to wait.
I'm trying to find the son
of a bitch who killed my kid!
Lisa,what are we looking at?
Initial estimate is three days
to complete the move of scylla.
Unacceptable.
Respectfully,this is not as simple as unplugging
a laptop and moving it to another room.
The data on scylla is too delicate.
I don't want excuses.
All I care is that it's done
right and done right now.
I understand the urgency,but
it will take three days.
And if I may sak freely,
I think it's a mistake to move
scylla to the raven rock bunker
when the los angeles facility is
one of the most secure ones we have.
The most secure location we have
is the one they don't know about.
Sir.
still no word from wyatt.
He only uses the company-issued
cell,so we can't track him.
We have no way of confirming if he
successfully completed his operation.
Keep calling him!
And draft a press
release,photographs,criminal records,
everything we have on
scofield,burrows,all of them.
Tell our friends in
the media I want them
to saturate the evening
news and the morning papers.
I want it impossible for them to walk down the
streets of los angeles without being spotted.
I assume we haven't made much
progress with our friend overhere?
Any suggestions?
How about we talk to him?
Great,want to give him some milk
and cookies while you're at it?
No.How about just
some nice conversation?
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync: »ğ¼ı¼ı °îÖíÖí
Prison
Break Season4 Episode09
So they sent florence nightingale
toet me all ready to cooperate.
Actually,I'm here to help
you,despite what you've done.
Because I'm still a doctor
and you're a prisoner.
You're going to save me?
Don self has a metal case out
there and I don't know what's in it.
I imagine you don't want to find
out,so I figure if you and I had a talk.
you'd make me see the light.
If you don't call the
general,you're as good as dead.
I've already been a lot of things
worse than dead in my life,doctor.
You better have more than
that to threaten me with.
Come on,mike,she's okay.
He's a professional killer.
Don't worry,he's locked up.
Let's go.
Come on,let's go!
So what'd you do with roland's body?
Roland?
He's been,uh,reconfigured and
given a permanent resting place.
Good.
Take his bowling shirts and the rest
of his crap with you when you leave.
Come on linc,the guy died.
He died a punk!
He ratted us out,bellick.
You guys,you deal with
the matter at hand.
Assuming these pages are correct,
and there's no way of knowing
that they actually are.
we follow this basement hallway
through the boiler room to here.
There's some kind of elevated walkway.
We follow that to the end,
and we've covered most of the distance
between gate and the company's headquarters.
What's this thing at
the end of the walkway?
I don't know-- whistler
marked it with an "x"
so I'm thinking it's some kind
of wall or serious impediment.
That's why we're going
down there prepared.
Tools,thermal lances,sledgehammers.
okay,so we get through that wall.
what's on the other side?
Again,I don't know.
It's because gretchen
has the rest of the pages.
But once we're through this location,
we can't go any further
until she gives them back.
What's her game in all this?
I mean,if she wants
the company to go down,
she should just give us the pages.
Look,we're going to deal with
gretchen when the time is right,okay?
You guys need to go to
gate and get started.
I'm going to stay here with wyatt
and make sure we get what we need.
No more dawdlin' now.
Move your ass.
High gear,gentlemen,high gear.
My boss will be here any minute.
I assume I don't have to mention
that discretion is paramount.
In other words,silence is golden.
You just make sure you stay in your
office and you keep other people out.
Oh,I'll stay in my
nice,air-conditioned office,pretty.
And you can crawl down
into your little hole now.
Go ahead.
Go ahead,crawl.
Vamonos.
Cole?
What the hell is going on here?
Mr.White,are you back already?
How are you?
Fine,until I found a resignation fax
waiting for me from andrew blauner.
A resignation?
Yeah,I can't get him on the
phone,I reached out to his fiancée,
she hasn't seen or heard from him.
She's worried sick.
He's probably on a bit of a
bender,just sleeping it off somewhere.
Blauner?
He's a boy scout.
None of this makes any sense,cole.
But I'll tell you what,I'm
going to look into it.
Let me know if I can
be of any assistance.
Good morning.Assistance.
What is that sound?
Yeah?
I hope you're having a
lovely enjoyable morning,
because while you are
nowhere to be found,
there is sleuthing going on here regarding
the whereabouts of one mr.Andrew blauner.
And?
And if I'm going down for this
little homicide,I ain't going alone.
We're going together
like traffic and weather.
Relax,okay?
They'll never find the
body where I put it.
Now,where are scofield and burrows?
Just doing their end of the bargain.
Which begs the question,what
the hell are you doing?
Me?
I'm getting ready for a meeting.
So,your friends have been calling a lot.
They must be wondering where you are.
That's right.
They're wondering,and the longer
they do,the more danger you're in.
Call the general,and say
what they want you to say.
And what?
You'll let me go?
No,but don self will make sure
that you spend the rest of your life
in a decent facility
without the death penalty.
Either way,if I make
the call or not,I'm dead.
You know that.
And we both know that you,as
a doctor,won't let that happen.
So,please,let's you and I figure a way
out of this mess that works for everybody.
Sit your ass down!Get out of my way!
Out!
I will cuff your ass to that table,okay?
All right,I know this is hard.
And I know what y want to do.
Okay,but I'm trying to do something here
and you need to deal with that reality.
Have you lost a kid?
Yeah,I did,too.
My wife was pregnant.
And there were complications
and the doctor messed up.
And she.
and they both.
they didn't make it.
Okay?So I understand.
What would you do if you were me
and that doctor was right there?
***What would you do?
I don't know what I would do.
Look,I'm giving you my word.
When the time is right,I
won't stand in your way.
When the time is right I won't let you.
- Okay.
Did you see the way mahone
was looking at wyatt?
The guy is hurting.
It was more than just
hurting,that's pain.
I never cared about anything like that.
I look at what I've done with my
life,beating on cons at fox river,
chasing money,trying to keep
my own ass out of prison.
This the pathway you talking about?
According to the map,this runs
almost the length of that courtyard.
It should put us directly
beneath company headquarters.
Shh,listen.
There it is again.
What's that noise,scofield?
I don't know.
Okay,just so we're clear,we get to go up
that ladder towards the noise
that we don't know what it is.
But if we're lucky,we get to basically
just walk smack into the company?
Sounds about right.
You up for it?
Oh,yeah,after you.
I am no different than
that man over there.
who wants to kill me.
Alexander mahone was forced to do
things by the company,and so was I.
But I know people.
People in government.
People that can help you and michael.
I can give you a phone number.
Arrangements can be made.
All you have to do is trust
me and this will all be over.
It is over.
Has,um,white had anything
new to say about blauner?
No,but he might.
Mr.Pfeiffer?
That would be moi.
Detective conor mara I was hoping I
could talk to you about andrew blauner.
Of course.
Great.
It's down this way.
This is it!
This is where the sound was coming from.
One of the main conduit
pipes for the la water supply.
30,000 gallons of water
rushing through th very spot.
Every second.
Oh,great.
There's got to be some other way to get
around it,some other pathway or something.
No,we took the only pathway
down and it leads right here.
How about over it?
We can't risk tunneling
too close to the surface.
What do we do?
We dig.
Truth be told,uh,mr.Blauner
isn't officially a missing person,
but his fiancée has a cousin at
the mayor's office so,here we are.
Here we are.
Hey,that's not to say though that there
aren't some things that concern me.
Really?Such as?
Well,the fax that came into white's office
anging continues came from a copy shop,
but blauner had a fax
machine at his house.
Okay.
And about a half hour after he resigned,
his car was seen
leaving the gate garage.
Now,the driver couldn't be identified,
but it appeared as though a woman's hands
were seen gripping the steering wheel.
Let me stop you right there.
It always seemed to me that mr.Blauner was,how
can I put this delicately,um,a swordsman.
You know what I mean?
Actually,I don'T.
He might be dipping his
snout into a different trough,
and the fiancée is none the wiser.
From what I've,uh,heard about
him from his other co-workers,
that doesn't sound too likely.
If you don't mind me asking,what
is that banging noise?
That's,uh.
it's trouble with the pipes.
You know,they loosened up,
it was a moderate quake and now they
shake more than the trembler itself.
Mr.Pfeiffer,uh,some people here have told
me that you and blauner didn't get along.
Would you mind talking to
me a little bit about that?
A few years ago,a partner of mine did
this same move agait an enemy combatant
we picked up at the
new mexico border--
this guy didn't want to
talk,he didn't know anything.
It worked then,
it should work now
- is that ambulance you got us still out back?
- Yeah.
Hey,come on,pal,
I got almost a decade on you
and you don't see me sucking air.
I got shot,brad.
Oh,yeah.
Guys,we ain't making any progress here.
There's nothing beneath
this cement but granite.
We couldn't get through
it with a jackhammer.
Maybe we should go back to
the warehouse,find another way.
There is no other way.
This is it!
This is where the plans lead;
this is our way to scylla.
What?
We got millions of gallons
of water in this drain pipe.
We can't go under
it,we can't go over it.
I know.
But maybe we can go through it.
it's loose!
All right,linc,this ought to do it.
After I'm done,how much time we got?
Not a lot.
Be careful.
You,too.
when I was a little boy,I
had an old tomcat named rufus.
He was a good mouser.
Tough as nails,solid feline all around.
One day,I bring home this little kitty
from a giveaway box outside the pic 'n save.
Old rufus didn't like that one bit.
He arched his back,hissed like a rattlesnake
and sprang out his claws like a switchblade.
You know,that new little kitty
didn't do nothing wrong but be new.
Now,that's all I did.
I was being new,and blauner was being
this old tomcat spraying his territory.
Now,I don't hold that against him.
If he didn't prote his turf
I'd question his character.
But aside from a little jealousy on his
part,our issues were as thin as tissues.
I assure you that.
detective,I pulled blauner's
travel schedule as per your request.
Thank you.
Uh,what's this?
Uh,sir,uh,we need to step out for a few
more bracket-joints for the shelving.
Uh,all right,yeah.
But I ain't paying you to stop for,uh,a
coffee and donuts,so get back here toot sweet.
Hey,wait up,manuel.
I hired some men,uh,out of
my own pocket of course,to,uh,
add some built-in uh,uh,storage in
my closet-- I hope you don't mind.
Nah.
Here's the monthly breakdown
of where he traveled.
you're gonna talk to me now?
Me?
No.
We're done talking.
but you're not.
wyatt's voice: They are all dead.
It's over.
wyatt's voice: This will all be over.
This will all be over.
It's over.
They are dea they are all dead.
I'm going to take this.
Self.
can you take a walk?
Yeah.
come on,sara,we should go.
Let's go outside.
My son's autopsy report said that he'D.
that he'd been shot twice.
Once in the stomach.
why,man?
Why?
Just to terrify my wife?
and then a full five
minutes later,right in the.
you too will suffer.
And when.
and when you can't
stand the pain anymore,
you'll make a phone call for me.
You know,scofield said
that torture wouldn't work
because the general would
hear the fear in your voice.
But the thing is.
I want the person on the other end of
my call to hear the fear in your voice.
Press release,sir.
In short,it sets forth that
members of the fox river eight
and their accomplices are
alive and well in los angeles.
where have you been?
They are all dead.It's over.
Good work.
Your payment will be
left where we arranged.
This is no longer necessary.
go ahead.
The access code to the covert entrance
is still both your daughters' birthdays.
Everyone leave us alone.
I said everyone leave us alone.
It's okay.
She won't hurt me.
Lisa.
I knew you'd come home.
So,how are you holding up,you
know,not being with lj and all?
Good,he's a smart kid.
He can look after himself.
I can see it,how much you love him.
My dad died when I was a little kid.
But he was a good father.
Let's just focus and get
this thing done,all right?
Michael said the manual override should
be somewhere near the main conduit.
This look like the main conduit to you?
One way to find out.
That look like it to you?
- Looks like it.
- Fire it up.
All right,let's get out of here.
Hurry up,bro!
Almost done,buddy.
All right,ease it back.
it worked.
how long we got?
I don't know.
Water cut off to thousands of people.
The city will probably have that taken care
of in about an hour,which means we've got.
60 minutes to do 90
minutes worth of work.
Or we don't t to scylla.
What's wrong,papi?
Hey,mike.
Michael!Michael!
What's wrong,papi?Papi,talk to me!
What's wrong?Talk to me!
Michael!
Michael,what's wrong?
You want some water?
I'm okay.
You're alot of things right now,my
friend,and okay ain't one of them.
You know,I may not be the
smartest guy,but I hear things.
Sara and your brother have been talking
about you not feeling well or something.
Look,I'm just,I'm just saying.
I need your help.
So,please,just,uh.
cover for me.
You got it.
Truth is,gretchen,I know you
better than you know yourself.
So you keep telling me.
When I first met you,you
were a 20 year old girl
who'd just been dumped by the wheeling police
academy for failing her psych evaluation.
But where those good old west virginia
boys could only see an emotional disconnect
with traces of sociopathic tendencies,
I saw a machiavellian streak that
would make failure an impossibility.
I had to let wyatt do what he
did because I needed to know.
What my little bulldog may have known
about whistler and his plans for scylla.
I told you that I knew nothing.
You should have believed me.
I knew you'd never take it personally,
because you are,and have been ever
since I took you under my wing.
My girl.
The most sensitive nerve
endings are right here.
That's why acupuncturists avoid
placing needles anywhere near them
because opening up the nerve
endings in the fingertip--
even a little pinprick-- can
result in quit a painful hot flash.
So a five inch needle being
driven up the length of the finger.
can make your insides
feel like they're on fire.
Another fact of physiology,the human body
when in extreme duress begins to shut down.
Brain activity decreases
and your heart rate slows
until you just can't
feel the pain anymore.
And that's where the heart
monitor and the battery come in.
'Cause when your heart
rate dips below 50,
that battery will give
you a wake-up call,
preventing your body from shutting down.
And then you will feel every ounce.
of the pain.
and that's when you're going to
beg me to make the phone call.
What can I do you for?
I.I found some more inconsistencies
in your sales reports.
Listen up here.
From that little computer of yours,can
you access into gate's records?
If I access the network as an administrator,I
can see the files in a non-pdf format.
I don't know what that
means,but I assume it was a yes.
So you let your fingers do the walking across
that keyboard and you get me my sales records.
You are hurting my arm.
And don't make me hurt
any more of you.Now,go.
That's good work.
Here.
I need you to measure this hole.
And then make one of the same
size in the wall opposite.
How?
You got a belt?
We have less than 30 minutes until
this pipe is flooded with water again.
acceptance is important,wyatt.
I had to accept I had to
accept that my son is gone.
And you have to accept that your life,
your very,very short life-span ahead of you
is just ing to be filled with agonizing pain.
At least until you do
what I've asked of you.
And then.
then the pain will go away.
We're running out of time!
- Aw,man.
- What's wrong?
The stupid thing is empty!
All right.
I'm coming in.
You can't do this,bro.
Just finish it.
Hello?
It's me.
What's going on?
Somebody needs to tell you something.
You call her by her fit name.
Pam.
I'M...
sorry.
It's over.
And I love you.
I love you.
This thing is heavy!
Sure,show up when all
the hard work is done.
All right,ease it back.
We heard on the radio that dwp is going
to have the water running in 10 minutes.
You all right?
The sleeve is too heavy to
just slide it through the pipe.
Two of us are going to have to go inside
and guide it through that other hole.
That pipe can flood at any time.
I'll do it.
I'll go,too.
No,I'll go.
Oh,no offense,college
boy,but this sucker's heavy.
You're going to need a
little bulk down there.
All right.
Use this to brace the sleeve when
you pull it through to the other side.
And,uh.
let's get the hell
out of there,all right?
How's emmy?
I didn't come here to listen to
you pretend to care about her.
or me.
I came here to tell you
that I'm a free agent now.
The community we run with know
that I'm alive and available.
I can just as easily work for
one of them as I can for you.
So the question is,what's your offer?
Actually,the question for you is why
would you want to go anywhere else?
It's not a time for grudges,gretchen.
It's a time for coming together.
The salad days are fast approaching.
Laos worked perfectly.
Soon the populace
will turn to us--
the leaders of the military,finance
and energy-- to right the ship.
And then.
we'll rebuild this
country in our own image.
And when we do,I want you
there beside me,gretchen.
As my number two,like I always promised.
What about lisa?
I've already td yoU.
You're my girl.
Come on.
Over there.
Right up there.
You and I are the same,alex.
I've done things.
push!
Bellic keep going,keep going!
keep going!
Keep going!
Yeah,it's good right there.
- You got it?
- That's it.
I don't know how long
that's going to hold.
All we got to do is
pull this thing through.
Oh,my god.Come on,guys,push!
It broke!
The beam,it broke!
mr.White.
I'm sorry to bother you,but,uh,
after my talk with detective mara,
I was thinking about mr.Blauner and
some of the conversations we had.
Salesmen are a lot like fishermen,right?
Always bragging about their big catch.
well,andy never talked about his
sales,no matter how much I pried.
So I took the liberty of.
looking them up.
And there were,to say the least.
irregularities.
good afternoon to you,too,andy.
Two of your top buyers don't have
valid social security numbers.
I checked out the social security numbers of
the clients he allegedly sold gate workshops to.
In some cases the numbers
are just pure fabrications.
But the checks must've cleared.
He's must've been money laundering for god
only knows what kind of criminal exploits.
The point is.
if the good officer gets
his hands on these papers,
you know you're going to be up
to your eyeballs in irs auditors.
I suggest you go tell mr.Mara that you found
some irregularities in blauner's expenses.
Writing off personal matters,et cetera.
This will explain why he disappeared
and will placate the po-po.
Okay.
Listen,detective.
pick it up!Pick it up!
I can't,it's too heavy!
The brace must have snapped.
Let's try and get it up!
It's not moving!
The water's coming.
The water's coming!
Come on!
We got to leave it there.
But then we'll never get scylla.
We don't have a choice.
You don't,I do.
What the hell are you doing?
Brad,don't do this!
Brad!
Grab it,grab it,now!
The water's coming!
Get your ass up here,now!
Come on,come on!
You hear that?
They're flooding the pipe.
Linc!
Get out of there!
It's too loud,he can't hear you!
Linc!
Come on,man,there's still enough
room for you to get through the hole.
I let go othis you could drop it.
It's too heavy!
Brad,drop the sleeve
and get out of there!
Don't do this.
You have a son!
Don't do this.Don't do this!
Push it!
Push it,scofield!
Push!
Push it!
Push it!Push it!
Brad!
Brad,no!
Brad!Brad,no!Brad!Brad!
Brad!
You can all come back in now.
Everything's fine.
It always was.
You're okay?
Couldn't be better.
More important: What's
happening with scylla?
I'll tell you in private.
You can tell me in front of gretchen.
Not until I say something else.
If you ever come near
him with a gun again.
you'll what?
That will do.
Scylla.
We got preliminary safeguards
in place faster than we expected.
We could move scylla
tomorrow if we wanted,
but now that wyatt's eliminated
scofield and burrows,there's no need.
Scofield and burrows are dead?
Dead as latin.
Go ahead with the plan.
If a couple of boys from illinois could
get that close,it's time to mix things up.
I want scylla out of los angeles
by the end of the day tomorrow.
He wouldn't climb up.
He just wouldn't climb up.
Whe does the south pipe lead to?
- Maybe we can follow.
- no.
No,he's gone.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync: »ğ¼ı¼ı °îÖíÖí
www.tvsubtitles.net