LINCOLN: You ready?
Didn't think I'd be this nervous.
Now or never.
All right, papi. Let's do this.
He's over there.
You must be Michael.
Your friend Fernando tells me
you could use my services today.
Very much so.
And I assume
that's the other half of your team.
- You look beautiful.
- Thank you.
It's my understanding
you'd like to keep this simple?
We've never actually managed
to keep anything simple.
(BOTH LAUGH)
You can try.
Well, let's begin then, shall we?
Family and friends, we gather here
to celebrate the union
between Michael Scofield
and Sara Tancredi.
(BAND PLAYlNG UPBEAT MUSlC)
(SlNGlNG lN SPANlSH)
Hey, papi. This one has
Puerto Rican blood in her, I think.
Look at her.
(LAUGHlNG)
(POLlCE SlREN WAlLlNG)
Sorry to break up the party.
- LlNCOLN: What the hell's going on?
- We have an arrest warrant.
- LlNCOLN: What?
- Wait, wait, wait.
Talk to Agent Paul Kellerman in DC.
We settled this with the Feds.
- We settled this with the Feds weeks ago!
- Sir, back up.
- We were exonerated.
- Sir.
- We were exonerated!
- AGENT: Back up!
We're not here for you. We're here for her.
She didn't do anything.
She wasn't involved.
AGENT: Don't make this escalate.
Sara Tancredi, you're under arrest
for the murder of Christina Hampton.
LlNCOLN: What? She didn't kill anyone!
Funny, surveillance camera footage
says different.
Michael.
POLlCEMAN 1: Please.
POLlCEMAN 2: Right this way.
- Michael. Michael.
- POLlCEMAN 1: Second car, please.
- Second car.
- MAN: What's going on?
AGENT: Back up, please.
They're not gonna let me see her.
Why did Kellerman send you
if you can't do anything?
They're trying to break both of you.
Look, she has a constitutional right
to reasonable visitation.
I'll draw up an order to show cause
and get it before a judge immediately.
While you're at it,
can you argue self-defense?
How?
Anything that might help her
is out-of-frame.
Security camera only shows Sara
stepping up and firing at the victim.
Pull the trigger, Michael.
Drop the gun!
(GUN CLlCKlNG)
Misfire.
(GUNSHOT)
- She worked for the Company.
- To you.
To a jury, she's Christina Hampton,
technology consultant.
And because she was so good
at hiding her true identity,
we can't prove otherwise.
Look, you were all exonerated.
It did not sit well with law enforcement.
If they can make Sara pay for it, they will.
How much time is she looking at?
Twenty-five to life.
(BELL RlNGlNG)
You, over here.
You, here.
This one's yours.
- Am I supposed to be in a different facility?
- I don't think so.
I haven't been convicted of anything yet.
I'm supposed to be in a jail. This is prison.
Overcrowding and budget cuts, Fish.
This is the jail. That's the prison.
What's up, homie? You need some help?
Got everything you need over there?
Why don't you go help her make her bed?
Don't let them spook you.
They just like to intimidate.
They're good at it.
Look, this jail/prison hybrid thing is BS.
Come on,
the other one's practically empty.
You can ride it out
till your court date there.
Thank you.
Here. This should be
a little bit more comfortable for you.
Okay.
What's going on?
You know, at first
I couldn't place your name, Tancredi.
Sounded so familiar.
Then Hucks here figured it out.
I remembered your pretty face
from the papers.
You're not going anywhere, Fish.
This is gonna happen.
Half a dozen guards
lost their jobs and pensions at Fox River,
another dozen were put on probation,
after you decided to leave a door open for
your boyfriend and his seven convict pals.
And we ain't gonna let
anything like that happen again.
(GRUNTS)
Don't worry. We won't hit the baby basket.
That's right.
Look like that welcome wagon
ran over your face.
It looks that way, huh?
I just came by to help you get adjusted.
If you need something,
I know all these guards.
Most of them owe me.
I appreciate that.
But I can take care of myself.
Oh!
My bad.
I don't know what made me think
you couldn't take care of yourself.
(ALL LAUGH)
All right. Well, if you need something,
you just ask for me.
Everybody calls me "Daddy."
Special delivery.
You know, all we need is a little cash
to spread around the place.
I told you,
the government's frozen my assets.
You telling me
you can't get your hands on your cash?
I mean, that's the least you could do,
considering you was gonna kill me
not too long ago.
Goodbye, Theodore.
You ain't never been incarcerated before
and I ain't never been
incarcerated here before,
and let's just say this handicapped con
ain't got the juice he had
back in Fox River.
Your pathetic existence here
could be ameliorated, as can my life,
all with a little Roberto Dinero.
One of our friends
has been apprehended by the authorities.
Looks like we've got a new neighbor.
KRANTZ: I'm never gonna get out
of this prison alive. I know that.
I want to bring my enemy down with me.
I want her dead.
Either way, it's gonna require capital,
capital you no longer have.
My rainy-day fund, you know where it is.
Jonathan, I'd assumed that
that would be used for your defense.
It's good money after bad, Joe.
They're not gonna let me out of here,
no matter how many shysters I hire.
Get that to our friend
in the sister cells across the compound.
(LAUGHlNG)
Excuse me.
SUSAN B.: Bad move.
Last time someone touched her
they got a cracked kneecap.
You're much braver
than I gave you credit for.
Either that or you're amazingly naive.
Why do you think I want to talk to you?
Just saying, a woman in your position
might opt for some protection.
Join a prison gang? I don't think so.
Not a gang, no... A family.
They don't call her "Daddy" for nothing.
That's her wife and those are her kids.
(COUGHlNG)
- Are you okay?
- You stay the hell away from me.
I need to go to the Infirmary.
You can't go to the Infirmary
without a release form.
I'm having muscle contractions
in my throat,
and my jaw is tightening up.
It's strychnine ingestion. It's rat poison.
No, that's that government cheese.
You'll get used to it.
If I don't get to the hospital
in the next 15 minutes
I will die and my baby will die. Please.
Cowler, why don't you
let her go see the doc?
(GASPlNG)
Please.
This is Cowler.
We have an inmate going to the Infirmary.
We were able to administer
the charcoal lavage in time.
You and your baby are gonna be okay.
You know the strychnine didn't get
into my meatloaf all by itself, right?
Well, then,
you need to talk to the warden about it.
Then how about talking to me
about your face?
Do you want to tell me
how that happened?
I caught an elbow playing basketball.
We should discuss your situation.
As I'm sure you've ascertained
this isn't going to be
a run-of-the-mill pregnancy.
- Do I deliver in here?
- No.
The day we induce,
we'll secure you in an ambulance,
take you to Saint Lucia down the road,
we'll cordon off a room.
There'll be three armed guards
in there with me when you give birth.
Do I get to see my baby?
You'll have 30 minutes
before we take it away.
I've seen this process a dozen times.
After the mothers come back here,
the depression is almost unbearable.
My advice, it's a lot less messy
if you just think of yourself as a surrogate.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
Yeah.
Michael, it's Blue Phillips.
Listen, your wife had an incident
earlier today.
Someone tried to poison her.
What are you talking about?
Michael, I need you to focus.
Do you have any idea
who might've done this?
Michael? Michael.
All right. Let him in.
If I had a list of all the people
who might come to visit me,
your name would be at the bottom,
somewhere below
Jesus Christ and Scooby Doo.
Someone tried to poison Sara today.
Mercy!
Only you would be depraved enough
to think that killing an innocent woman
and her unborn child
would bring you some kind of peace
before your execution.
Sara is with child?
Congratulations.
This is like the 4th of July
and Christmas day rolled into one.
I'm asking you, father to father,
to leave her alone.
You can kill me if you want to kill me.
I'll trade my life for hers.
But leave Sara alone.
Michael, if you were killed,
your pain would last a moment.
If Sara were killed,
your pain would last the rest of your life.
Now, that's got to be appealing
to whoever put out this hit.
But don't worry, Michael,
if I find out anything
I'll be sure to let you know.
WARDEN: Prison life can be tough.
If I remember correctly
you have two missing toes
that can attest to that fact.
I don't think you understand.
She's not safe here!
Please. Please just approve the transfer
to another facility.
If I grant her a transfer,
everybody is gonna want one.
What about segregated housing?
Is there something that I should know
about the structural integrity of SHU?
Great. I can see where this is going.
I know who you are
and I'm not gonna let you
turn my prison into the next Fox River.
All I'm trying to do is keep my wife alive.
- You do know she's pregnant.
- I don't care.
- Here.
- Thanks.
In case I haven't made myself clear,
Sara Tancredi is not getting
any preferential treatment.
Well, you've made yourself
perfectly clear. Thank you for your time.
- LlNCOLN: What happened?
- The General wants Sara dead
and the warden's just gonna let it happen.
Look, we got a lawyer on the case,
and he's gonna get her out, all right?
There's not enough time.
If she stays in that prison,
someone's gonna kill her.
I guess we don't have a choice.
We're breaking her out.
LANG: In my 16 years in the Bureau,
I've worked cases under
43 different agents.
Alexander Mahone is
the smartest, bravest,
most honorable man
I've ever had the pleasure of serving with.
Well, as one of those 43 agents,
I can't help but feel a bit offended,
because, obviously, I'm not as honored
as this drug-addicted murderer.
Alex has been clean and sober
for four months.
And he's been completely exonerated
of all crimes associated
with his involvement with the Company.
That doesn't include the shooting
and murder of one Oscar Shales
and burying his body under the birdbath.
That is just an allegation.
Let's move on, shall we?
All those in favor of
reinstating Alexander Mahone
as Special Agent
in the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
Aye.
- All those opposed.
- All right. All right.
(EXHALES)
Thank you for the invite, Richard.
It's always a pleasure.
You know, Alex,
this ruling can be revisited
if you are able to sufficiently demonstrate
just how committed you are
to a life of service.
Now, as you may know,
Sara Tancredi was arrested recently
and is currently being housed
at the Miami-Dade State Penitentiary.
We have concerns that Michael Scofield
may have other plans for her.
(LAUGHS)
So this...
This is why you invite me in here?
SULLlNS: Well, obviously, if Scofield
were to be able to pull off
this plot of another breakout,
the public embarrassment
would be immense to the Bureau.
So, having someone to get us
credible information,
that would be worth something to us.
Agent Wheatley is set up in Miami.
He would be your contact.
You're something else.
Now, we both know
how badly you want that badge back.
Give me a reason to give it to you.
What's your plan after we break her out?
We on the run again?
First things first. Let's get her out of there.
Hey, papi, the Fed that arrested Sara,
he's outside, staking us out.
Look, if you're worried about
getting into trouble again,
go back to Chicago, go back to your family.
I'll understand.
Are you kidding me?
After all the crap we've been through,
I'm just gonna leave you here
and Sara in there?
You shut up and don't bring it up again.
What's all that?
Newspaper clippings covering
seven different escape attempts
from Miami-Dade State Pen
over the last 60 years.
None of them... None of them successful.
So, we read them all
and we learn what not to do.
Well, the prison officials learned a lot.
They reevaluated, they retrofitted.
Prison's practically escape-proof.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Okay, so if we can't go through,
what if we go down?
Like down into the prison,
like we parachute in.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you parachute in, you find her,
- and we get her out.
- Are you kidding?
- I'm serious.
- That's suicide.
Hey! Hey, hey. Newspaper clippings
are only gonna get us so far.
We need some more information
about the prison.
So let's do some recon work.
"Camera, electronic tape measure,
dry ice." What's this?
It's a shopping list.
You need to come with me, doll.
I have a doctor's appointment
for my pregnancy in 15 minutes.
It'll wait.
In here.
Hold it.
I don't know what you want,
but I promise you, I will go down fighting.
Damn, baby, I ain't gonna hurt you.
Hell, I ain't even gonna touch you.
See, I run the motor pool detail in here,
and I was thinking,
if you want to get yourself a little fresh air
and not have to worry about
getting stuck in the back,
then you could come and work with me.
You're the Fed from my wedding.
- Yeah, you can call me Agent Wheatley.
- I could call you a lot of things.
- Where you headed?
- SeaWorld.
- SeaWorld? There isn't one in Miami.
- My loss.
No, what'd really be your loss
is getting your wife killed
by doing something stupid.
- Are you threatening Sara?
- No, no, no. Not at all.
I'm just saying, if you were gonna try
and revoke her sentence,
bullets fly, Michael.
And if she were to get hurt,
that'd be on you.
Funny, hearing that from the guy
who put her in prison in the first place.
No, I didn't put her in prison.
The State of Florida did.
It's just my job to make sure
that she stays there.
So, where's all your little buddies?
All right. Drop in some more dry ice.
(CAMERA CLlCKlNG)
(BEEPlNG)
Fence line is four feet from the road.
And 32 feet from the east camera.
Hurry up. They're gonna see the laser.
I'm going as fast as I can.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
- He follow you?
- Yeah, but he's gone now.
You guys almost done?
- Almost.
- Great.
I'll meet you back at the loft.
Why, you just a natural.
I bet you was a hell of a surgeon.
Handing out condoms to cons
don't make you no damn surgeon.
What in the hell is the matter with you?
You ain't even ask me
if she can come on over here!
One day! Morrill!
Can't we go one day
without your mouth? One!
Let it be today.
I'm sorry. You got to forgive my old lady.
She...
You just a little bit easy on the eyes,
and she's just the jealous type,
you know, so...
Crazy type is more like it.
What? You want to
watch your tongue, Agatha?
- Sorry.
- Or you want me to take off my belt?
AGATHA: All right.
(LAUGHS)
Kids.
It's rough. It's hard running a family.
It's important though that you have one.
I have a family. I have a husband.
Oh. You got a husband? Is he here?
They let him bring you in here
with you when you came?
No.
Yeah, I had a husband, too.
Eighteen years is a long time to wait.
So, you know,
if this ain't for you, that's cool.
Then you pick up that nasty oil,
and take it out and put it in the repository.
Okay.
We gotta go, bro.
- Get your hands off me.
- When I'm good and ready.
What's Burrows doing by the fence?
Please don't make me ask you again, Sara.
Nobody here to help you but yourself.
Are you gonna answer me?
You tried to kill me.
Wind it up, cons. Back inside.
You, get back to your detail now.
I want you to pass along
an offer to your boy.
What he's paying his people to dust
that Tancredi chick in bitch pop,
my woman will do it for a cut rate.
Just what kind of discount
are you proposing here?
Tell him, if he's offered 100 grand,
my girl will take 30.
No, 40, 40.
Perfect. I'll tell him.
Hey, five-star.
So, you have no cash whatsoever?
I'm sorry. I couldn't hear you
over the sound of that broken record.
Got it.
I won't ask again.
DADDY: You act as stupid as you look...
Oh. To what do we owe the honor?
I've been thinking.
Well, no need to be shy, just spit it out.
Changed my mind.
Yeah, well, maybe Daddy
changed her mind.
Maybe she don't want you here anymore.
DADDY: Squirt's right.
I recently have rolled up my welcome mat.
Peace.
- Please.
- Please what?
Please, may I be a part of your family?
Take a walk.
Take a walk!
I would love that. I...
Sit down. I really would.
But see, it's not that easy
as just saying, "I do."
See, you're making a commitment
to a family.
It's something you gotta prove.
That's right. We all did it.
DADDY: It's a commitment
to the family code.
It's a code you gotta wear.
(SCREAMlNG)
(TlRES SQUEALlNG)
Alex.
- Hey, papi.
- Hey, Sucre.
- How you doing, Linc?
- What's going on?
We gotta talk.
All right.
They're watching you.
- We know. We got a Fed on us.
- No, not just one. The whole department.
Sounds a lot like inside information, Alex.
What did you do?
Make a deal with the Feds?
They offered me my old job back
if I came down here to spy on you.
(CHUCKLES)
Now, the Fed you're talking about,
his name is Wheatley.
- He's running point.
- So now we know.
So, if you're really gonna do this,
you gotta do it right.
And I'll help you if you need me.
What else did you get?
Sara was working motor pool today
at 4:00.
Motor pool is here,
visible by two security cameras
along the perimeter of the prison.
What about secondary entrances?
No loading dock, no personnel entrance.
- Fences?
- Fifteen feet high, covered in razor wire.
SCOFlELD: Electrified?
SUCRE: No, why?
If Sara can get herself back to motor pool,
I think we can find our way inside.
With all the different retrofits
over the years,
the fence line was widened.
But the security cameras remain
exactly where they've always been.
They never accounted for the difference.
- There's a blind spot.
- Yeah. Right here.
If Sara can get back to that spot,
we can breach the fence.
LlNCOLN: It's risky, Michael.
It's all we've got.
Now we just have to tell Sara
where we're going to meet her.
How? We got no visitation
and no phone calls.
It's clean. Take it to Tancredi.
SCOFIELD: Remember what I taught you
about flowers?
I wish I was with you now
to see you holding one in your hand.
To see you holding one in your hand.
Tomorrow, p.m., 7:00, oil dump.
(DOOR OPENlNG)
Sure looks like you've been busy.
You have a warrant, Agent Wheatley?
(LAUGHS) A warrant. No, I don't need one.
My testimony will be
that your brother let me in,
and once inside, saw all this evidence
right in plain sight.
What judge is gonna take your word
over mine?
What evidence?
Those pictures were taken
from public property,
and that prison was paid for
by the tax payers.
So all you have evidence of
is an exonerated citizen
standing on a public road
taking pictures of a public building.
Last I checked, it's not a crime.
What if I said that
I could get you on attempt
just for having all this stuff?
What if I told you
that all of this was a peace offering?
The warden won't let me see my wife,
so I figured if I found
a few lapses in security,
pointed them out
as a gesture of good faith,
she might change her mind.
Is that so?
- Find anything yet?
- No, looks airtight.
You sure about that?
Nothing that some scumbag can't exploit?
Airtight.
Well, thank goodness for that.
But you guys will let me know
if anything comes up, right?
You'll be the first to know.
I won't keep you.
On the outside, I was known
for getting the job done no matter what.
I got paid well for it.
Now I'm broke.
- But I still need things.
- Like what?
- A favor?
- I don't do favors for cons.
Really? It's not what it says
on the bathroom wall.
As I understand, you do favors
for those who reciprocate.
Is that true?
Hey, this is bush league, boss.
I'm a Fed around here.
Ain't no reason to toss me.
You... Hey... You know me.
Looky, looky here.
No, that brown ain't mine, boss.
You know this.
I don't do no drugs.
Who put that in there?
You... Get your hands off me.
I know where the hole is.
What you looking at?
I don't do no drugs.
Somebody is going down for this.
I love you, too.
Sofia is making arrangements
in Central America.
Once you break Sara out,
we're on a boat and we're gone.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
- Hey.
- It's Blue.
Just got the decision from the court.
They are ordering the warden
to allow supervised visitation.
(SlGHS)
- Where you going?
- They're letting me see Sara.
Wait up, wait up, wait up.
They're going to be listening
to every word you say.
You gotta be careful about this.
If she understood my letter,
she'll find a way to tell me.
How? She gonna blink Morse code?
Oh, my God.
- Who did this to you?
- I'm okay. Baby's okay.
Sara, I'm so sorry.
You're in here because of me.
I'm sorry. It's just hard.
- I miss you so much.
- No touching.
I miss you, too.
You just have to hang in there, okay?
I'm trying, but my protection's gone.
- Did you get my letter?
- I did.
I know sometimes it's hard for me
to express what I wanna say,
but I hope you understood
what I meant to tell you.
I did.
Is he getting cute?
You were there for me.
I will be there for you.
Okay.
All right, that's it.
Time's up.
See you soon.
Bye.
WOMAN OVER PA: Attention all inmates
and visitors. Visiting hours are now over.
Please proceed immediately to the exit.
Michael.
I was thinking a lot
about the photos and the mockup
that you showed me at the loft,
and I ran a few tests.
Lo and behold, I found a blind spot
right along the fence line over here
due to a retrofit.
You didn't know about this, did you?
No. No, of course not.
Because you would've told me
or the warden about it if you did. Right?
It's a good thing I found this when I did
before anyone tried to escape.
Well, if we can't go through the fence,
then that leaves under or over.
Look, how's she gonna climb that fence
without being seen? Huh?
I'm guessing there's no telephone wire
for her to climb across.
Then she's gotta go under.
All right. Let's get some shovels.
What was that you were saying
about parachutes?
MAHONE: Parachutes?
Guys, come on. You can't be...
Parachutes?
MAHONE: A couple of thoughts on that.
A, we don't have a plane.
B, we don't have a pilot.
Have you ever worn a parachute?
Don't worry. I think I've got a plan.
But we're gonna need some help
from an old friend.
Who?
You want a favor from me.
Just hear me out.
Of course, I mean, when you and Michael
sent me back to that prison,
you did give me a piece of chewing gum.
I mean, what kind of man would I be
if I didn't quid your pro quo.
Look, all you gotta do is set off the
fire alarm in here tomorrow night at 7:30.
That's it.
You're breaking her out?
Krantz has put a hit on her.
It's our one shot of keeping her alive.
Well, you're in a pickle covered in jam,
Lincoln.
We'll put five grand in your kick
once this whole thing jumps off.
The love of Michael's life.
That's only worth $5,000?
It's the best we can do.
- I need six figures.
- It's all we've got.
Well, lucky day for you,
I know somebody who does.
The General's man.
He's got the payout for Sara's hit.
You wire that money to me
by 7:00 p.m. tomorrow,
- and we're in business.
- What's his name?
Get your brother to use that noggin of his.
Come on, you gotta give me
more than that.
Tomorrow, 7:00 p.m. Go on, fetch.
You're a tough girl to get alone.
I know he's breaking you out.
I'm coming with you.
Relax.
Krantz sent me to kill you,
but after what he's put me through,
I'm done taking orders from him.
You were sitting next to me in the mess
when I was poisoned.
You think you would've lasted this long
if I wanted you dead?
I want you dead. You're still alive.
You think it's hard to stay alive
when you know who's coming after you?
There's 200 women in this prison.
Could you even get out of Gen Pop?
I'm coming with you or nobody's going.
(SNlFFlNG)
You should've seen the look
on Michael's face
when he saw me fixing that fence
and installing that camera.
You did a great job.
Well, job's over now.
If Michael has this misguided belief
that Sara's life is in danger,
he's gonna find a way back
into that prison.
Your job won't be over
until you give us enough evidence
to put him back behind bars.
So, what's the latest?
There's nothing concrete,
but I'll let you know when I get something.
All right.
Good man.
(SlGHS)
Well, if you're watching this, I'm glad,
because that means you're safe.
How does he think he's gonna do this, bro?
He's gonna jump out of a plane.
I know he's gonna jump,
but the question is, can he land?
Not without getting caught.
And how's he gonna get her out
of the cell block?
- Even if T-Bag...
- It's a big "if."
Trusting T-Bag is just crazy.
Michael, we really have to rethink this.
I have, and there's no other way.
Okay, I'm gonna drop down
into this outer area here,
and I'll cut the parachute off
before anyone can reach me.
They're gonna be right on your ass.
I can hide behind this building,
wait for a window.
And I'll make my way over here.
That's the chapel,
where hopefully Sara will be waiting.
LlNCOLN: Why the chapel?
During a riot in '88,
prison employees escaped
through the administration building
and wound up here, outside the fence.
The administration building
is connected to the chapel,
which means that
somewhere in that compound
there's a subterranean exit.
If we can get through it,
you can meet us there.
How's Sara gonna get to the chapel?
She'll have to find a way.
Look, we're doing this at 7:00 p.m. tonight
just like we planned.
Where have you been?
What did I miss?
I need you to find a plane and a pilot.
And I need you two to take care of T-Bag.
Find out exactly who has this money
and where they're keeping it.
And then we have to get it.
By 7:00 p.m. tonight,
or Sara's gonna die in there.
Is everybody onboard?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Tell me you've completed
your assignment.
Well, I've got the cash, but
there may be some delay in final delivery.
The woman we hired is having trouble
getting near Sara Tancredi.
Then hire somebody else.
Call it open season.
Put a bounty on her head.
I don't care how you do it.
I want Sara Tancredi dead
by the end of the day.
GUARD: Open cell, one hour.
Yo, we're about to play cards.
Do you want in?
I'm okay, thanks.
You should. With Daddy gone,
you gonna need your backup.
Hell, we all do.
I've got a prenatal thing.
- It's cool.
- Thanks.
Not too smart, though,
for a girl with a bounty on her head.
Or ain't you heard?
Tancredi, you have a visitor.
Say hello to your husband for me.
(DOOR BUZZlNG)
What's wrong?
Look, I know you don't have any control
over what's happened here,
but things aren't working out.
Okay.
I've been trying to find a way to do this,
but from where we stand right now
there's only one option.
Do you need more time to think?
No. No, it's not that.
I've made up my mind.
There's really nothing you can do about it,
except pray for us tonight.
Pray for us?
You can pray for us to be together.
Maybe I'll do the same.
How can I rob someone
if I have no clue who he is?
The log book outside says that Krantz
had one visitor yesterday. Joe Daniels.
Well, using the power of deduction,
I'd say Daniels is your bagman.
You know how many Daniels
live in Miami? Thousands. I need more.
Well, you better get cracking,
'cause if I ain't got that money by 7:00,
you ain't got your fire,
you ain't got your fire alarm,
and that means Pretty
ain't got his Mrs. Pretty.
Listen, my friend, you're in no position
to make demands.
(SHUSHlNG) Okay. I ain't talking
about backing out of the deal.
I'll put my ear to the ground
and come up with some details.
Good. Now go fetch.
(SlGHS)
We got a pilot.
It's a guy I busted 20 years ago
running drugs across the Gulf.
Went legit, runs a charter business now.
You must've jumped out
of a few planes, huh?
Yeah. Several.
Some for sport, some necessity.
It's a big difference, Michael.
It's not easy hitting the X,
especially at night.
Don't worry. I can go alone.
- What do you got?
- It's a test.
See, the prison was built in the mid '80s,
so that exit in the administration building
is probably protected
by an electronic coded lock
modified by a security card.
Those locks don't have power protection,
which means you can override them.
And you can't just go to the building's
generator and blow it out?
No, a 1,200 volt power surge
will just set off the other alarms.
Not to mention maybe kill you.
- It's why we have to find another way.
- Yeah.
(CELL PHONE BUZZlNG)
Yeah.
Talk to me, Mahone. What do you got?
- Nothing yet.
- I don't need updates on the hour.
I need evidence. Intent, it's not crap.
Call me when he's in the process
of committing a crime.
- Yeah.
- I'm not gonna let him walk away from me
like he did from you.
He's going down
if I gotta shoot him in the back.
Sorry.
Time for me to get paid, now, Fish.
(WOMEN SHOUTlNG)
Are we friends now?
Get out of the way.
What happened here?
I didn't see anything, sir.
- Move.
- Me neither.
What?
Bad news.
Agatha Warren is dead.
- Who did that?
- No one's talking.
But I hear it's those fish,
Tancredi and Morgan.
No!
MAHONE: Here he is.
If you don't like this guy,
we can still find someone else.
Good to see you, Sidney.
What you getting into here, Mahone?
Jumping at 1,500 feet
ain't going to be easy.
You going back on your word already?
Let's not forget
who's doing who a favor here.
Favor?
Favor? Did I bust your old lady
for trafficking? No, I did not.
If anyone asks,
I was flying a tourist to the Keys
and it's not my fault he jumped.
Sounds good to me.
If you don't like this guy, we take a day,
we come up with a new plan.
No. There's no time, Alex.
- It's not just Sara's life at risk.
- I understand that.
I know you do. That's why I also know
I can ask for your help.
Yeah. What do you need?
If I don't make it,
I want you to make sure Sara and
my brother get out of the country alive.
I need to know they're gonna be okay.
And I'm gonna trust that you'll do
everything you can to make that happen.
Take this.
I trust you, Alex.
Remember that.
- Special delivery.
- What is it?
Don't exactly know.
Came via messenger from the ladies' side.
My man on the outside needs to know
who to call for the birthday present.
Whose birthday is it?
Okay. See to it
it gets back to the same place.
Will do.
This is Joe Daniels' number, right?
That's it. Is that enough information,
or you need a social security number, too?
- It'll do.
- Remember, I want that money wired
to the account number specified.
No wire. No fire.
You boys do me wrong,
I have no qualms at all
about singing loud and clear,
you understand?
You know what? Just be ready.
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)
That was Sofia.
She'll meet you in the San Andres Harbor
in the Dominican Republic
and then you guys can fly to Costa Rica.
Cool. I know where Daniels is.
And after we rob him, I'll take the money
to Quik Green and wire it to the bank.
And you're gonna meet us
at the airstrip, right?
- I'll give it a shot, yeah.
- Okay. This is it.
(SlGHlNG) We're ready.
Thanks, buddy. For everything.
Good luck, papi.
See you on the other side.
Nobody's talking, huh?
Girl's dead and no one says anything.
I made it in the woodshop.
Want to give my daughter, Emily,
her birthday gift on her actual birthday.
That's why I need to get out of here.
- How very sentimental.
- I'm not. It's just for her.
We need to get to the chapel.
We?
There's no way out of here, right now,
I'm gonna need you.
Yeah.
Mr. Daniels, American Paint Company
here for the job.
Well, this is Mr. Daniels
and I didn't order any painters.
It's Wednesday, sir. I believe you did.
Okay, hold it right there.
I'm calling the police.
Get out.
SCOFlELD: This is it.
I'll be right back.
I gotta get that parachute.
Michael, come here.
There's a better way.
GUARD 1: Mess! Mess, half hour.
GUARD 2: Okay, let's go, girls.
GUARD 3: Clean up.
Little faster. We don't have all day.
GUARD 4: Let's go.
- Got any ideas?
- Yeah.
Keep your head down and follow me.
I'll think of something.
GUARD 4: Single line! Single line!
You better think of something fast
'cause we have company.
GUARD 1: Keep walking, keep walking.
I hope you're ready for a fight, princess.
This one's to the death.
Do you think you can overpower her?
Yeah.
I don't think it's her
you have to worry about.
Just be ready.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
Hello.
It's me. I got the message
about the birthday present.
Was the gift earned?
What in the hell are you talking about?
- The birthday present.
- The birthday present?
Two guys showed up at my house,
they took the money
and they beat the crap out of...
Howdy, General.
I just thought I'd let you know
I came into some green.
My personal preference is two Zagnut bars
and a copy of The Times.
So I'll see you in the a.m.
You worthless son of a whore. Go to hell!
Careful I don't get there first,
lest I become king of that prison, too.
All right, from takeoff to prison's
gonna come up real fast.
So whatever you got to do to get ready,
do it now.
We got it.
You got the money?
Sucre just dropped me off
on the way to wire him.
Good. That means T-Bag's set.
I'm gonna see
how long it's gonna take him to get going.
- You sure that thing's gonna hold you up?
- Yeah, it'll be fine.
What about you?
It's not my first time inside a prison.
Hopefully, it'll be my last.
(DlALlNG)
LlNCOLN: Think about all the amazing
stories you'll be able to tell your kid.
You're gonna be the type of father
our dad never was.
Someone to look up to.
Take care, Michael.
WHEATLEY: Unless you've got details,
I'm hanging up.
You can forget about
getting your badge back.
He's got a plane.
He's gonna parachute into the yard.
- What?
- Yeah. I swear to God.
He's gonna be over prison airspace at 7:00.
Call in reinforcements.
I want 20 armed COs in the yard.
And be ready to turn off all exterior lights.
Scofield won't see what's coming
until it's too late.
And bring me Sara Tancredi.
Wait. Wait.
What you think happened with Agatha,
it's not what happened.
I need to make this right with you, okay?
Go ahead.
I was hoping I'd see you here.
You know I still owe you
one big juicy favor.
Later, blue eyes.
I swear to God, she wanted to kill me
and I was just defending myself.
- Remember this?
- Yes, I do.
My mama gave me that.
Told me I was going to give it
to one of my kids one day.
I never did get knocked up.
But I grew up a family.
And I practically raised Agatha.
She was no killer.
Now, I can't say that much for myself.
You don't even know
what I had in mind yet.
Okay, listen, you're right.
Agatha isn't a killer.
She's just a greedy little bitch
who bit off more than she could chew.
(GRUNTS)
Skittlez.
Okay, we're cool. We're cool.
(STAMMERlNG) We're cool. We...
GUARD: Cowler, Simms wants you
to bring Tancredi to her office.
All right. Okay.
(GRUNTlNG)
(ALL SCREAMlNG)
(SCREAMS)
Son of a bitch.
They'll be coming back
through here, okay?
Federal Agent Todd Wheatley,
I need to get inside right now.
Emergency team takes priority, sir.
I'm the leader of the emergency team.
Now let me inside.
- Sir, I have strict orders.
- Go talk to your supervisor. Come on.
Yo, Evans, let the suburban through.
The planes will be overhead any minute.
Hey, fellows, kill the lights.
As soon as he hits the ground,
that's when I want you to start firing.
Stand by.
We're standing by.
Easy there. Hold your fire.
Stand by.
Now.
- Let's go.
- POLlCEMAN: Move in, men.
GUARD: Hold your fire! Hold your fire.
Sixteen, hold your fire.
Moving in.
Where the hell is Scofield?
Emergency team takes priority, sir.
I'm the leader of the emergency team.
Now let me inside right now.
I have strict orders,
no one gets inside at this point, sir.
I don't care what your orders are.
Go talk to your supervisor.
(ALARM BLARlNG)
(ALL SCREAMlNG)
WARDEN ON RADIO: Why isn't Tancredi
in front of me right now?
Well, we just got this situation
under control.
- We're looking for her right now.
- WOMAN: I didn't do anything.
Oh, my God.
- Are you all right?
- It was Morgan.
Check the kitchen.
They might be in the kitchen.
I'm not gonna make it on my own.
Either leave me or don't, Sara,
but make up your damn mind.
You gonna be able to make it?
- Yeah.
- Okay. It's now.
POLlCEMAN: Hold up.
(ALARM CONTlNUES BLARlNG)
No, I think we're good.
POLlCEMAN: Don't move!
Skirt in the dirt, now!
- Please, I just...
- On the ground.
You here alone?
Damn it, con!
When I ask you a question, you answer.
Is there anyone else here?
Yes.
Who?
- God.
- Excuse me?
He's always here.
I was worried about
my little girl on the outside.
So I came to pray.
See if someone would watch over her.
Go check it out.
GUARD OVER RADIO: I want some asses
over in the women's cell block now!
We got to get these animals locked down.
We better head over there.
I hope that daughter of yours
is a hell of a lot smarter than you.
So do l.
Hey!
- You ready to go?
- (SlGHlNG) Yeah.
WHEATLEY: Nobody gets in
or out of this prison.
I don't care if it's the president
having to take a piss,
you tell him to turn the hell around.
And get a team.
I want every inch of that fence line
checked for points of compromise.
Yes, sir.
Michael said
this is where they're gonna come out.
You think Sucre made the drop on time?
Don't know.
(BANGlNG ON DOOR)
No, no, no, no!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Please enter your account number.
Nine, two, four, eight, pound.
Your account balance is
zero dollars and zero cents.
If you would like to access
another account...
Nine, two, four, eight, pound.
Your account balance is
zero dollars and zero...
What the hell do you think you're doing,
Fish? We in lockdown.
What for?
Something's going on in bitch block.
I don't know.
What's it worth to you to find out?
We gotta get through here?
On the other side is a kind of
escape hatch for the administrators
in case of a riot.
If this is the same system they have
in Fox River,
that door can only be opened remotely
from the central control room.
That's why we had to ask for help.
T- Bag.
Tell them what you told me.
Michael Scofield's about
to stage a prison break.
And I know exactly
how he's going to do it.
Exactly what did Scofield ask you to do?
Just light a fire in my cell,
and the rest will just take care of itself.
Fire alarm. When that goes off,
what's your protocol?
State law, mandatory evac.
Yeah, he wasn't gonna break her out,
he was gonna get you to escort her out.
Shut up. Get him out of here.
All right. Evacuation's only
going to get him out in the yard.
Whatever he's up to,
he needs noise and he needs chaos.
Deactivate the smoke detector system,
the fire alarm,
and while you're at it, kill the horn.
If anybody so much as bends
a blade of grass in this place,
I want to be able to hear it.
- What are we waiting for?
- We made a deal.
For the right price,
T- Bag would set off the fire alarms.
(ALARM STOPS)
That's what we were waiting for.
- Michael, there's a...
- It's okay.
See, there's only one thing you can
count on when you're dealing with T-Bag.
He's a rat.
Anything?
So far, just a female inmate
loose in the yard.
- Tancredi?
- No, Morgan, first name, Gretchen.
- Over by the chapel.
- All right.
SCOFlELD: All right.
Great. Let's go.
Okay, down there.
Okay.
Beyond this door should be
a hundred yards of tunnel.
On the other end of that is Linc,
and after that there's a boat
bound for white sand and blue water.
I'll power-surge this system. It will
override the reader for just a few seconds,
just long enough for you
to open the hatch, so get ready.
Three, two, one.
One more time.
I was afraid this might happen.
That's okay. It's all right.
We're gonna keep moving and
we're gonna find another way out of here.
I know what I have to do.
I need units to the chapel now.
POLICEMAN: Unit five-three, ten-four.
- Where are they?
- I don't know.
They should have been here by now.
The battery wasn't
generating enough power.
We have to blow the system
for the whole building.
Okay, what do you want to try?
This is the main fuse. If I yank that,
everything will go dark for a second.
If I reconnect these two cables...
If I reconnect these two cables,
there'll be a lot of noise.
Every light bulb
in this place is gonna blow.
As soon as that happens,
you need to open that hatch.
And then I want you to start running.
Okay. What about you?
Michael?
Sara...
Someone has to stay here,
and someone has to open the hatch.
And that someone's got to be you.
Okay. So I'll leave it open for you.
You don't understand.
This is the only way.
I'm not leaving
unless you're coming with me.
I am coming with you.
I love you.
God! I love you too.
(BANGlNG ON DOOR)
Go.
Go, Sara. Go.
Downstairs.
Where's Michael?
Sara, where's... Where's Michael?
Where is he?
He's not coming back.
(LlNCOLN BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
- He's not coming back.
- What?
What do you mean, he's not coming back?
What do you mean by that?
He's not coming back.
LlNCOLN: He'll be here.
He's gone, Linc.
Linc, we got to go.
We got to go.
GUARD: Gate 2 will be
open in a minute.
T- BAG: Why am I being punished?
I'm the guy who blew the whistle.
You aided and abetted an escape,
Mr. Bagwell.
As far as the authorities are concerned,
you're an accomplice.
Scofield!
Michael asked me to give you this
if he didn't make it out.
He said it would help you understand
why he did what he did.
It's his blood work.
This is the General's money.
I was supposed to wire it down
to Costa Rica for you to pick up, but
I ran into some trouble.
I'm sorry.
You take care of that baby, okay?
You take care of yours.
This is for you.
He never said anything to me.
Why didn't he just tell me?
Because he knew you'd try to stop him.
He knew you'd do anything
to protect your family.
But I didn't.
MAHONE: Well,
you will soon.
Take it easy.
Sara.
Thank you.
Yeah.
(SlGHS)
Well, if you're watching this, I'm glad,
because it means you're safe.
And that's all I ever wanted.
I wish I could be there with you.
But as you probably know now,
I wouldn't have had much time anyway.
So, I made my choice,
and I dont regret it.
Anyway, not too long from now
there's going to be another
little Scofield running around.
And Linc, I want you to promise me,
no matter what, they're going to grow up
knowing their uncle's never far away.
And Sara, I want you to promise me
that you're gonna keep an eye on Linc.
As you may have noticed,
he has a tendency to get in trouble.
(LAUGHS)
You know, we spend so much of our lives
not saying the things we want to say.
The things we should say.
We speak in code and we
send little messages, origami.
So now, plainly and simply,
I want to say that I love you both
very much.
And I want you to promise me
that you're going to tell my child...
That you're going to tell my child
how much they're loved every day.
And remind them
how lucky they are to be free.
Because we are.
We're free now.
Finally.
We're free.
www.tvsubtitles.net