Previously on Prison Break:
This is Scylla.
You're not even close
to getting out of here.
- Dad, it's me.
- Lisa?
I'm at gunpoint. It's Tancredi.
She says if you don't let Michael and
the others leave with Scylla, she'll kill me.
Don't move.
- I'm leaving.
- No, Mr. White.
- Turn around.
- Gentle, now, sugar.
That's "Special Agent Miriam Holtz"
to you, sugar.
- We have it.
- They got it.
I never thought you'd make it this far.
I was wrong.
What now?
This is all your transfer paperwork.
I need to get to Dallow ASAP.
- What happened to Gretchen?
- She got away.
Self.
- He screwed us.
- Self can't do that.
He's government.
He can do what he pleases.
The vans are coming. They're just late.
- He ain't coming back.
- You don't know that, Linc. They're coming.
What do we do now?
Call Homeland.
See how much they know about Self.
- Stanton.
- Herb, it was Scofield and Burrows.
- Are you at the senator's office?
- Look, I'm shot.
I'm shot.
- Miriam's gone, okay?
- What's your position?
You were right
about this whole operation.
No. Burrows. Burrows!
Don. Don!
No, no, no.
I need to find Gretchen.
You gonna help me, or are you gonna
make me shoot you in the face?
Help.
Department of Homeland Security.
I'd like to talk to Don Self's superior,
please.
One moment, please.
We gave this guy
something worth $ 100 million.
Is he even with Homeland?
Did we see a badge?
We were given guns
and flown out on a C-130.
He didn't work for the DMV.
- That doesn't make him the law.
- No, it don't.
What if Homeland was in on this
from the beginning?
This is Herb Stanton. Who is this?
Hello? Hello?
The way Self played this, no, no, no,
he kept himself too insulated.
That's why he hesitated with official
authorizations on behalf of our mission.
He kept saying
he didn't want the Company to find out.
It's because he didn't wanna get caught,
the son of a bitch.
He kept the circle tight
and left the rest of us holding the bag.
If Homeland knows where we're at,
sooner or later they're coming for us.
Let them come. We didn't
do anything wrong. We have deals.
No, we have paper. That's what Self left us.
We gotta get out of here.
We can't leave. Michael needs surgery.
I'm not talking about running.
I'm talking about surviving.
What I want is to see the Company
burn to the ground...
...and you in prison.
We did this to you.
They're ready for you downstairs, sir.
Today marks a critical juncture
in our endeavor.
Do we have a bead on Scylla yet?
Our security, our future,
stands at a great precipice.
It's a yes-or-no question, Jonathan.
We don't need a soliloquy.
Howard,
why don't you wait in my office?
No.
I'm in here making sure
this operation isn't fumbled as well.
Out. Now.
What's your plan, Jonathan?
That's what we're all here for, right?
You tried to move Scylla
over our better judgment, and it backfired.
So spill it.
Any further questions?
Very well. You have your assignments.
Access your assets
and retrieve Scylla today.
Yeah, well, a lot of people have believed
in me in the last few months, Agent Self.
Not all of them are alive today.
I can't shake that line.
"All that avails is flight."
Come on.
Here, take that.
Sara's right.
We're need to get you to a hospital now.
We were so close to the finish line, Linc.
- So close.
- Yeah, I know. Yeah, I know.
Listen...
...I spoke to L.J. Yesterday.
Told him this was almost over.
I'm keeping my word to my son, Michael.
- I should have seen this coming.
- No, no, it's no one's fault.
Self played all of us.
But we gotta get out of here.
This is our last option.
Yeah.
- Check upstairs.
- Clear.
It's clear.
- Got anything?
- Clear.
Now we know where we stand.
Let's go.
Hello?
- Michael Scofield?
- Yes.
Herb Stanton,
Department of Homeland Security.
We wanna talk. Can you please come back
to the warehouse?
All right.
But first we're gonna need
some assurances.
- What kind of assurances?
- Look, we held up our end of the deal.
We're gonna need you
to honor the terms of our agreements.
I'd have to look at those terms...
...but I'm fairly certain
it didn't include stealing Scylla...
...or killing two federal agents
in cold blood.
What are you talking about?
Here are the new terms
I'm prepared to offer.
- Come back, turn yourselves in.
- Wait a minute, Self set us up.
Don't and I'll hunt you down
like animals.
We did what they said.
I ain't going down
on some trumped-up murder charge.
Self pinned two murders on us.
- What are you doing, Linc?
- Lf Homeland Security comes...
- Then we'll handle it.
- You know what?
There's a point where you draw the line.
Now's the time to draw that line.
Don't be stupid.
You can't fight off Homeland Security.
Stupid is listening to the government.
I ain't going back to death row.
We can still hold on to our deals.
All we have to do is flush Self out...
...prove he has Scylla.
- And how are we gonna do that?
- Devise another strategy.
No, we should start devising a plan
that can get us across the Mexican border.
That's what we should do.
My cousin can hook us up.
We're not running.
I can't.
Negative on Scofield,
Burrows and Mahone.
TDZ think that Self
may be using a bakergrip...
...to mask his cell-phone signal.
Place a tactical team around Homeland.
If Self or any of those other bastards
show up...
...make well damn sure
they don't get near the building.
I can't go back
to living in and out of motels...
...constantly looking over my shoulder.
Nothing changes.
We take down the Company.
We finish what we started.
Who are you calling?
- The doctor.
- Sara, not now.
- When?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, listen.
Cole Pfeiffer, an employee of GA TE,
a downtown wellness organization...
... and his yet-unidentified
female accomplice...
... both seen here in police sketches.
- And them?
- Gretchen.
Bagwell?
Have our people at DOT
monitor every traffic camera...
...from San Diego to the Bay Area.
I can't believe you shot him.
Knowing when to sever a cancerous limb
to preserve the rest of the body...
He was one
of your most trusted advisors...
When I brought you in...
...I told you that a cardholder
has certain responsibilities.
If you can't handle
what we're doing here...
...it's time you let me know.
- Gregory White,
who was shot and killed in the standoff.
Police are trying to determine
whether revenge or robbery was the motive.
Cole Pfeiffer was a recent addition
to the Los Angeles...
Maybe we weren't
the only ones left hanging, huh?
If we're gonna flush Self out...
...how do you think he intended
to unload Scylla?
- Gretchen.
- He's gotta sell it.
Tell me when I'm getting warm.
You handpicked Michael Scofield
and the bunch...
...trucked them all out here
on Uncle Sam's dime to do your bidding...
...and now they're standing
right in the cross hairs for what you did.
I gotta hand it to you, Don,
if that ain't the Mona Lisa.
I always said cops are more crooked
than criminals.
Let me guess, a little slice of heaven?
Is that what it was for?
Gambling debt?
Maybe you're a geologist
of the rock-candy variety?
The information you got
from Gretchen's prints.
- You sure it's the right address?
- Right as rain.
Good, now shut up
or I'm gonna shoot you.
You understand me? Shut your mouth.
- I ain't...
- Shut your mouth.
- I know when to shut...
- Be quiet.
How long does it take
to find a payphone in this city?
They'll be back.
Okay.
- Same deal as before.
- Yup.
No physical duress
for the next eight hours.
Here's the thing. You need help.
And running around
trying to track down Self isn't...
...safe.
You could be in Mexico in a few hours.
There are doctors there that I trust.
And you've been taking care of all of us.
I think it's okay if we take care of you.
Surgery or no surgery, I'm never gonna
be able to live with myself...
...unless I find a way
to take these people down.
It's that simple.
And I get it.
I'm not gonna demand
that you feel the same way.
We can't trust anyone.
Government, law enforcement.
- We should consider getting out of here.
- No, we deal with this now.
I want this guy as much as you,
but we're scrambling.
I don't know
how long Self's been planning this.
From the looks of it, it's pretty airtight.
- Gretchen.
- I hope you are calling...
...to tell me where Scylla is, Lincoln.
- You don't know?
- I don't know. What's going on?
Self double crossed us,
and he took Scylla.
You know where he could be?
If I'm Self, I'm looking for a new buyer.
A new buyer? You know what?
If you're playing me,
I'm gonna split you in half.
Yeah. I want him just as badly as you do.
Where are you? I'm coming to you.
Grand Hope Park. One hour.
- What?
- Sis.
It's Emily. She's been in an accident.
Tell whoever's got that gun pointed at you
to grow a set...
... and get on the phone.
She wants to talk to you.
What's up, Gretchen?
Time to come home now.
Are we really gonna
keep trusting that bitch?
Gretchen and T-Bag were waiting at GATE
with machine guns, guys.
You think they just wanted
to provide cover?
This chick's a mercenary.
She'll do whatever it takes
to get what she wants.
We just happen to want the same thing.
We are taking precautions...
...but one way or the other,
Gretchen's gonna get us to Self.
Right now that is all that matters.
We don't stand a chance.
Our photos aren't plastered
all over the TV.
Homeland's keeping it in-house.
We have a chance.
- Senator.
- Herb.
We sponsored this operation
with the best of intentions...
...but the secretive manner
in which we've handled it...
...I now fear is working against us.
- How so?
- We're in the middle of a manhunt...
...and it's just you
and a couple of agents out there...
...trying to reign in these cons.
It's madness.
What we initially sponsored...
...didn't pan out.
That doesn't mean
that the boat is taking on water.
No one knows.
That's the way it's going to stay.
Come in.
Good afternoon.
Richard Sooter, U.S. Marshals Service.
I've been sent at the request
of Deputy Director Esmar...
...to get to the bottom
of the Scofield-Burrows supermax story.
I'm hoping you gentlemen can help.
Guys, if there's a reason
you're keeping secrets, just fill me in here.
I can help.
How strong is your stomach?
Very.
Herb Stanton.
He's working with Donald Self.
We got a record of all incoming
and outgoing calls from Homeland today.
Stanton received a call
lasting approximately one minute...
...that was connected to no one.
- No one that we could identify.
- Self's phone.
DOT has a positive ID on Gretchen
from a traffic cam.
She's still in Los Angeles.
Chris is on the phone from Johannesburg,
looking for an update.
I'll call back.
Now, about this Mr. Stanton...
Alex, how are you doing?
No sign of Gretchen yet.
Linc?
- No sign of Gretchen.
- Sucre?
She ain't here yet, bro.
Sara?
All clear.
All right, here we go.
That's far enough.
I'm sorry, Rita.
I promise everything's gonna be okay.
Yeah, we're all friends here, Rita.
Don't worry about a thing.
You know, sending Feng after me
almost cost me my life.
And it did cost me my plan,
which is why you're here, Gretchen.
You're gonna help me find a new buyer
for Scylla.
You been talking to Scofield
and the boys, huh?
Yeah.
- How are they?
- They're good and pissed.
Yeah? Where are they?
Gee, Don, I don't know.
I'm not their mother.
You're not their mother, but...
She looks just like you.
Doesn't she?
She's got those big blue eyes.
I'm supposed to meet them
in half an hour.
Get ready to phone in a tip to Homeland.
Where at?
Where?
To perform the operation,
that would require signatures...
...from 20 different department heads.
Now, the only way this is gonna work
is via freelancer, off the books.
I should be thanking you.
Because of what you've done,
lives are gonna be changed forever.
Scofield, you reconsider my offer?
If I get you Self, if I can get you Scylla,
are you gonna be able to hold up our deals?
How do you intend doing that?
Well, that's what we're working on.
The feds, they're here.
We were set up.
Hands where I can see them, right now.
- Turn him around.
- Hands behind your back.
- Got him?
- Yeah.
- Right now.
- Up against the car. Up against the car.
Killing two federal agents ought to put you
back on top of death row, Mr. Burrows.
We didn't kill anyone. Self's behind this.
Don Self was a decorated agent
and an honorable man.
Yeah.
But you wouldn't be the first guy to sit in
that chair and try to sell me a bill of goods.
Why weren't we to Mexico
by the time you worked things out?
- You slipped up.
- No, we were in the dark as much as you.
We know what happened, Burrows.
You're not putting this together.
Think how much Scylla's worth.
Think of the length's that Self went to
to keep this thing off the books.
And us, us, of all people...
...pulling this job off?
Where are the bodies?
For five minutes stop thinking about us
and focus on Self.
Why would we jeopardize our freedom?
It's the only thing
we've ever cared about.
- Where's Fernando?
- He's on his way.
I still have a friend in the bureau
we can reach out to.
Maybe she can see
where they're holding Linc.
Who are you calling?
- It's Scofield.
- All right, so answer it.
I should've put a bullet in your face.
- I'm not the one who set you up, Michael.
- Yeah? Who did?
You know,
I meant what I said before, Michael.
I like your style, okay?
You're a smart guy.
Unfortunately for you,
I'm just a little bit smarter.
Yeah, we'll see about that.
I heard Homeland made a surprise visit
to the plaza, huh?
Look, I'm gonna give you
some parting advice.
Run, okay?
Get your pals and just start running.
We gotta go. Michael, we gotta go.
I appreciate all your help.
I'm gonna go sell Scylla now.
Don, you're not going anywhere.
Really? Okay.
- Who's the buyer?
- His name is Vikan.
- And he's not a buyer, he's a conduit.
- A conduit to what?
We're not exactly moving heroin here.
It's a little bit more specialized.
There's about five people
who know what to do with Scylla...
...and are willing to pay for it.
All right, let's go.
And Bagwell's staying here.
You will remain captive in my negativity
if you lay a hand on either one of them.
I warned you not to screw me over.
How could you?
I'll be back very, very soon.
And I promise you
that that man is not gonna hurt you.
How could you?
I'm gonna fix this.
Wow, Gretchen,
you're making friends left and right, huh?
Now move your ass.
We've accessed Self's EID...
...and have been able to get the files
he tried to delete.
They're giving us a lot clearer a picture
of who he is and what he's been up to.
Honorable, huh?
What did you find out?
A name, Robert Walker...
...the new identity
Self was planning on using.
We found a Social Security number,
a bank account in the Caymans...
...credit cards, and a flight itinerary
out of the country for tomorrow morning.
So first of all...
...we owe you an apology.
Second, when we get our hands on him,
it's gonna be paramount to get your help.
- How?
- Your testimony...
...and the testimony of your brother
and the others against Self...
...in exchange for full immunity.
- You walk away.
- We already had a deal.
If you walk now,
there will be no one left to tell the tale.
DHS needs you to cover its ass.
We can't spend our time
chasing your friends.
They need to come in
so we can work out the details.
What if they don't?
We got a whole bunch of trust issues.
Then you'll all rot in a supermax prison.
DHS is prepared to fly
into the face of this thing or to bury it.
It's your choice, Mr. Burrows.
This is the best you're gonna do.
- Michael.
- Linc, where are you?
In the warehouse. Put me on speaker.
Homeland knows Self screwed us.
What do we have?
They found a file he thought he deleted...
...with an international bank account
and one-way ticket out.
So it's over?
Yeah, well...
...if we testify against Self,
we get full immunity.
Immunity from what?
We did the job they hired us to do.
Michael, Senator Conrad Dallow.
We have evidence
that supports your claims.
I'm giving you're my word,
your troubles are over now.
Please come in so we can end this.
Okay, I've decided...
...or rather I think,
that we should hear the senator out.
And if everything goes south,
then I do have a backup plan.
Go with Sara to the meeting
and get a lookout.
Alex and I make sure
they don't bring surprises...
...by doubling back to the warehouse...
...and then following them
to the rendezvous.
This is where we're meeting the senator.
- All right?
- We'll be there.
You know,
my father spent most of his political life...
...chasing justice.
It was sort of an obsession.
And my mother and I
could never understand...
...why he would so easily
make other people's problems his own.
And I think that's why she left him.
And, Michael, you remind me
more and more of him these days.
The way you put everybody else's problems
before your own.
That said...
...I want you to know...
...that if this meeting with Senator Dallow
doesn't go the way you want it to...
...you don't have to worry
about you and I.
Nothing's...
Nothing's gonna come between us.
Yeah.
And everything is gonna be okay, right?
You know, I figured it out.
DHS wined and dined you in the beginning
and promised you the world...
...and then they ultimately settled
on a broom closet...
...next to some schmuck from the FAA,
and you said no.
Gretchen,
you have a real keen sense of perception.
It's amazing.
And this all ends
with a three-story hut in Tahiti, right?
Flat-screen TV, a couple Jet Skis outside.
But what you're gonna find, Don,
is that when the rush is over...
...you're done patting yourself on the back,
and there's no one to tell the story to...
...you're gonna be just as alone
as you are now.
That's who Don Self is.
- Is that right?
- You tell me.
- Yeah?
- Take out your gun.
- What's going on?
- You want your cut or not, Bagwell?
- Take out your gun.
- Relax, Don.
All right.
Now point it at her head.
Don.
- Pull back the hammer.
- Don!
- Don.
- I want my money.
I wanna be on a plane
by the end of today.
Otherwise you and your family
are gonna find out who the real Self is.
- It's him.
- Do you understand me?
We're set.
Okay? That's him.
Please.
I'll call you back.
1714 East 7th Street.
- This can't be right.
- You sure this is what he wrote down?
That's what it says.
It's a parking lot.
Why would Michael pick here?
I thought you were going
to the warehouse.
Michael sent me ahead.
- What's going on? Where is he?
- He's safe. Michael's safe.
We're not gonna be able to do this alone.
He's doing what he has to do,
and we have to do our part.
And right now that's getting on that bus
and getting out of the city.
And we gotta go now.
He just wants you both to be safe.
- We gotta go. We really gotta go.
- Where's Michael?
Mr. Scofield, Herb Stanton.
This is Senator Conrad Dallow.
On behalf of all Americans,
thank you for your service.
Save it.
I'm here to give my testimony,
and then I'm leaving with my brother.
Right over here.
All right, gentlemen,
tell us what you know.
Are we really leaving?
You heard Mahone.
This is what Michael wants.
Right.
Okay, but if the deal with Dallow
is legit...
...there's no reason to run, right?
Michael's just covering the bases,
making sure we don't run into trouble again.
Yes, but if he's in trouble,
he's going to need our help.
Well, maybe he thinks there's nothing left
for us to do.
If we leave now,
we're leaving him behind.
I didn't know Don Self had it in him.
Now that we know he's behind this,
our situation's a lot worse.
We're not talking
about our careers anymore.
We're talking about real jail time.
We get 15 years just for conducting
an unauthorized operation...
...without congressional approval.
Or not.
This doesn't have to be
about containment anymore.
It could be about excision.
You all right with that, senator?
Then they all go.
Where are the others?
- Mahone, Sucre, Tancredi.
- They're not coming.
Linc and I will testify, but the others...
Well, we all get immunity.
Those are the terms.
Our testimony alone will put Self away.
Gentlemen,
we can't have the others running around...
...while we're trying to wrap this up.
I mean, can we call them?
Can we get them here?
The deal was for all of you.
Those were the terms.
Without everybody, there is no deal.
Listen, pal,
you're gonna get what you want.
Are you gonna call them or not?
There never was a deal,
was there, senator?
I wish I could give you a better answer,
Michael.
Don Self left a lot of rough edges.
We have to smooth them out.
You wanna tell me where they are?
It ain't gonna happen.
I can get you Self.
I can still get you Scylla.
Scylla? Oh, we're past Scylla.
Between getting it back
and ending this now, the choice is simple.
You wanted your supermax answer,
you got it, Richard.
Now time to go.
Escort Mr. Sooter out.
I'm gonna count to five.
One...
...two...
...three...
You've got an appointment
with the general.
There you go.
Wait right here.
Been a long time, Gretchen.
- No longer working for the general?
- Correct.
- Who's he?
- I'm the guy that's holding Scylla.
You interested?
Well, the general has offered a reward
for anyone who can return Scylla...
...along with the heads
of the transgressors.
I appreciate you
allowing me the opportunity...
...to kick the general in the teeth.
May I see it?
I said, move, move.
Long time coming, fellas.
You picked the wrong fight.
Let's see how well
you like your second term.
Let's go.
All of you.
- Sooter, please, I can give you cover...
- Save it. Save it. Save it, senator, save it.
The general specifically asked
that I bring you in alive. Just move.
- You were gonna kill us, senator.
- It was Stanton who made that call.
What was extremely complicated
30 seconds ago is not so now.
Six people knew about this operation.
Two of them are still alive,
one is on the run, and I'm the other.
I'm not saying a word.
You're not getting off that easy, senator.
You are going to help us.
There is a folder in that briefcase
on the conference table.
It contains the last remnants
of this operation.
Once you dispose of it,
none of this ever existed.
That's the saving grace
of a covert operation.
If you want...
...it never happened.
I'm gonna walk away now, catch a flight.
Maybe see my wife
before she goes to bed.
I only hope I don't catch a bullet in the back
on my way out.
I'm really very sorry, gentlemen.
We tried.
Let him go. Linc, let him go. Don't.
Let him go.
We running now?
I will kill you myself
the next time you do something like that.
Where's Mahone?
He's gone.
Well, we can do business
when you get the rest of Scylla.
What are you talking about?
- It's incomplete.
- Incom? Who is this clown?
- Clown?
- Yeah, clown.
There's a piece missing, slick.
Look, here.
Hello, Don.
I believe you have something
that belongs to me.
Come and get it.
www.tvsubtitles.net