previously on prison break:
From now on, I'm asking that
everyone keep their card on them.
At all times.
Gretchen didn't get us the sixth card.
So where does that leave us?
You know, gretchen did pass on this
one piece of information for you.
It's gonna be helpful.
I got a call from an old friend, heard scylla was
in play and he wants to know if he can get in on it.
I've set up a safe house
where you can hearim out.
- Do you have a pen?
- Just a minute.
1917 piermt.
Agent self...
we've been waiting.
When scofield and burrows walk rough the
door, give them an opportunity to surrender.
There's no way they're gonna
hand it over without a fight.
If they take that position,
we'll respond in kind.
We make one wrong move, the camera goes on
and general krantz will know we're inside.
I need a team downstairs now!
Shouldn't be long.
You sure we shouldn't be waiting down
there for michael to leave with scylla.
If you knew anything about tactics,
you would know this is the high ground.
Besides we have silencers.
So, scylla isn't one card.
It's six.
Make sure he's not armed with
explosives. Then kill him.
drop 'em.
Or I bw his head clean off.
You're gonna want to put that down.
Lower your wpons.
Come on. Get over there.
Get on over there.
The best minds in the world designed this
security system, and you almost beat it.
The frustration must be killing you.
You blew it.
Actually...
there's only one missing
piece of the puzzle.
And you just brought it to me.
I'm not sure what you're talking about.
Your scylla card. Now.
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
sync:ﬂ«»‚»‚ ∞Óµ¬÷Ì
Prison
Break Season04 Episode12
Not what you expected?
What I expect of a man like you is a
system where you've got all the advantage.
Looks like you're a few cards short.
Suck it, general.
- you're the worst partner I've ever worked with.
- What?
Leaving me with the one-handed freak and
crazy tch, while you hang out with gq...
be quiet. Be quiet.
- Be quiet.
- Don't tell me what to do! You're a coward!
Listen to me.
You think gretchen and bagwell
are gonna get you scylla,
but the people they're gonna
steal it from have a plan ...
- shut up!
- To trick them...
- you shut up!
- okay, be quiet.
Don't tell me To shut up! Don't tell
him anything! I can tell whatever I want!
- Be quiet!
- Don't tell me to shut up!
Don't!
We needed him.
He was going to kill you.
All right, jusgo get gretchen and
bagwell. M gonna take care of this.
Cole, you ought to be ashamed of youelf.
I don't know how things worked
back home, but around here,
we like to give our guest
a proper introduction.
I'm gregory white. Nice to meet you.
Susan anthony.
I've seen you around
the past couple of days.
Are you a prospective client?
Actually, no, I am a former
work colleague of cole'S.
She's a pretty convincing
salesman herself.
Really? Where did you work together?
Florida.
Florida?
Weren't you in the northeast division?
I was. But my very first job
with gate was, uh, in clearwater.
I guess you don't like
to stay put much, do you?
Lord, I was born a ramblin' man.
Well, it was, uh, wonderful
to meet you. I, uh...
I have to go jump on a conference call.
He knows.
No. No. No.
hang it .
Plse, that way. Right in mr. White's office.
Everybody just stay calm. Mr. White's office!
Sit!
Now listen very closely!
No one's gonna get hurt.
Now what?
How... did you get all five cards?
The frustration must be killing you.
Is that...
What is that?
The cards were keys...
and this...
this is scylla.
Guess right noyou wish you'd
framed somebody else, huh, general?
You're not even close
to getting out of here.
Let's go.
You sure, papi?
We have no idea what's
waiting for us back there.
Yeah, but we don't know
what's be up there either.
Trust me.
General, we're gonna need
you to activate this elevator.
Best of luck.
You're coming with us.
It's all right, damani. Put away
the gun. Everything's under control.
We have a major situation.
michael, thank god.
We got it.
How's it going on your end?
Pretty damn good.
But give me five more minutes.
Is that thdesk you sat at when
you told wyatt to kill my son?
Don't worry, alex.
He won't be giving any
more orders after today.
I'm curious.
How do you think you're
getting out of here?
The second we stepped off the elevator, my guard
made a call to put the entire building under lockdown.
Nothing gets in or out.
So whatever you're waiting
for-- it isn't coming.
- what are you looking at, huh?
- Nothing. Nothing.
- What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
don't yobe eyeballing
me, soldier. Back to work.
There's no way this is gonna end well.
We should get out of here.
Don't you think it's worth
20 minutes for $125 million?
Suck it up!
I want a team outside
of the general's office.
We need to get a handle on this.
Check the elevator.
Cover the stairwell.
All that design just to
hold some names and reports.
Names and reports?
Is that informatn from the
government, or your father?
Careful.
Top right-hand drawer.
It's something that should
be of interest to you.
I pulled it when your mes came up.
Lincoln: Why did you leave?
I took a position with a group of
multinationals we call the company.
They call every shot this country takes.
I knew your father since before you were
born u do know he worked for the company?
Yeah. He was data analyst.
Is that what he told you?
Well, it makes sense.
He wanteto protect you from the truth.
I'm warning you.
Your father was a brilliant man, but he
could never have defeated the company.
You don't have to make the same
misguided, fatal mistake that he did.
There's so much you don't
know about the company...
about scylla...
about your dad...
about your mother.
I swear to god, I'll kill you.
let's get through this.
What's the plan?
agent self?
Where are we?
The men went i about two hours ago.
No confirmation on whether
they've gotten scylla?
Not yet, but I promise you, herb,
you'll be the first to know, okay?
And as soon as I get word, I'm taking
an unmarked car to the pickup location,
- and then I'm gonna head bk over...
- no.
You go directlyto
senator dallow's office.
I'll have the attorney
general standing by.
We can't veer from the plan
here. It's too dangerous.
Yes, sir. We're almost
at the finish line.
I know.
I never thought you'd make it this far.
I was wrong.
We need to be prepared to go in as
soon as the general gives the order.
what is it you all want?
Fernando.Just say the word,
and your little girl's
college education is paid for.
We'll buy her a house to grow up in.
You think you can just
throw some cash at us, huh?
We'll forget everything, call it a day?
Pam needs you, alex.
Now more than ever.
You're both still hurting,
but given time, it'll pass.
And maybe some day you'll be ready to
bparents again, and if money is no object...
you should hear yourself right now.
The desperation in
your voice. You hear it?
But listen to what it is I'm saying.
Get away from me.
- Whatever you want...
- get away from me.
Whatever you want, i can provide.
Airle tickets for u and
sara anywhere in the world.
What I want is to see the
company burn to the ground,
and you in prison.
It's what we all want.
That'll never happen.
- I am so sorry.
- Please back off.
Excuse me. Let me help
you get some of that off.
You know what? Stop. Just...
Don't worry about it.
- Are you okay?
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
Thank U.
Damn it.
Everybody get into position.
This is going to end very soon,
and it's not going to be pretty.
One last chance.
Lee scylla, and you can all go free.
Just walk out the door.
Where are you going?
You shoot me, and then what?
You jump out the window
of my 19th floor office?
Michael, you kill me,
you lose your levera.
hello?
it's for you.
Oh, what is this?
Leverage.
It's me.
Lisa?
I'm at gunpoint.
What's going on?
It's tancredi.
She ys if you don't let michael and the
others leave with scylla, she'll kill me.
Dad?
Please.
Do what they want.
I suggest you take your
daughter's advice, general.
You son of a bitch.
Lisa, where you are?
Get her back on the phone!
You can talk to your daughter after
we've left with scylla, of course.
Look, I read enough intel on
your girlfriend to know th *****
maybe...
three months ago, but she's changed.
We've all changed.
This is a list of
everyone you've killed.
Fathers, sons, friends.
Do you really ink your daughter's
life is worth any more than theirs?
One of two things is
going to happen now.
You're going to let us
go, or lisa will die.
Either one is fine with me.
Just don't hurt R.
As long as you hold up your
end of the deal, we won'T.
You ordered scylla to be moved.
Show us how.
I'm walking them out!
Stand down. Stand down.
Yes, sir.
They must have found another way out.
That's impossible.
Well, then, they're caught or dead.
How much longer are we gonna wait?
You were the one who
said scofield had a plan.
And you put a gun in mr. White's face!
He was going to call the police.
It's okay. It's okay. Federal agent.
Quick. I'll help you. Quick.
Help me untie the others.
Okay, I'll keep an eye
on cole and the woman.
I want you to slip out two at
a time. Okay, you two first.
Why can't we all go together?
You're here. Go arrest them.
I want to get out as many of you as possible
before they realize what's happening.
Theodore bagwell's wanted for murder.
Now cole pfeiffer's a hostage-taker.
What am I gonna do?
You're gonna run for
your life, you idiot.
I'm leaving.
No, mr. White. No, mr. White. Wait!
No! Wait!
Everybody stay down! Drop yr weapon!
call 911!
How does it feel,huh?
Being forced to do something you don't want to do?
But knowing that if you don't go through with it,
someone you care about is gonna suffer; they're gonna pay?
what goes around,comes around,huh,general?
I...I can't imagine what you've been through.
I can't imagine that you'd want to.
Whatever they've done to you...
"they" are you,my friend.
Whatever they've told you,you need to realize that...
scofield and burws are bad men.
you used to be doctor.
You devoted your whole life helpg other people.
Now look at you.
They have you holding a gun on an innocent woman.
So you're innocent?
You're jus.
crunching numbers and running data to make the world a better place?
Mrs. Tabak?
You're fine.You need a couple of minutes.
hello,mrs. Tabak?
You okay?
Say it.
I'm soaking my skirt.
If I d't get the grease out before it gets to the cleaners,it'll be ruined.
Okay,ma'am.
I don't know what it looks like up there in your ivory tower.
Down on the ground,men and women are dying and lives are being ruined.
So,I'm prepared to do absolutely anything in order to stop you.
Turn around.
Turn...around,lisa.
you should've let me try to convince mr. White that everything was gonna be okay.
- That way,I could've...- what?
Put on a monkey suit every day and sit behind a desk.
How long you think that's gonna last?
you gonna walk down the street with an mp-5?
You can't be serious.
They can identify you,cole.
You're the only one linking me to that crime scene.
But,hey,it was nice working with you.
don't move!
Turn around.Turn around!
Gently now,sugar.
That's speci agent miriam holtz to you,sugar.
Let's go.
I want to speakwith my daughter,get confirmation that she's being released.
Sara will be keeping your daughter in custody
until she knows we're safely away from this place with nobody trailing us.
Company agents aren't just embedded in the fbi and the secret service.
They're in local l enforcement,hpils,dmv.
You'll never see us coming.
Actually,once we get scylla into the right hands,alyour agents,all your operations--
it'll all be out in the open,and then everyone...
will see you coming.
We did this to you.
Don't you forget that,old man.
Want to know what your father really did for the company?
He was an executioner.
He killed people who defected from the company.
And now the men he trained will be coming after Y.
come on.Something's not right.
Mrs. Tabak?
she just left-- tancredi-- she has to be right outside.
are you all right?
Yeah,I'm fine.I'm fine.
I'm heading back now.
No.I want you in a secure location,under supervision.
- You go home.- But I really need to be there.
I'll call youonce we get scylla back.
We've given the truck's license plate and vin number to the local police...
we lost our tactical initiative the minute that scoeld figured out our sops.
If we want to defeat him,we've got to alter our way of operating...
become unpredictable.
it's them.
Michael,where are you?
The company's armored truck.
We havit.
They got it.Okay,listen.
Michael,stay on alert,okay?
I will.
See you at the rendezvous.
You guys get someplace safe.Wait till you hear from us.
- You got it.- Good luck,bobby.
the rport.
We have visual confirmation.
Make sure not a single plane leaves the ground before we've got them.
Understood,sir.
Stay with scofield and burrows.
Scylla's the priority.
Attention,ladies and gentlemen,due to technical issues,
all flights have been temporarily grounded.
Check it out.
They're rit behind us.
Let's go.
Hey,my name's john burton.
I'm an off-duty cop from chicago.
Listen,I'm walking throh ontario airport,terminal 2,
right by the ticket counters and I just saw something that you guys definitely want check out.
We got company.
Michael scofield and lincoln burrows.
- Let's get out of here.- No,no,no...
the last thing you want to do right now is run
why is that?You gonna shoot us?
Yeah.
I say the word and my men will take you both out.
In front of all these people?
You'd never risk that kind of exposure.
I think it's clear by now that you've miscalculated how far 're willing to go.
Give me the bag.
Now.
Tell krantz this isn't finished.
Oh,you can tell him in person.
Sir?Please come with us.
Excuse me?
Just a security precaution.
- Yeah,sure.- *******
is this really necessary?
Please empty the contents of your bag.
Look,all I've got in there is a laptop and an external hard drive.
I'm telling you,you've got the wrong guy.
Let go of the bag,sir.
***********
yeah?
Well?
Yeah,we got it.
so you knew who I was from the start,huh?
My real name,my record...
I read your file,yeah.
What if you hadn't?
What's your point?
What if you never knew I was theodore bagwell,the convict?
Would you have believed I was cole pfeiffer?
Stellar salesman...
talented speaker?
I don't know.
You certainly had a lot of other people fooled,though.
Till you pled a machine gun on them.
I guess it's like they said over at gate:
"We are captives of our own identities
living in prisons of our own creation."
who would've thought they'd actually be right about something?
So if u drop this,does thamean we all go back to prison?
Don't worry.
If this doesn't get in the right hands in one piece,I'm going to be in as bad a spot as you are.
Congratulations.
What now?
Now,I live up to my end of the deal.
The vans are going to be here in a half an hour.
They're going to be sent to a field office where you can go through processing.
Th is all your transfer paperrk.
Get this to an agent schmidt.
He's going to be heading up the convoy.
I wish I could drive you myself,but I need to get to dallow asap.
Are you okay?
Yeah,I'm okay.
No,he's not.He needs to go to a hospital.
All right,I'm going to send an ambulance with the vans.
You're going to get the best medical care available.
Thk you.
No,I should be thanking you.
Okay,because of what you've done,lives are going to be changed forever.
listen,I need a,uh,ambulance to come with the convoy.
Sir,what are your orders?
Sir?
I don't know.
None of us will ever have to look over ourshoulders again.
That's the most important thing.
No matter what comes next.
You're gonna make it,michael.
You'll have the operation and,and you'll get through this.
Just like we've gotten through everything else.
She's worried about you.
It's nice to know that the next time I want to drink one of these,
I won't have to drink it in this crappy warehouse.
Yeah.
I can't even remember being able to sit down at a restaurant or go to a bl game.
God...it seems like I've been running forever.
But time to stand still.
Take in the sun.
Salud.
I know I'm supposed to be happy right now.
I'm still scared.
I'm scared we're going to have come all this way and I'm going to lose you anyway.
Come here.
Come on.Sara...
just don't tell me that everything's going to be okay,please.
Okay.
I won'T.
I see you brought your friend along.
What happened to gretchen?
Uh,she got away.
So here it is.
Oh,my god.
I can't believe it so what's next?
Senator dallow?
No,I need to tie up some loose ends.
Did gretchen and bagwell say anything else about scylla in terms of other buyers?
- Feng.- He's dead.
They didn't talk to anyone else?
We need to get as many indictments on this thing as possible.
Well,bagwell might know.
Once we get him in an interview room and offer him a deal,his mouth will start moving.
Remember wt I said to you the first y we got here?
Yeah,you said that when this was over,we were gonna settle up.
We're settled.
Michael.
It's been an hour.Would you call self and check on that ambulance?
is he not picking up?
Maybe something's wrong with the signal.
The number you have reached is notn service at this time and there is no new number.
What is it?
you did really good on this one,miriam.
You really held your own.
Thank you.
Can I take a closer look at that?
I'm sorry.
*********
Self.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- Proudly Presents
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=- Sync: YTET-ﬂ«»‚»‚ ∞Ó÷Ì÷Ì
www.tvsubtitles.net