My name is Michael Scofield.
I am a fugitive.
Three weeks ago, I was incarcerated
in a Panamanian prison.
While I was there,
I was approached by the Company...
...a corrupt organization
involved in all levels of industry
They gave me two options:
break one of
their men--
James Whistler--
out of that prison...
or they would kill the
only woman I ever loved--
Dr. Sara Tancredi.
I held up my end and
broke Whistler out.
The Company...
...they killed Sara anyway.
I don't know why the
Company wanted James Whistler
out of prison, but I've
tracked him here to Los Angeles.
He's with an agent I
know only as Gretchen...
...the same agent who murdered Sara.
It ends today.
I will seek the justice
that I now know the
system cannot provide.
So if you're reading this letter,
you'll know I died
avenging Sara's death.
You get the data card.
We drop it off in the racing
form, and we get the hell
out of there.
Who's the contact
we're leaving it for?
The Company wants
the card back, period.
All you need to worry about
is getting this rig the
hell out of there in a hurry.
Oh, I' be getting it out of there.
Don't you worry about that.
You worry about getting your
ass back in that seat in time.
If you pull this off, you
can come up to my room later
and the word "no" won't
be in my vocabulary.
Just make sure we get paid.
In and out.
Good to see you again.
You, too.
Didn't hear from you for a while.
Started to wonder if you
were still interested.
I am, very much so.
Well, I needed to
approach this carefully.
I'm sure you understand.
Who you buying it for?
A competitor?
A foreign country? Jason,
you know I can't get into that.
Now, we've bn negotiating
this for months.
I've jumped through all your hoops.
I've agreed to meet you here.
Do you want to sell
the card to me or not?
Be right back.
That's a lot of secrets on
a little piece of plastic.
Let me give you a
little bit of advice--
and this is
on the house--
watch your step with that thing.
The Company will do
anything to get it back.
Don't I know it.
What the hell are you doing? Yeah.
We got to get out of here.
I need to hide the gun.
Take the gun with you!
Where is she?
Michael, you don't understand.
Call Gretchen, get her in here now.
You have to trust me.
I'm not your enemy, Michael.
GRETCHEN: James.
We need to leave.
You know, despite everything...
if Sara could weigh in right now,
she'd tell me not to kill you.
That's the kind
of person she was.
That's the kind of
person you took from me.
James,
didn't you tell him?
He walked in five... Shut up!
Gretchen, look at me.
This is for Sara.
I never killed Sara.
I wouldn't expect someone like
you to take this with dignity.
I swear to God she's alive.
Don't insult me and don't insult her.
She escaped.
We knew if you found out we
wouldn't have any leverage.
I fabricated the whole thing.
My brother saw... A head in a box!
From a cadaver.
You ask Lincoln what he really saw.
Listen to her, Michael.
Don't lie to me.
I'm not lying to you.
Lincoln bought it,
you bought it, it worked.
Michael.
Then where is she?
I'll tell you when we get outside.
Right now,
we need to get out of here.
They found the bodies.
Give me the gun. She's lying.
Is she?
If you pull that trigger,
you'll never know.
Kill him, James.
Shut up.
Where is she?
Where is Sara?!
Michael,
if you don't give me that gun,
I'm going to shoot you in the head.
Let's go.
We got a double homicide
at the Roosevelt Hotel.
Sara
Do you know the difference
between a perfectly
executed operation
and a failed mission?
Sir? It's small unit leadership.
The Allies spent two and a half years
planning the invasion of Normandy,
but on D-Day it came
down to a handful of men
on a strip of beach
to decide the fate of the world.
What I'm getting at, Gretchen,
is even the best plan is only as good
as the moving parts on
the ground executing it.
General, we got your
card-- what's the problem?
We have nothing.
It's a duplicate.
Almost flawless,
but a duplicate.
That's impossible.
I saw... You know
how important the
retrieval of this card
is to me, Gretchen.
You know that this
is a security breach
that could have
catastrophic ramifications
for the Company.
The only thing I can think of...
there was a blind spot
when Whistler was hitting the target.
Maybe he made a duplicate
and he still has the original.
You hired him.
You kept him at the tip of the spear.
You insisted that we
get him out of Sona.
We had to.
He had already made
contact with the target.
At that point, it was
him or no one, sir.
What's your stake in all of this?
I had nothing to do with it.
Whistler acted on his own.
I swear to you.
General, I can fix this.
You trained me.
Not well enough, apparently.
Please.
I have a bank account in Dubai
left over from a slush
fund from COBRA II.
It's yours.
No, please, please...
Hello.
Hey, it's me.
Where are you, man?
Los Angeles.
You okay, Michael?
No, I'm, I'm safe.
Thank God, thank God.
How's LJ
and Sofia? Yeah, they're, um...
I'm staring at them
right now in fact.
They're fine.
You hear about Sona?
What about it?
Burned down three days back.
The inmates--
they rioted.
Bellick
T-Bag, or Sucre.
Sucre
He got popped--
I don't know how.
I mean, the papers listed
the names of the inmates,
and he was in there
when it went down.
I found Whistler and Gretchen...
and, uh...
...Gretchen said...
...she said Sara is still alive.
What did you see, Linc?
What do you mean what
did I see, Michael?
I need you to tell me
exactly what you saw.
Michael, Sara's gone.
Well, you said
it was in a garage,
right? So it was dark.
Yeah, it was dark.
But if you're asking me
if I picked up the head
to check to see if it was
Sara, no, Michael, I-I...
LJ said he...
he only heard them kill Sara, right?
You just got to come back, please.
Come back. Let's just...
let's just start a new life.
Tell Sofia I said hi.
And tell LJ...
tell him his uncle loves him.
Michael, don't do this, please.
Out, out!
You need some better
ventilation back there, amigo.
ue?
Want to translate that?
Don't worry about it.
Gracias.
Where's your mom?
She'll be here.
What do you mean she'll be here?
We're-we're running out of time.
-I got to be up there.
- Don't worry.
My mom wouldn't let me down.
At least, she hasn't yet.
Bradley
Over here!
Mom! Mom! Here!
I told you! Don't worry,
you'll make it there!
Ah!
Oh! Oh!
What is it called?
EuropeanGoldfinch.net
It's what we can all
use to communicate.
Michael
Don't worry, I'm alone.
It's good to see you.
So where's your new best friend?
Well...
I don't know about that,
but Whistler's not
who you think he is.
We're working together
against the Company.
-Yeah?
- Yeah.
And what about Gretchen?
She working with you?
He needed her to further his plan.
Look, if the guy was Company,
he'd have shot you dead
back at that conference
like she wanted him to.
Do you have any information
about Sara or not?
Let's go somewhere a
little more private.
I want you to tell me right now.
I want you to tell me
right now, right here!
Or we can get Gretchen on the phone.
Gretchen's dead.
She never showed up.
Come and talk to me, please.
Whistler and I were at that
conference to get a data card.
It's like the Company's black book.
And it lists all their
agents, all their operations.
They refer to it as
"Scylla."
Whistler's got it.
Alex, talk to me about Sara.
That's all I care about.
I understand that.
I want nothing more
than to get home to
my wife and my son.
But that's not gonna
happen for either of us
with the Company out
there trying to kill us.
You don't know anything
about Sara, do you?
Whistler does.
He tells me he does.
And he wants to tell you.
But he wants something in return.
What? What does he want from me?
To talk to you.
I'm sorry about all
that the other night.
If I had more time, I would've
explained myself better.
Sure.
What are we doing here?
Alex told you about Scylla? Yes.
I have it.
There's one last step involved
in order to read the data.
And that step involves breaking
into a secured structure.
So now you need my help.
Yeah.
My book, the bird
book, the one I lost
in Sona contained information
that would've helped
facilitate the break-in,
but it can still be accomplished,
with your help.
Where's Sara?
The only thing I know for sure,
a week ago, some information
came through the wire.
Sara may have bought a
bus ticket in Santa Fe.
Headed where?
Chicago.
Michael, if Sara's
out there, she's not
safe-- none of us are.
The Company knows we still have
the original card, and that's why
Gretchen was the first to go.
I think we're done here.
Michael,We... have a chance for once
to get Scylla to people that
want to take the Company down.
I don't want to run anymore.
We won't have to run anymore.
I spent the last month
thinking Sara was dead
and that it was my fault.
If she's out there,
I'm gonna find her.
That's all I care about.
This can be done within a week.
Less.
At least let me show you...
Oh, I'm gonna miss
these gams, girl.
Don't go.
This ain't no home for
a white boy from Alabama.
They're here, seur.
The bags are packed.
You kept your word to me.
You're the first that's
ever done that. Gracias.
Why must you go after this man?
You could choose not to.
Where I come from, there's
something called a blood feud.
Comprende?
Yes.
Michael Scofield left me for dead
one too many times, as it turns out.
What is Spanish for "little angel"?
Angelita.
Adios,angelita.
Is this legit?
Oh, S¨ª seur
For the money you're paying,
first class, all the way.
So these are coyotes one could trust.
Oh, S¨ª seur.
Vamanos.
As you've seen,
what you're entering
into is quite serious.
I realize that.
You're responsible for this now.
You have nothing to worry about.
We'll talk soon.
It's time to clean up now.
Thoroughly.
Everyone who was close to Whistler:
Scofield,
Mahone, Burrows.
Burrows is still in Panama.
Clean up.
Hello.
Hi, Pam.
Where...
Where are you?
Uh, you know.
In the middle of it, as usual.
Panama still?
No.
Are you okay?
Definitely.
Are you?
Yes.
And Cameron?
He's fine.
I have to tell you, Pam, you know,
I had a plan for all
of us to be together.
And...
I'm not gonna stop working on it.
Why do you need a plan if
you want to be with someone?
You just be with them.
Don't say that unless you mean it.
'Cause I'll turn this world
upside down to get back to you.
So don't say it unless you mean it.
I mean it.
Okay.
Come on, babe.
I-I hate plantains, you know that.
I try your chili burger.
Chili-chili burger? You
loved the chili burger.
Okay, I'm gonna
make them with my
mom's special recipe.
Your mom's special recipe?
You'll love it.
Really?
Yeah! You're gonna love it.
It's delicious.
Let's get out of here. Drop 'em.
Let's go. Give me your hand. LJ.
Yeah, come with me.
Lincoln, what's going on?
Dad.
We're safe now.
Relax. No.
I saw someone.
Looks like Company, I'm sure of it.
Let's just go, okay?
Let's go.
We'll-we'll be fine.
All right, all right. Yeah.
Okay.
Let's go.
Get back.
Dad!
Dad, we have to run.
Go. Get out of here.
Run!
Get going!
Lincoln!
I'm looking for Alex.
I don't know where he is.
No?
No.
Uh, we've been divorced
for almost two years now.
We haven't had contact in months.
I would think that might change
now that he's back in the U.S.
I am so sick of you people--
what are you a fed?--
thinking that you can
keep on harassing...
I'm not with the government, Pam.
Mom, could you come here?
We're done talking...
Bruce Bennett.
Do you know who this is?
I do.
I'm looking for Sara, and right now,
you're the only person I
can think of who can help me.
Hold on.
Where are you?
Back in Chicago.
Have you heard from her?
Meet me in front of the
Drake Hotel in a half hour.
Please just tell me... is she alive?
Are you Michael Scofield?
Yes, I am.
Michael Scofield.
Special Agent Don
Self, Homeland Security.
Were youhere when James
Whistler was killed?
I didn't kill him.
I know you didn't.
He was an independent contractor
who worked for the Company
for about ten years.
He was assigned to retrieve
Scylla once it went missing.
Do you know what Scylla is?
It's the Company's little black book.
So he was going to make a
copy of it and give it to me.
What do you want from me?
You're looking at major time.
You know that, right?
So how would you like to
walk away from it all...
not do a day?
In exchange for...? Scylla.
All right. Sara Tancredi,
last seen in Panama,
if you help me find her,
maybe we've got a deal.
I'm sorry, she's not my
department, Scylla is.
Then go find it yourself.
It seems to me,
the U.S. government should
have a little more reach
than someone who's
looking at major time.
To perform the operation, Michael,
that would require signatures
from about 20 different
department heads.
Do you want to bet at least
one of them is Company?
The only way this is going to work
is via freelancer, off the books.
It sounds complicated.
I'll take a pass.
I'm giving you an opportunity
to avoid 15 years in jail,
not to mention the time
that your brother's facing.
What are you talking about?
The Company tried to
take him out in Panama.
He, um... reacted,
apparently.
But I just made a deal
with the Panamanian authorities
for him to serve out
his time in the U.S.
He should be touching
ground any time now.
You recognize this handwriting?
This is your father's.
He spent the last two years
of his life going
after this very thing.
Do you believe in fate, Michael?
I think I'd like to
talk to my brother.
Oh, no.
What's going...?
Hey, hey! Whoa, whoa!
Stop! Stop! Hey! You
don't want to go in there.
You don't want to go in there.
God, she's...
Lilah Maria Sucre.
She gave her my name?
Soy tu papa.
You're setting me up?
Sucre, you can't keep
bringing Maricruz down.
You can't do this to her anymore.
Wait. Don't...
Sucre, don't...
Go! Go!
Oh, boy.
We're screwed.
You know why Scofield
gets all twisted up
when he's around me?
We're the same, and
he just can't stand it.
Drives his ass crazy.
We got the same brilliant mind,
the same natural-born
leader tendency,
the same one-in-a-million-type
charisma, yes?
He just gonna look
down his nose at me?
How you gonna find him?
This.
You're both into birds?
No, no.
It's either gonna take
me to him, or he to me.
I just know it.
If I was you, I'd forget
about this Scofield.
You have plenty of
money. See? I mean...
how much money you have in that bag?
Why don't you just mind
your own beeswax, huh?
You just keep pointing
this jalopy northbound, all right?
Get me back to the land 'o cotton.
Of course.
Ready.
Only a few people in government
will know of the operation.
It has to stay that way,
or people's lives will be
in danger, mine included.
Taking down the Company
sounds a little bigger
than a two-man job, no?
I'm going to get you help.
I thought you said, you
couldn't trust anybody.
Yeah, but maybe you can.
All right, two
of your cohorts--
Fernando Sucre, and Brad
Bellick were arrested,
they're both facing time,
and Alexander Mahone is
in a Colorado jail cell.
Good, let him sit there.
You're going to need Mahone if
you want to make this happen.
He was working with Whistler.
And you'll have me.
Okay? Whatever you
need, I'll provide.
Whistler also said something
about a second step,
something about a break-in.
Yeah, the card has
all the data on it,
but it's encrypted.
Once you get your hands on it,
you're going to need
to find a way to break
into the Company's headquarters.
It's the only way to
unlock what's on the card.
Where's the building?
L.A. Where in L.A.?
I don't know.
So, we've got a data card,
which could be anywhere,
and we've got to
break into a building,
the location of which
has yet to be determined.
Simple enough.
You've broken out of
two penitentiaries.
I'm thinking, uh,
breaking into a building
isn't too far outside
your wheelhouse.
How do you know our dad?
He heard from contacts
that I could be trusted.
Your father was a good man.
Why now?
Look, I've been going after
the Company for five years.
Okay? When Whistler
was killed yesterday,
the plug was going to be
pulled on the entire operation.
But, uh...
I convinced my superiors
to give it one more chance.
So this is like job security for you?
What's that?
Well, when we go out
there and risk our necks,
you can collect your pension.
No, no, no, Lincoln.
Okay, some people still
care about their job.
Some people still
fight for th country.
Maybe you've been a
little too distracted
boosting car stereos
and breaking heads
to remember that.
If we do this deal,
after it's done,
you can look for
Sara... if she's alive.
If we take this deal,
we'll both be dead
long before I get the chance, Linc.
You guys must have
some big-time friends.
What are you talking about?
Somebody just posted
a significant amount
of bail for both of you.
Who?
I don't know, but they're outside.
You're free to go.
Here, take your dad's
file. My number's inside.
We ain't doing this.
Just take it anyway.
This file, it means
nothing to me anymore.
Bruce Bennett.
Let's go for a drive.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I have something for you.
Okay.
You left this behind.
Is that what this is about?
You just getting me my rose back?
Yeah. I guess I'm done now.
I can retire.
How much time are you looking at?
They're saying 15 years.
I have to find out for sure.
I heard Lincoln say
something about a deal.
No jail time.
In exchange for taking
down the Company.
How?
Exactly.
I love you.
That's all I know right now.
"Will you not yield
to the immortal gods?"
"That nightmare cannot die.
"Eternal evil itself.
"There is no fighting her, no.
No power that can fight her."
Now, listen to me--
it's up to you now.
"All that avails is flight."
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to scare you.
I'm sorry.
Do you want to talk about it?
It's not your fault.
It's not.
Tell me what happened.
It's just the Company.
It's just what they do.
It wasn't just me.
God, it was you and LJ and-and
Lincoln.
And they won't stop,
and I don't know how
to deal with that.
Hey, come here.
Come here. Come here.
Let's go!
Are you okay?
I can't believe they
found us so fast.
Should I call... should I call Bruce
and-and get some place safe?
No place is safe.
They're not gonna stop
unless we stop them. Linc?
You are thinking what I'm
thinking? Let's end this.
But I'm not gonna
leave you behind again.
Yeah?
We're in.
Hey, papi.
Linc.
I can't tell you how grateful
I am for you including me.
Well, Sucre vouched for you, Bellick.
He said you came through
for him down in Panama.
Alex?
Michael.
You ready for this?
Yeah. I am.
So I hear Whistler's bird book
has details about
what we need to steal.
Yeah.
You know who's got it, right?
Please.
We'll die out here.
Thanks for the cashgringo.
First class all the way.
Do we have any idea where T-Bag is?
That snake could be anywhere.
When we're in L.A., we
can think like convicts,
we just can't act like them.
If we do, we're done.
It goes
without saying--
this is your last chance to back out,
'cause first on the list of things
I cannot guarantee
you is your safety.
We're all a long way
from where this started.
But what I can guarantee you
is that if we do this thing right,
we'll be close to where it ends.
Freedom.
Finally.
You two--
let's go.
Hey, Mike?
What about Sara?
Sara's in.
All right, we're
heading out tomorrow.
I have to finalize a
few things before we go.
No games and no stunts.
Otherwise, I promise,
you're gonna see a whole
different side of me.
Likewise.
Fake IDs.
It's a good start,
but there are some
things you can't fake,
and there are some things
you can'de.
Know what I mean?
How high is your threshold for pain?
You sure you don't want a sedative?
We're gonna go into the night.
How do you feel?
Lighter somehow.
Look, I don't know how
we're gonna take them down.
I don't even know who they are,
but I do know
one thing--
the Company's gonna pay
for what they did to you.
SELF: Let's go.
You sure you're up for this?
If we can
do it together, um... yeah.
Absolutely.
A C-130? What do they want...
want us to parachute
out of this thing?
This guy called in a
favor to the Air Force.
It's not like we can be
flying commercial, you know?
If you're successful
with obtaining Scylla,
you'll not only avoid jail time,
but you can take great pride
in knowing you helped dismantle
this country's greatest threat
to its own democracy.
If you're killed while doing so,
a proper funeral will be provided.
But if you try to escape,
you will have no funeral.
You will have nothing,
and you will be
apprehended and buried where
we find you.
I sincerely hope we
understand each other.
You better hold up
your end of the deal.
Let's go!
www.tvsubtitles.net