My name is Michael Scoldfield.
And I am a fugitive.
Three weeks ago, I was
in Panamanian Prison.
I was there, I was
approached by the company.
The company is a corrupted orgnization.
Involved all levels of industry and government.
They gave me two options.
Break one of their man
James Whistler, out of that prison.
Or they will kill the only
woman that I ever loved.
Doctor Sarah Tancredi.
I held up my end of deal.
And I broke Whistler out.
But the comany, they
killed Sarah anyway.
I dont know why the company want
James Whistler out of prison.
But I have tracked
him here to Los Angles.
He is with another company agent
that I only known as Gretchen.
The same agent who murdered Sarah.
This ends today.
I came here seeking justice.
The justice I now know
the system can not provide.
So if you reading this letter,
You know I died revenging Sarah's death.
We drop it off in the racing
form, and we get the hell
Out of there.
Who's the contact we're leaving it for?
The company wants the card back, period.
All you need to worry about
Is getting this rig the
hell out of there in a hurry.
Oh, I'll be getting it out of there.
Don't you worry about that.
You worry about getting your
ass back in that seat in time.
If you pull this off, you
can come up to my room later
And the word "no" won't
be in my vocabulary.
Just make sure we get paid.
In and out.
Good to see you again.
You, too.
Didn't hear from you for a while.
Started to wonder if you
were still interested.
I am, very much so.
Well, I needed to
approach this carefully.
I'm sure you understand.
Who you buying it for?
A competitor?
A foreign country? jason,
You know I can't get into that.
Now, we've been
negotiating this for months.
I've jumped through all your hoops.
I've agreed to meet you here.
Do you want to sell
the card to me or not?
Be right back.
That's a lot of secrets on
a little piece of plastic.
Let me give you a little bit of advice-
And this is on the house-
Watch your step with that thing.
The company will do
anything to get it back.
Don't I know it.
Yeah.
What the hell are you doing?
We got to get out of here.
I need to hide the gun.
Take the gun with you!
Come on!
Where is she?
Michael, you don't understand.
Call gretchen, get her in here now.
You have to trust me.
I'm not your enemy, michael.
James.
We need to leave.
You know, despite everything...
If sara could weigh in right now,
She'd tell me not to kill you.
That's the kind
of person she was.
That's the kind of
person you took from me.
James,
Didn't you tell him?
He walked in five... shut up!
Gretchen, look at me.
This is for sara.
I never killed sara.
I wouldn't expect someone like
you to take this with dignity.
I swear to god she's alive.
Don't insult me and don't insult her.
She escaped.
We knew if you found out we
wouldn't have any leverage.
I fabricated the whole thing.
My brother saw...
A head in a box!
From a cadaver.
You ask lincoln what he really saw.
Listen to her, michael.
Don't lie to me.
I'm not lying to you. lincoln bought it,
You bought it, it worked.
Michael.
Then where is she?
I'll tell you when we get outside.
Right now,
We need to get out of here.
They found the bodies.
Give me the gun.
She's lying.
Is she?
If you pull that trigger,
you'll never know.
Kill him, james.
Shut up.
Where is she?
Where is sara?!
Michael,
If you don't give me that gun,
I'm going to shoot you in the head.
Let's go.
We got a double homicide
at the roosevelt hotel.
Sara.
Do you know the difference
between a perfectly
executed operation
and a failed mission?
Sir?
- It's small unit leadership.
The Allies spent
two and a half years
planning the
invasion of Normandy,
but on D-Day it came
down to a handful of men
on a strip of beach
to decide the fate of the world.
What I'm getting at, Gretchen,
is even the best
plan is only as good
as the moving parts on
the ground executing it.
General, we got your card--
what's the problem?
We have nothing.
It's a duplicate.
Almost flawless,
but a duplicate.
That's impossible.
- I saw...
- You know
how important the
retrieval of this card
is to me, Gretchen.
You know that this
is a security breach
that could have
catastrophic ramifications
for the Company.
The only thing I can think of...
There was a blind spot
When whistler was hitting the target.
Maybe he made a duplicate
and he still has the original.
You hired him.
You kept him at the tip of the spear.
You insisted that we
get him out of sona.
We had to.
He had already made
contact with the target.
At that point, it was
him or no one, sir.
What's your stake in all of this?
I had nothing to do with it.
Whistler acted on his own.
I swear to you.
General, I can fix this.
You trained me.
Not well enough, apparently.
You know what to do.
Please.
I have a bank account in dubai
Left over from a slush
fund from cobra ii.
It's yours.
No, please, please...
Hello.
Hey, it's me.
Where are you, man?
Los angeles.
You okay, michael?
No, I'm, I'm safe.
Thank god, thank god.
How's LJ and sofia?
Yeah, they're, um...
I'm staring at them right now in fact.
They're fine.
You hear about sona?
What about it?
Burned down three days back.
The inmates - they rioted.
No sign of bellick,
T-bag, or sucre.
Sucre?
He got popped,
I don't know how.
I mean, the papers listed
the names of the inmates,
And he was in there when it went down.
I found whistler and gretchen...
And, uh...
...gretchen said...
...she said sara is still alive.
What did you see, linc?
What do you mean what
did I see, michael?
I need you to tell me
exactly what you saw.
Michael, sara's gone.
Well, you said it was in a garage, right?
So it was dark.
Yeah, it was dark.
But if you're asking me
if I picked up the head
To check to see if it was
sara, no, michael, i-i...
LJ said he...
He only heard them kill sara, right?
You just got to come back, please.
Come back. let's just...
Let's just start a new life.
Tell sofia I said hi.
And tell LJ...
Tell him his uncle loves him.
Michael, don't do this, please.
Out, out!
You need some better
ventilation back there, amigo.
Want to translate that?
Don't worry about it.
Gracias.
Where's your mom?
She'll be here.
What do you mean she'll be here?
We're-we're running out of time.
I got to be up there.
Don't worry.
My mom wouldn't let me down.
At least, she hasn't yet.
Bradley!
Over here!
Mom! mom! here!
I told you! don't worry,
you'll make it there!
What is it called?
Europeangoldfinch.net.
It's what we can all use to communicate.
Michael.
Don't worry, I'm alone.
It's good to see you.
So where's your new best friend?
I don't know about that,
But whistler's not who you think he is.
We're working together
Against the company.
Yeah?
Yeah.
And what about gretchen?
She working with you?
He needed her to further his plan.
Look, if the guy was company,
he'd have shot you dead
Back at that conference
like she wanted him to.
Do you have any information
about sara or not?
Let's go somewhere a
little more private.
I want you to tell me right now.
I want you to tell me
right now, right here!
Or we can get gretchen on the phone.
Gretchen's dead.
She never showed up.
Come and talk to me, please.
Whistler and I were at that
conference to get a data card.
It's like the company's black book.
And it lists all their
agents, all their operations.
They refer to it as
"scylla."
Whistler's got it.
Alex, talk to me about sara.
That's all I care about.
I understand that. I want nothing more
Than to get home to my wife and my son.
But that's not gonna
happen for either of us
With the company out
there trying to kill us.
You don't know anything
about sara, do you?
Whistler does.
He tells me he does.
And he wants to tell you.
But he wants something in return.
What? What does he want from me?
To talk to you.
I'm sorry about all
that the other night.
If I had more time, I would've
explained myself better.
Sure.
What are we doing here?
Alex told you about scylla?
Yes.
I have it.
There's one last step involved
in order to read the data.
And that step involves breaking
into a secured structure.
So now you need my help.
Yeah.
My book, the bird book, the one I lost
In sona contained information
That would've helped
facilitate the break-in,
But it can still be accomplished,
With your help.
Where's sara?
The only thing I know for sure,
A week ago, some information
Came through the wire.
Sara may have bought a
bus ticket in santa fe.
Headed where?
Chicago.
Michael, if sara's out there,
she's not safe, none of us are.
The company knows we still have
The original card, and that's why
Gretchen was the first to go.
I think we're done here.
Michael, we... have a chance for once
To get scylla to people that
want to take the company down.
I don't want to run anymore.
We won't have to run anymore.
I spent the last month
thinking sara was dead
And that it was my fault.
If she's out there, I'm gonna find her.
That's all I care about.
This can be done within a week.
Less.
At least let me show you...
Oh, I'm gonna miss
these game, girl.
Don't go.
This ain't no home for
a white boy from Alabama.
They're here, signor.
The bags are packed.
You kept your word to me.
You're the first that's
ever done that. gracias.
Why must you go after this man?
You could choose not to.
Where I come from, there's
something called a blood feud.
Comprende?
Yes.
Michael scofield left me for dead
One too many times, as it turns out.
What is spanish for "little angel"?
Angelita.
Adios,angelita.
Is this legit?
Si, signor.
For the money you're paying,
first class, all the way.
So these are coyotes one could trust.
Si, signor.
Vamanos.
As you've seen,
What you're entering
into is quite serious.
I realize that.
You're responsible for this now.
You have nothing to worry about.
We'll talk soon.
It's time to clean up now.
Thoroughly.
Everyone who was close to Whistler:
Scofield,
Mahone, Burrows.
Burrows is still in panama.
Clean up.
Hello.
Hi, pam.
Where...
Where are you?
Uh, you know.
In the middle of it, as usual.
Panama still?
No.
Are you okay?
Definitely.
Are you?
Yes.
And cameron?
He's fine.
I have to tell you, pam, you know,
I had a plan for all
of us to be together.
And...
I'm not gonna stop working on it.
Why do you need a plan if
you want to be with someone?
You just be with them.
Don't say that unless you mean it.
'cause I'll turn this world
upside down to get back to you.
So don't say it unless you mean it.
I mean it.
Okay.
Come on, babe.
I hate plantains, you know that.
I try your chili burger.
Chili-chili burger? you
loved the chili burger.
Okay, I'm gonna make them
with my mom's special recipe.
Your mom's special recipe?
You'll love it.
Really?
Yeah!
You're gonna love it, trust me.
It's delicious.
Let's get out of here. Drop 'em.
Let's go. Give me your hand. LJ.
Let's go.
Lincoln?
Yeah, come with me.
Lincoln, what's going on?
Dad.
We're safe now.
Relax.
No.
I saw someone.
Looks like company, I'm sure of it.
Let's just go, okay?
Let's go.
We'll-we'll be fine.
All right, all right.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's go.
Get back.
Dad!
Dad, we have to run.
Go. Get out of here.
Run!
I'm looking for alex.
I don't know where he is.
No?
No.
Uh, we've been divorced
for almost two years now.
We haven't had contact in months.
I would think that might change
now that he's back in the US.
I am so sick of you people-
what are you a fed?
Thinking that you can
keep on harassing...
I'm not with the government, pam.
Mom, could you come here?
We're done talking...
Bruce bennett.
Do you know who this is?
I do.
I'm looking for sara, and right now,
You're the only person I
can think of who can help me.
Hold on.
Where are you?
Back in chicago.
Have you heard from her?
Meet me in front of the
drake hotel in a half hour.
Please just tell me... is she alive?
Are you michael scofield?
Yes, I am.
Hands on your head.
Michael scofield.
Special agent don self,
homeland security.
Were you there when
james whistler was killed?
I didn't kill him.
I know you didn't.
He was an independent contractor
Who worked for the company
for about ten years.
He was assigned to retrieve
scylla once it went missing.
Do you know what scylla is?
It's the company's little black book.
So he was going to make a
copy of it and give it to me.
What do you want from me?
You're looking at major time.
You know that, right?
So how would you like to
walk away from it all...
Not do a day?
In exchange for...?
Scylla.
All right. sara tancredi,
last seen in panama,
If you help me find her,
Maybe we've got a deal.
I'm sorry, she's not my
department, scylla is.
Then go find it yourself.
It seems to me,
The US government should
have a little more reach
Than someone who's
looking at major time.
To perform the operation, michael,
That would require signatures
From about 20 different
department heads.
Do you want to bet at least
one of them is company?
The only way this is going to work
Is via freelancer, off the books.
It sounds complicated.
I'll take a pass.
I'm giving you an opportunity
to avoid 15 years in jail,
Not to mention the time
that your brother's facing.
What are you talking about?
The company tried to
take him out in panama.
He, um... reacted,
Apparently.
But I just made a deal
With the panamanian authorities
For him to serve out
his time in the US
He should be touching
ground any time now.
You recognize this handwriting?
This is your father's.
He spent the last two years
Of his life going after this very thing.
Do you believe in fate, michael?
I think I'd like to talk to my brother.
Oh, no.
What's going...?
Stop! Stop!
Hey! you don't want to go in there.
You don't want to go in there.
I'm sorry.
God, she's...
Lilah maria sucre.
She gave her my name?
Soy tu papa.
You're setting me up?
Sucre, you can't keep
bringing maricruz down.
You can't do this to her anymore.
It's ok.
Wait. Don't...
Sucre, don't...
Go! Go!
Oh, boy.
We're screwed.
You know why scofield
Gets all twisted up when he's around me?
We're the same, and
he just can't stand it.
Drives his ass crazy.
We got the same brilliant mind,
The same natural-born leader tendency,
The same one-in-a-million-type
charisma, yes?
He just gonna look down his nose at me?
How you gonna find him?
This.
You're both into birds?
No, no.
It's either gonna take
me to him, or he to me.
I just know it.
If I was you, I'd forget
about this scofield.
You have plenty of money.
See? I mean...
How much money you have in that bag?
Why don't you just mind
your own beeswax, huh?
You just keep pointing
This jalopy northbound, all right?
Get me back to the land 'o cotton.
Of course.
Ready.
Only a few people in government
will know of the operation.
It has to stay that way,
Or people's lives will be
in danger, mine included.
Taking down the company
sounds a little bigger
Than a two-man job, no?
I'm going to get you help.
I thought you said, you
couldn't trust anybody.
Yeah, but maybe you can.
All right, two of your cohorts-
Fernando sucre, and brad
bellick were arrested,
They're both facing time,
And alexander mahone is
in a colorado jail cell.
Good, let him sit there.
You're going to need mahone if
you want to make this happen.
He was working with whistler.
And you'll have me.
Okay? Whatever you need, I'll provide.
Whistler also said something
about a second step,
Something about a break-in.
Yeah, the card has all the data on it,
But it's encrypted.
Once you get your hands on it,
You're going to need
to find a way to break
Into the company's headquarters.
It's the only way to
unlock what's on the card.
Where's the building?
L.A.
Where in L.A.?
I don't know.
So, we've got a data card,
which could be anywhere,
And we've got to break into a building,
The location of which
has yet to be determined.
Simple enough.
You've broken out of two penitentiaries.
I'm thinking, uh,
breaking into a building
Isn't too far outside your wheelhouse.
How do you know our dad?
He heard from contacts
that I could be trusted.
Your father was a good man.
Why now?
Look, I've been going after
the company for five years.
Okay? When whistler
was killed yesterday,
The plug was going to be
pulled on the entire operation.
But, uh...
I convinced my superiors
to give it one more chance.
So this is like job security for you?
What's that?
Well, when we go out
there and risk our necks,
You can collect your pension.
No, no, no, lincoln.
Okay, some people still
care about their job.
Some people still
fight for this country.
Maybe you've been a
little too distracted
Boosting car stereos and breaking heads
To remember that.
I don't know. if we do this deal,
After it's done,
You can look for sara... if she's alive.
If we take this deal, we'll both be dead
Long before I get the chance, linc.
You guys must have
some big-time friends.
What are you talking about?
Somebody just posted
A significant amount
of bail for both of you.
Who?
I don't know, but they're outside.
You're free to go.
Here, take your dad's
file. My number's inside.
We ain't doing this.
Just take it anyway.
This file, it means
nothing to me anymore.
Bruce bennett.
Let's go for a drive.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I have something for you.
Okay.
You left this behind.
Is that what this is about?
You just getting me my rose back?
Yeah. I guess I'm done now.
I can retire.
How much time are you looking at?
They're saying 15 years.
I have to find out for sure.
I heard lincoln say
something about a deal.
No jail time.
In exchange for taking down the company.
How?
Exactly.
I love you.
That's all I know right now.
"will you not yield
to the immortal gods?"
"that nightmare cannot die."
"eternal evil itself."
"there is no fighting her, no."
"No power that can fight her."
Now, listen to me,
it's up to you now.
"all that avails is flight."
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
I'm sorry.
Do you want to talk about it?
It's not your fault.
It's not.
Tell me what happened.
It's just the company.
It's just what they do.
It wasn't just me.
God, it was you and LJ and-and
Lincoln.
And they won't stop,
And I don't know how to deal with that.
Hey, come here.
Come here. come here.
Let's go!
Are you okay?
I can't believe they found us so fast.
Should I call... should I call bruce
And-and get some place safe?
No place is safe.
They're not gonna stop
unless we stop them. linc?
You thinking what I'm
thinking? let's end this.
But I'm not gonna
leave you behind again.
Yeah?
We're in.
Hey
Hey, papi.
Linc.
I can't tell you how grateful
I am for you including me.
Well, sucre vouched for you, bellick.
He said you came through
For him down in panama.
Alex?
Michael.
You ready for this?
Yeah. I am.
So I hear whistler's bird book has
details about what we need to steal.
Yeah.
You know who's got it, right?
Please.
We'll die out here.
Thanks for the cash, gringo.
First class all the way.
Do we have any idea where t-bag is?
That snake could be anywhere.
When we're in L.A., we
can think like convicts,
We just can't act like them.
If we do, we're done.
It goes without saying-
This is your last chance to back out,
'cause first on the list of things
I cannot guarantee you is your safety.
We're all a long way
From where this started.
But what I can guarantee you
Is that if we do this thing right,
We'll be close to where it ends.
Freedom.
Finally.
You two,
let's go.
Hey, mike?
What about sara?
Sara's in.
All right, we're heading out tomorrow.
I have to finalize a
few things before we go.
No games and no stunts.
Otherwise, I promise,
You're gonna see a whole
different side of me.
Likewise.
Fake ids.
It's a good start,
But there are some
things you can't fake,
And there are some things
You can't hide.
Know what I mean?
How high is your threshold for pain?
You sure you don't want a sedative?
We're gonna go into the night.
How do you feel?
Lighter somehow.
Look, I don't know how
we're gonna take them down.
I don't even know who they are,
But I do know one thing-
The company's gonna pay
for what they did to you.
Let's go.
You sure you're up for this?
If we can do it together,
um... yeah.
Ok.
Absolutely.
A c-130? What do they want...
Want us to parachute out of this thing?
This guy called in a
favor to the air force.
It's not like we can be
flying commercial, you know?
If you're successful
with obtaining scylla,
You'll not only avoid jail time,
but you can take great pride
In knowing you helped dismantle
this country's greatest threat
To its own democracy.
If you're killed while doing so,
A proper funeral will be provided.
But if you try to escape,
You will have no funeral.
You will have nothing,
And you will be
apprehended and buried where
We find you.
I sincerely hope we
understand each other.
You better hold up your end of the deal.
Let's go!
They are in projection
you asked for general
you clear, go ahead
there has been a complication
burrows and scofield had transferred to...
I read the newspapers,
you don't have to tell
me what's in the headlines
the exact penitary where they
are been held is under disclosed.
But you can guarantee
the federal...
...supermax.
No more updates.
Call me when they are dead.
Welcome to Los angeles. As it turns out,
Men who have escaped not one,but two penitaries
are considered as a bit of fight risks.
So we need to know where you are
and what you're doing at all times.
These are GPS ankle monitors.
Now step up, take one and put it on.
I ain't wearing that.
Let's make this clear
I'm your ally,
but more importantly, I'm your boss.
Which means if this fails-
it's my ass on the line
as much, if not more,
than yours, so from this point on,
if I ask you to do something, you do it.
If I ask you to say something,
you say it.
And if I ask you to put on a monitor-
you put on a monitor.
As far as the general
public is concerned,
you're being contained in a
supermax facility somewhere
in the United States.
So to avoid any messy explanations
and stay off the Company's radar-
you need to keep
your heads down and your ears open.
We've provided cell phones,
clothing, and toiletries-
all the basic necessities
to get you up and running.
you-you patted these guys down
before you let them in, right?
'Cause I can't be getting
shanked or shivved.
Who's this?
This is Roland Glenn.
He'll be assisting you.
We've already got our team.
No, Scofield, see, this is my team,
And Roland's working off
a sentence just like the rest of you.
In fact, with the amount of security
that's gonna be around Scylla,
Roland's expertise will be a necessity.
So, if no more questions,
let's get to work on finding Scylla.
What about that second step?
What about the break-in?
You let me worry about step two, okay?
You just worry about finding Scylla.
I've got an idea where to start.
That's excellent, Alexander.
See, there's a man who's thinking.
All right, let's let these
men get to work.
Good luck.
To all of us.
since I was here first I think I'll
just go ahead and
grab that S.S. bedroom,
if that's cool.
Sara...
Yeah?
...you take the bunk.
You know, when this is,
when this is all done-
you and me, we're gonna settle up.
All right, obviously,
there's a lot of history in this room.
That's a given.
But it we're gonna pull this off,
it's gonna take all of us.
We got to work together.
So if anyone has a
problem, get it out now.
You want to clear the
air with someone...
now's the time.
All right.
Let's get to work.
Whistler's assignment was to drop off
this, this, this data card-
th-this 'Scylla' to
a Company Executive.
Someone he referred
to as "The Cardholder."
And his job was to-to protect it.
To... keep it safe.
Now, I didn't
see who he was, but I
got a look at his driver.
His driver?
You want to sketch this guy's face
and match it up to 10
million people in Los Angeles?
Well, that's just great.
I saw more than just the guy's face.
All the drivers were
hanging around, talking shop,
but this guy, he was
standing by himself.
Legs apart, hands behind his back,
at rest he's former military.
His car
rides a little lower
than the rest of 'em.
Probably signifies private security.
Weighed down by bulletproof siding.
His suit, his suit-
you don't buy a suit like that
on a cop's salary or pulling
weekend gigs as a driver.
That means he's full-time.
He's highly paid.
You ask our friend
Mr. Self to run tax records
on the 45- to
55-year-old white males
in Los Angeles drawing
a military pension,
and taking six figures from
a private security company,
and you narrow your field
from 10 million till about 50.
And then I can pick
the guy out from there.
Find the driver, you
find the Cardholder.
We haven't ate or
drank anything for days.
Oh, I don't want
to die out here.
We ain't gonna die, Sancho.
Hey, hey, we ain't gonna die.
Okay. We just gotta find
what's called a compass cactus.
Due to the fact it always
leans toward the south.
Inside there's delicious fruit
which'll fill our bellies.
Plus, we find out which way is south,
we're gonna find out which way is north.
Comprende?
Tell you what.
Why don't we, uh, rest
here for a while, huh?
Travel at night when it's cooler.
Si. That sounds good.
What are we gonna do when we get there?
To San Diego.
You mean after Michael pays
for the vile he's transgressed upon me?
I'm still trying to figure that out.
Nice to work with Homeland.
The FBI would take days
to gather this intel.
Well, the FBI should'a hired me
'cause I could've gotten
whatever info you wanted
in 25 minutes tops.
You some kind of hacker?
I design silicon lithography
for personal gain.
He's an identity thief.
He's a douche.
Hey, why don't you sit in the corner
and we'll get you when we need you.
This is him.
That's the driver.
Now what?
Well, he takes us to the Cardholder,
and the Cardholder takes us to Scylla.
You could have left me there, in jail.
Could have or should have?
Maybe both.
Are you thanking me, Alex?
I don't know.
Don't bother.
You're here because we needed you.
Not because we wanted you.
That's him.
That's the guy.
What's that, private security?
It's like a fortress.
Slow down. Slow down.
This thing we gotta get,
it's in there?
Motion sensors, alarm systems,
armed guards.
In and out of that place
without anybody knowing.
You better have one
hell of a plan, Michael.
So, basically, there's no
freaking way to break in
to the place.
Not quickly.
Not without being seen.
What about the neighbors,
uh, somewhere we can be staged
from, you know, go under and up?
Closest neighbor is
here, across the street.
And even that would take weeks.
The government's story
about us being held in a supermax
will only last so long.
What does that mean? I mean,
then what if somebody
finds out we're not.
What if we don't have
to be in the house?
If the cd-ar
this Scylla
- is so important
maybe the guy is carrying it on him.
Well, according to
public records, the owner
of the estate's name is Stuart Tuxhorn,
and he's a CEO of a
company called Spectroleum.
Heavy hitter like that's
gonna have security 24-7.
And we gotta get this thing
Without anyone knowing it's gone, right?
So even if he's got it on
him, how do we get it off him?
You don't steal the card.
You copy it.
Oh, now you're interested
in what I gotta say, right?
Copying it will make it harder.
Not only do you have to steal it,
you have to return it, genius.
Only if you don't got me, hombre.
What's that?
This is the reason I got busted.
Oh, you stole the cell phone?
Oh, yeah, yeah, no,
I'm lookin' at federal
time 'cause I stole
a cell phone
- seriously?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I invented this
so that I don't have to steal.
It looks like a cell
phone but it's really like
a digital black hole.
Wireless hard drive that
swallows up any electronic data
within ten feet of it.
Like what?
Like the account info
of anyone at Starbucks
with a latte and a laptop.
Like the PIN number of any
credit card used at a gas pump.
I can walk out of here
and get the identities
and financial statements of
ten people in ten minutes,
On a slow day,
with one hand on my junk.
And the information embedded in Scylla?
If we can get close enough...
It's ours.
Is this number... acceptable to you?
10,000 people?
- Yes.
-Good.
Now that you're on board,
we can issue the op-order today.
He's on his way.
All right, hold on.
Sara, it's me.
Everybody's on.
OK.
Now, while I'm monitoring the device,
I'm not gonna be able to see
exactly what data's being copied.
But, like downloading
quality porn from the Internet,
progress bar's gonna tell me
when it's time to rock and roll.
How long do they need to stay in range?
Encrypted data like this is
gonna take at least two minutes.
Here he comes.
Sucre, you're on.
Good luck.
Easy.
Huh?!
Sir, would you mind stepping
away from the vehicle?
Talk to me, Roland.
I got nothing, man.
Last time I had this
little action, I was
dry humping my way through fifth grade.
Calm down.
Sir...
Step away from the vehicle!
Okay, bro, just relax,
we don't have to get all excited.
You speak English now.
Only a little, but, uh...
How about now?
Nada.
Try to get closer to them.
If he was any closer,
he'd be in the car.
I get your little act, Pedro.
Hit the brakes,
let the rich guy pay for
damage you don't intend to fix.
Just give the man some money
So we can leave.
Congratulations.
He was there.
I think Tuxhorn was in the car.
So did we get it or not?
Nope.
Nothing.
Can I help you?
So how did you find me?
I never lost you.
The, uh, the new nose
threw me a bit, but...
What do you want, Don?
I got customers.
Look, back in the days, when
you worked with the Company...
Well, for the Company.
I did economic forecasts
of their operations.
I mean, I wasn't one of the guys...
But you had access.
Come on,
the last time I helped you,
the only thing I got out of it
was plastic surgery
and a $100,000 pay cut.
You know, so either you buy
one of these exceptional family cars,
with above average gas mileage,
or you leave me the hell alone.
I know about Scylla
And I'm going after it.
You know, I knew you were crazy.
I didn't know you were stupid, too.
Well, let's just say I was
able to get hands on it.
It's my understanding that
Scylla could only be used
if it's plugged into a decoder box
that's hidden in one of
the Company facilities.
Am I right?
You know, I wish I could help,
but I can't.
No, you are helping, Jasper.
Just a matter of whether
you do it before or after
I shame you in front
of your coworkers here.
Tell me where the Company
keeps the box, Jasper.
Could be anywhere; I don't know.
Somebody does.
Right?
Somebody that you might
have access to.
You know, if you go down this road,
your government job won't protect you.
Then I bet not get caught, right?
If I don't find something to eat soon,
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
We're not gonna make it.
we just got to keep...
keep talking, Sancho.
Keep our brains focused
on something other than
our empty bellies and
our dry mouths, okay?
Come on.
Let's start with, uh,
your-your favorite color.
Hell you doing?!
I'm hungry, Teddy.
Why should the both of us die
out here when one of us
could help the other one survive?
You don't want to do this. Please.
I'll make it quick. I promise!
Sancho.
Sancho!
Why'd you have to go
and do something so...
So Tuxhorn doesn't keep the card on him.
It must be in there, right?
Look, there's no way we're getting
in that house without being seen.
I know.
Well, if the card's in
there, how we gonna copy it?
We're not.
She's gonna do it for us.
What you reading?
"There is no fighting her.
"No power can fight her.
All that avails is flight."
Thatomer.
That's from The Odyssey.
Is this from my father's folder?
Yeah.
And it explains why
Scylla sounded so familiar.
If I'm not mistaken, it's
from that chapter in the book
where Odysseus is told
he has to confront a monster
known as Scylla.
Wonder why he wrote this down.
I could be wrong, but I believe
Odysseus is told that in order to
continue on his path, to pass Scylla,
it'll require the
sacrifice of six of his men.
His only other alternative
is to abandon his path.
And he chooses to make the sacrifice.
Well, it's a hell of a choice.
One I'm not sure
I'm comfortable making.
Sara, um, about tomorrow,
the plan,
housekeeper...
If you're not up to it...
No, no, I am.
Tell me,
is Claudia Mauricio a good roommate?
A good person?
I hope she feels the same about you.
Oh, Shelby, you wouldn't believe
the traffic on the...
You'll want to be quiet now,
Claudia.
There are levels of clearance
at the Department of Corrections
that are simply not available,
even for friends as connected as mine.
So, listen carefully,
if you even remotely
value your friend's life.
You're going to use your
security code to access
the records for prisoner transfers
and tell me where they sent
Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows.
Thanks. Sure.
That's a great bag.
Can I ask you where you got it?
It was a gift from my boss,
so I don't really know, sorry.
Sure. Thanks.
There you go.
I, uh... I can never find a good bag.
I'm a teacher, and I have books
and grading materials and...
I should probably go
ahead and just invest
in a wagon one of these days.
Yeah, that's why I love this bag.
It has so many pockets.
Do you mind if I take a look?
Oh, no.
Thanks.
Ah, thank God, thank God.
You all right, mister?
Yeah, my damn truck blew
a gasket a few miles back.
I've been, uh, hoofing it ever since.
Where you headed?
San Diego.
Hell, we can give you
a ride, if you'd like.
Hey, what's wrong, man?
Eat some bad Mexican?
Something like that.
Same as yesterday, right on schedule.
I hope to hell she's still got
that thing in her purse.
Tuxhorn residence.
Hello, I'm from the alarm company.
We've been receiving some, uh,
strange signals from your property.
We'd like you to check
the windows, please.
Make sure all the
contacts are still active.
All the windows?
Yes, ma'am.
Every room in the house.
Okay, hold on.
Does she still have the bag?
Yeah.
She's got it.
I'm picking up all kinds
of gak from the house, man.
Small stuff, maybe a digital
camera, an MP3 player.
Nothing of the size of what
we're looking for, though.
Keep her moving.
So far, so good, ma'am.
Uh, please move on to the next room.
How we doing?
Still don't got it.
If the card's in there,
it'd be in some kind of... a safe.
Office.
Ma'am, our system is showing
that the malfunction
is coming from a room
that's designated as,
uh, an office or a den.
You mean the library?
Mister doesn't like me going in there.
Well, I think he'd like it
even less if you went home
without properly setting the
alarm first, don't you think?
All right, I'll check.
We got something.
The card?
Oh, yeah.
File's so big it can't be anything else.
Now you just gotta keep her there
for two minute while
it finishes the burn.
Stall her, we need two minutes.
Ma'am, I think we found the source
of our problem
- if you could just stay
at that particular
window and hold it closed
while we reset the
system, that should do it.
Talk to me, Roland.
It's almost there, almost, almost.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
Got it. Got it.
All right, ma'am, thank
you so much for your help.
All we need to do now, man, is just...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
she's heading back inside.
What for?
I don't know.
Oh, no.
No, we're good.
She's out.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, stop it!
Wait here.
I actually had to slow down
- not to catch you.
-I think I pulled a groin.
It's not in the bag.
It's not here. How
could it not be in here?
The device, it's not here give me it.
Son of a bitch.
twenty-six... twenty-seven...
twenty-eight...
Go ahead.
Before Burrows and Scofield
were allegedlly transferred
to Arlington, someone posted their bail.
I need to know who.
I'm showing a Bruce Bennett,
former aid to Governor Frank Tancredi.
You think it fell out?
We looked everywhere.
You think we got the thing copied?
Like I said, I can't read the content
without downloading the device, but...
unless this Tuxhorn's got,
like, a 50,000-hour Tivo,
then, yeah, I think we got it.
Doesn't matter if we got it
if we can't find it.
Where the hell is it?
It's still inside the house.
That's why the maid went back inside.
She must have found it,
assumed it belonged to her boss,
and then she left it behind.
Well, then guess what,
fellas, it's game over.
You know how many months
it took me to make that thing, Michael?
What, you just think I
can whip up another one
in a couple seconds?
- Losing it is not the problem.
If they find it, that's the problem.
If they find out someone was
after that card, we're done.
What do you mean, done?
What does that mean?
Does that mean we're
gonna go back to prison?
Are they gonna kill us?
- What the hell does that mean?
- Shut up!
Means we go in and get it
if we had a few days, we'll figure out
a way to pull this off, but I gather
we don't have that kind of time.
Yeah, you gather right.
Look, if you want us to get that device
out of there, you gotta throw us a bone,
give us some extra help.
What you're asking for
requires involving additional people,
which, given the covert
nature of this operation,
I cannot do.
Then you're asking for the impossible.
No, what I'm asking
for is competence, okay?
I'm not the one who
put the entire mission
in the hands of a damn maid.
Look, if the Company finds that
copy of Scylla before we do,
that's it, Michael, that's ball game.
They're gonna find
out who was behind it,
and they're going to ghost us.
All of us.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
Look, I didn't choose you to do this
because I had you in custody.
I chose you to do this
because I believed
you could pull it off.
Yeah, well, a lot of
people have believed in me
in the last few months, Agent Self.
Not all of them are alive today.
Can you get me back the device or not?
All right, this is what we got.
The housekeeper saw the device
as she was leaving the house.
Then she disappears back
inside for 15 seconds.
So, we know, wherever it is,
it's somewhere close to the door.
So, 15 seconds,
that's all we have to buy ourselves.
Listen, I'm not sure
how close we're gonna get
to this house, let alone inside of it,
but let's say that we do.
The alarm they got installed
in this house is triggered
1.2 seconds after broken
contact in any door or window.
Which would immediately send
the private security guards
with their 47 guns
rushing into the property.
And after 30 seconds, the alarm company
will dispatch vehicles to the property.
Three to four, depending
on availability.
After confirmation of a break-in,
they'll dispatch additional vehicles
to seal off any and all
exits from the property.
I don't know about this, Michael.
It's getting pretty clear
why they hired a bunch
of cons to do this job.
It's not because they
wanted it off the books.
It's because we're expendable.
Who's gonna care if a bunch
of crooks wind up dead?
It's suicide.
I'm gonna keep looking
and see what I can find.
That quote from The Odyssey.
What about it?
I can't shake that line.
"All that avails is flight."
What if flight is our only option, Linc?
What if our father-
after everything he discovered
about the Company,
what...
...what if that's what
he finally realized?
You know, uh, the one
thing I remember most
about Dad was the back of his head.
Always walking out the front door.
Always running from something.
Mom, us, himself.
But the one thing he never ran away from
was his belief that the
Company needed to be taken down.
And we got an opportunity to do that.
Then this is our fight, not theirs.
Man, this... this ain't Fox River.
These guys chose to be here.
Remember that.
They got a choice.
Almost...
Ready?
Go.
Let's go! Let's go! Go!
Come on, let's go.
Where's it coming from?
It's across the street.
Come on.
Go.
Just something across the street.
We got a team checking it out now.
You can go back inside, sir.
Must be out of town.
Yes!
Daddy, is everything okay?
Alex...
Thanks, Jim.
Alex!
Let's go.
Go!
Don't turn around,
unless you'd like to
experience a great deal of pain
over an even greater length of time.
You-you know, just-just
take whatever you want here.
The only thing I want from you,
Bruce, is the answer
to a simple question:
Where are Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows?
I only know what-what I
read in the papers and...
Three days ago,
there were 105 inmates
in the supermax wing
of the U.S. penitentiary
in Livingston, Texas,
where the brothers were allegedly sent.
There are still 105 inmates there,
and no one has been
released during that time.
Someone is playing a shell game, Bruce.
I'm just trying to find out who.
I have no criminal jurisdiction over...
I know you bailed them out.
I know you've been in contact with
Sara Tancredi.
I swear to you, I-I have no idea
where they are.
I guess we'll see about that.
Good luck, Teddy.
Who needs luck when you got
friends like you fellas, huh?
Hey, you mind if I take this
old newspaper of yours with me?
No problem.
Sorry to hear about your friend, dude.
It's all right.
He had a full life.
Later, Teddy.
There you go.
Thirty-six,
twenty-four,
thirty-six.
Did you get it?
Let's make sure we got what we wanted.
Linc.
Yeah.
Don't let that thing out of your sight.
All right.
We're halfway there.
All we got to do is
that little B and E, and-
we're out of here.
Reminds me, I need to get ahold of Self,
see when we can get started.
So what are you gonna do
when all this is over?
That's a good question.
Brother, whatever this Scylla thing is,
it is a monster of a code.
Sara, I was gonna come down here
and ask if you wanted to talk some more
about what happened in Panama,
but, um, I think I already
know what you're gonna say.
How's that?
Because you're a little like me.
Because you're gonna say you're
fine, that you can handle it.
So, um,
I'll just leave it at this.
I'm here.
Whenever you want to talk,
Thank you.
You know that the only
thing that kept me alive
when I was being held was
the thought of being with you.
But I also knew that if
anything happened to me,
you were gonna blame
yourself, and you would spend
the rest of your life
punishing yourself for it,
and... I can't
bear the thought of that.
So can we make a deal
right now that we're even,
and just wipe the slate clean
and no guilt and no responsibility?
If we're gonna be together,
I don't want it to be out
of a sense of obligation.
Or-or even that we should be,
because of what we've been through.
I-I...
I just want to start over.
Start over.
Okay.
But, uh, does that mean
I have to divorce my wife?
Because you're still married
to a Russian stripper.
Well, "A": I've been a little busy,
and "B": I'm pretty sure she was Czech.
Hey, Michael.
What's wrong?
Whatever it is, it ain't it.
I don't understand.
I thought you said we copied the card.
No, we did.
But according to the encryption code...
Okay, how do I make this clear?
If-If Scylla was like a
pizza, all we got's a slice.
So where's the rest of the data?
I don't know. I don't know.
I mean...
I mean, I don't know how
we didn't see this coming.
I mean, it-it makes perfect sense.
It's like the nuclear launch codes.
You don't give all that
information to just one person.
How many do you give it to?
Okay, that quote your father held onto-
in The Odyssey, Scylla
is a six-headed monster
that requires a
sacrifice of six soldiers
in order to pass.
So Scylla isn't one card,
it's six.
What does that mean? How we gonna find
five more of these things?
Michael! Michael!
I'm busy.
I don't care what she looks like.
Three tablespoons of water,
one of honey.
Nothing more.
If she knows something about
anything that's going on,
I'm going to find it.
Rise and shine, bitch.
Breakfast.
Michael?
Hey, Michael!
You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
All this security makes you wonder
what the Company's hiding.
Only way to know
for sure is to find
those five other cards,
see for ourselves.
Think we'll have enough time?
Yeah.
We'll, uh...
We'll be fine.
www.tvsubtitles.net