previously on prison break:
Someone at homeland security did an
enhanced image search on you today.
-Who?
-His name is don self.
Yes.
What do you say you give me that
little piece of paper in your hand.
From now on,I'm asking that everyone
keep their card on them at all times.
-where's the bird book?
-Bird book?
Where's the book?
Someone was following me.
Is this the guy?
Yeah.
Who's that?
That's the man who killed my son.
Now he's come to kill us.
Don't get used to it.
Sparklekid,gate 8.
Excuse me.
Hi,there. I would like
to place some bets,please.
Uh,I'd like to place an exacta on captain
brody and mister hooper in the first race.
All righT.
$20,please. Thank you.
I think you made a mistake here.
I wanted a quinella for captain brody
and mister hooper in the first race.
Uh,you gave me an exacta.
That's what you told me you wanted.
No,it's not what I told you.
And I want you to fix it!
Sir,I gave you exactly what you asked.
no,you didn't-- what the
hell kind of place is this?
If you'll just calm down,please.
I'm not-- calm down? What-what
are you talking about?
I want you to fix this.
This is-- you gave
me the wrong bet.
I placed a bet on a quinella on doctor
brody and mister hooper in the first race.
Yo,somebody's freaking out
on one of the clerks inside.
We'll check it out.
***
Hey,louis,we've got a
disturbance by the windows.
I'm on my way.
What the hell kind of
place is this anyway?
If you'll just calm down,please.
I'm not. what,what
are you talking about?
I want you to fix this!
This is-- you gave
me the wrong bet.
I'm not leaving this place
until I talk to the guy.
-Hey,you need to calm down.
-Who the hell are you?
I'm the operations manager,all
right. Take it easy.
Do you run background checks on your
employees or do you just let cons work here?
Okay,there are no cons
working here,all right?
Look at her. What is she doing?
Ma-mave-mave,do you
have a record,mave?
Excuse me. Sir,hey!
Excuse me,miss.
Oh,my god. Thank you so much.
I would have been in so much
trouble if I'd lost those.
You don't know my boss. He would have
gone up one side of me and down the other.
-Thank you.
-Any time.
Look at her-- why is she
lookin' at me like that?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Let's not yell at anyone,all
right? We'll take care of it.
I'm not yelling at anyone.
Oh,sorry,sir.
I'll keep an eye on the monitors.
He's heading back.
Let's go.
-How's it look?
-I'm getting a clear signal. We're all set.
Cardholder number four,you're up.
Here you go,darling.
Yeah. Thanks.
The clocker said sparklekid was
edging on the track record at prep.
Oh,that's great,honey.
T's go.
They're up! Good
afternoon,ladies and gentlemen
and welcome to the first race
of the day here at los alamitos.
The starters are at the gate.
and we're ready to go.
and they're off and running.
What the hell?
Oh,we have a stall! It's
stuck,it's stuck. The gate's stuck.
I'll go talk to the manager.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
Sync:马大爬墙遇大猪
Prison
Break  Season 4 Episode 6
-I need to see the manager.
-Yes,sir.
It'S.
you better have a damn good
explanation about what just happened.
All right,I'll get back to you.
We're looking into it
right now,Mr. Edison.
Cue up the tape. Now.
We've made contact. 15% and counting.
Right there,it's stuck.
-What happened to his gate? I
-I don't know.
-Lewis you better come down here.
-Not now.
We found something on gate 8
where sparklekid was placed.
I'll be right back.
I'm coming with you.
Did we get it?
100% we're all there. Card's all there.
You've never jerked a loser before.
'S all your fault!
We're gonna need some backup.
Here come the cops. You better
go before you get recognized.
-Someone has to be lookout.
-I'll take care of it. Go!
Go!
All right,break it up,guys.
Let's go!
Hi,there. Um,excuse me.
I was wondering if you could help me.
I placed a bet on
sparklekid for my boss.
Do you know what happened?
Not right now,sweetheart.
Okay.
My boss had me put more money
on him than I make in a week.
Um,he's gonna flip out
when I tell him about this.
I'm really not the right person to ask.
Okay,but,here,i put $500 here
for orca's revenge. Maybe I could.
you're gonna have to talk
to one of the window clerks.
But maybe I could add it to that?
Look,I-I can't help you,all right?
Now,move it along,honey.
Okay,um,listen.
I'm just trying to ask
you a couple questions.
Yeah,well,you asked one too many.
How about this?
Why don't you help me find somebody
who could help me sort all this out?
How's that?
If you don't take your hands off me you're gonna
have a lot more to worry about than an angry boss.
All right,well,um.
you take good care of
yourself today,officer.
Excuse me?
This is a restricted area,sir.
You can't be back here.
Yeah,I'm looking for a manager
because I'm getting the money back
that I bet on the horse
that got stuck in the gate.
Did you see that one? Yeah.
I said you can't be back here!
I need back up.
where's mahone?
He's right there.
That's great. He's got the device.
We're screwed.
***
Mommy?
Go back to your
room,okay,sweetheart. Okay.
Oh,my god.
What happened to you?
Hey,sis.
***
we have an issue.
Good afternoon to you,too,andy.
I've been reviewing your roster
from the northeast division,
and apparently two of your top buyers
don't have valid social security numbers.
Care to explain that?
when I'm about to make
a sale to a client,
I ask myself two questions:
"Is the client being helped?
" And,"are we gettin' paid?
" There's a reason why I was
the top seller in the northeast.
I don't get hung up on the details.
And what you're saying is.
there might be a typo
or two in my reports,
but I'm pretty sure
those checks cleared.
Fair enough.
***
you've had a busy morning,frank.
Unlawful entry,resisting arrest.
It's not even lunchtime.
You're trying to put
the fear of god into me.
mission accomplished.
Listen,sergeant,I know a decent
amount about the justice system,
enough to know that if you wanted
to,you could drop this whole thing and.
it would save a lot of
trouble for everybody,huh?
What kind of phone is this?
It's a,a japanese brand. Off market.
What about the ankle
monitor you're wearing?
I've been on the straight and narrow,and
it's due to come off in a couple of days.
Press your fingers in the ink.
I had two grand go up in
smoke because of a bum gate.
I mean,I got a little
upset for a second.
You know what I mean? Who wouldn't?
let's talk about this.
Should we talk about how
you punched an officer first?
Or how you tried to flee the scene?
Pick a felony.
Take him to the holding cell.
Self : What do you mean he
got arrested? W-what happened?
It's a long story,but we need you
to get mahone and the device out.
Can you do that?
What,what do you think,that
every time you guys screw up,
I can just magically
make things disappear?
We ain't interested in your excuses.
Can you do it or not?
Lincoln,y-you know
what? I'll call you back.
Excuse me. Who are you? What is this?
I'm brian. I work in the it department.
We were getting some registry
inconsistencies on the server,so.
I'm just running a few
routine spot checks.
So you just barge in
here without asking?
I have level two clearance. See?
It's what I do. I go into people's
offices,I fix their computers.
I just figured it was better
to do it when you weren't here.
Well,you know what? You got to go.
Don't come back in here.
Sure thing. You're all set.
So what's the word?
Self's on it.
On it,as in he's getting mahone out?
He said he'd handle it.
What's there to handle?
Self yanked us all out of
prison for way bigger charges.
Getting mahone out should
be easy,shouldn't it?
Yeah.
Let's concentrate on
finding the next cardholder.
As soon as we get the device
back,we'll move forward.
Would you please walk us
through what we know so far?
Sure.
Howard scuderi runs agrisow,which is the
world's largest agricultural conglomerate.
It actually has huge holdings in laos,
which,given the current inflation,means
that they are making money hand over fist.
"My friends are playing at the park.
" Sweetheart,why don't you go play
in your room for a little bit,okay?
How are you feeling?
Better.
I,I made you a sandwich.
Thank you.
Um,you never explained what happened.
Well,um.
my car broke down in the
middle of the desert,and,uh.
there was no one around for
miles,and my cell phone was dead,
so I walked here.
Hey,do you still have that
owl that I sent from germany?
Yeah.
-I need to see it.
-Okay.
Thank you.
Oh,my god,gretchen!
Is that,is that,that a real gun?
It is.
You don't work for the irs?
I don'T.
Who do you work for?
As of now?
Myself.
He attended touro law
school in long island.
He spent the next 18 years
bouncing around the D.O.J.And D.O.D.
Before being dumped on the
doorstep of homeland in '02.
come in.
General.
What did you find out?
I tried accessing self's user account,
but he has a tricky
firewall system in place.
There's no easy way to
get past it,not without.
drawing attention.
So we still don't know
why he's interested in me.
maybe if you gave me more time.
I'll look into it.
Look,he's important to me.
Okay,he's doing a job for me.
-Yeah,well,your ci punched one of my officers in the face.
-I understand.
you're lucky he's not
being charged with worse.
I apologize for him. Okay?
Look,I-I'm asking for a favor
here,okay,from one badge to another.
When was the last time
you looked at your badge?
'Cause I'm pretty sure mine says
"issued by the city of los angeles,"
not the federal government,so
unless you get a court order that.
hey,hey! You want to go that
route? You want to get smart?
Want to get detained at the guadalajara airport
when you're coming back from visiting your nana?
How does that sound?
You ever hear of a no-fly list?
That's what my badge could do. Okay?
Want to see what else it could do?
I was starting to worry.
-Sign these.
-Yeah.
these aren't release papers.
Well,I need you to sign that
so I can collect your personal.
they're gonna run my
prints,and once they.
-you punched a cop.
-Yeah,trying to save the mission.
Keep your voice down. Okay?
I did the best I could do.
You need to sign those so I
can collect roland's device.
You.
you want me to give up the one thing
that makes me valuable to the team.
Yeah,you knew the deal
when you came on board.
Okay,we all sacrificed
a lot to get this far.
You want to flush it down the
toilet because you made a bad move?
got it.
Self got the device.
Mahone's still in jail.
But mahone-- he-he's
part of the team.
Was.
Look,I feel just as bad about
his kid as everyone else,
but we can't blow this
mission on one person.
Oh,yeah?
So if I get popped tomorrow,you guys
are just going to forget about me?
Yeah.
Hey,listen.
An assassin is trying
to hunt us down,okay?
And that t-bag character is out in
the wind with the keys to the castle.
We got enough problems without having
to worry about this guy's ass in jail.
You shut up.
Okay.
Alex has an alias,but if they run his
prints, they're gonna find out that he'S.
not if-- when they
run his prints,
they're going to figure out who he is and that
he's not in a supermax like he's supposed to be,
and then they're gonna
realize we're not.
michael.
Linc's right.
We don't have a choice. We
move forward with the plan.
***
agent self.
I'm an associate of general krantz.
Word has gotten back to the general that
you've been pulling information on him.
Why is that,Mr. Self?
I'm homeland security.
It's my job to protect people who
make attractive terrorist targets--
people in upper ranks of
military,people like krantz.
Is there a particular
threat I should know about?
Maybe you can debrief
me on the situation.
What's your division?
You want to give me
your clearance level?
I'm A.
hired contractor.
right.
Well,I usually don't make a habit of giving civilians who corner
me in underground parking structures classified information.
Okay? So if the general has
a problem,he can call me.
Is there something else
you want to say to me?
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
I'm just here to give you
a little friendly advice.
What's that?
The general-- he
likes his privacy.
That's all.
Yes,so that was wyatt.
I gotta tell you,I'm not a big fan of
almost catching a bullet in my head.
Well,now you know what it's like.
So,how well do you know mahone?
I know he wants to take down the
company just as much as we do.
You also realize he's a major liability.
I mean,if wyatt could find
me,he could find mahone.
- And then people.
- so get him out.
I told you I can'T.
But I can get to him.
I mean,he can be touched.
I don't know,maybe
mahone is a stand-up guy.
Or maybe he likes to run his mouth
to work an angle,I'm not sure.
But if need be,I can
get rid of that angle.
I can eliminate that threat.
That's not an option.
Oh,yes it is.
Okay,because if a choice has
to be made between him or us.
hey,frank.Got some good news.
Oh,yeah,what's that?
I can cut you a break.
As easy as that?
Spoke with the manager
down at the racetrack.
Said you were spotted with another male
caucasian about ten years your junior.
That sound about right?
Here come the cops.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
What was it?
The two of you were gonna
go in there,rob the vault?
Grab as much cash and get out?
Someone has to be lookout.I'll
take care of it.Go!
Look.
Maybe you got a wife to get home to.
Family.
If you're willing to give me the name of your
accomplice I think we can change your charges.
I thought we worked together,you
know.Help each other out.
You're on your own.
You holler if you change your minD.
All right,let's talk
about the fifth cardholder.
The general is requiring all the cardholders
to have their cards on them at all times,
so scuderi will have his card,too.
Now,scuderi has major
security around his house.
Big fence,lots of guard dogs.
- Where are the documents?
- These are from the county surveyor's office.
It shows the layout of his property,and its
proximity to every other house on his street.
He has-- surprise,surprise-- a top of the line electronic alarm
system that will alert him if there's a breach in the structure.
If we cut the power--
the alarm goes off.
If we double the power with a
voltage spike the alarm system,
in order to protect itself against
an overload,will shut itself down.
And that's how we're getting in.
Then what?
Look,I know what the score
is.It's every man for himself.
You get left behind you get locked up.
Tough titties.
Now,I signed on the dotted line like everyone else
and I want to know exactly what I'm doing on this job.
I'm with bellick on this one.
You know,maybe we should have a plan for when
the cops get here 'cause if mahone squeals
they're gonna come real quick.
He's a fed-- how many deals do you
think this guy's made in his life?
- You think he's just gonna tuck tail between his.
- shut up.
Look,we can sit here and debate what mahone
is or is not gonna do for the rest of the day,
but it comes down to this: We cannot
break him out of a police station.
1 2 3 4 5 6 no
Too big.
1  2 3 4 5
eight by ten.
This is the lowest gauge I could get.
It's perfect.Cool.
Well.
I guess,uh.
I guess we're gonna leave him in jail.
Is that a statement or a question?
It's just if something
happens to alex-- if,uh,
if the company finds him.
if the roles were reversed
and you were the one locked up,
you really think alex would
risk it all to get you out?
I mean,I don't know.
But.he was a federal agent.I
think he'd finish what he started.
I think he'd bring the company down.
Can I help you with something?
Yes,I-I'm here to see frank zwan.
I'm a family friend.
I'm afraid you can't see him right now.
He's about to be transferred
for his arraignment.
Actually,I'd like to be
there.for moral support.
Could you tell me which courthouse?
Hello?
Michael.
Alex,look,I'm sorry.
He found me.
Wyatt-- he showed up at the station
house where they're holding me.
I don't know how he did it.
I don't know how he figured it out.
Let me call agent self.
- No,michael,listen.
- no,maybe he can get you moved.
It's-it's over for me.It's done.
It's-- and I'm not gonna
say anything about anything.
But you need to promise
me something,okay?
Okay,what?
Promise me.
that you will get to wyatt and
you'll kill the son of a bitch.
And then you'll call pam and
you'll tell her that he's gone.
All right.
I promise.
Okay.
Okay.All right.
You ready to go?
Michael?I'm his wife.
I'm sorry,I'm-I'm still in shock.
I'll be down this afternoon.
Thank you.
Who are you?
I just have some things
I need to take care of.
You don't need to worry.
You have this.
switch inside you.
I don't know how you could
just.shut yourself off.
You did it when mom died.
Did it with emily.
Did it with me.
I do it because it'S.
it's just who I am.
No,it's not.
- You used to be.
- I have to go.
But thank you.
for everything.
So,you're not here to take her?
If I was capable of being her mother,I
wouldn't have given you custody.
You be a good girl,okay?
Bye,emily.
Bye,auntie.
I love you.
Will we see you again?
I don't know.
Call me if it goes south.
To listen to your messages press.
***********
I was planning to make those grilled pork
chops,unless you're not in the mood for them.
I hope you're having a great day.
Hey,what are you guys doing?
We'll call you when we're done.
Wait.
Where are you guys?
We're almost ready.
- you have a problem.
- What's that?
what can i do you for?
I just-- I've found some more
inconsistencies in your sales reports.
Actually,many more.
In fact.
kind of looks like fraud,actually.
I knew you were rotten
from the beginning.
I want you in my office in five
minutes to walk me through this,
and if you can't,well,I'm
gonna call the authorities.
what are you doing?
Nice knowing you,sugar.
Cole,wait.
I was traveling abroad
when he passed away.
Again,I'm very sorry.
Is this your husband?
Yes.
I need to see some identification so I can
sign over his personal belongings to you.
So...you and your spouse
had different last names?
That's correct.
I realize this is an inconvenience,but I need to
see other documentation proving you were married.
Do you have any idea
what I've been through?
I'm sorry,ma'am.
Rules are rules.
Mr. Pfeiffer,this is crystal from
instahomes getting back to you.
Just wanted to let you know that
your security deposit check cleared
and your one bedroom
is ready. Thank you.
hi,I'm,uh,representing frank zwan.
I- 'm going to need his jacket from you.-
I've been informed he's going indigent.
Uh,he was.His mother in santa barbara,however,is
not,and she retained me this morning.
- Be my guest.
- Much obliged.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Sir,sir.
- Two.
- Please take a seat.
- One.
Everybody out!
Just make your way to the
exits in an orderly fashion.
Let's go.
Move it,people.
You,back there,let's move.
Everybody out.
***********
I don't know if,uh,you guys.
did this for the team or
if you did it for me,and.
I don't care.
I just.
thank you.
- yes.
- I got your message.
I was wondering when
you were going to call.
You told my wife you
wanted me to turn myself in.
So,uh,why don't you tell me
where to go and I'll meet you?
Let's get this over with.
This thing is far from over,alex.
First I find sara
tancredi here,then you.
Seems like there's a great deal
of things for us to talk about.
Oh,no.No,no,no.
There's only one thing
for you and I to discuss.
You worked for the company once,alex.
You should know better than
to take things so personally.
I'm gonna wrap this up,just in case you
decided to trace this call,but I promise you.
we will meet again,and when we ,
I'm going to show you just
how personal things can get.
Oh,yeah.
cole pfeiffer.
What you gonna do now?
who the hell are you?
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
YTET
-  马大爬墙遇大猪
www.tvsubtitles.net