Previously on Prison Break:
If Scylla was like a pizza,
all we got's a slice.
So Scylla's in one card. It's six.
- How long has it been happening?
- No big deal.
It was when you were 13.
- Michael told you about Mom?
- No.
As a kid, she got nosebleeds.
In her 30s, they started up again.
How old was your mom
when she passed away?
Thirty-one. Michael's just turning 31.
Who's that?
That's the man who killed my son.
Yes.
It's like a digital black hole that
swallows up electronic data within 10 feet.
- Mr. Glenn.
- We got a problem.
- What's that?
- A battery pack for a video game console.
You'll need to buy a new one.
Scylla. Get it to me by tomorrow
and you will receive 50 percent of your fee.
Two days, 25 percent.
Three days,
I shoot you through the brain.
Who is this?
Hello, Michael.
You know what? If Crab ever
throws a psycho at us like this again...
...l'm gonna kill him.
If we don't get this psycho,
Crab's gonna kill us.
Just have the burner ready.
Got it covered.
After this job, I'm done, man.
I can't do this anymore.
What do you think Crab'll say?
I don't care what Crab says about that.
How can I be a good father
if I'm always in prison?
I missed out on my kid's childhood.
I'm not gonna miss out on
him becoming a man.
Hey, not for nothing,
but this plan is crazy, even for you.
- You sure this is the only way?
- Yeah.
Hey, look. He's coming out.
He's got the keys.
Let's buckle up.
Put your hands up! Put your hands up!
- You're welcome.
- Let's go.
So wait a minute,
this is your brilliant plan?
A kamikaze mission
on the General's car?
Hey, now that that device is gone,
your opinion doesn't matter.
Now shut up and pump.
We know the General travels light.
One limo and a couple guards.
It ain't the guards, what I'm worried about.
It's the crash.
Look, I never said
this was gonna be easy.
Just relax.
First off, Panama was a job.
Some other time.
- What do you want with Scylla?
- That's my business.
We're not in Panama anymore.
And I'm not behind a fence.
So again, what do you want with Scylla?
Same thing you want.
- Bring down the Company.
- Great.
Then give me those missing pages
and disappear.
I'd love to.
Remember that day that Roosevelt
and Whistler made off with Lief's card?
Who do you think took the fall for that?
Her name's at the top of the same hit list.
I don't know what arrangement you have,
but I need traveling money.
Talk about that later.
Talk about the kind of scum
you'll put on the payroll.
Give me a way to do it without her
and we'll do it. We need the pages.
It's a package deal.
Are we partners?
Partners.
I barely dropped the nickel
in the slots when this guy...
- We ought to blanket-party your ass.
- Where's the device and can it be salvaged?
Tell him.
Pit boss walked off with it.
Okay. Well, we're gonna call this
your early retirement.
You can either sit on your cot
and ride out the rest of this thing...
...or I call Agent Self and you ride out
the rest of your prison sentence.
Your choice.
I need to talk to you.
So your brother told me
about your nosebleeds.
And about your mom.
- That wasn't his place.
- To be worried about you?
When Mom got sick,
Linc was at the hospital every day...
...holding her hand, watching her die.
And he was 13.
It changed him.
It made him overprotective.
Now he's jumping to wrong conclusions,
for the wrong reasons.
And it's over nothing, because I'm fine.
You don't look fine.
Well...
...maybe that's because there's something
I have to tell you.
Gretchen's alive.
She's working with T-Bag.
They have several pages
from Whistler's Bird Book...
...and they want in on Scylla.
Self is cutting them a deal as we speak.
Self knows that they have
their own agenda, but so do we.
As soon as we get those pages back...
...Gretchen and T-Bag
are gonna pay for everything.
They're gonna get exactly
what's coming to them.
Okay.
This isn't about Gretchen.
It's not about any one person.
And we have to finish it.
I need a minute.
Please.
I can't believe this.
What choice do we have?
Gretchen's on the team, like it or not.
We need those pages.
Another perra we're jumping in bed with.
Not exactly new territory for us.
I don't care who we partner with.
We get those papers, break in,
get this job done.
- She could still have ties to the Company.
- I don't know.
We'll worry about Gretchen
when the time is right.
For now, let's focus on the General.
This thing with Gretchen
doesn't change a thing.
We're... We're still close.
Closer to Scylla, farther from Wyatt.
You don't know that.
- Just stay focused, all right?
- This is my focus, okay?
I'm doing the job, okay?
All right? All right?
Look, every day, the trail to my son's killer
gets a little bit colder.
That's all I do is focus.
What are you doing?
- Was just...
- We're gonna need that downstairs.
Yeah, I'll just be up here.
I see you two have come
to an agreement.
She's on work release.
Just like you.
What kind of work?
You and the secretary keep things quiet
in the office while Michael tunnels to Scylla.
You really think Scofield's gonna keep
his word, huh?
You horsewhipped the woman he loves.
Michael wants Scylla as badly as we do.
Yeah, he wanted out of prison too.
Our partnership lasted long enough
for that to happen...
...and then... we parted ways. Trust me.
Yeah, go in, sir.
Scofield will use you, and then
he's gonna bury the knife in your back...
...for what you did to his lady friend.
- Mr. Pfeiffer? Cole?
Where's Scylla?
Good morning to you, too, sir.
- Gentlemen.
- I gave you three days.
Where's Scylla?
Mr. Feng, let's not do anything rash.
So you're Feng.
We haven't met in person.
I was the liaison between the Company...
...and your Chinese employers
on Operation Copperhead.
- Susan?
- That's right.
You went from working
for the Company...
...to stealing the one thing that could
destroy them. Tight turn.
With the price Scylla commands
on the open market, anybody would turn.
Which is, by the way, 200.
Our paths never crossed on Copperhead,
but I did deal with one of your colleagues.
A less capable associate.
What ever happened to him?
He was skinned
and hung from an overpass.
Oh, yes. I recall.
He couldn't deliver on promises made.
You may also recall
that he was my predecessor.
When I joined Copperhead, you got
what you wanted. You'll get Scylla too.
If I don't, I'll peel you
like a white grape.
And the price is 100.
One-fifty.
One-twenty-five.
Don't disappoint me.
Now...
...a hundred and twenty-five?
- Million.
Well, then, Susan, Gretchen,
whatever your name is...
...I suggest you find a way to bury
the hatchet with Michael Scofield's woman.
We got work to do.
Why do I get the feeling some bastard woke
up to an empty driveway this morning?
Relax. We got it from a scrap yard.
And you're pinning the hopes
of the entire mission on that relic?
If it was Card 1, I'd say no.
If this was Card 5, I'd say no.
But it's the last card.
I really think we can stage a hit-and-run
and get away with it.
All right.
We know where this guy works.
We know his route.
I'm gonna wait for him at this intersection.
He drives through...
...I smash him with my car
and get the card.
If by miracle you walk away from the crash,
the General will know you ripped him off.
Not if I pump him full of morphine first.
He'll wake up tomorrow in the hospital
happy as a clam...
...with no idea what happened.
While he's out cold, we download the card
onto the laptop, put the original back on.
Don't think this'll look suspicious
for the paramedics that show up?
That depends on
who the paramedics are.
At the federal impound lot downtown...
...there are currently four ambulances seized
from a drug smuggling ring.
All we need is one.
Go make yourself useful.
Time was, commanders would assemble
their troops before battle...
...and rehearse schemes of maneuver
on a square of dirt...
...using rocks
to depict enemy positions.
They called these rehearsals
"rock drills."
Laos was our rock drill.
Now it's time for the battle
to commence.
Griffin.
Flooding the Laotian market
with counterfeit kip was highly effective.
In phase two, the effect will take longer,
but the result will inevitably be the same.
I'm signing off on the order
to open up the next theater of operations.
Excuse me.
The message is untraceable.
Someone went to a lot of trouble
to cover their tracks.
How do we know this person
can deliver the brothers?
We don't.
Bait the hook. See if he bites.
Hey, my friend.
- Who the hell are you?
- Don Self.
Homeland Security.
Phil Stroger.
- How's it going?
- Good.
This is a grande.
This thing cost me 9 bucks.
You California types
and your gourmet coffees.
Can I help you with something?
- This is a federal impound lot, correct?
- Yeah.
Okay, I think it's pretty obvious, Phil.
I need a car.
- You told Sara about the nosebleeds, huh?
- I'm worried about you.
Stop starting fires that I have to put out.
Mom couldn't outrun this.
You think you?
I'm not Mom, all right?
That was 20 years ago. This is different.
It's totally different.
Get in.
My chief comes over
to the rookie's stretcher.
And he goes, "You got one hell of
a workmans' comp. Claim, kid."
Hey, now let's get that trip ticket
started.
Looks like I can hook you up
with a sedan for your stakeout.
You know what, Phil? I gotta go.
- What are you talking about?
- I gotta give a briefing to higher-ups.
Okay, can I come back for the sedan?
Suit yourself, Self.
I'll be back.
Don Self.
I need you to deliver a message.
Okay.
I see your boyfriend's no longer supporting
the latest fashion in GPS technology.
If neither one of you are wearing monitors,
what are you still doing here?
Should be having hot fugitive sex...
...in every cash-only, no-tell motel
from here to Mexico.
Some things are more important
than what two people want.
I honestly hope that someday
that makes sense to you.
Look, Sara.
I'm sorry.
For Vegas.
I'm sorry for Vegas.
- Hello?
- I have a message to you from Gretchen.
She wants to meet with you tonight
at 7 p.m. At the Safari Motel on 109.
- Why?
- She said she wants to clear the air...
...whatever that means.
Sara?
I'm not interested.
Okay.
I got a bad feeling about this.
I'm the one on point.
You're on the ambulance.
Why are you so worried?
I just got a feeling.
If anything should happen,
call my mom in Chicago.
Tell her I didn't die like a damn convict,
locked up in some penitentiary.
Nothing's gonna happen.
- You ready for this?
- No.
Me and Sucre got this.
I know you do.
Good luck.
All right.
I'm in position.
Good. The rest of us are standing by
at the intersection.
No one's expecting you
to actually treat this bastard, right?
Yeah, I'm still a doctor.
Sucre, how you guys doing?
Sucre?
You gotta be kidding me.
Sucre, are you there?
We're good.
Being as I was the original recipient
of the late Mr. Whistler's artwork...
...what's my cut?
Twenty-five million.
A hundred and twenty five, that's...
Just so you know,
I have a very keen sense of ownership.
Six headstones in Coosa County Cemetery
can attest to that fact.
The names on those grave markers
took a six-pack of Schlitz...
...I had cooling in the river.
That particular transgression
put me back 5 bucks.
Imagine what I'd do for 25 million.
You'll get your cut,
but you're gonna earn it.
And how much of that payday
is Scofield and his crew earning?
I doubt they'll be around to collect.
There's a lot of blood being spilled...
...and a lot of money being offered up
for just a little old black book.
What's so funny?
That everyone thinks that Scylla's
just the Company's little black book.
Hey, buddy.
I understand from Lincoln your mom
had a hamartoma in her right frontal lobe.
That's right.
When a tumor like that gets
to be problematic...
...it's gonna come with a lot of symptoms.
Loss of short-term memory...
...problems with your depth perception,
with your motor skills.
- Lf you had that, you'd let me know?
- Yes, but I haven't.
And I won't.
And I'm fine.
"Two-l-B-A-3-3-3."
Michael?
- Yeah?
- General is leaving.
General is leaving.
All right, everybody get ready.
- You doing all right?
- I'm fine.
Not so good around blood, is all.
Well, I'll take care of the messy part.
Just help me get him on the gurney.
Doesn't take two people
to crash a car, you know.
You're kidding, right?
After all I've been through with you...
...now you're worried about my ass?
- Hey, shut up and drive, okay?
- Buckle up.
- What is it?
- Linc, we got him.
- He's two blocks away from you.
- We're on it.
Here we go.
- What's he doing?
- Something's wrong.
He's turning around.
- Linc, pull back. It's a trap.
- Let's get out of here.
Sucre. Sucre, get down.
- Get us out of here, man!
- Get down.
- Faster!
- Hang on. Hang on!
You all right?
Damn, you're hit.
Stay with us. You're gonna be all right.
- He came straight at us.
- We were set up.
They knew we were gonna be there?
Then they know about this place.
- Exactly.
- Brad, I'll need gauze.
Somebody could be coming here now.
- Lf they knew, we'd be dead.
- What if that Gretchen chick knows?
She had a couple pages from Whistler's
Bird Book. It doesn't make her psychic.
Brad, I need some gauze.
Well, it looks like someone set us up.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
And I'm wondering if it was you.
First you give me the leper treatment,
now I'm a traitor.
Who could have known
we'd be at that intersection?
You know, just because I didn't do time
with you guys doesn't make me a rat.
I put just as much into this job
as anybody else.
I make one mistake,
all of a sudden I'm Judas?
No. You know what? No.
Call Self, okay,
because I'm going back to the can.
- I'm done with this.
- All right, just calm down.
Calm down.
I want you to look up the local businesses
at the corner of King and Willow.
I need the ones
with exterior security cameras.
Because I'm looking
for a license plate number, all right?
How about an apology?
Where is Scofield? We've been waiting
for him to break ground all day.
He's taking care of one last thing.
He'll be here.
And what'd Sara say about our meeting?
She's not interested.
Okay, well, if she changes her mind,
I'll be there.
Just so everyone knows,
this is Sara's last chance to settle up.
I want all the grievances out on the table,
so we can move forward.
Listen to me, skank.
You just got your stripes stripped off
your sleeve by your old boss.
So whatever clout
you had with the Company, it's gone.
You work for me now.
So you could try to pull rank
on the hick here all you want.
But don't mistake my patience
for weakness.
You're alive right now for one reason:
Because I'm allowing you to be.
So when I get Scylla,
you'll get your traveling money.
But when this is over,
if you step one foot on American soil...
...l'm gonna take this gun...
...and I'm gonna put a bullet right there.
And that goes for you, too, Gummo.
Are we clear?
We're clear.
Here. I made this.
It's a chart of all the people
coming in and out...
...showing which times of the day are
the busiest and which are best for digging.
Just answer the phones.
I'll handle this.
- Did you get it?
- Hold on.
Hurry up.
Why are we doing this again?
It's an insurance policy.
If she tries to get out
of that big Scylla payday...
How big of a payday?
One million dollars.
You put a gun on me again,
these aren't the only prints I'll be copying.
From this moment on, we are allies.
- Is she watching?
- Yes.
- Brace yourself.
- For what?
Don't you ever come in my office again
unless you're summoned.
Burrows was in the car.
It appears our source is dependable.
When I said bait the hook,
I did not mean with me.
- They came that close to killing me.
- I wouldn't let that happen.
But if you're unhappy with my methods...
...maybe you should parcel out the job
to someone else.
I don't accept resignations.
Close the deal with the mystery man
and bring the brothers to me today...
...or your severance pay
will be a body bag.
Broad daylight.
City street and they knew your route.
If Scofield's mission was to kill you...
...he'd have a better way to do it.
- You have everything you need?
- Yup, I'm good.
You're gonna be just fine.
All right.
Almost done. Breathe.
There you go.
I would've died on this table
if it weren't for you.
Just wait until you get my bill.
Hang in there, Sucre.
Even if the warehouse ain't
on the Company's radar, we sure as hell are.
- This job's over.
- You don't know that.
I know I ain't going back to Fox River.
What do you think Self's gonna do
when he finds out the Company's made us?
We're about to find out. Yeah.
Hey, where the hell is Roland?
His just GPS went offline.
- Well?
- He took the Corolla.
- He take his laptop too?
- Yeah.
Alex.
You doing okay?
- How much longer, doc?
- Almost.
Hey, you got this covered?
What are you still doing here?
Go get the son of a bitch.
All done.
You got my money?
I thought this was gonna be
a legit transaction.
Don't got my money,
I don't got the location of the brothers.
Where are they?
What are you doing?
Sara.
Hello, Sara.
A former mentor of mine...
...once told me a story
that I think applies to this situation.
At the end of the Civil War...
...Grant's Union Army had Lee's Confederate
soldiers outflanked at Appomattox.
Lee understood the futility
of more bloodshed...
...so he requested a cease-fire.
He wanted to bring an end to the fighting.
Soldiers that had been killing
each other that morning...
...walked across the lines
for the first time as allies...
...to trade Northern coffee
for Southern tobacco.
Now, I don't expect us to exchange gifts,
but that doesn't mean we can't be allies.
Of course, you can't have a cease-fire...
...without both parties getting
what they want.
You have five minutes.
Put as many scars on my back
as possible.
I don't wanna rush you,
but you have four minutes left.
What was her name?
This is a one-time deal, Sara.
You want your pound of flesh, take it now.
- What was her name?
- Who?
The guard you shot
and left to die in my arms.
That's what this is about?
A guard that couldn't do her job?
What was her name?
- Taylor.
- Her first name.
Michelle, I think.
You should know
that this isn't about me.
I can handle the scars you put
on my back.
- But what you did to Mi...
- I had orders.
- She tried to help you escape.
- She did help me escape. She didn't try.
Sara.
You were too busy making an example
of her to find the key she left me.
Then she got what she deserved.
She saved my life.
And you took hers.
You proved your point.
We're even.
We're a long way from even.
And when this is over,
you'll pay for Michelle.
Where are they?
The thing about a gunshot
to the kneecap...
...it takes days to die from it.
Now, if I were to shoot you,
let's say here...
...the hollow point
would tumble through you...
...leaving white-hot slivers
in your insides...
...causing unimaginable pain...
...only ending when you bled out
on this pavement.
You don't want that, do you?
Then tell me where the brothers are.
In a warehouse.
Pier 31 in San Pedro. They're all there.
Please.
Thank you.
No! What are you doing?!
I told you where they were!
What are you?!
No, no. No.
All right, all right.
No.
You'll get your shot. Back off.
- Alex, listen to him.
- Hey, hey, hey.
You'll get your shot, man.
You'll get your shot.
Michael, come on. He sold us out.
What are you doing?
We gotta go.
Michael.
Michael, let's go.
Don't hand me any more updates.
They're surveilling me.
They're coming after me.
General, we'll get them.
This isn't the first time
someone's made an attempt on your life.
This is not an attempt on my life.
This is an attempt on my card.
- Get Wyatt.
- We're trying to contact him.
Don't try anything. Just get Wyatt.
- How do you wanna proceed?
- I want it moved.
To make the necessary arrangements
for security would take days...
I don't care about logistics.
I want it moved.
Move Scylla.
Now!
As soon as we possibly can.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I know.
I'm not ready to go, man.
www.tvsubtitles.net