Previously on Prison Break:
If you're successful with obtaining Scylla,
you'll not only avoid jail time...
...you can take pride
in knowing you helped dismantle...
...this country's greatest threat
to democracy.
If you're killed while doing so,
a proper funeral will be provided.
Gretchen has the rest of the pages.
We can't go further until
she gives them back.
- Why are we doing this again?
- It's an insurance policy.
You put gun on me again, these aren't
the only set of prints I'll be copying.
Mike.
Michael, what's wrong?
Talk to me! Michael!
I want Scylla out of Los Angeles
by the end of the day tomorrow.
Brad? Get out there!
- Push it.
- Don't do this.
Brad!
If anything should happen,
call my mom in Chicago.
Nothing's gonna happen.
- Where's Brad's body now?
- On its way to the morgue.
It's at the cooler at Homeland Security
where nobody can find it.
- Ain't the deal.
- You said if anything happened...
...we'd be returned to next of kin.
- That's not what I said.
- That is exactly what you said.
- It isn't exactly what I said.
And he needs to stay a John Doe
until I say otherwise. Okay?
I'm dealing with enough stuff
and I've had my ass...
He's got...
He's got a mother, you know.
If you want Scylla,
and I assume you still do...
...Brad Bellick's body goes home
to his mother.
All right, all right.
All right, I'm gonna take care
of the body.
But you guys need to get out
of mourning.
Okay, we need to get back to work.
We need to pack Brad's stuff up
and we need to get back to work.
And Fernando, my friend,
let me tell you something.
If you ever put your hands on me again,
I promise you, okay...
...there's gonna be two bodies
in the fridge.
But I need results.
Yeah, well, I need
to see those missing pages.
So, what's it gonna be?
I heard you were dead.
Who told you that?
Little bird.
- Awfully generous of you.
- It's all a matter of timing.
The Company's moving Scylla
to a bunker in Pennsylvania.
- When?
- Tomorrow.
You wanna make sure to mention that,
like on the phone, like right away?
For an ex-employee, you seem to know an
awful lot about current company business.
Don't get paranoid. I'm keeping one ear
to the ground for your benefit...
...which is a good reason to work with me
and not against me.
All right, you know what?
We got our pages. Let's go.
That's Enzen from Transpo.
He's responsible for the power transfer.
And you know Powell?
He's supervising the security override.
It's a big job.
Perhaps we should call in David Baker...
...just to be safe.
That won't be necessary.
We can do this all in-house.
And Scylla will be gone by morning.
I promised Brad I would call his mom
if anything happened.
I'll do it, if you want.
No, it's okay. I'll do it.
Look at this.
He kept the badge
from the police benefit.
When he was a C.O. In Fox River...
...he failed the test
to get into the academy five times.
These are right, right?
This is a map
of the Company's basement, right?
I don't know. It looks too simple.
I assumed it would be
a lot more complicated than this.
The symbols, they're...
They don't make any sense.
And the letters...
There's just something wrong.
This letter C, it usually designates
some kind of heating vent.
The M designates a meter.
This is some sort of condensing unit.
This is a plumbing part.
It's called a P-trap.
They're all completely dissimilar items.
Logical design dictates they'd never
be installed that randomly. It just...
...doesn't make sense.
C, M, E.
That's, "see me."
These letters don't make sense
if you think of them as symbols.
But they do if you think of them literally.
Do you see me?
He's asking if you see him.
- Where?
- Here.
David Baker.
But who besides you two
would come up with something like that?
I mean, what's the point?
I don't know. But we're never gonna
figure this blueprint out...
...if we can't find the person
who drew it.
We need David Baker.
- Hello, darling.
- Good morning.
Here is your coffee.
One sugar, two creams.
And those fingerprints you ordered.
- Gretchen's?
- Yes.
Gretchen Louise Morgan.
How'd you pull off a thing like that?
I have a friend who works with the chips.
But don't get too excited.
There's not much there.
"Gretchen Louise Morgan.
DOB: 3-29-77.
Johnstown, West Virginia.
Sister lives in Riverside.
Daddy, deceased.
Award-winning equestrian.
Iraqi war vet."
I'll be damned.
Clean-cut chick. At least on paper.
I don't see any evidence that
she's related to Chinese organized crime.
No husband in Beijing?
- No prior arrests for extortion?
- No.
- No mention of any of our friends?
- I checked. No Scofield.
No Burrows. No Whistler.
Whistler?
- How do you know that name?
- James Whistler?
- I heard Scofield mention him one day.
- What day?
The day that I met him.
In what context?
I don't remember.
Why, what's the big deal? Who is he?
Nobody.
That'll be all for now.
Here's another one, David Allen Baker.
Adviser to the city planning commission.
Won an award
for designing low-income housing.
Wife is named Elaine.
And there's the address.
I'll print a map.
We still need that sixth card, all right?
Really?
All right. We've got at least
30 more yards to go...
...past the water main
before we get to the Company building.
See that? That looks like it could be
some sort of obstruction in the tunnel.
Whatever it takes. We gotta get
through that in the next few hours.
I want you guys to go down there
and get started.
Sara and I will go look and look
for David Baker.
And Bellick gets back to his mom.
Yeah, and when we get Scylla...
...we're walking away from this crap.
- Absolutely.
Sara?
Michael.
I'm okay.
Get him in the car.
- Where are you gonna take him?
- Hospital.
- Let's not freak out. Calm down.
- This is my decision.
- We're going to the hospital.
- What's wrong with him?
David Baker.
I'll go. I'll find him.
Don't forget to use fake ID
at the hospital.
- Shut the door.
- Okay.
Yeah, excellent.
Make sure you get that on my desk...
Mr. White.
If you'll allow me to be nosy...
...how long has Trishanne
been part of the organization?
Temp agency sent her over about a week
before you got here.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to take a look at her application.
I always check out the background
of anyone who deals with my affairs.
- I understand. I'll talk to H.R.
- Thank you.
Cole, you know what?
Today around noon...
...I really need you
to step in for Andrew Blauner.
Host an intro.
New franchises from Idaho.
We gotta knock them out.
I'd like to see
some of that Cole Pfeiffer magic.
Abracadabra.
Excuse me, sir?
Are you a salesman?
Yes, indeedy, I am.
What can I do for you?
Cole, I can see that you're busy,
but I didn't want you to be the last to know.
Scylla is moving.
- Come back?
- Don't worry.
We're gonna stick to our original plan.
- What exactly is the plan?
- We wait.
- Wait?
- Yes.
- Okay, have you ever heard of noodling?
- I don't believe so.
Then what kind of hillbilly are you,
really?
I'll explain it to you.
Noodling is when a foolhardy bastard
swims to the bottom of a muddy riverbed...
...and he sticks his hand
down into the deepest, darkest hole.
He's looking for a prize catfish.
Now, sometimes,
the catfish does live there.
And the noodler pulls it out
with his bare hand and he drags it ashore.
But sometimes, he reaches in that hole
and he finds a snapping turtle.
Bites his hand clean off.
Scofield's your noodler.
Yes. And if he reaches into
the Company hole and he finds Scylla...
...we take it and we sell it to Feng.
If he gets a turtle, well...
...not our hand.
The contractors are here.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm a client.
- You're a client?
- Keep it down.
It's all part of the rules.
We need some help.
I'm already providing my services,
white-collar style, all right?
Where's pretty and the fat man?
Bellick's dead.
Make a joke about it
and I'll rip your tongue out.
Let's go, Linc.
Sorry to bother you. I'm an internist.
I brought my husband.
He's in and out of consciousness.
His symptoms concern me.
I'd be really grateful
if we could see a neurologist.
Does he have insurance?
Yeah. I don't have the card,
but I have his ID.
Here. Just fill this out.
Okay. Thank you.
Mr. Freeling?
Yes. Yes, that's me.
Is it always low?
A little.
Has anyone in your family ever
suffered from epilepsy, stroke, TIAs...
...any neurological disorder?
My mom.
Okay.
Jimmy, take this gentleman back
to Bay 4.
Why are we relocating?
Scylla's security is the foundation
of this entire organization.
I realize that. But have you thought
about the ramifications?
We lose critical access.
It could compromise our timeline
on stage two.
The plates and the facility
are ready to print...
...as much currency as we need
at any time.
But when will Scylla be installed
in Pennsylvania?
Lisa, what's our timeline?
Actually, there's been a bit of a problem.
Dismantling the security surrounding sill
is a bit tricky.
- It may take longer than we thought.
- How much longer?
I can make this happen right now.
Yes, general?
- Go get David Baker.
- Yes, sir.
Yes?
Hello, I'm looking for a Mr. David Baker.
He's not taking any new projects
right now.
Actually, I have some questions
about something...
... that he worked on a few years ago.
Are you familiar
with a project called Scylla?
I'm working.
This man would like
to talk to you about Scylla.
You're Company?
Yes, sir.
I'm in logistics.
And I'd like to ask you some questions
about your original design.
Been a long time
since I thought about that.
Be lucky to remember anything.
Looks like you're pretty busy.
Do you mind if I take a look?
You know, Bellick saved my life.
What?
Back when we were in prison in Panama.
T-Bag went crazy. He went nuts.
What happened?
He lit Sona on fire.
Told everyone to run.
"They can't shoot us all," he said.
It was a stampede, bro.
I was down, getting trampled.
I couldn't get up.
I couldn't breathe.
I thought I was gonna die and...
But then something put me back
on my feet.
It was Bellick.
He saved my life.
That wall's gotta come down?
Unless you got a better idea.
Okay.
What was that?
I don't know.
I think I stepped on something.
What's going on, Linc?
I don't know.
It's some kind of explosive.
Explosive. Then shouldn't I be dead?
If you move, you will be.
They're underground.
You're not gonna be able to reach them.
Right.
And you know what?
They'll be fine without you.
Right.
You ever heard of Fox River?
Maybe we could talk about it over dinner.
I got a gift card to the Red Lobster
over off the interstate.
I never thought the guys would be so sad
for Brad Bellick.
A lot of things have changed
since Fox River.
You know you can't control this, yeah?
That's funny. I was just about
to tell you the same thing.
Whatever it is, we can manage it.
Just need to know
what we're dealing with.
What if I don't want to know?
Kevin Freeling?
Should only take a few minutes.
- You ready?
- I'm ready.
My goal is to build one city
that entirely self-sustains.
Dependent on no outside resources.
A community living entirely in harmony.
How close is it to becoming reality?
Well, it's a matter of opinion.
People look at something like this
and they think it's impossible.
In reality,
I could make it happen tomorrow.
Look what they built in Dubai.
Exactly. Grand ideas brought into reality.
This won't just serve the rich.
How long have you been working
for them?
Too long.
I came in in '94.
I was never good at collecting
a paycheck. Always freelance.
Partially retired all the time.
I like to finish a job and then move on.
Put it in the past.
You always leave your name behind?
Instead of the correct specifications?
Only on the Scylla project.
Well, we're considering modifications...
...and I was hoping
that you would help me...
...figure out what should really appear
on those blueprints.
As of right now,
they don't mean much.
Didn't you read the legend?
Sure.
But we still had a lot of trouble.
You're not Company.
What should I do?
- Stay calm.
- Calm?
- I'm standing on a bomb.
- We'll work it out.
You think Gretchen set us up?
Lessons taught by our founder, Mr...
...Harvey Hall.
The pathway to personal freedom...
Do people actually buy this nonsense?
- Let go of me.
- You're coming with me...
...or through that glass. Choose.
This is a place of business.
GATE allows us to find the pathway
to personal freedom.
Define our boundaries.
See past them.
Let me tell you a story
about the founder of this great program.
You know, I'm gonna tell you a better story
about captivity than the regular old spiel.
Years back,
I was providing volunteer leadership...
...in a local penitentiary.
I worked with the head guard...
...a big, burly bull named Brad.
Mean as the devil.
All the prisoners were afraid of him.
Even the murderers.
And one day, Brad said to me,
"Cole, I want you to get out of here.
I want you to get out of here now.
Because I can tell
you're a man who loves freedom."
And I said,
"Well, what about you, Brad?
What about you?"
He said, "Well, yeah,
I'm gonna be free someday when I retire."
I recently got the news
that he had passed away.
And where was he?
Still in that prison.
Still in the captivity of negativity.
Sorry, folks.
Old Brad.
As my papi used to say:
"Stand by, your glasses steady
And drink to your comrade's eyes.
Here's a toast to the dead already
And hurrah for the next to die."
I needed to make sure
I'd have access to your test results.
So I told the triage nurse
that I was your wife.
Has a nice ring.
Are you Kevin Freeling?
Yes. I am.
I'm Dr. Malden. I'm a neurologist.
- And you are?
- Cameron Eberline.
I'm an internist. Do you have the results?
It's gonna take a little while.
Looking at the family history,
I'd like to admit you here.
We're working on a room. Just for now,
till we get the test results.
That won't be necessary. Thank you.
It would be best if you could rest
where you could be monitored.
After that, we'll determine
what the best course of action is. Agreed?
I think we have to go. Sorry.
Hold on, hold on. How long will it take
to get the results?
Couple hours.
But we'll get you in a room before then.
- Just wait here.
- Thank you.
Come on.
You know what happens. They take over
your life. You don't own it anymore.
That is not what happened to me.
Then somehow,
you stayed out of trouble.
You did what they told you to do.
Maybe that's why you stuck around,
huh?
Right here in Los Angeles.
In my case, they had something on me.
And they used it.
And they never let me go.
They've killed hundreds, thousands
of people in the pursuit of power.
You know that.
We lost a good man yesterday
trying to stop them.
They hurt a lot of people, David.
- David.
- Look...
...I stay out of the politics.
It was a job.
I specialized in security engineering.
Scylla was a choice assignment,
so I took it.
They told you what it was, didn't they?
They told you what it was.
Now you wish you'd never helped them,
but you're trapped like I was.
- You talk like it's all in the present.
- It is.
I know you wanna move on. I'm...
Look what you're doing.
Trying to make up for something?
Forget the charitable city of the future.
Worry about the world
that you live in right now.
What they did,
what they're doing, is not my fault.
You put your name in there for a reason.
You wanted someone to find you.
And if you tell me what I need to know,
I can do something for both of us.
Where's your husband?
Running errands.
He should be right back.
That's his car in the driveway, isn't it?
Just a moment.
I'll go call him on his cell.
- Excuse me!
- Backup request at southeast door.
You knew about this, didn't you?
First of all, I have no idea...
...why the Company would put an explosive
of any kind underneath their own building.
- We're under the courtyard.
- You know, I honestly had no idea...
...that any of this was even here.
That being said...
...these look a lot like JZ33
anti-personnel blast mines.
Back in Fallujah, the muj used
to bury them outside their firm base.
Well, get rid of them.
Well, I'm no expert, but I have an idea.
- What's beeping?
- It beeps.
Wow, you must have stepped
on this just right.
Your weight is evenly distributed
across the pressure plate.
And you haven't engaged the firing pin.
You can't move an inch.
We know. What's your idea?
My idea is that he moves an inch.
I can get to the hole
and dismantle the firing pin.
- He's standing on it. I can't do anything.
- No.
No, no, no, Linc:
- What?
- Call your brother, please.
You, you stay here.
Fine.
- It's my brother.
- Michael.
Let's go.
Sara.
Not leaving, are you?
You have our number.
- Who are you?
- He prefers to wait at home.
- I'm monitoring.
- He's leaving...
...in a potentially fragile condition.
Look, I'm not stupid.
I know who you are.
And I'm not gonna turn you in.
My concern is for what's going on
with your health.
They aren't here for you.
And in your condition...
Thank you, doctor.
I appreciate your help.
Please do call us.
Can I help you?
I messed up.
What do you mean?
Today, I was working with Bagwell.
He's been compliant as hell.
I thought I'd make him happy.
He wanted to talk about Gretchen.
- Right. And what happened?
- And I slipped up.
I mentioned Whistler.
This one is tough. I'm telling you.
Bagwell, Gretchen Morgan.
They're thugs.
I have been faced down with a gun
to the back of my head more than once.
All right.
Look, I don't want you to do something
that you don't wanna do.
You're a good agent.
We could reassign...
No. No, that is not it.
Look, I can handle this. I'm just...
I'm just kicking myself.
I could find something else for you to do.
This thing's gotten way out of hand.
Dallow's on my back.
- And the Company is moving Scylla.
- No.
I'm fine.
Are you sure?
I really think we can do this, Don.
We can bring the Company down.
Ego is the only reason
I coded my name into those blueprints.
I don't feel guilty about anything.
I gotta take this. I'm sorry.
Hello?
Alex, we got a problem.
- What?
- We got a problem.
There's a damn minefield down there.
Hello, I can't hear you.
Sucre's in trouble.
He's standing on a mine.
We need to deactivate it.
Linc, I gotta go. I'll call you back.
What?
They're here, David.
- What do they want?
- They're moving Scylla, protecting it.
Everything you did for them,
they want you to do it again.
You think you can stop them?
I know all about you.
I've known about you for six months.
Since somebody stole
those plans from the Company.
It will never work.
You won't get past the first wall.
What about the first wall?
What's gonna stop me, huh? The minefield?
Please.
Don't tell them.
Got him. Sweep the area.
There's a dirt road
at the bottom of the hill.
- It'll take you out.
- Your husband...
Just go.
He won't help you. That will.
Linc, go call him again.
Linc, go call him. Linc, go call him.
What will Michael know about this?
I mean, it's not exactly
within his realm of expertise.
We're wasting time.
I gave you a semi-professional assessment.
What's wrong?
You don't trust me, Fernando?
Why should he?
Because we all want the same thing,
Scylla.
I won't let a giant pack
of firecrackers stand in our way.
Or would you like me
to call the bomb squad?
Look, I am offering to do you
a massive favor here.
If that thing blows while I'm pulling the pin,
he loses a leg. I loose a face.
Now, don't worry, Fernando.
I'm known for my steady hand.
Take a deep breath, okay?
Keep your weight even.
And I need you to shift slowly,
very slowly...
...one inch to your left,
so I can get to the pin.
No, no, I can't. I can't. I can't do it.
You all right?
Have you heard anything?
They have to deactivate.
I got a key, a legend to the blueprint.
Baker gave you this?
No, his wife gave it to me.
They came for Baker.
All right, well, this makes more sense.
These symbols aren't for P-traps.
They're... They're microphones.
And the letter V isn't for vacuum.
That's the generator.
This is a line of JZ33 land mines,
buried 80 millimeters underground...
...about 7 feet from the outer wall.
That must be what Linc was talking about.
It says, "manual override only.
All conventional attempts to dismantle
the JZ33 will activate the Scylla alarms."
This isn't just a land mine. This is...
This is an alarm.
We can't sit here all night.
Okay?
You ready?
Hey, it's Linc. You know what to do.
What are you doing?
Linc?
Sucre!
Stop. Stop!
Don't move. Don't move. Don't move.
You can't dismantle the land mine
without setting off the alarm.
- So I either set off the alarm or die.
- No.
There's a manual override.
It will cut the power long enough
for you to step off...
...without removing the pin.
- How do you know for sure?
- I found David Baker.
Sucre, step off.
You can do it.
You only have 20 seconds. Come on.
- I can't...
- Yes, you can.
Michael and I figured it out.
Step off right now.
No, you guys all go.
We all don't have to die. I'll do it alone.
Nobody's gonna die today. Step off!
Step off.
What's behind this wall?
Scylla.
When do you find out?
The doctor's supposed to call...
...any minute.
Look...
...l'm sorry I wasn't there for you today.
Don't worry about it.
You know, what Gretchen did for Sucre
made me realize we can use her.
I asked for the sixth key.
What'd she say?
She's on it.
You all right? All right.
I'm about to go to the airfield,
ship Brad's body to his mother.
We've got his things here.
Where is he?
Over here.
His mom will appreciate that.
Mrs. Bellick...
...this is Fernando Sucre.
Great job today.
I'm sorry to hear about your friend.
But that's admirable work...
...volunteering with a bunch
of criminals like that.
We're all the same, really.
Here's the application
you requested for the desk girl.
You have a good night, Cole.
You too. Thanks.
Hello.
Hello?
Okay. We will. Thank you.
As we've all learned the hard way...
...there's an electronic alarm barrier
around the perimeter of the foundation.
Unfortunately that is Scylla's
most primitive line of defense.
The wall itself is fortified with steel fiber.
The good news is, on the inside here,
there are no cameras.
The Company doesn't want
any visual evidence that Scylla exists.
The bad news is that there are both weight
and microphonic sensors here and here...
...that will alert Company security...
...to the presence of any breathing human
being that weighs more than 2 pounds.
As far as I can tell...
...the first challenge
is getting around that wall...
...and then we can worry about
crossing the floor.
Without touching it.
In silence.
It's complicated.
But I'm already working on something.
Brad didn't die in vain.
We can make this work.
That was the neurologist.
You have a hypothalamus hamartoma.
It's really rare.
You were probably born with it.
Things have changed.
It's been growing...
...which is why you've been experiencing
your symptoms.
And the doctor feels
that you need surgery.
Two days. That's what I need.
Tomorrow.
Otherwise you could die
and there's no alternative.
www.tvsubtitles.net