Well, if you're watching this,
I'm glad.
Because that means
you're safe.
How does he think
he's gonna do this, bro?
He's going
to jump out of a plane.
I know he's gonna jump.
The question is, can he land?
Not without getting caught.
And how is he going
to get out of the cell block,
even if T-Bag--
It's a big "if".
Trusting T-Bag is... crazy.
Michael, we, uh...
We really have to re-think this.
I have.
And there's no other way.
Okay.
I'm going to drop down
into this outer area here.
And I'll cut the parachute off
before anyone can reach me.
They're going to be
right on your ass.
I can hide behind this building,
wait for a window.
Then I'll make my way
over here.
That's the chapel.
Well hopefully, uh...
Sara will be waiting.
Why the chapel?
During the riot in '88,
prison employees escaped through
the administration building.
They wound up here,
outside the fence.
The administration building,
is connected to the chapel.
Which means that
somewhere in that compound,
there is
a subterranean exit.
If we can get
through it,
you can meet us there.
How's Sara gonna get
to the chapel?
She'll have
to find a way.
Look, we're doing this
at 7 PM tonight,
just like we've planned.
- Where have you been?
- What did I miss?
I need you to find a plane
and a pilot.
I need you two,
to take care of T-Bag.
Find out exactly who has this money,
and where they're keeping it.
- And then we have to get it.
- By 7 PM tonight.
Or Sara's going
to die in there.
Is everybody onboard?
Okay.
Tell me, you've completed
your assignment.
Well, I got the cash.
But there'll may be some delay
in final delivery.
The woman we hired is having trouble
getting near Sara Tancredi.
Then hire somebody else.
Call it open season.
Put a bounty on her head.
I don't care how you do it.
I want Sara Tancredi
dead by the end
of the day.
Open cell!
One hour!
Yo, we about to play cards.
Do you want in?
I'm okay.
Thanks.
You should.
With Daddy gone,
you're gonna need your backup.
Hell, we all did.
I've got, uh...
a pre-natal thing.
It's cool.
Thanks.
Not too smart though, for a girl
with a bounty on her head.
Aren't you heard?
Tancredi,
you have a visitor.
Say hello to your husband
for me.
What's wrong?
Look, um...
I know you don't have
any control
over what's happened here,
but uh...
Things aren't working out.
Okay.
I'm trying
to find a way to...
To do... this.
But from where
we're standing right now,
there's only
one option.
Do you need more time...
to think?
No. No, it's not
about that.
I've made up
my mind.
'Cause there's nothing
you could do about it.
Except...
pray for us tonight.
Pray for us?
You can pray for us
to be together.
Maybe
I'll do the same.
How can I rob someone
if I've no clue who he is?
The logbook outside says that
Krantz had one visitor yesterday.
A Joe Daniels.
Well if he was in
the power deduction, I'd say,
Daniels
is your bagman.
You know how many Daniels
live in Miami?
Thousands.
I need more.
Well you better
get crackin',
'cause if I ain't get
that money by 7 o'clock,
you ain't got your fire,
you ain't got your fire alarm.
And that means Pretty
ain't got his Mrs. Pretty.
Listen, my friend,
you're in no position
to makin' demands...
Okay, shh--
I ain't talking about
backing out the deal.
I put my ear on the ground
and come up with some details.
Good.
And now, fetch.
We got a pilot.
There's a guy
I'd busted 20 years ago,
running drugs
across the Gulf.
Went legit.
Runs a charter business now.
He must've jumped
out of a few planes, huh?
Yes, several.
Some for sport.
Some necessity.
It's a big difference,
Michael.
It's not easy hitting the X,
especially at night.
Don't worry.
I can go alone.
- What do you got?
- It's a test.
See, the prison was built
in the mid-80's,
so that exit in
the administration building
is probably protected
by an electronic code of lock,
modified by
a security card.
Those locks don't have
power protection,
which means
you can override them.
Then you can't just
go to the building,
shut it,
or blow it out?
No.
1200 volt power surge will just
set off the other alarms.
Not to mention
that it'll kill you.
That's why we have
to find another way.
Yeah.
Talk to me, Mahone.
What have you got?
Nothing yet.
I don't need updates
on the hour.
I need evidence, intent.
It's not crap.
Call me when he's in the
process of committing a crime.
Yeah.
I'm not going
to let him walk away
from me
like he did from you.
It's going down if I've got
to shoot him in the back.
Sorry.
Time for you
to get paid now, bitch.
Are we friends now?
Get out of the way!
What happened here?!
I didn't see anything, sir.
- Move!
- Me neither.
Bad news.
Agatha Warren
is dead.
- Who did that?
- No one's talking.
But I hear it says fish.
Tancredi and Morgan.
No!
There he is.
If you don't like this guy,
we can still find someone else.
Good to see you, Sni.
What you get into here,
Mahone?
Jumping at 1500 feet
ain't going to be easy.
You've gone back
on your word already?
Let's not forget who's doing
who a favor here.
Favor?
Favor that I bust
your old lady for traficking.
No, I did not.
If anyone asks,
I was flying tourists to the Keys,
and it's not my fault
they jumped.
Sounds good to me.
If you don't like this guy,
we'd take a day.
- We come up with a new plan.
- No, there's no time, Alex.
- It's not just Sara's life at risk.
- I understand that.
I know you do.
That's why I also know
I can ask for your help.
- Yeah. What do you need?
- If I don't make it...
I want you to make sure
Sara and my brother
get out of
the country alive.
I need to know
they're gonna be okay.
And I'm gonna trust
that you'll do everything
you can
to make that happen.
Take this.
I trust you, Alex.
Remember that.
Special delivery.
- What is it?
- I don't exactly know.
It came via messenger from uh...
the lady side.
"My man on the outside needs to know
who to call for the birthday present."
Whose birthday is it?
Well, just see to it that it gets back
to the same place.
Will do.
So this is
Joe Daniels' number, right?
That's it.
Is that
enough information,
or you need
a social security number too?
- That'll do.
- Remember--
I want that money wired
to the account number specified.
No wire, no fire.
You boys
do me wrong,
I have no qualms at all about
singing it loud and clear,
you understand?
You know what?
Just be ready.
That was Sofia.
She'll meet you
in the San Andreas Harbor
in Dominican Republic
and then
- you guys can fly to Costa Rica.
- Cool.
I know
where Daniels is.
And after
we rob him,
I'll take the money
to Quik Green and, uh...
wire to the bank.
You're gonna meet us
at the airstrip, right?
Might give
a shot now.
Okay.
This is it.
We're ready.
Thanks, buddy.
For everything.
Good luck, papi.
See you
on the other side.
Nobody's talking, huh?
Girl's dead. No one's said any?
I made it
in the woodshop.
Want to give
my daughter Emily
a birthday gift
on her actual birthday.
So I need
to get out of here.
It's funny.
- You're never sentimental.
- Oh, I'm not. It's just for her.
We need to get
to the chapel.
We?
There's no way out of here,
right now.
I'm gonna need you.
Yeah?
Mr. Daniels,
American Paint Company,
here for the job.
Well, this is Mr. Daniels,
but I didn't order any painters.
It's Wednesday, sir.
I believe you did.
Hold it right there.
I'm calling the police.
Get out!
This is it.
I'll be right back.
Gotta get that parachute.
Michael!
Come here.
There's
a better way.
Mess!
Mess,
half hour.
Little faster.
We don't have all day.
Let's go!
Got any ideas?
Yeah. Keep your head down
and follow me.
I'll think
of something.
You better think of something fast,
'cause we have company.
I hope you're ready
for a fight, princess.
This one's
to the death.
Do you think
you can overpower her?
Yeah. I don't think it's her
you have to worry about.
Just be ready.
- Hello?
- It's me.
I got the message
about the birthday present?
Was the gift earned?
What in the hell
are you talking about?
- The birthday present.
- Birthday present?
Two guys showed up
at my house,
they took the money
and they
beat the crap
out of me.
Howdy, General.
I just thought of let you know
how I came in with some green.
My personal preference is
two Zegna bars and a copy of the Times.
So I see you
in the AEM?
You worthless son of a whore.
Go to hell!
Careful
I don't get there first.
Lest I become
king of that prison, too.
Alright, from takeoff,
the prison's gonna come up
real fast.
So whatever you gotta do
to get ready, do it now.
You got it.
We've got the money.
Sucre's just dropped me off
on the way to wire it.
Good.
That means T-Bag's set.
I'm goin' to see how long
it's gonna take and we get going.
You sure that thing's
gonna hold you up?
Yeah,
it'll be fine.
What about you?
This is not my first time
inside a prison.
But hopefully...
will be my last.
Think about all the amazing stories
you're gonna be able to tell your kid.
You're gonna be the type of father
our dad never was.
Someone
to look up to.
Take care, Michael.
Unless you've got details,
I'm hanging up.
And you can forget about
getting your badge back.
He's got a plane.
He's got a parachute into the yard.
- What?
- Yeah, I swear to God,
he's gonna be over
prison airspace
at 7 o'clock.
Call in reinforcements.
I want 20 armed COs in the yard.
And be ready to turn off
all exterior lights.
Scofield won't see what's coming
until it's too late.
And bring me
Sara Tancredi.
Wait, wait.
What do you think happened
with Agatha,
it's not what happened.
I need to make this
right with you, okay?
Go ahead.
I was hoping
I'd see you here.
You know I still owe you
one big juicy favor.
Later, blue eyes.
I swear to God
she wanted to kill me
and I was just
defending myself.
- You remember that?
- Yes, I do.
My momma
gave me that.
Told me I was going to give it
to one of my kids one day.
Not only did I get knocked up,
but the girl in the family...
And I practically raised Agatha
and she was no killer.
Now I can say
that much for myself.
You didn't know
what I had in mind yet.
Okay, listen, you're right.
Agatha isn't a killer.
She was just a-- real bitch
with a bit of more than she need to.
Skittles.
Okay.
We cool.
We cool, we--
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Kaorla. She wants you
to bring Tancredi to her office.
A'ight? Okay.
Son of a bitch!
They'll be coming
right through here, okay?
Federal agent Todd Wheatley.
I need to get inside right now.
Emergency team
takes priority, sir.
I'm the leader of
the emergency team.
Now let me inside.
- Sorry. Strict orders.
- Go talk to your supervisor.
Come on!
No weapons!
Let the suburban through.
The plane should be overhead
any minute.
Hey, fellas!
Kill the lights.
As soon as he hits the ground,
I just want one of you to start firing.
Standby.
We're standing by.
Easy now.
Hold your fire.
Standby!
Now!
Let's go.
Move in, men!
Where the hell's
Scofield?
Emergency team
takes priority, sir.
I'm the leader of the emergency team.
Now let me inside right now.
I've strict orders.
No one gets inside at this point, sir.
I don't care what your orders are.
Go talk to your supervisor.
Why isn't Tancredi
in front of me right now?
We've just got
the situation under control.
We're looking for her
right now.
Oh my God!
- Are you alright?
- Yeah. It was Morgan.
Check the kitchen.
They might be in the kitchen.
I'm not gonna make it
on my own.
Either leave me with tools here
or make up your damn mind.
Are you gonna be able
to make it?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's now.
Alright, hold up.
Nah,
I think we're good.
Don't move!
- Stand on the dark, now!
- Please, I just...
On the ground!
You're here alone?
Damn it, con. When I ask you
a question, you answer.
Is there
anyone else here?
Yes.
Who?
- God.
- Excuse me?
He's always here.
I was worried about my little girl
on the outside.
So I came to pray.
See if someone would
watch over her.
Go check it out.
The stove mess is open.
Need support right now!
I've got to get
these animals locked down!
We better head
over there.
I hope that daughter
of yours
- is hell a lot smarter than you.
- So do I.
Hey.
Are you ready
to go?
Nobody gets in or out
of this prison.
I don't care if it's the President
having to take a piss,
you tell him
to turn the hell around.
Get a team.
I want every inch of that fence line
checked for points of compromise.
Yes, sir.
Michael said this is where
they're gonna come out.
You think Sucre
made the drop on time?
I don't know.
No, no, no.
Please enter
your account number.
9248.
Your account balance is
zero dollars and zero cents.
If you would like
to access another account--
9248, pow!
Your account balance is
zero dollars and zero cents.
What the hell you thinking
you're doing, fish?
We're in lockdown.
What for?
Something's going on in bitch block.
I don't know.
What's it worth to you
to find out?
We're going to get
through here?
On the other side is
a kind of an escape hatch
for the administrators.
In case of a riot.
If this is the same system
they have in Fox River,
that door can only be open remotely
from the Central Control.
That's why we've gone
and ask for help.
T-Bag.
Tell them
what you told me.
Michael Scofield is about
to stage a prison break.
And I know exactly
how he's gonna do it.
Exactly what did
Scofield asked you to do?
Just light a fire
in my cell.
And the rest...
The rest will just
take care of itself.
A fire alarm.
If that goes off,
what's your protocol?
State law, mandatory evac.
Hell,
he won't go break,
I was goin' to get you
to escort her out.
- Shut up!
- Get him outta here.
Alright, the evacuation's only
going to get him out in the yard.
Whatever he's up to,
he needs noise
and he needs chaos.
Deactivate the smoke detection system,
the fire alarm,
and while you're at it,
kill the horn.
If anybody so much as bends
a blade of grass in this place,
I want him to be able
to hear it.
- What are we waiting for?
- We made a deal.
With the right price,
T-Bag will set off the fire alarms.
That's what
we're waiting for.
- Michael, there's a--
- It's okay.
See, there's only one thing
you can count on
when you're dealing
with T-Bag.
He's a rat.
Anything?
So far, just a female inmate
loose in the yard.
- Tancredi?
- No, Morgan. First name, Gretchen.
- Over by the chapel.
- Alright.
Alright.
Great.
Let's go.
Okay,
down there.
Okay.
Beyond this door should be
a hundred yards of tunnel.
On the other end
of that is Linc,
and after that,
there's a boat mounted
for white sands and blue water.
A power surge to the system,
will override the reader,
for just a few seconds.
Just long enough for you
to open that, so get ready.
3, 2, 1.
One more time.
I was afraid
this might happen.
It's okay.
It's alright.
We're going
to keep moving
and we're gonna find
another way out of here.
I know
what I have to do.
I need units to the chapel.
Now!
- Where are they?
- I don't know.
They should've been here
by now.
The battery wasn't generating
enough power.
We have to blow the system
for the whole building.
Okay.
What do you want to try?
This is
the main fuse.
If I yanked that,
everything will go dark
for a second.
I reconnect
these two cables...
If I reconnect
these two cables,
there'll be
a lot of noise,
every light bulb in this place
is going to blow.
As soon as that happens,
you need to open that hatch.
And I want you
to start running.
Okay.
What about you?
Michael?
Sara...
Someone has
to stay here,
and someone has
to open the hatch.
And that someone's
gotta be you.
Okay. So I'll leave it
open for you.
You don't understand.
This is the only way.
I'm not leaving unless
you're coming with me.
But I am coming
with you.
I love you.
God,
I love you too.
Go!
Go, Sara.
Go.
Downstairs.
Where's Michael?
Sara, where is he?
Where is he?
He's not coming back.
What do you mean,
he's not coming back?
What do you mean
by that?
He's not coming back.
He'll be here.
He's gone,
Lincoln.
Linc,
we gotta go.
We gotta go.
Hey,
I'll be over there in a minute.
Why am I being punished?!
I'm the guy through the window!
You aided and abetted an escape,
Mr. Bagwell.
And as far as
the authorities are concerned,
you're an accomplice.
Scofield!
Michael asked me to give you this,
if he didn't make it out.
He said it would help you understand
why he did what he did.
It's his bloodwork.
This is
the General's money.
I was supposed
to wire it down
to Costa Rica for you
to pick up but uh...
I ran into
some trouble.
I'm sorry.
You take care
of that baby, okay?
You take care yours.
This is for you.
He never said
anything to me.
Why didn't he
just tell me?
'Cause he knew you'll try
to stop him.
He knew you'd do anything
to protect your family.
But I didn't.
Well...
You will soon.
Take it easy.
Sara.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Well, if you're watching this,
I'm glad.
Because that means
you're safe.
And that's
all I ever wanted.
I wish I could...
be there with you.
But as you probably
know now,
I wouldn't have much
time anyway, so...
I made my choice,
and--
I don't regret it.
Anyway,
not too long from now,
there's going to be another
little Scofield running around.
And Linc,
I want you
to promise me,
no matter what,
they're going to grow up knowing
their uncle is never far away.
And Sara,
I want you
to promise me
that you're gonna keep
an eye on Linc.
As you may
have noticed,
he has the tendency
to get in trouble.
You know we spend
so much of our lives,
not saying the things
we want to say.
The things
we should say.
We speak in code,
we send little messages.
Origami.
So now,
plainly, simply,
I want to say that
I love you both.
Very much.
And I want you
to promise me,
that you're gonna
tell my child,
that you're gonna tell my child
how much they're loved every day.
and remind them
how lucky they are...
To be free.
Because we are.
We're free now.
Finally.
We're free.
Proper Transcript:
TheSurferGuy
Final Edits and Synchro:
VeRdiKT
Exclusively For:
SubScene.com
www.tvsubtitles.net