1
00:00:00,260 --> 00:00:05,130
previously on prison break:

2
00:00:10,530 --> 00:00:11,760
Michael!

3
00:00:14,800 --> 00:00:16,460
Scylla is complete.

4
00:00:16,530 --> 00:00:18,400
What the hell are you doing?!

5
00:00:18,460 --> 00:00:20,060
The buyer is already on the way.

6
00:00:22,630 --> 00:00:23,700
Yeah,I got one.

7
00:00:23,760 --> 00:00:25,000
It's Bagwell.

8
00:00:25,060 --> 00:00:28,330
There is no meeting with the attorney general,is there?

9
00:00:28,400 --> 00:00:29,460
He's sick,Lincoln.

10
00:00:29,530 --> 00:00:31,330
If they haven't killed him already...

11
00:00:31,400 --> 00:00:33,000
We'll get him back,I promise.

12
00:00:33,060 --> 00:00:35,630
Michael needs an operation to remove a tumor

13
00:00:35,700 --> 00:00:37,030
from his temporal lobe.

14
00:00:37,100 --> 00:00:39,760
The price of the operation is the safe return of Scylla.

15
00:00:39,830 --> 00:00:40,830
What's that?

16
00:00:40,900 --> 00:00:42,760
Added incentive.

17
00:00:47,900 --> 00:00:49,630
What's going on?

18
00:00:49,700 --> 00:00:51,230
Where's Michael?

19
00:00:51,300 --> 00:00:53,400
Michael needs surgery,he's gonna get it.

20
00:00:53,460 --> 00:00:54,730
Where?

21
00:00:54,800 --> 00:00:57,300
- Here.  - What?

22
00:00:57,360 --> 00:00:59,930
Krantz has arranged for the best doctors in the world.

23
00:01:00,000 --> 00:01:01,600
We can't let them near him.

24
00:01:01,660 --> 00:01:02,860
We're out of time.

25
00:01:02,930 --> 00:01:05,160
It's our last option.

26
00:01:05,230 --> 00:01:08,600
I don't understand why the Company would help him.

27
00:01:08,660 --> 00:01:10,000
Dr. Tancredi,welcome.

28
00:01:10,060 --> 00:01:11,860
Please...

29
00:01:11,930 --> 00:01:13,800
there's nothing to be afraid of.

30
00:01:13,860 --> 00:01:15,700
All we want is to help.

31
00:01:15,760 --> 00:01:17,530
You're going to save Michael?

32
00:01:17,600 --> 00:01:19,360
You question our capabilities?

33
00:01:19,430 --> 00:01:21,360
No. I'm questioning your motives.

34
00:01:21,430 --> 00:01:24,160
When a fellow human being is suffering,

35
00:01:24,230 --> 00:01:26,960
why would we not want to lend a hand?

36
00:01:27,030 --> 00:01:28,830
Empathy,Sara,

37
00:01:28,900 --> 00:01:32,160
it's the only thing that separates us from the beasts.

38
00:01:32,230 --> 00:01:34,060
For the duration of the surgery,

39
00:01:34,130 --> 00:01:37,200
you'll be treated as a guest in my home.

40
00:01:37,260 --> 00:01:39,660
And afterwards?

41
00:01:39,730 --> 00:01:42,700
Sir... the patient is ready.

42
00:01:44,100 --> 00:01:46,160
It's going to be all right,Sara.

43
00:01:46,230 --> 00:01:48,430
Trust me.

44
00:01:55,230 --> 00:02:00,330
Mr. Scofield,although you're going to be anesthetized

45
00:02:00,400 --> 00:02:03,800
and should feel no significant pain,we will need to keep

46
00:02:03,860 --> 00:02:06,260
you awake for the duration of the procedure.

47
00:02:06,330 --> 00:02:08,860
As a safety precaution,we'll need to continually monitor

48
00:02:08,930 --> 00:02:12,830
your speech and sensory activity to insure the tissue

49
00:02:12,900 --> 00:02:16,930
being removed will not leave you impaired in any way.

50
00:02:17,000 --> 00:02:18,900
What hospital is this?

51
00:02:18,960 --> 00:02:21,230
Don't worry about it. You've got some good doctors

52
00:02:21,300 --> 00:02:24,100
who are going to take great care of you.

53
00:02:26,200 --> 00:02:27,400
I have to get Scylla.

54
00:02:27,460 --> 00:02:28,930
No,no,no,no.

55
00:02:29,000 --> 00:02:30,260
Not now.

56
00:02:30,330 --> 00:02:32,060
Where's Linc?

57
00:02:32,130 --> 00:02:33,900
He's here.

58
00:02:33,960 --> 00:02:35,800
He's just fine.

59
00:02:35,860 --> 00:02:39,060
I'm not leaving until Michael has his surgery.

60
00:02:39,130 --> 00:02:41,030
And I'm not starting surgery until you prove

61
00:02:41,100 --> 00:02:43,260
you can hold up your end of the deal.

62
00:02:43,330 --> 00:02:46,830
Scylla's slipping through our fingers as we speak.

63
00:02:46,900 --> 00:02:50,700
Time is not on our side,nor on your brother's.

64
00:02:50,760 --> 00:02:52,730
Now,you'll get full cooperation

65
00:02:52,800 --> 00:02:54,530
from my office.

66
00:02:54,600 --> 00:02:56,660
If you need anything,just call this number.

67
00:02:56,730 --> 00:02:59,700
I'm gonna need everything you've got on Self and Gretchen.

68
00:02:59,760 --> 00:03:02,000
Aliases,whatever you got.

69
00:03:02,060 --> 00:03:04,100
How about an accomplice?

70
00:03:14,000 --> 00:03:15,730
Now,if you're gonna want...

71
00:03:15,800 --> 00:03:16,930
Shut up.

72
00:03:17,000 --> 00:03:18,200
You can save yourself a lot of pain

73
00:03:18,260 --> 00:03:20,200
and the embarrassment of begging me to stop

74
00:03:20,260 --> 00:03:21,960
if you just tell me where they are.

75
00:03:22,030 --> 00:03:24,360
Gretchen and Agent Turncoat?

76
00:03:24,430 --> 00:03:25,560
Yeah.

77
00:03:25,630 --> 00:03:27,430
Information like that seems like it could be

78
00:03:27,500 --> 00:03:29,460
of a certain intrinsic value.

79
00:03:29,530 --> 00:03:31,260
If there were offers made,

80
00:03:31,330 --> 00:03:34,360
carrots dangled,I could see...

81
00:03:34,430 --> 00:03:37,130
Look,I deserve some kind of something here,

82
00:03:37,200 --> 00:03:38,860
all the work I put in.

83
00:03:38,930 --> 00:03:41,960
If it wasn't for me finding Whistler's bird book then...

84
00:03:44,560 --> 00:03:47,260
The only thing you deserve is the opportunity

85
00:03:47,330 --> 00:03:49,100
to keep your teeth and fingernails.

86
00:03:49,160 --> 00:03:50,060
No. You...

87
00:03:50,130 --> 00:03:52,130
I'm not gonna tell you anything.

88
00:03:54,530 --> 00:03:56,660
I'm gonna pull out every single tooth,every single one.

89
00:03:56,730 --> 00:03:58,960
How about it?

90
00:03:59,030 --> 00:04:00,230
Look,I was just fooling...

91
00:04:00,300 --> 00:04:01,760
All right!

92
00:04:01,830 --> 00:04:04,630
Arlington Pier! Arling... Arlington Pier!

93
00:04:04,700 --> 00:04:07,130
When? What time?

94
00:04:07,960 --> 00:04:09,500
Three o'clock.

95
00:04:12,200 --> 00:04:15,500
This is the last of the anesthetic

96
00:04:15,560 --> 00:04:17,930
From here on out,you shouldn't feel a thing,Mr. Scofield.

97
00:04:18,000 --> 00:04:20,460
I'm going to be right over there the whole time.

98
00:04:20,530 --> 00:04:22,660
I'll be right in here the whole time.

99
00:04:24,530 --> 00:04:25,860
We're ready.

100
00:04:30,030 --> 00:04:33,000
I'm not going to leave you,okay?

101
00:04:33,060 --> 00:04:35,030
Don't you dare leave me.

102
00:04:58,230 --> 00:05:01,230
How many surgeries has your team performed using the gamma knife?

103
00:05:01,300 --> 00:05:03,400
The gamma knife has

104
00:05:03,460 --> 00:05:06,500
a recurrence rate of over 13 percent.

105
00:05:06,560 --> 00:05:09,160
We'll be using a technique that's more advanced.

106
00:05:54,430 --> 00:05:56,230
What's going on with Michael?

107
00:05:56,300 --> 00:05:57,900
They're gonna operate.

108
00:05:57,960 --> 00:05:59,800
Just like that,they agreed to do that?

109
00:05:59,860 --> 00:06:01,660
I convinced them Michael knew who was gonna buy Scylla.

110
00:06:01,730 --> 00:06:03,530
What are we gonna do?

111
00:06:03,600 --> 00:06:05,000
Get our hands on it before they do.

112
00:06:05,060 --> 00:06:07,230
- And give it to who?  - I'm still working on that.

113
00:06:07,300 --> 00:06:08,560
Linc,I need to know what we're doing.

114
00:06:08,630 --> 00:06:10,530
- We finish this!  - Really?

115
00:06:10,600 --> 00:06:11,700
Because it feels like it's finishing us.

116
00:06:11,760 --> 00:06:15,960
You,me... we're the only ones left,bro.

117
00:06:16,030 --> 00:06:17,430
One more day and we're done.

118
00:06:17,500 --> 00:06:19,100
I can't do this without you.

119
00:06:37,800 --> 00:06:38,930
When the buyer gets here,

120
00:06:39,000 --> 00:06:40,460
why don't you let me do the talking.

121
00:06:40,530 --> 00:06:41,730
For what?

122
00:06:41,800 --> 00:06:43,830
I engineered this whole thing,Gretchen.

123
00:06:43,900 --> 00:06:45,130
I can handle my business.

124
00:06:45,200 --> 00:06:47,530
Oh,yeah? Why don't you start

125
00:06:47,600 --> 00:06:48,560
by handling that river of nerves

126
00:06:48,630 --> 00:06:51,300
that's running down your forehead.

127
00:06:51,360 --> 00:06:52,400
Did you think this would be easier?

128
00:06:52,460 --> 00:06:53,560
I hoped.

129
00:06:53,630 --> 00:06:54,800
But I guess I always knew

130
00:06:54,860 --> 00:06:56,700
it was going to come down to a pile of bodies.

131
00:06:56,760 --> 00:06:58,400
I never pegged you for a killer.

132
00:06:58,460 --> 00:07:00,630
Yeah,well,I never pegged you for a mom.

133
00:07:02,800 --> 00:07:07,160
Is there anything that you'd like to peg me for,Don?

134
00:07:07,230 --> 00:07:11,060
Oh,stop. Okay. Don't embarrass yourself.

135
00:07:11,130 --> 00:07:12,560
That may work on everyone else,but right now,

136
00:07:12,630 --> 00:07:15,300
the only thing I'm thinking about is that $125 million.

137
00:07:15,360 --> 00:07:17,530
So close up your blouse and open your eyes,

138
00:07:17,600 --> 00:07:19,060
because the buyer's on the way.

139
00:07:19,130 --> 00:07:22,360
And I don't want any surprises when he gets here.

140
00:07:31,360 --> 00:07:32,830
How much longer?

141
00:07:32,900 --> 00:07:35,100
Another hour or so. Just sit tight.

142
00:07:35,160 --> 00:07:37,960
I need to use the men's room.

143
00:07:38,030 --> 00:07:39,500
Congratulations.

144
00:07:39,560 --> 00:07:40,700
What do you think I'm gonna do,run?

145
00:07:40,760 --> 00:07:41,960
That's exactly what I think you're gonna do.

146
00:07:42,030 --> 00:07:43,800
You want me to go in the back seat,right here?

147
00:07:43,860 --> 00:07:44,860
I want you to have a little bit of respect

148
00:07:44,930 --> 00:07:46,200
for my intelligence,Alex.

149
00:07:46,260 --> 00:07:48,360
I do,which is why I know you wouldn't violate

150
00:07:48,430 --> 00:07:51,700
Code 42-13-72B,which states that an individual

151
00:07:51,760 --> 00:07:53,200
being transported by a representative

152
00:07:53,260 --> 00:07:55,930
of the criminal justice system must be afforded the opportunity

153
00:07:56,000 --> 00:07:57,360
to relieve himself

154
00:07:57,430 --> 00:07:59,660
if the duration of the transport is more than three hours.

155
00:07:59,730 --> 00:08:03,260
And I do believe we're creeping up on that time.

156
00:08:03,330 --> 00:08:05,860
All right,I'll see what I can do.

157
00:08:05,930 --> 00:08:07,800
But I'm going to remind you of a code.

158
00:08:07,860 --> 00:08:11,160
The one that says if a prisoner attempts escape during transfer,

159
00:08:11,230 --> 00:08:13,300
the accompanying agent has the right to shoot them

160
00:08:13,360 --> 00:08:14,760
through the back of the head.

161
00:08:17,030 --> 00:08:19,230
You sure you don't want to hold it,Alex?

162
00:08:19,300 --> 00:08:22,600
Oh,yeah,I'm sure.

163
00:08:27,230 --> 00:08:30,300
Any pain or discomfort,Mr. Scofield?

164
00:08:30,360 --> 00:08:32,000
No.

165
00:08:32,060 --> 00:08:35,630
Those needles,they're for... stabilization?

166
00:08:35,700 --> 00:08:38,460
Not exactly. Throughout the surgery,different portions

167
00:08:38,530 --> 00:08:41,760
of Michael's cerebral cortex will be stimulated,

168
00:08:41,830 --> 00:08:43,500
triggering the areas

169
00:08:43,560 --> 00:08:46,430
that control senses like hearing,smell,memory.

170
00:08:46,500 --> 00:08:48,160
That's why some people,

171
00:08:48,230 --> 00:08:50,160
right before death,often speak of...

172
00:08:50,230 --> 00:08:51,430
Their life flashing before their eyes.

173
00:08:51,500 --> 00:08:53,900
Exactly.

174
00:08:53,960 --> 00:08:55,930
When oxygen is cut off to the brain,

175
00:08:56,000 --> 00:08:58,560
it kicks into overdrive,tapping into every resource

176
00:08:58,630 --> 00:09:00,700
to continue operating the body.

177
00:09:00,760 --> 00:09:04,360
As a result,all of the senses fire off at once.

178
00:09:04,430 --> 00:09:08,600
Everything you've ever known,felt,believed...

179
00:09:08,660 --> 00:09:11,960
it all passes in a blink of an eye.

180
00:09:47,660 --> 00:09:48,960
Hello,Michael?

181
00:09:58,860 --> 00:10:00,000
Charles?

182
00:10:00,060 --> 00:10:04,900
I guess you can probably call me DB now.

183
00:10:11,830 --> 00:10:13,660
The answer is no.

184
00:10:13,730 --> 00:10:15,030
The answer?

185
00:10:15,100 --> 00:10:17,060
You're wondering if you're dead.

186
00:10:17,130 --> 00:10:18,830
The answer is no.

187
00:10:18,900 --> 00:10:22,060
Then why am I here?

188
00:10:22,130 --> 00:10:24,360
I believe that's a question

189
00:10:24,430 --> 00:10:27,400
we all need to find the answer to.

190
00:10:36,330 --> 00:10:39,060
This is officially now the most secure bathroom break

191
00:10:39,130 --> 00:10:40,500
in the history of law enforcement.

192
00:10:40,560 --> 00:10:41,960
Yes,it is.

193
00:10:42,030 --> 00:10:44,500
Hey,look,if you want to cuff me,block off all the exits,

194
00:10:44,560 --> 00:10:46,660
take it out and give it a tap,if it makes you happy.

195
00:10:46,730 --> 00:10:48,960
Would that make you feel happy,Alex?

196
00:10:49,030 --> 00:10:51,060
I hear prison can change a man.

197
00:10:51,130 --> 00:10:53,500
Can we just get this over with.

198
00:11:00,530 --> 00:11:01,530
All clear.

199
00:11:01,600 --> 00:11:03,400
You have 15 seconds.

200
00:11:30,460 --> 00:11:32,000
That wasn't so bad now,was it?

201
00:11:36,100 --> 00:11:38,360
You should've trusted me,

202
00:11:38,430 --> 00:11:41,630
like I trusted you.

203
00:11:55,100 --> 00:11:56,600
All right.

204
00:11:56,660 --> 00:12:00,800
We're ready to begin to isolate the tumor now,Mr. Scofield.

205
00:12:00,860 --> 00:12:02,730
As we talked about,

206
00:12:02,800 --> 00:12:05,530
I'm going to ask you to slowly recite the alphabet.

207
00:12:05,600 --> 00:12:08,160
If you have any trouble finding a letter,

208
00:12:08,230 --> 00:12:10,700
any problem saying a letter,

209
00:12:10,760 --> 00:12:13,000
you let us know. All right?

210
00:12:13,060 --> 00:12:15,160
All right.

211
00:12:22,360 --> 00:12:24,060
Okay.

212
00:12:24,130 --> 00:12:26,330
Ready?

213
00:12:26,400 --> 00:12:27,830
And begin.

214
00:12:27,900 --> 00:12:30,330
A...

215
00:12:30,400 --> 00:12:31,700
B...

216
00:12:31,760 --> 00:12:34,730
C...

217
00:12:34,800 --> 00:12:36,630
D...

218
00:12:36,700 --> 00:12:38,360
E...

219
00:12:38,430 --> 00:12:39,360
F...

220
00:12:39,430 --> 00:12:41,530
G...

221
00:12:41,600 --> 00:12:43,400
H...

222
00:12:45,030 --> 00:12:46,500
I'm sorry,Charles.

223
00:12:46,560 --> 00:12:47,660
For what?

224
00:12:47,730 --> 00:12:49,530
For everything.

225
00:12:49,600 --> 00:12:51,630
For all the lies I told.

226
00:12:51,700 --> 00:12:54,260
For all the pain I caused.

227
00:12:54,330 --> 00:12:57,130
Are you asking for forgiveness?

228
00:12:57,200 --> 00:12:59,560
I'm not sure I'm entitled to it.

229
00:13:02,100 --> 00:13:05,900
I guess that's for a power

230
00:13:05,960 --> 00:13:08,230
higher than us to decide,isn't it?

231
00:13:13,400 --> 00:13:18,300
It's just hard... hard to believe we've lost,

232
00:13:18,360 --> 00:13:20,360
that it was all for nothing.

233
00:13:20,430 --> 00:13:22,960
It doesn't have to be.

234
00:13:39,730 --> 00:13:41,160
It looks like

235
00:13:41,230 --> 00:13:43,200
the tumor is nestled behind the hippocampus.

236
00:13:46,930 --> 00:13:48,860
You have the answers,Michael.

237
00:13:48,930 --> 00:13:51,030
What are the questions?

238
00:13:52,200 --> 00:13:54,930
I don't know,but you do.

239
00:13:55,000 --> 00:13:57,400
You just haven't realized it yet.

240
00:14:07,700 --> 00:14:08,800
Up here,make a right.

241
00:14:08,860 --> 00:14:10,430
No,no,left,left,left.

242
00:14:12,960 --> 00:14:14,630
We got ten minutes... what do you think?

243
00:14:14,700 --> 00:14:15,830
It's gonna be tight.

244
00:14:19,730 --> 00:14:21,430
All right,any minute now.

245
00:14:21,500 --> 00:14:23,130
There's no sign of him.

246
00:14:23,200 --> 00:14:25,330
Check Vikan's PDA.

247
00:14:25,400 --> 00:14:27,630
See if the buyer left him a message.

248
00:14:27,700 --> 00:14:28,960
Oh,this thing is broken.

249
00:14:29,030 --> 00:14:31,330
It must have cracked when he hit the ground.

250
00:14:31,400 --> 00:14:33,100
Can you still see the contact number?

251
00:14:33,160 --> 00:14:34,460
Yeah,it's a Miami area code.

252
00:14:34,530 --> 00:14:36,900
Okay,read it out...  I'll put it in mine.

253
00:14:36,960 --> 00:14:38,360
I won't reading out anything.

254
00:14:38,430 --> 00:14:39,460
I'm gonna keep that number

255
00:14:39,530 --> 00:14:40,900
for now,if you don't mind.

256
00:14:42,000 --> 00:14:43,000
Who is it?

257
00:14:43,060 --> 00:14:44,460
It's my sister.

258
00:14:44,530 --> 00:14:46,230
Don't answer it.

259
00:14:46,300 --> 00:14:47,860
I said don't answer it.

260
00:14:48,900 --> 00:14:50,200
Shoot me.

261
00:14:52,630 --> 00:14:53,930
Hello?

262
00:14:54,000 --> 00:14:54,930
We're free.

263
00:14:55,000 --> 00:14:55,930
He's gone.

264
00:14:56,000 --> 00:14:56,930
What?

265
00:14:57,000 --> 00:14:58,400
The... the guy

266
00:14:58,460 --> 00:15:00,330
with the,uh,fake hand... he let us go,

267
00:15:00,400 --> 00:15:03,330
so we,uh... we ran across the street to the Patels' house,

268
00:15:03,400 --> 00:15:04,960
and a couple minutes later,I looked out the window,

269
00:15:05,030 --> 00:15:05,960
and I saw these,uh...

270
00:15:06,030 --> 00:15:07,760
these two guys in,uh...

271
00:15:07,830 --> 00:15:09,460
in these suits,and they,uh,dragged him offinto some van.

272
00:15:09,530 --> 00:15:11,560
All right,Gretchen,put Bagwell on the phone.

273
00:15:11,630 --> 00:15:13,300
He's not there. Gretchen,I'm not playing anymore...

274
00:15:13,360 --> 00:15:16,000
Don,the Company took him.

275
00:15:20,000 --> 00:15:21,500
How's Emily?

276
00:15:23,240 --> 00:15:24,500
She's... She's fine.

277
00:15:25,540 --> 00:15:27,200
Listen,Gretchen.

278
00:15:27,270 --> 00:15:29,840
You need to stay away from us.

279
00:15:29,900 --> 00:15:31,170
For everyone's sake.

280
00:15:31,240 --> 00:15:32,670
Here,baby.

281
00:15:32,740 --> 00:15:34,800
Bye,Auntie.

282
00:15:38,870 --> 00:15:40,870
Forget that hick,Bagwell.

283
00:15:40,940 --> 00:15:42,970
No,I can't.

284
00:15:43,040 --> 00:15:45,600
He knows the location of the exchange.

285
00:15:45,670 --> 00:15:47,870
If he knows we're here...

286
00:15:47,940 --> 00:15:49,840
then the Company does,too.

287
00:15:59,600 --> 00:16:00,540
Hey,that's it.

288
00:16:00,600 --> 00:16:02,300
Right there... Arlington Pier.

289
00:16:02,370 --> 00:16:03,370
Pull over.

290
00:16:37,970 --> 00:16:39,040
Blood,papi.

291
00:16:39,100 --> 00:16:40,640
We just missed them.

292
00:16:42,100 --> 00:16:43,540
I'll go look around.

293
00:16:49,470 --> 00:16:50,770
Operations.

294
00:16:50,840 --> 00:16:52,570
The General said to call this number if I needed help.

295
00:16:52,640 --> 00:16:54,400
Your clearance code,please.

296
00:16:54,470 --> 00:16:56,100
Clearance code?

297
00:16:56,170 --> 00:16:58,440
How about I'm Lincoln Burrows and you're about to lose Scylla?

298
00:16:59,440 --> 00:17:01,170
Proceed.

299
00:17:01,240 --> 00:17:02,700
I need to trace this line.

300
00:17:02,770 --> 00:17:03,840
We've already tried.

301
00:17:03,900 --> 00:17:05,070
You're in a zone

302
00:17:05,140 --> 00:17:06,400
where visual surveillance is an impossibility.

303
00:17:06,470 --> 00:17:07,670
Well,how about you look

304
00:17:07,740 --> 00:17:09,640
outside the zone and check for a vehicle leaving

305
00:17:09,700 --> 00:17:10,940
in the last 15 minutes.

306
00:17:11,000 --> 00:17:13,140
If you see one,get a match and call me.

307
00:17:15,270 --> 00:17:16,340
Nothing.

308
00:17:16,400 --> 00:17:17,800
No tracks,but I found these.

309
00:17:17,870 --> 00:17:19,870
They know we're onto them.

310
00:17:19,940 --> 00:17:22,770
We got to find these people before they split.

311
00:17:36,440 --> 00:17:38,570
Someone's here,but it's not the seller.

312
00:17:38,640 --> 00:17:40,970
What do you want me to do?

313
00:17:50,240 --> 00:17:51,940
I'm just curious,Lang.

314
00:17:52,000 --> 00:17:54,000
When did you decide to turn your back on me?

315
00:17:54,000 --> 00:17:55,740
Probably about the same time

316
00:17:55,800 --> 00:17:57,040
you decided to become a fugitive.

317
00:17:57,100 --> 00:17:58,900
I wasn't talking to you.

318
00:17:58,970 --> 00:18:00,900
I took an oath to uphold the law,Alex.

319
00:18:00,970 --> 00:18:02,440
Did you do it for a promotion?

320
00:18:02,500 --> 00:18:04,440
Did they promise you anything to serve me up?

321
00:18:04,440 --> 00:18:07,500
The only thing I ever wanted was your safety,Alex.

322
00:18:09,270 --> 00:18:10,570
The longer you're on the run,

323
00:18:10,640 --> 00:18:12,970
the lower my chance of getting what I want.

324
00:18:20,100 --> 00:18:22,000
What you looking for out there,Alex?

325
00:18:23,770 --> 00:18:25,300
There.

326
00:18:35,070 --> 00:18:37,000
Agent Wheeler... I've got a suspect

327
00:18:37,070 --> 00:18:38,840
fleeing custody off Route 14

328
00:18:38,900 --> 00:18:40,240
about three miles north of Greenburg.

329
00:18:40,300 --> 00:18:41,670
Requesting backup and air support.

330
00:18:55,340 --> 00:18:57,100
I didn't mean to startle you.

331
00:18:57,170 --> 00:18:58,900
What are you doing here?

332
00:18:58,970 --> 00:19:00,600
Customer service.

333
00:19:00,670 --> 00:19:02,240
Quality control.

334
00:19:02,300 --> 00:19:06,000
I like to keep a hand in all our theaters of engagement.

335
00:19:06,070 --> 00:19:07,970
Spoken like a military man.

336
00:19:08,040 --> 00:19:12,000
So easy to discuss lives in the balance when it's just theater.

337
00:19:12,070 --> 00:19:14,140
I admire your devotion,Sara.

338
00:19:14,200 --> 00:19:17,670
It's an attribute I value above all others,

339
00:19:17,740 --> 00:19:19,570
but I wonder...

340
00:19:19,640 --> 00:19:21,170
is it the cause

341
00:19:21,240 --> 00:19:23,640
you believe in or the man?

342
00:19:23,660 --> 00:19:27,300
I mean,are you an ideologue

343
00:19:27,360 --> 00:19:32,530
or just a silly schoolgirl following the brooding boy

344
00:19:32,600 --> 00:19:33,730
who finally noticed her?

345
00:19:33,800 --> 00:19:35,260
I'm the girl whose father was murdered,

346
00:19:35,330 --> 00:19:37,360
who's looking for the bastard responsible.

347
00:19:37,430 --> 00:19:39,660
Would you like me to make a few phone calls,

348
00:19:39,730 --> 00:19:41,330
see if I can point you

349
00:19:41,400 --> 00:19:43,060
in the right direction?

350
00:19:43,130 --> 00:19:45,760
You can relax,he's receiving

351
00:19:45,830 --> 00:19:46,930
the best possible care.

352
00:19:47,000 --> 00:19:48,160
Is he?

353
00:19:48,230 --> 00:19:49,860
Because I've never seen this equipment before,

354
00:19:49,930 --> 00:19:51,630
and I've never seen this procedure.

355
00:19:51,700 --> 00:19:53,000
It's experimental,isn't it?

356
00:19:53,060 --> 00:19:55,430
Well,you could say that,but it has been used once before.

357
00:19:55,500 --> 00:19:57,060
How long did the patient live?

358
00:19:57,130 --> 00:19:59,400
Dr. Tancredi,

359
00:19:59,460 --> 00:20:03,230
I know your opinion of the work we do here,but know this.

360
00:20:03,300 --> 00:20:06,300
Not everything is as it seems.

361
00:20:07,330 --> 00:20:08,930
And for what it's worth,

362
00:20:09,000 --> 00:20:12,700
the patient lived a long,happy life.

363
00:20:29,330 --> 00:20:30,830
What are you doing?

364
00:20:30,900 --> 00:20:33,930
It is the job of a structural engineer

365
00:20:34,000 --> 00:20:36,100
to make sure everything he creates is designed

366
00:20:36,160 --> 00:20:39,060
to withstand the weight placed upon it.

367
00:20:39,130 --> 00:20:41,600
What I've built here...

368
00:20:41,660 --> 00:20:43,700
does not hold up.

369
00:20:44,730 --> 00:20:45,960
If you discovered

370
00:20:46,030 --> 00:20:48,860
that a structure you built was deficient,

371
00:20:48,930 --> 00:20:52,000
would you tear down the building

372
00:20:52,060 --> 00:20:53,960
or find a way to fix it?

373
00:20:54,030 --> 00:20:57,330
I've tried to fix it.

374
00:20:57,400 --> 00:21:00,930
I've tried to make things right.

375
00:21:01,000 --> 00:21:05,130
All I've done is add more weight to it.

376
00:21:05,200 --> 00:21:06,600
And now...

377
00:21:08,660 --> 00:21:11,060
...now I can't take anymore.

378
00:21:13,760 --> 00:21:17,060
All I wanted to do was save my brother's life.

379
00:21:17,130 --> 00:21:19,060
Did you do that?

380
00:21:19,130 --> 00:21:21,200
Yes...

381
00:21:21,260 --> 00:21:23,100
but how many other people

382
00:21:23,160 --> 00:21:25,500
lost their lives in the process?

383
00:21:25,560 --> 00:21:27,930
Knowing that now,

384
00:21:28,000 --> 00:21:29,700
would you have let him die?

385
00:21:29,760 --> 00:21:32,160
No.

386
00:21:32,230 --> 00:21:36,030
And that makes you feel like some kind of murderer?

387
00:21:39,230 --> 00:21:40,730
Perhaps.

388
00:21:42,100 --> 00:21:44,330
Take ten lives,you're a serial killer.

389
00:21:44,400 --> 00:21:46,400
Take thousands,you're a war hero.

390
00:21:46,460 --> 00:21:47,860
This isn't war.

391
00:21:47,930 --> 00:21:49,530
Are you sure?

392
00:21:49,600 --> 00:21:52,230
There's nothing more than the Company's little black book.

393
00:21:52,300 --> 00:21:56,030
Names,numbers,operation reports.

394
00:21:56,100 --> 00:21:59,730
Not everything is as it seems,Michael.

395
00:22:01,760 --> 00:22:03,360
But you know that...

396
00:22:03,430 --> 00:22:04,900
don't you?

397
00:22:17,930 --> 00:22:19,800
All right,look,we need to reestablish contact with the buyer,

398
00:22:19,860 --> 00:22:21,860
explain to him what happened,

399
00:22:21,930 --> 00:22:23,030
and then set a new location

400
00:22:23,100 --> 00:22:24,500
for the exchange.

401
00:22:24,560 --> 00:22:25,760
I got to say...

402
00:22:25,830 --> 00:22:27,060
I'm amazed at you,Don.

403
00:22:27,130 --> 00:22:29,330
Yeah,all this time,and you never once asked to see

404
00:22:29,400 --> 00:22:31,460
- the information in Scylla.  - That's because I don't care

405
00:22:31,530 --> 00:22:33,300
about the information; I just care what it's worth.

406
00:22:33,360 --> 00:22:34,630
Maybe you're just worried

407
00:22:34,700 --> 00:22:36,630
if you actually knew what was on it,

408
00:22:36,700 --> 00:22:39,560
you'd have second thoughts about who you're selling it to.

409
00:22:53,130 --> 00:22:54,530
Hello?

410
00:22:54,600 --> 00:22:56,800
Mr. Burrows,we have a hit on the targets.

411
00:22:56,860 --> 00:22:58,730
Traffic camera picked them up entering a convenience store

412
00:22:58,800 --> 00:23:00,030
on Valley and 14th.

413
00:23:02,030 --> 00:23:03,430
Looks like they left a footprint.

414
00:23:40,800 --> 00:23:42,330
Don't move.

415
00:23:45,860 --> 00:23:47,930
That's a hell of a job,Agent Lang.

416
00:23:48,000 --> 00:23:49,660
You're the one who taught me how to read the mind

417
00:23:49,730 --> 00:23:50,860
of a convict on the run,remember?

418
00:23:50,930 --> 00:23:52,830
If you take me in,I'm as good as dead.

419
00:23:52,900 --> 00:23:53,830
You know that.

420
00:23:53,900 --> 00:23:56,260
So...

421
00:23:56,330 --> 00:23:58,260
I'm gonna run now.

422
00:23:58,330 --> 00:24:00,030
And if you need to stop me,

423
00:24:00,100 --> 00:24:01,460
you're gonna have to shoot.

424
00:24:01,530 --> 00:24:03,260
Don't make me do this.

425
00:24:03,330 --> 00:24:05,100
I'm sorry.

426
00:24:08,130 --> 00:24:10,060
Another time,another place,eh,Felicia?

427
00:24:10,130 --> 00:24:12,830
I will pull this trigger.

428
00:24:27,560 --> 00:24:29,800
What happened?

429
00:24:29,860 --> 00:24:31,800
He got away.

430
00:24:31,860 --> 00:24:33,060
Did you have him?

431
00:24:33,130 --> 00:24:35,060
Uh,yeah,I...

432
00:24:35,130 --> 00:24:37,800
I thought I had him unless I...

433
00:24:37,860 --> 00:24:39,300
I just missed.

434
00:24:39,360 --> 00:24:40,600
Did you see which way he went?

435
00:24:40,660 --> 00:24:41,960
Or did you just miss that,too?

436
00:24:43,060 --> 00:24:44,800
He went east.

437
00:24:58,760 --> 00:25:00,230
Hey,buddy. What's up?

438
00:25:00,300 --> 00:25:03,260
I'm looking for a,a tall chick with black hair

439
00:25:03,330 --> 00:25:05,430
and a guy... tall guy,uh...

440
00:25:05,500 --> 00:25:07,130
He looks like Bozo the clown.

441
00:25:07,200 --> 00:25:08,400
You know,Bozo and Elvira?

442
00:25:08,460 --> 00:25:10,560
You guys

443
00:25:10,630 --> 00:25:12,000
cops or something?

444
00:25:12,060 --> 00:25:14,100
Not even close.

445
00:25:16,400 --> 00:25:17,960
So how about it?

446
00:25:18,030 --> 00:25:19,560
Nah.

447
00:25:19,630 --> 00:25:21,300
I don't remember anyone like that.

448
00:25:23,000 --> 00:25:24,830
How about now,you punk?

449
00:25:24,900 --> 00:25:26,160
How 'bout now?! Okay! Okay!

450
00:25:26,230 --> 00:25:27,500
They bought a phone,man.

451
00:25:27,560 --> 00:25:28,730
I want the receipt.

452
00:25:28,800 --> 00:25:30,760
All right.

453
00:25:37,460 --> 00:25:39,400
On their way.

454
00:25:39,460 --> 00:25:41,130
You have any idea who the buyer is?

455
00:25:41,200 --> 00:25:42,700
No. And we never will.

456
00:25:42,760 --> 00:25:44,860
Whoever's walking away with the information that's on Scylla

457
00:25:44,930 --> 00:25:46,200
will do whatever it takes

458
00:25:46,260 --> 00:25:48,200
to stay below The Company radar.

459
00:25:48,260 --> 00:25:50,200
Besides,would you screw some guy's wife

460
00:25:50,260 --> 00:25:51,830
and then leave your card on his pillow?

461
00:25:51,900 --> 00:25:53,000
Isn't that what you just did

462
00:25:53,060 --> 00:25:54,830
to the General?

463
00:25:54,900 --> 00:25:56,000
Come on.

464
00:25:56,060 --> 00:25:57,230
After all we've been through,

465
00:25:57,300 --> 00:25:58,530
we can't be honest with each other?

466
00:25:58,600 --> 00:26:00,000
Your little photo shoot.

467
00:26:00,060 --> 00:26:02,030
And your weak ass attempt at the sixth card.

468
00:26:02,100 --> 00:26:04,160
You wanted him to know you were involved,right?

469
00:26:04,230 --> 00:26:06,200
Come on. He punished you,

470
00:26:06,260 --> 00:26:08,660
treated you like crap... just like your real daddy.

471
00:26:08,730 --> 00:26:11,500
You want at least one of them to pay for it,right?

472
00:26:11,560 --> 00:26:12,530
Come on,Gretchen.

473
00:26:12,600 --> 00:26:13,660
I-I know you.

474
00:26:13,730 --> 00:26:16,060
I did my homework.

475
00:26:16,130 --> 00:26:18,330
Gee,Don,you...

476
00:26:18,400 --> 00:26:21,360
you just cracked my whole Electra complex wide open.

477
00:26:21,430 --> 00:26:23,400
Kudos.

478
00:26:23,460 --> 00:26:25,400
But you're not the only one who did their homework.

479
00:26:25,460 --> 00:26:26,730
Just so you know.

480
00:26:26,800 --> 00:26:28,560
Yeah? You got something to say? Right now,

481
00:26:28,630 --> 00:26:30,360
we need to be ready for whatever's coming.

482
00:26:31,430 --> 00:26:33,100
You better watch your six,Don.

483
00:26:33,160 --> 00:26:35,130
Okay.

484
00:26:37,100 --> 00:26:38,700
You wanted to see me? Yeah.

485
00:26:38,760 --> 00:26:40,300
I-I can't quite tell from the monitors,

486
00:26:40,360 --> 00:26:42,860
but from what I can see,the-the grow,

487
00:26:42,930 --> 00:26:44,600
it looks like it isn't just on the hypothalamus.

488
00:26:45,900 --> 00:26:48,830
I understand that was the initial diagnosis,

489
00:26:48,900 --> 00:26:51,700
but once we got in there,it appears to have spread

490
00:26:51,760 --> 00:26:53,700
to the hippocampus as well.

491
00:26:53,760 --> 00:26:55,030
Okay. Um,

492
00:26:55,100 --> 00:26:57,900
so with the removal,will there be any memory loss?

493
00:26:57,960 --> 00:26:59,700
Well,in cases like this,

494
00:26:59,760 --> 00:27:01,930
where small portions have to be removed,

495
00:27:02,000 --> 00:27:04,960
it hardly ever affects what's referred to as "net memory."

496
00:27:05,030 --> 00:27:07,630
We're all tapped into such small portions

497
00:27:07,700 --> 00:27:10,260
of what we've experienced in our lifetime.

498
00:27:10,330 --> 00:27:12,760
The bulk of it's just kept in storage,

499
00:27:12,830 --> 00:27:14,900
rarely acknowledged by the conscious mind.

500
00:27:14,960 --> 00:27:16,460
So while there may be some

501
00:27:16,530 --> 00:27:17,930
gross memory loss,

502
00:27:18,000 --> 00:27:19,460
he won't ever know it's gone.

503
00:27:19,530 --> 00:27:21,660
Because he'll never know it was there.

504
00:27:50,060 --> 00:27:50,930
Nurse?

505
00:27:51,000 --> 00:27:52,630
BP's dropping,90/60.

506
00:27:52,700 --> 00:27:53,530
What's going on?

507
00:27:53,600 --> 00:27:54,800
I don't know.

508
00:27:54,860 --> 00:27:57,060
Increase dopamine delivery rate to 12.5.

509
00:28:01,060 --> 00:28:03,260
We'll use the Bargain when the time is right.

510
00:28:03,330 --> 00:28:04,300
The time is now.

511
00:28:04,360 --> 00:28:07,300
Bargain. Bargain.

512
00:28:07,360 --> 00:28:09,100
We'll use time... time is right.

513
00:28:09,160 --> 00:28:10,700
We'll use the Bargain when the time is right.

514
00:28:13,830 --> 00:28:17,000
perhaps the time is now.

515
00:28:18,060 --> 00:28:19,530
EEG's spiking.

516
00:28:19,600 --> 00:28:20,660
Brain activity's all over the place.

517
00:28:20,730 --> 00:28:22,200
MAP's at 55.

518
00:28:22,260 --> 00:28:23,630
BP's erratic. Dropping.

519
00:28:23,700 --> 00:28:25,060
85,84.

520
00:28:25,130 --> 00:28:26,700
Give him one mil of Atropine. Michael?

521
00:28:26,760 --> 00:28:28,060
Are you still with us?

522
00:28:28,130 --> 00:28:31,460
The best minds in the world designed this system,

523
00:28:31,530 --> 00:28:32,700
and you almost beat it.

524
00:28:36,060 --> 00:28:37,500
But as long as we have...

525
00:28:39,300 --> 00:28:40,830
...we have... as long as we...

526
00:28:44,400 --> 00:28:45,730
So what are you hearing,uh,

527
00:28:45,800 --> 00:28:46,560
Scylla's worth?

528
00:28:46,630 --> 00:28:48,900
Me,I'm hearing millions.

529
00:28:48,960 --> 00:28:49,960
We have Scylla.

530
00:28:50,030 --> 00:28:51,800
Things have happened

531
00:28:51,860 --> 00:28:53,200
in the past few days that

532
00:28:53,260 --> 00:28:54,730
have made me uneasy.

533
00:28:54,800 --> 00:28:57,260
But as long as we have Scylla,we have power.

534
00:29:03,900 --> 00:29:05,760
I'm sorry,Michael.

535
00:29:05,830 --> 00:29:07,930
We're losing him. 78. Get the crash cart.

536
00:29:08,000 --> 00:29:09,730
Laryngeal scope... we need to intubate. No.

537
00:29:09,800 --> 00:29:11,100
What's going on?

538
00:29:11,160 --> 00:29:12,560
It's time to go.

539
00:29:18,660 --> 00:29:20,200
Michael?

540
00:29:20,260 --> 00:29:21,030
Michael?!

541
00:29:29,830 --> 00:29:30,900
Michael! What's going on? Why's he crashing?

542
00:29:30,960 --> 00:29:31,660
Ms. Tancredi,you cannot...

543
00:29:31,730 --> 00:29:32,360
No,it's okay.

544
00:29:32,430 --> 00:29:33,860
Michael,don't do this.

545
00:29:33,930 --> 00:29:35,530
Don't do this.

546
00:29:35,600 --> 00:29:36,560
Don't do this.

547
00:29:36,630 --> 00:29:37,600
Don't go.

548
00:29:37,660 --> 00:29:39,060
We're not finished with this.

549
00:29:39,130 --> 00:29:40,400
Not finished yet.

550
00:29:40,460 --> 00:29:41,660
Michael,I'm sorry.

551
00:29:41,730 --> 00:29:42,700
It's time.

552
00:29:42,760 --> 00:29:44,600
Please,Charles.

553
00:29:44,660 --> 00:29:45,900
Michael,not like this.

554
00:29:45,960 --> 00:29:47,030
Not like this.

555
00:29:47,100 --> 00:29:48,300
It doesn't happen like this.

556
00:29:48,360 --> 00:29:49,900
You promised me we would finish together.

557
00:29:49,960 --> 00:29:51,560
It's okay.

558
00:29:51,630 --> 00:29:52,730
You've done your part.

559
00:29:52,800 --> 00:29:54,230
I haven't figured it out yet!

560
00:29:54,300 --> 00:29:55,900
Yes,you have.

561
00:29:55,960 --> 00:29:57,260
Would you do something?

562
00:29:57,330 --> 00:29:58,430
I'm trying!

563
00:30:07,330 --> 00:30:08,800
Relax.

564
00:30:08,860 --> 00:30:11,430
You might think it's bad,

565
00:30:11,500 --> 00:30:13,260
but it's not.

566
00:30:15,300 --> 00:30:16,260
Dying?

567
00:30:16,330 --> 00:30:17,200
No!

568
00:30:20,630 --> 00:30:22,060
Don't give up.

569
00:30:22,130 --> 00:30:23,230
Don't give up.

570
00:30:23,300 --> 00:30:24,360
Don't give up.

571
00:30:41,330 --> 00:30:42,900
Not everything is as it seems.

572
00:30:45,660 --> 00:30:46,830
Good-bye,Michael.

573
00:30:49,060 --> 00:30:50,030
Charles.

574
00:31:11,500 --> 00:31:12,300
Michael?

575
00:31:13,360 --> 00:31:14,660
Michael,don't leave me.

576
00:31:15,660 --> 00:31:17,160
Don't you dare leave me.

577
00:31:24,030 --> 00:31:26,030
Sara.

578
00:31:38,200 --> 00:31:40,060
Company tracked the serial code off the receipt.

579
00:31:40,130 --> 00:31:42,060
Gretchen just placed a call five minutes ago

580
00:31:42,130 --> 00:31:43,730
matching the tracking number. From where?

581
00:31:43,800 --> 00:31:44,800
Two miles away.

582
00:31:50,800 --> 00:31:53,430
I was told there'd be three of you.

583
00:31:53,500 --> 00:31:54,730
Well there aren't.

584
00:31:54,800 --> 00:31:56,730
You have the money? Because that's a small case

585
00:31:56,800 --> 00:31:58,730
for $125 million... We don't deal in cash.

586
00:31:58,800 --> 00:32:01,760
Once I verify the validity of the item,

587
00:32:01,830 --> 00:32:05,300
the funds will be wired to an account number you provide.

588
00:32:12,160 --> 00:32:13,600
The item,please.

589
00:32:13,660 --> 00:32:15,730
No,no,no,you're not gonna see the item

590
00:32:15,800 --> 00:32:17,660
until I see the money,okay? You'll have to

591
00:32:17,730 --> 00:32:20,400
forgive me if I don't trust a shiny case with some buttons.

592
00:32:20,460 --> 00:32:23,730
I need to confirm that the data is intact.

593
00:32:23,800 --> 00:32:25,730
Without it,the item you possess

594
00:32:25,800 --> 00:32:29,060
is nothing more than a fancy box.

595
00:32:29,130 --> 00:32:30,130
Speaking of...

596
00:32:30,200 --> 00:32:32,700
Give this man the item.

597
00:32:32,760 --> 00:32:34,200
No,I'm not giving anyone...

598
00:32:34,260 --> 00:32:35,860
This is a businessman

599
00:32:35,930 --> 00:32:37,530
making a business transaction.

600
00:32:37,600 --> 00:32:40,100
One with the longer you take,

601
00:32:40,160 --> 00:32:42,630
the more danger you put us all in.

602
00:32:59,330 --> 00:33:00,830
Can you read what's on there?

603
00:33:02,900 --> 00:33:04,930
You better hope so.

604
00:33:22,630 --> 00:33:24,830
They're not just gonna give us Scylla.

605
00:33:24,900 --> 00:33:25,960
You know what that means,right?

606
00:33:28,430 --> 00:33:30,300
Okay.

607
00:33:42,660 --> 00:33:44,230
Let's split up.

608
00:34:06,360 --> 00:34:07,460
I'm sure you understand

609
00:34:07,530 --> 00:34:09,600
no one can know where Scylla's going to.

610
00:34:30,860 --> 00:34:32,800
It's your lucky day,sugar.

611
00:34:32,860 --> 00:34:34,900
Not yours.

612
00:34:37,560 --> 00:34:39,700
Drop it.

613
00:34:39,760 --> 00:34:41,260
Cover her.

614
00:34:48,430 --> 00:34:49,860
Where is he? I don't know.

615
00:34:49,930 --> 00:34:51,330
Where is he?

616
00:34:51,400 --> 00:34:52,900
I don't know!  Gone.

617
00:34:52,960 --> 00:34:54,100
Stolen.

618
00:34:55,130 --> 00:34:57,060
By who?

619
00:34:58,430 --> 00:34:59,860
By who?

620
00:34:59,930 --> 00:35:02,930
If I die... you'll never know.

621
00:35:38,830 --> 00:35:40,830
Oh.

622
00:35:42,500 --> 00:35:44,100
You look beautiful.

623
00:35:45,330 --> 00:35:48,760
You're a liar.

624
00:35:48,830 --> 00:35:50,730
How'd it go?

625
00:35:50,800 --> 00:35:53,830
They're still running some tests,

626
00:35:53,900 --> 00:35:56,430
but they feel pretty confident they got it all.

627
00:35:56,500 --> 00:35:58,900
And what is this place?

628
00:35:58,960 --> 00:36:01,700
You need to know something about your surgery.

629
00:36:03,400 --> 00:36:05,800
It was performed by Company doctors,

630
00:36:05,860 --> 00:36:08,230
and the General made all the arrangements.

631
00:36:08,300 --> 00:36:09,500
Why?

632
00:36:09,560 --> 00:36:10,960
I don't know.

633
00:36:11,030 --> 00:36:12,760
Lincoln's handling it.

634
00:36:12,830 --> 00:36:14,060
He says he has a plan.

635
00:36:14,130 --> 00:36:16,330
I'll be honest. Right now,you're alive,

636
00:36:16,400 --> 00:36:18,730
and that's all I care about.

637
00:36:22,060 --> 00:36:24,600
You're gonna laugh,but I had a dream about Scylla.

638
00:36:26,130 --> 00:36:29,430
The only thing we really know about it is what Self told us.

639
00:36:29,500 --> 00:36:30,700
You need to rest.

640
00:36:30,760 --> 00:36:32,460
I'm serious.

641
00:36:32,530 --> 00:36:34,700
What if it's not just the Company's little black book?

642
00:36:34,760 --> 00:36:35,860
What if it's...

643
00:36:35,930 --> 00:36:38,060
Not everything is as it seems.

644
00:36:38,130 --> 00:36:40,700
...something more?

645
00:36:40,760 --> 00:36:42,600
Like what?

646
00:36:42,660 --> 00:36:45,730
Something good.

647
00:36:45,800 --> 00:36:48,230
Why go to so much trouble

648
00:36:48,300 --> 00:36:50,230
to protect information about the past,

649
00:36:50,300 --> 00:36:52,600
information the Company could just delete

650
00:36:52,660 --> 00:36:55,600
any time they wanted to?

651
00:36:55,660 --> 00:36:57,400
The General said...

652
00:36:57,460 --> 00:37:00,630
As long as we have Scylla,we have power.

653
00:37:00,700 --> 00:37:03,960
I don't think he was talking about power

654
00:37:04,030 --> 00:37:05,530
like control or influence.

655
00:37:05,600 --> 00:37:07,600
I think he was talking about energy.

656
00:37:07,660 --> 00:37:09,630
Boron.

657
00:37:10,330 --> 00:37:12,930
Argon.

658
00:37:13,000 --> 00:37:15,460
Gallium.

659
00:37:15,530 --> 00:37:17,200
Indium.

660
00:37:17,260 --> 00:37:19,660
Bargain.

661
00:37:21,160 --> 00:37:23,730
There's a theory that if you can find a way

662
00:37:23,800 --> 00:37:27,460
to combine these elements into the design of a solar cell,

663
00:37:27,530 --> 00:37:32,500
you can harness 100% of the sun's energy.

664
00:37:32,560 --> 00:37:35,760
With that kind of power,

665
00:37:35,830 --> 00:37:38,130
possibilities are limitless.

666
00:37:38,200 --> 00:37:41,500
It would certainly explain all the security around Scylla.

667
00:37:43,160 --> 00:37:45,100
They're not protecting the past.

668
00:37:45,160 --> 00:37:46,530
They're protecting the future.

669
00:37:46,600 --> 00:37:48,330
Wow.

670
00:37:48,400 --> 00:37:50,230
Wonder what else is on it.

671
00:37:50,300 --> 00:37:52,460
I mean,the equipment you were treated with,

672
00:37:52,530 --> 00:37:54,030
and the drugs they gave you...

673
00:37:54,100 --> 00:37:56,500
none of it exists on the open market.

674
00:37:56,560 --> 00:37:58,600
Which would explain why some people are willing

675
00:37:58,660 --> 00:38:01,830
to pay hundreds of millions to get their hands on Scylla.

676
00:38:01,900 --> 00:38:03,660
It's not about taking down the Company.

677
00:38:03,730 --> 00:38:04,860
It's about

678
00:38:04,930 --> 00:38:07,200
becoming the Company.

679
00:38:07,260 --> 00:38:09,530
It's about knowing what they know,

680
00:38:09,600 --> 00:38:11,700
controlling what they know.

681
00:38:13,130 --> 00:38:14,530
What do we do now?

682
00:38:20,330 --> 00:38:22,260
So,what's the next move?

683
00:38:22,330 --> 00:38:23,660
I'm gonna check on Michael.

684
00:38:23,760 --> 00:38:25,360
No,I mean,after that.

685
00:38:25,430 --> 00:38:26,930
I mean,Scylla's out there somewhere.

686
00:38:27,000 --> 00:38:28,760
Are we really gonna keep chasing it?

687
00:38:28,830 --> 00:38:30,930
I don't know. We'll figure it out later.

688
00:38:31,960 --> 00:38:34,000
No.

689
00:38:34,060 --> 00:38:35,700
I won't be here,Linc.

690
00:38:37,600 --> 00:38:39,230
I can't do it anymore.

691
00:38:39,300 --> 00:38:41,200
Sara said Mike was okay,

692
00:38:41,260 --> 00:38:43,400
and that's all I needed to know.

693
00:38:43,460 --> 00:38:46,030
But now I got to go live my life.

694
00:38:46,100 --> 00:38:48,900
And that's a life where I can go a day without seeing

695
00:38:48,960 --> 00:38:52,330
a dead body,or-or almost becoming one.

696
00:38:53,900 --> 00:38:55,500
I'm not running away,papi.

697
00:38:55,560 --> 00:38:58,030
I'm-I'm just... I'm just moving on.

698
00:39:00,400 --> 00:39:02,330
This was never about you.

699
00:39:02,400 --> 00:39:04,700
Everything you did,you did for us.

700
00:39:04,760 --> 00:39:07,860
I'll never forget that.

701
00:39:09,300 --> 00:39:11,200
I know you got

702
00:39:11,260 --> 00:39:12,500
something cooking,so...

703
00:39:12,560 --> 00:39:15,100
whatever it is,just be careful,okay?

704
00:39:15,160 --> 00:39:18,930
Yeah.

705
00:39:21,900 --> 00:39:24,460
Thank you.

706
00:39:26,760 --> 00:39:28,760
Hey.

707
00:39:30,460 --> 00:39:32,230
And when you and Mike get down below

708
00:39:32,300 --> 00:39:33,400
and open that surf shop...

709
00:39:33,460 --> 00:39:34,730
Scuba shop.

710
00:39:34,800 --> 00:39:36,230
Scuba shop.

711
00:39:36,300 --> 00:39:38,730
Maybe there will be a job there for me.

712
00:39:38,800 --> 00:39:40,930
You can count on it.

713
00:39:53,360 --> 00:39:56,060
Do you know who took it?

714
00:39:56,130 --> 00:39:58,800
No,but Self and Gretchen do.

715
00:39:58,860 --> 00:40:00,060
Good.

716
00:40:00,130 --> 00:40:01,360
Then you've got your team.

717
00:40:01,430 --> 00:40:03,400
I'm not working for them.

718
00:40:03,460 --> 00:40:05,360
You'll work with a basset hound in a birthday hat

719
00:40:05,430 --> 00:40:06,930
if that's what I tell you to do.

720
00:40:07,000 --> 00:40:08,930
That's what being an employee means.

721
00:40:11,400 --> 00:40:13,760
You're determined and dedicated.

722
00:40:13,830 --> 00:40:15,630
But there are holes in your resume

723
00:40:15,700 --> 00:40:18,530
thatGretchen or Self or even Bagwell can fill.

724
00:40:18,600 --> 00:40:20,100
Now,you all took something from me,

725
00:40:20,160 --> 00:40:21,930
and you're all going to get it back.

726
00:40:23,360 --> 00:40:25,930
Besides...

727
00:40:26,000 --> 00:40:28,930
you can't handle this by yourself.

728
00:40:29,000 --> 00:40:32,330
And deep down,I think you know that.

729
00:40:33,360 --> 00:40:35,830
Have them meet me outside.

730
00:40:37,930 --> 00:40:40,300
Who knows?

731
00:40:40,360 --> 00:40:42,700
You may find that you like it here.

732
00:40:42,760 --> 00:40:44,300
Stranger things have happened.

733
00:40:44,360 --> 00:40:46,800
They've certainly happened in your family.

734
00:40:46,860 --> 00:40:48,500
Now,

735
00:40:48,560 --> 00:40:51,130
about Michael.

736
00:40:52,600 --> 00:40:54,730
Are you going to tell him,

737
00:40:54,800 --> 00:40:56,800
or should I?

738
00:41:06,530 --> 00:41:08,030
Do you have it?

739
00:41:08,100 --> 00:41:09,530
In my hand.

740
00:41:09,600 --> 00:41:11,730
Good. You know what to do.

741
00:41:11,800 --> 00:41:13,360
(phone clicks off on other end)

742
00:41:28,360 --> 00:41:30,400
Last time I saw you in a hospital,

743
00:41:30,460 --> 00:41:31,860
you busted your arm in Little League.

744
00:41:31,930 --> 00:41:34,760
Yeah,some bruiser knocked me down

745
00:41:34,830 --> 00:41:35,930
sliding into second.

746
00:41:36,000 --> 00:41:37,100
Sorry about that.

747
00:41:37,160 --> 00:41:38,300
But you healed good,though,right?

748
00:41:38,360 --> 00:41:40,000
Yeah.

749
00:41:40,060 --> 00:41:42,800
This will,too.

750
00:41:42,860 --> 00:41:44,830
Look,whatever plan you're working on

751
00:41:44,900 --> 00:41:48,360
to get us out of here,we better make a move on it.

752
00:41:48,430 --> 00:41:50,530
You're not getting out of here,Michael.

753
00:41:53,860 --> 00:41:55,030
What do you mean?

754
00:41:55,100 --> 00:41:56,330
I made a deal.

755
00:41:56,400 --> 00:41:58,260
Your life in exchange for Scylla.

756
00:42:00,560 --> 00:42:02,500
Why would you do that?

757
00:42:02,560 --> 00:42:04,600
Same reason you covered your body in tattoos

758
00:42:04,660 --> 00:42:06,160
and-and broke into Fox River.

759
00:42:06,230 --> 00:42:08,000
This is not just about us...

760
00:42:08,060 --> 00:42:10,360
That's exactly who it's about. It's all it's ever been about.

761
00:42:13,460 --> 00:42:15,500
We do this one thing for the Company,

762
00:42:15,560 --> 00:42:17,430
then they set us up for life.

763
00:42:17,500 --> 00:42:18,930
And you actually trust them?

764
00:42:19,000 --> 00:42:20,930
Who else am I gonna trust?

765
00:42:21,000 --> 00:42:22,930
The government? Guys like Don Self?

766
00:42:23,000 --> 00:42:25,300
I'm done watching loved ones and friends die,Michael.

767
00:42:25,360 --> 00:42:28,860
Scylla isn't what we thought it was.

768
00:42:28,930 --> 00:42:31,560
Not even close. I don't care.

769
00:42:31,630 --> 00:42:33,700
I don't understand how you can say that.

770
00:42:33,760 --> 00:42:36,000
'Cause the only thing worth fighting for is family.

771
00:42:36,060 --> 00:42:39,060
I'm gonna do everything and anything I can to end this,

772
00:42:39,130 --> 00:42:40,700
so you,me,all of us

773
00:42:40,760 --> 00:42:42,230
can get on with our lives.

774
00:42:42,300 --> 00:42:43,700
You think you can do that

775
00:42:43,760 --> 00:42:45,400
knowing what you know about the Company?

776
00:42:45,460 --> 00:42:47,400
You want to know what I know about the Company?

777
00:42:47,460 --> 00:42:50,900
Mom worked for them before she died.

778
00:42:52,800 --> 00:42:56,530
I'm just moving on in the family business.

779
00:42:56,600 --> 00:42:57,730
Linc,don't do this.

780
00:42:57,800 --> 00:42:58,730
It's done.

781
00:42:58,800 --> 00:43:01,700
Linc? Linc! Linc!

782
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:00,000


783
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:00,000


਍਍㤹㤹਍〰〺㨰ⰰ〵‰ⴭ‾〰〺㨰ⰲ〰਍昼湯⁴潣潬㵲⌢晦晦〰•楳敺ㄽ㸴睷⹷癴畳瑢瑩敬⹳敮㱴是湯㹴਍