Previously on Prison Break...
Your mother works for us.
Your mother is alive.
You know, I'm thinking
more and more that
this is an inside job.
- Why?
The hardware
he brought to the meet.
He could read Scylla
right on the spot.
Hands on your head.
We've got to get
out of here!
Get in!
Sorry, but right now
I want my life back
more than I want your money.
Where's Scylla?
Let's talk about
that, okay?
Where is he?
I can get him.
No, he can't.
He's stalling, Linc.
He's gone.
- You're right.
You have no idea who this guy's working for?
- No.
No clue.
Your boy's dead.
And now
I'm coming after you.
Who was that?
It was my son.
Lincoln.
What is this?
I don't know...
Just found them
on the doorstep.
Son of a...
They lay one hand on my mama,
I swear on my life...
She's in a state home.
I thought we were working
with these people.
So did I.
I'm gonna make a call.
Find out what's going on.
Mr. Burrows.
We had a deal.
Our deal is contingent
upon the retrieval of Scylla.
Based on the mediocrity
of your performance
on that front thus far,
I thought it best to make sure
you're all properly motivated.
Just tell me
how your team is progressing.
I swear to God, man, when I,
when I get a hold of you...
If I were you,
I'd be doing
everything in my power
to demonstrate
my competence right now.
We killed the guy
who came to Miami.
We found some keys on him.
We're looking into them.
Are we done?
Not quite.
A new competitor
has joined the search.
We're the ones getting Scylla.
Well, that's good to hear,
because the competing party,
is your brother Michael.
Michael's with you.
Michael's getting treatment.
With you.
Apparently Michael's
a little more headstrong
than either of us imagined.
But don't worry.
We have a lead on him
somewhere in central Arizona.
Mr. Oren is waiting
in his limousine.
If you speak to Michael,
tell him to find
a very good hiding place.
Because if any
of my men spot him,
they've been given
a green light.
2,500 miles to go.
If we take turns sleeping
we can be there
by tomorrow night.
Should we call Lincoln?
Let him know we're coming?
Michael, he took
the Company's deal
to save your life.
And for what it's worth,
I might've done the same thing.
Then you'd be wrong, too.
You know, this promises to be
a really, really long ride.
So, how about we just...
Call truce, all right?
Forgot napkins.
Come on.
He comes anywhere
near my kid...
You know, Don,
you seem to be taking
this whole thing pretty well.
Yeah, well,
I'm a pretty calm guy.
All I'm saying is,
my mama, his son, his wife.
We don't even know
who they got on you.
That's 'cause it's
none of your business.
All right, all you
need to worry about
is that I'm here
to do a job.
Hold-Secure.
The company that
manufactures the keys.
It's called Hold-Secure.
Listen to this.
Each key they produce is
implanted with a computer chip.
That chip sends out
a unique
electronic signal
that opens its lock.
Something that high-tech,
I'm telling you,
I'm betting they got a database
that'll tell us exactly
where each key's
corresponding lock
has been installed.
Look at that.
These keys run about 500 bucks?!
You only spend that
kind of money if you're
protecting something
of vital importance.
Like Scylla.
Someone just tried to access
Carruth's account
at Hold-Secure.
And what information
was compromised?
We don't know yet.
And who was trying to access it?
We don't know.
Thank you for bringing that
to my attention. Good work.
Yes?
It's your son.
We already have safeguards
in place to deal with Lincoln.
I'm talking about Michael.
He's escaped Company custody.
He's coming
to Miami right now.
Christina?
If only they understood
what it is I'm trying to do.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Okay, what now?
We'll think of something.
Michael, we can't
afford to buy a car
and we can't fly.
It's time to call
your brother.
Got it.
We've got the locations
of those two locks.
One's in Little Havana.
The other one's
down by the water.
Perfect. Lincoln,
why don't you and I...
You take Self and
go to Little Havana.
We're gonna head south.
Huh, that's a surprise.
We need suntan lotion.
Be right there.
It's me.
What's your problem?
Look, I need you to hear me out
on this, Linc.
Everything was all set up
and you blew it.
You couldn't just
let me handle this, could you?
If by "handle," you mean
give Scylla back to the General,
then no, I couldn't.
It's more complicated than that.
Actually, it's not.
Listen to me,
I want my life back
and this is the only way
we can do that!
I don't believe that's true.
You know what, man?
You need to grow up.
Look, if that's how
you really feel, Linc,
I should warn you I'm going
to do everything in my power
to stop you.
Listen to me:
I had a deal with the General.
You blew it.
He finds you,
he's gonna kill you.
Surprise, surprise.
I did this for us, Michael.
You, me, Sara,
LJ, so you could be with Sara.
Two seconds,
just think of your family.
Feels like family's
the only thing
I can think about these days.
What does that mean?
Michael?
Linc, Mom is alive.
What?
Guess I'll see you in Miami.
We gotta get out of here.
Sir, you mind if I ask
where you're going?
Dallas.
Mind if we hitch a ride?
I got 100 bucks; gas money.
Please?
Sir?
Cab's not big enough
for the two of you.
If you want to
ride together
you're going to have
to ride back here.
Done.
Get comfortable.
Gonna be eight hours
till we stop again.
Linc...
If Scylla really is in there,
there's gonna be security.
I need you focused.
Yeah.
Clear upstairs.
You find something?
Picture of my mom.
Someone must have known
I was coming.
Someone who's connected enough
to be working with Carruth
and who knows you well enough
to get their hands
on that picture.
There's only one person
I can think of
that fits that description.
You're saying
my mom's in Miami?
If she was operating
out of this house,
she certainly had
access to money.
She's a Company agent.
Gretchen said she thought
that this could be
an inside job.
Linc...
Your mother could have Scylla.
She used to bake cookies
when we'd come home
from school,
play kickball with us
in the backyard.
There's just no way
that woman was a Company agent.
You did read her file,
didn't you?
I saw medical reports
that said she had the
same diagnosis I did
and that Company
doctors operated
on her, too.
Now I'm wondering
if they took her off
to a log cabin in the woods
after they were done,
introduced her
to a friendly shrink.
How else could someone
just stand by and watch
while their own children
were hunted down like dogs?
Maybe she didn't know.
She knew.
Maybe it was over her head.
Or maybe she didn't care.
Anyway, I'm just surprised
the General waited so long
to drop this bomb on us.
Actually, I think
that part makes sense.
I mean,
for whatever reason,
your mother didn't want you
to know she was alive
or you would have known
years ago.
The General was just keeping
that secret, right?
Keeping her happy,
keeping her working.
But now the game has changed.
Yeah, now he thinks
you might be useful.
Just like Mom.
Beyond question, he possesses
the most gifted mind
of any man
I've ever encountered.
Well, I'll try not to
take that too personally.
He drilled
into your office safe
and copied your card
without you even noticing.
As I recall, you were sitting
right next to me.
If we could have turned
Michael Scofield,
it would have been like having
30 more years of Christina.
Pull over.
That's my ride.
What's going on?
Good-bye, Jonathan.
This ain't the place.
I could pick
that lock with my stump.
- No, n-no, n-no.
Remember what they say
about books and their covers.
When Harry Winston
donated the Hope Diamond
to the Smithsonian, you know
how he got it from New York
to DC?
Registered mail.
It's the safest way to go.
After all,
who is going to be looking
for the Hope Diamond
at the post office, right?
And who would be looking
for Scylla
at some run-down
storefront church
in Little Havana?
All right, let's
say you're right:
they got Scylla
back there somewhere.
You walk in there,
reeking that cop stink,
you won't last
a second.
That's a good point.
That's why you're going in.
May I help you?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
I'm Charles Patoshik.
I'm a professor
of anthropology
at Southern Florida
University.
I'm doing some various research
on various different kinds
of, uh, uh, uh,
Caribbean religions, and, uh...
perhaps you could start
back there where you, you
do your, uh, services.
That is our sanctuary.
Only the pure of soul
may venture
inside.
I know.
I-I have been
in many such rooms.
Let me see your hand.
Your soul is black,
stained with the blood
of the innocent.
I cannot let you pass.
I have never been
so offended in my life.
I suggest that you continue
your research
elsewhere.
If you drop
something
by accident,
you leave a fingerprint
on it.
She wanted you
to find this.
Why?
- You ever seen it before?
No.
Do you remember
anything about that day?
I was four years old.
Any idea where
it was taken?
No.
Hey.
You okay?
I mean, if I found out my mom was...
- Listen,
as far as I'm concerned,
she's not my mom.
She's just someone
in the way of my freedom.
All right?
So, on my sixth birthday,
um, my father was
long gone by then,
so it was just me,
Mom, and Linc, and...
Mom hands me my present--
my, uh, my only present--
and I just know...
I just know it's the
Millennium Falcon.
With the battle alert sound?
Exactly.
I totally owned that.
- Of course you did.
Anyway, I had been asking
for this thing for weeks,
and the package is just
the right size, and...
I rip open the
wrapping paper
and... it's a birdhouse.
Oh, no.
Oh, yeah, except
it's not even a birdhouse.
It's actually a
birdhouse kit.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't talk to her
for two days after that,
but when she finally got
me to open the thing,
we sat there
together,
put it together
piece by piece,
and it was the first
thing I ever built.
And I loved it...
and she knew I would.
She knew me better
than I knew myself.
That's what moms do.
Yeah, but the strange thing
is...
even though I haven't seen her
for 23 years,
there's this part of me
that feels
like maybe she still does.
Your truck looks
a little low to the ground.
You mind
stepping outside?
I just got weighed
20 miles back.
You highway patrol?
Where are you going?
You've got no
business in there.
Unless you show me
a warrant,
you get the hell out of there
right now.
Thank you.
Goodness.
I got my weigh station ticket
right here on the dash.
As soon as you see that...
You'll see I got it right here.
Here you go.
I need you to follow me
back to Phoenix.
Are you crazy?
I got to get this load
to Dallas.
Well, that's your choice.
I got 'em.
I think we need
to call your brother.
No signal.
We must be in the
middle of nowhere.
Lincoln said that
if the Company caught you...
I think I saw a side door
back here.
What about the main door?
You'll never get that open.
I'm sure it's latched
from the outside.
Can you open the side door?
Maybe.
Sara.
Help me out.
I don't think we're going
to be able to move this.
Maybe we won't have to.
I have troubling news
about General Krantz.
He's alive.
I don't see how that's possible.
Yes, well, what I'm hearing is a
helicopter with a medic took off
from Company headquarters
in Los Angeles one hour ago.
It landed for two minutes
in Canyon Country
and now it's back
in Los Angeles.
So you got the corpse?
The helicopter landed
back at Company headquarters.
You know how important
getting rid of him is
to what we're trying
to accomplish.
All right,
I can still get this done.
Not in our time frame.
All right, I'm pulling the plug.
We need to start dealing
with the consequences.
Wait, wait, wait.
First things first.
He knows that I've betrayed him.
I need to disappear.
I think that's a good instinct.
I have a house in Sun Valley.
I have another idea.
Do you mind
putting me on speaker?
You know, Griff,
you're a brave man.
And I thank you
for everything you've done.
It's been an honor.
Now.
"Now" what?
The car in this picture
has Florida plates.
Did you ever
vacation there?
No.
- Do you know anyone
from Florida who came up to visit?
- No.
Why did they take this picture
in front of that car?
We didn't.
It's been doctored.
I'm not sure about that.
I mean, the lighting,
the shadows,
all sync up perfectly.
This is a '78 Zephyr.
Michael was born in '76.
You're the only one
who could've picked up on that.
She doctored that for you.
Let's see what else
she might've changed.
What's the license plate
on that Zephyr?
M-L-K 4-4-1.
Martin Luther King Boulevard
intersects with Route 441
about five miles north of here.
Good.
You guys are here.
Listen, we're a little outmanned
down in Little Havana.
We could use some backup.
We got a lead
on the buyer.
Great, what are
we waiting for?
I think I'm going to do this myself.
- No, no.
Come on, let's stay together.
- We're a team, right?
I said I got it.
- After our little
special deliveries
this morning,
each one of us
has an equal stake.
Whoever started this, we're all
going to take them out.
The buyer, we think
it's Lincoln's mother.
What?
Like I said, I'm
doing this myself.
Linc!
If she has Scylla,
she's not just going
to hand it over
any more than the
general would have.
You don't know that.
We always thought
whoever had Scylla
would do what the general did.
Maybe she won't.
Are you serious?
Your mother is a Company agent?
She was.
She might be one
of the good guys now.
With all due respect,
I don't think you're in a place
where you can make
a clear determination
about that.
Listen, this MLK 441
could be nothing.
But at the church,
there could be Scylla.
If I need you, I'll call.
This should work.
Come on.
Christina?
You need to acknowledge
that our chance
of success has substantially
declined in the last 24 hours.
There are people
out looking for us.
We need to start thinking
in terms of contingencies.
Just a little while longer;
only a few more days.
General Krantz
refused to adjust
when there were credible
threats against him.
That's the reason
we have Scylla now.
Are you honestly
comparing me to him?
I understand what you think
your role is in all of this,
and I appreciate
your efforts.
But if you can't tell
the difference
between he and I,
perhaps you need to ask
the general
for your old job back.
Oh, look.
Here he is.
Would you like to take the call?
Jonathan.
Good afternoon, Christina.
It's good to hear your voice.
I assume this means
you've retrieved Scylla.
Not yet.
Oh, troubling news.
Have any idea where it is?
Where are you, Christina?
Johannesburg.
Where else would I be?
I've had some of my contacts
in your area
check on your house.
There's no one home.
Well, of course not.
As long as Scylla's in play,
that address is blown.
Where are you, Christina?
I don't like your
tone, Jonathan.
Excuse me
if I sound a bit abrasive.
But it's been a while since
anyone's tried to kill me.
Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
What happened?
Oren.
"Oren"?
We found his body... executed.
I can only assume that
he's working with someone.
Someone who doesn't
tolerate failure.
Now, where are you, Christina?
You listen to me.
If you're implying that I had
anything to do with this...
Where are you?
After everything
I've given the Company:
my husband, my children...
I think it's time
that we had a sit-down.
Talk.
Tell you what.
Why don't you gather up
the brain trust:
that half-witted daughter
and your psychotic mistress?
Why don't you get together
and figure out where Scylla is?
Then call me.
Mr. Burrows.
May I escort you
to your table?
You haven't changed a bit.
I'm glad you
got my message.
I know it wasn't
the most straightforward
mode of communication,
but I had to be sure it was you.
At least now I know
where Michael gets it from.
I'm sure you have
many questions.
Where's Scylla?
It's safe.
That's all I can
tell you for right now.
Then we've got
nothing to talk about.
Really?
That's the only reason
you came here?
Yeah.
I really would've thought
you wanted to know the truth.
I know the truth.
You work for the Company.
The same people
that set me up for murder.
Lincoln...
The same people
that have been
trying to kill me and Michael
ever since we
escaped Fox River.
You can think it as much
as you want, I'm not a monster.
23 years
and not even an apology?
If I thought an apology
would do any good,
I would offer it.
Please.
Please sit down.
Leaving you two boys...
was the hardest thing
I ever did.
But you did.
And then you went off
and worked for the Company.
You know, you think you know
what the Company is,
but you don't.
It is a body
that bends
to the will of its head.
And right now, it is
bloodthirsty and war-hungry,
because that's who
General Krantz is.
But what if a woman,
a mother, ran it?
Can you imagine the different
that would make?
You think you're a mother?
A mother's priority
is her family.
If I give Scylla to the general,
he leaves me
and Michael alone,
and I get to spend time
with my son in peace.
Look, I could sit here for days
and try to explain to you
why I did what I did.
Suffice it to say,
I couldn't protect you then,
but let me protect you now.
What if General Krantz
were no longer in the picture?
Once he is
dealt with,
no one would
come after you.
But I need time, Lincoln.
I need two days
to put everything
into place.
If you give me
two days...
...then I can give you
and Michael
your complete
and utter freedom.
All right.
I'm going to get started
right away.
But if Krantz
suspects any of this,
he's going to hunt us both down.
And for that reason,
I can't risk
being seen with you
until all of this is over.
How will I get
in touch with you?
You can't.
I'm sorry.
Once we pull this box down,
it'll push
the water machine
right through the side door.
We're slowing down.
I think we're getting off the highway.
I'm almost ready.
Hold on.
Sara, grab that
strap over there.
All right, hold it.
Sara, get behind me.
Come on!
Ready?
Jump!
You all right?
After you clear the area
I don't anticipate
any problems.
All right?
Scylla or not here we come.
All right.
- Hold on.
Hold on.
What the hell are
those guys doing?
We're not going against any
additional people in there.
We wait until they come
back out.
So Lincoln's mother is
really the buyer?
It appears that way.
I hope he
understands,
that if I need to take her
out to get to Scylla,
I'm not going to hesitate
to kill her.
No question.
Well, let's just hope
it doesn't come to that.
You serious?
Yeah. Am I serious
if we can get Scylla
without killing Linc's mother,
that's the preferable outcome.
Wait a second.
If I'm gonna be in the
foxhole with you,
I need to know that
you have my back.
Mrs. Burrows
has the item,
and the only way to get it
is to kill her.
What is your move?
I pull the trigger.
There they go,
come on.
Don Self,
Homeland
Security.
We're investigating
a cruelty to animal charge.
I have no idea what
you're referring to.
We're referring
to ritual
slaughters of chickens.
Okay, that might be allowed
where you come from
but here in America,
that's no mas.
Chickens?
This is preposterous.
This is because
I'm Caribbean.
I swear to God, I smelled
chicken blood.
Worse than the place
down the street we shut down.
- Hey.
You want to turn this
into something?
Sit down.
If there aren't
any chickens,
there aren't any chickens.
But we're not going to know that
until we take
a look around.
The smell was coming
from back there.
That is our sanctuary.
I cannot let you
to disrupt it.
I understand your concerns,
but I need to go back there.
I insist,
you cannot do that.
Best I can do is have you
accompany us, please.
Please.
You,
come on, let's
go outside
until they're done.
Let's go.
That's not a very heavenly thing
to do.
Find anything?
Oh, yeah.
Wow.
What the hell are they up to?
I don't know.
He just asked to rent
that closet.
Did a woman ever come
down here with him?
Yeah, once.
I'm telling you,
that's all I know.
Drop it.
Don't.
Come here.
Both of you,
on your knees.
I said on your knees.
I told you not to come in here.
Where's the
other guy?
He ran. Let's go.
Let's go.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Let's go.
Come on.
We're not going to make
it back to the truck.
I know.
Here.
Take this.
I'll be right back.
Michael.
Michael!
You all right?
Yeah, thanks.
The General should know by now
not to mess with us.
The General...
didn't send me.
Who did?
Who sent you?
Lincoln!
We've got news.
So do I.
We're staying low for two days.
Christina's promised
to get rid of Krantz.
I think she's lying.
I know it sounds crazy,
she said she's going
to change the Company
in the way it operates.
So what, the Company's gonna go
nonviolent now?
Just hear me out.
I'm telling you. I think she's lying.
It's from the church.
Some kind of credential.
There were some automatic
weapons in there, too.
And trust me, if there's
fake IDs and weapons
something big's
about to go down.
Your mom,
she said after two days,
that's when she would
make the change.
Yeah.
Take a look at the date
on that laminate,
two days away.
You think that's just a coincidence?
- Come on,
Lincoln, you can't be surprised
that a woman that would abandon
her kids
would be less
than truthful
about her intentions
right now.
Hey, were you going?
- I need to talk to her.
Just take a moment.
Let's figure this out.
If she's looking to
head the Company,
there has to a more realistic
plan than a one-man
frontal assault.
She'll listen to me.
She asked you not to come back,
Linc.
That's a warning.
Lincoln's back at the plaza.
I think we need
to realize
he's more of a threat
than we gave him
credit for.
He found the mansion.
His guys got the stash
at the church.
He's not going to stop.
I told him to stay away.
Sir,
Alpha is a go.
Christina,
we have a clean shot.
Take it.
Subtitles by LeapinLar
www.tvsubtitles.net