Previously, on Prison Break...
Excuse me,
I need to ask you a few questions.
And then that dirty southerner,
he snuck out the back.
Do you really think
the diaper sniper got all of it?
If you were Bagwell,
and you just got your hands
on $5 million,
where would you go?
All right, listen,
in the Rainbow Room.
Restaurant in New York city.
I am gonna be waiting
in that spot.
And that's all that I want...
in this whole world,
is for my two girls
to be waiting there for me.
Three dots, third letter.
Question is "where"?
What? What are you trying
to tell me, Michael?
I think I owe you an apology.
Because I lied to you.
About Oscar Shales.
Right there.
That's where I put the bullet in him.
What are you doing, man?
You've been hired to do a job.
The reasoning...
does not concern you.
You don't ask any questions about us,
maybe we'll continue to make sure
no one asks any questions about you.
Are we clear?
They all die.
Hey.
Are you new?
Yeah.
No one told me we were getting
a new volunteer.
I've been working, uh,
night shifts, cleanup and...
Jimmy said I could change
my shift, so...
You know what you're doing?
Yeah.
I'll see you around.
Right.
This might be Scofield.
Copy that.
You take that side.
Freeze!
Take it easy, man.
- Stay on the ground!
- What's the deal?
He's gone.
How you feeling?
Okay, I guess.
Tired.
I'm a target, kid.
As long as you're with me, so are you.
Things could get a lot worse
before they get better.
You understand?
But after we meet up with uncle Mike
and get to Panama...
Panama ain't a sure thing,
Your uncle's plan is dangerous.
I mean really dangerous.
Listen...
all the charges against you
have been dropped;
you're free and clear
to start a new life.
A good life.
Not be constantly running,
- looking over your shoulder...
- You want me to leave?
No.
Good, 'cause I'm not.
Turn the sound up on the tube, Jenny.
Do you have any thoughts
on the death of David Apolskis?
It was unfortunate.
- Tests show he was shot at close range.
- Oh, David.**
Was there any opportunity
to subdue him...
let me remind you that despite his age,
David "Tweener" Apolskis
was a fugitive who made a move
for my weapon.
I did not want to have to kill him,
but sometimes, things happen
that are just out of your control.
That good ole boy's hunting 'em all
down, ain't he?
Mr. Mahone, sources claim
that you've recovered Scofield's
hard drive and have obtained
substantial data from it.
What sources?
Allegedly you've retrieved information
detailing not only
how he broke out, but how he plans
to stay out. Comments?
No.
The event at Blanding
Botanical Gardens earlier today,
that was a result of hard-drive data
you collected.
No comment.
You found other locations
where Scofield might be headed?
- True?
- I believe I said no comment.
There's something about this guy,
it's like he knows where we're going,
what we're thinking.
Mr. Mahone, could you tell us
where you're headed next?
What role will the hard drive
play in your search?
Heard it came back
from the lab, any findings?
Yeah, 3,200 nitroglycerine ampules.
Scofield knew these needed
to be stored in a cool, moist area.
Best place for that in the Utah desert
is the botanical gardens.
It's stable?
All medical grade, safely used
by heart patients all the time.
But in the aggregate...
it could take out an entire building.
That box right there.
This is why we can't have...
leaks...
coming from this office.
God help the agent
who goes behind my back
and talks to the press.
Can you elaborate on
any of your tactics in this manhunt?
Sun Tzu said
that if you know your enemy,
you need not fear a hundred battles.
I know these men...
who they are, where they came from,
where they want to go.
These convicts,
are in an constant battle.
Not only with me,
but with themselves,
second guessing
every decision thet make.
Do I turn left?
Do I turn right?
Stay, or go?
My job is to know
how they answer these questions.
The only way to win a war
is to try to know your prey completely
and then you get to go after your enemy
with everything you've got.
Sync and corrected by: www.sub-way.fr
Transcript: www.sadgeezer.com
Our half-priced stuff is in the back.
I'm looking for something very specific.
Okay.
This is it.
This is exactly what I need.
Great.
We were just inches away today,
inches.
I want these blown up, huge.
- Put them in my office on the walls.
- What are these?
Somewhere in there is information
regarding a rendezvous
that Scofield set up,
and we're going
to crack that code today. Lang!
Today's the day Franklin told his wife
he's going to meet her
at the Rainbow Room.
- Right.
- Wrong. Today's the day
Franklin's going down. Are you ready?
Everything's arranged.
It's all here?
Hey, yo, Tray, wassup, big?
I know that ain't you.
Ain't a ghost, man.
You holding up all right?
Yeah. Caught a whole bunch of buses
just to get here to Chi-town, man.
How you think I'm supposed to feel?
Chris. Jay.
Wassup, Flam?
You look like you lost a few, bro.
Slim-fast, baby.
Is that what it is?
The Feds been
in your old lady's business, no joke.
Up in your crib,
- and following her around sometimes.
- Yeah, I know, man. I know.
Yo, I know you love Kacee,
but I don't know if it's a good idea
for you to be coming around here.
You're a wanted man.
I'm wanted because I kept my mouth shut,
and I kept you out of Fox River.
See, man, we feel that,
and we owe you one.
Good, 'cause I'm collecting right now.
My wife is waiting for me today,
and I am not leaving Chi-town
without my family.
You understand?
Now, y'all going to help me.
Let's roll out.
Where you going?
Take my kid to school.
I know about the Rainbow Room.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Phone lines are tapped.
We heard your entire telephone
conversation with your husband.
And, since you and Dede aren't booked
on any flights to New York,
don't tell me the Rainbow Room
is a restaurant in Manhattan.
Now, you can tell me
where you're meeting your husband,
or I can arrest you
right in front of your daughter.
You go to hell.
I haven't done anything wrong.
You spoke with an escaped felon
about meeting him today.
You've already done enough to be charged
with attempt to aid and abet.
Please, okay?
- Listen to me.
- One phone call
and child welfare is here,
and you're going to county
and Dede will be in foster care.
- No.
- Don't worry.
I hear the families
in the foster system are top-notch.
You are asking me to choose
between my daughter and my husband.
Exactly.
Anything?
I'm on the phone with Fox River,
Checking T-bag's file.
Hey, what you got for me?
Really?
52 times?
Where?
I owe you, Patterson.
We got a lot of road to cover.
We're good?
No more stops
until we get to New Mexico.
- You forgot your change.
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- You were in such a rush.
Thanks.
Keep walking.
Come on, keep walking.
Damn it.
You don't have to ditch the car.
We can keep driving.
Can't. The waitress made me
and the car. It's useless.
Sorry, you know.
Maybe we can find another car.
Cars ain't exactly
growing on trees out here.
We've got 400 miles to go
and no way of getting there.
We don't get to Michael in time,
he's going to leave without us.
Uncle Mike wouldn't do that.
He doesn't have a choice.
It's a one-shot deal out of the country.
I said I was sorry.
There was a sign
back there for a train station.
- It ain't that easy.
- We'll follow the road...
- We won't be seen.
Hey, I'm not an idiot.
I was on the run, too, you know.
Yeah, you were on the run
and you got caught.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry I'm not a pro
at being a con like you, dad.
Maybe I should have just left
when you gave me the out, huh?
It's not like you care.
Take it easy.
I'm sorry, all right?
Sorry, I'm just...
Let's get out of here.
Mrs. Pamela Mahone?
- Yes?
- Agent Wayne Merrick, F.B.I.
I'd like to talk to you
about your husband.
I'm surprised...
that you're coming to me
for a background check on Alex.
It's standard procedure.
We run these kind of checks
when an agent
is about to be promoted to a,
to a higher security clearance.
No, I know that.
I did this dance
the last time he was promoted.
I just figured that
since we were divorced...
I mean, I rarely speak to him
and I certainly don't follow his career.
I really need to get this done today,
so... I promise I won't take up
much of your time.
I've given enough time
to my ex-husband, Mr. Merrick.
I see.
The...
The bureau can take
its toll on your family.
I understand that.
My ex-wife is a...
An agent and...
let's just say I know how you feel.
Promise me that he won't find out
we spoke?
Oh, it's totally confidential.
Do you mind if I ask why?
To be perfectly honest,
he scares me.
Information.
Hi, I need the number
for a Sundown hotel please.
What state?
- All of them, please.
- Got one in Pierre, South Dakota.
- Ay.
- Another in Sutton, West Virginia
and one more in Gila, New Mexico.
What can I do you for?
A batch of them sunflowers, please.
You don't mind me
saying, you do not sound
like you hail from Kansas.
You've got a sharp ear.
I hail from what we call the,
yellowhammer state.
What brings you to Tribune?
Sir?
Romance.
Thank you so much.
Somebody's going to get hurt.
Feds going to be swinging bigger bats
than these.
We gotta have ours.
Look, man, that's all we need
is your car, your truck,
and some guts, man.
We don't need all of this.
- Maybe we should think about it.
- I said no!
What's going to happen, man,
when the bullets start flying,
Can you guarantee me that my family
ain't going to get hurt?
Johnny law is going to strapped up.
I'm going in hot.
I don't think you heard me, little man.
No, I don't think you heard me, Bruh.
I'm not going in naked.
I know we said
we'd ride with you on this,
but I'm not going in there
without some of these.
You want to punk out, man?
Then punk out,
'cause I can do this myself.
Ain't nobody punking out.
And no guns.
But you'd better be right about this
'cause if bullets do start flying,
the only blood being spilled
is going to be ours.
Feel me?
I feel you.
Agent Kellerman.
Agent Kellerman!
Yes.
That name you wanted me
to track, Kelli Foster.
She booked a flight to New Mexico,
just landed.
You got someone on it?
No, but we got an ID on her rental car.
Should I update Mr. Kim?
No, I'll take care of this myself.
Got a tip from a waitress
who thinks she saw Burrows
and his son outside St. David, Arizona.
get a road team out there to confirm.
Once they got a bead on Burrows,
notify me immediately.
Everybody out! Let's go, come on!
Yeah?
Sara Tancredi just booked
a one-way ticket across the country.
- To where?
- New Mexico.
Of course.
Any luck breaking that code?
- This helps.
- Good.
Wheeler!
Sir.
Every combination that has "nm" in it.
I want you to check it
to see if it contains
the name of a location in New Mexico.
- And I want it done now. Right now.
- Now, you got it.
So, how well do you know Alex?
He knows me better than I know him.
He's a closed book, all right.
But he wasn't always like that.
In the first few years of our marriage,
he was actually... romantic.
And then,
one day, out of nowhere...
Out of nowhere what?
Everything changed.
He became obsessed with getting out.
Out of the marriage?
Getting out of the marriage,
getting me out of the house,
out of his life.
He left me.
He left the both of us.
You said you were scared of him.
Why is that?
He started acting strange.
Started spending all of his time
in the backyard gardening,
of all things. I mean,
the man was a neat freak.
He'd throw away a pair of shoes
if they even got scuffed.
But he'd be out there
all covered in dirt
and surrounded by these huge bags
of fertilizer and lye.
We'd just put this new sod in
and he just tore it all up
and planted a flower bed.
And I went out back once to talk to him
and he screamed at me
and said not to come near the garden.
Said that it was his.
I'm sorry. If you...
If you wanna take a break...
All I wanted was an explanation.
Why things ended so suddenly.
And all Alex could say was:
"Sometimes, things happen"
"that are just out of your control."
So the picture
in your daughter's bedroom,
the exact location where it was taken
was a merry-go-round, right?
Yeah.
So, all you have to do
is wait by the merry-go-round.
Right where Benjamin's expecting you.
Is that necessary?
- I mean, Benjamin's not..
- It's precautionary.
Look, I do this,
you leave me and my child alone.
You have my word.
Is my wife there?
- Yeah, she's here.
- Well, let's go get her.
73, ready at position n°1.
In 15 seconds,
a black Jeep is going to pull up
by the parking lot's entrance.
Run to it.
Chris?
Go!
I can't.
They're gonna take Dede.
Look, no, they won't.
Is that guy talking to her?
Get a read on him.
Move to position.
It's taken care of. Go!
Go!
She's running! She's running!
Go, go, go, go! Move, move!
Get in!
Hold on!
It's a 2007 black Jeep.
License plates have been removed.
We're in pursuit, headed... No!
Move the truck.
Move the truck!
I said move it!
Where is my child?
Here.
- Dede?
- Hey, it's me, baby.
Look, I just want to tell you
that everything is going to be okay.
We're gonna be a family again.
I promise you that.
Where is Dede? He said that you had her!
No, no. Be easy, baby.
Easy.
Darius is picking her up
from school right now.
Dede Franklin, Dawson elementary.
I want her pulled from school now!
What the hell is going on, man?
They say she's taking a test, man,
but I think they're stalling.
What about...
What about Oscar Shales?
Oscar Shales?
Why is he important?
Well, he's...
He's just the only fugitive
to ever successfully elude your...
Your ex-husband.
Alex was consumed with finding him.
I mean, after what Shales did
to all of his victims,
who could blame him?
It was all he worked on,
all he did for a year.
But I don't think that it was the stress
of chasing Shales
that caused Alex
to start behaving erratically.
Why is that?
Because Alex changed
after the trail went cold.
I remember it like it was yesterday.
He just...
walked into the kitchen,
after 12 years of marriage,
and says that he wanted me
out of the house immediately.
I'll never forget the date.
It was june 15.
I think I have everything I need.
But you didn't even ask about
social history or education?
That's standard in these checks.
That's been handled.
I have to get these reports filed
with Strategic Operations asap.
You're with Strategic Operations?
They handle these checks.
Not since the 9/11 realignment,
Mr. Merrick.
The Chief Information Officer
does them now.
They handled Alex's last check.
When an agent reaches a level
as high as your ex-husband's,
S.O. takes over, again.
Bureaucracies.
Thank you for the coffee.
Look,
just get her out of here.
They're here.
- No, C! We gotta go!
- No, don't worry about it.
Just get the car started, all right? Go!
- Daddy!
-Hey, baby!
- You ready to go?
- Where are we going?
Disneyland.
Mr. Franklin! You can't...
They're here!
Come on, let's go!
Go, baby. Go, baby.
Go, go, go!
Franklin has the child!
Repeat, Franklin has the child!
'Evening, Mrs. Hollander.
Don't you look lovely this evening.
You should have told me what you were!
My God, I let you near my children!
Don't think I won't remember
what your front steps look like.
Come on, get away from the road.
You wanna get caught?
I...
I saw you checking out
those girls back at the diner.
What?
Come on. Fess up.
No. I was just making sure
they weren't staring at us.
With what? Their asses?
Beautiful girls in Panama.
They love Americans.
Cool.
So, how long have you known about girls?
Long enough.
Since when?
Thirteen.
Thirteen?
With who?
Donna Anselmi.
She was the kid next door.
She was about...
She's four years older than me.
Your mom was paying her
for French lessons.
Well, she earned the money.
Come on.
Away from the road.
You're still way too close. Let's go.
You wanna learn some tricks, Gracey?
Like what?
Yeah.
I let you into my life.
Twenty seven!
Evening, Mrs. Hollander.
How are you feeling, little teddy?
Six.
Tomorrow.
Pam, I really can't talk right now.
Maybe I should call back.
Who is this?
I think you already know.
If you've done anything to Pam...
or my boy...
We both know your family's fine.
Although, Pam did seem
a little upset about you leaving.
But then you had to,
didn't you?
'Cause you couldn't let her find out.
Find out about what?
Oscar Shales.
You remember?
The one that got away.
Except he didn't get too far.
Did he?
- You're slipping, Scofield.
- Maybe.
Let's hypothesize for a moment.
Let's pretend I was the one
who caught Shales.
I don't think I could have just
handed that psychopath
over to the courts,
not after he'd eluded me for so long.
Made me look bad.
You've been out in the sun
way too long, boy.
You Feds make a nice living,
but not so nice you go around
tearing up expensive sod.
Not unless you had to do
a little digging,
not unless you wanted
to hide something...
or someone.
That's what all the lye was for.
Wasn't it?
See, because there are two kinds
of lye.
Small amounts, the first kind
can be a garderner's best friend.
And large bags, the other kind
decomposes bodies.
You should write mystery novels.
Now, I don't know about you,
but if I buried someone
in my own backyard,
I'd think about it all the time.
I'd think...
I'd think maybe
I should move that body.
But then I'd remember,
that D.N.A. leeches into soil.
So even when the body was gone,
the proof of what I'd done
would still be there.
I can imagine how it feels.
The pressure...
the constant fear.
It's more than a man can bear.
I give you a chance.
Back off.
Let me and my family disappear.
And in return,
I'll keep your little secret.
How does that sound?
Like a dead man talking.
I know it's not how you wanted this
to play out.
But sometimes,
things happen that are just...
out of your control.
This is one of those times.
Take care of yourself.
I'll see you soon, Michael.
And... Michael!
It just may be sooner than you think.
Did you have a nice nap?
Visions of 12 year olds
dancing in your head?
You're trespassing.
Nobody lives here anymore, Goldilocks.
Seems the owner hit the bricks
as soon as she heard
a certain someone had reentered society.
Left in a hurry, too,
even left some stuff behind.
So this is where Theodore practiced
pervert knows best.
This...
is where he had his family supper.
And that, I believe
is where you and Ms. Hollander
expressed your love.
Tell me, little Teddy,
did you make her wear Dr. Denton's
and hold a lunch box
to help you get all worked up?
Bradley, I couldn't possibly expect
a grown man
who still lives with his momma,
to understand the machinations of love.
You wanna know how we found you?
52 mash notes,
sent by you to this address.
All of them beggin' Ms. Hollander
to take your white-trash ass back.
And every one of them
boomeranged to Fox Rive marked
"return to sender."
The guards had a real laugh
readin' them,
- didn't we, Geary?
- Damn right, we did.
That is one
mangy lookin' paw you got there, slick.
What happened? A boy scout fought back?
Geary?
Now you're gonna tell me
where you stashed Westmoreland's money,
or I'm going to pluck you
like a chicken,
stitch by stitch.
Fine. You wanna know where the money is?
I did spend a whole bunch of it
last night on your momma.
Wrong answer.
Come here, baby.
How are you?
- You good?
- Yeah.
She's okay.
- Baby?
- Yeah?
What do we do, now?
What are we gonna do?
Get a ticket on the train.
Come on.
Just wait here until the train comes.
Two caucasian males on foot,
fleeing the Willcox station.
L.J!
Don't move!
Please. Please.
He's got nothing to do with this.
Face down. Both of you, face down!
- Please.
- Now!
Cuff 'em.
L.J, I'm sorry.
Suspect in custody.
Possible I.D: Lincoln Burrows.
I'm sorry.
L.J, I'm sorry.
www.tvsubtitles.net