Previously on Prison Break:
Listen, why don't I give you
half the money and we call it a day?
All right, 60-40.
You thieving son of a bitch.
You better get down on your knees
and pray to God that I don't find you.
Because if I do, mark my words,
I'm gonna gut you bow to stern.
-Mr. Bellick?
-Yeah.
Do you mind answering
a few more questions?
We have a lead as to where Burrows
will meet with his brother.
A place he referred to as Bolshoi Booze.
They're numbers.
Plug them into your GPS. It'll take you
to a spot in the New Mexico desert.
-Daddy!
-Hey, baby. You ready to go?
Come on. Go, go, go!
What do we do now?
-Has she told you anything?
-Not yet.
-Then kill her.
-Well, if she knows something....
You disobey me, you are done.
Put her in the ground, Paul.
You're going to die.
And all you had to do was tell me
what your father gave you.
Go to hell.
The plane's gonna stop
at the seven-mile marker...
...Route Four, at sunset.
-We gotta go.
-I brought someone. Dad?
We've met before.
-lt was you.
-Go easy, son.
Stay away from me.
-What the hell's going on?
-I know him.
-You know him? That's impossible.
-I know him. I know this man.
-Michael.
-Maybe that's far enough.
-This doesn't concern you.
-What the hell's going on, Dad?
After Mom died...
...you were in juvie.
They put me with this foster father...
...down on Pershing Avenue.
He punished me.
Locked me up.
If you leave someone alone
in the dark for that long...
...their eyes start to adjust.
You start to see things,
no matter how small...
...because if they exist,
they can help you.
Help you do
the only thing you wanna do...
... when you 're alone in the dark.
Get out.
I've used just about every lure
that you can use.
Most of them,
you need to be an expert to use.
This MotoLure's a little different.
Everybody, I mean,
everybody, can fish with it.
Catch bigger fish,
you 're gonna catch more fish.
It even works in weedy areas
where most top water lures won 't work.
Take a look at this baby.
This thing looks like a real minnow.
It's one very cool bait.
I have never seen anything quite like this.
Even if you 've bought lures off TV
in the past and been disappointed...
...and believe me, I know how you feel.
-Oh, sorry, man. I thought you ' d left.
-Hey. No, still here. Here I am.
It' s just that a couple guests
are complaining...
...about the volume of your TV.
Oh, sorry. I fell asleep.
I must've hit the remote.
-I'll take care of it. Thanks. Sorry. Thanks.
-That's great.
So could you do that for me now, please,
so it's taken care of?
-Yeah.
-Thanks.
Taken care of.
Is everything okay in your bathroom?
Excuse me?
In your bathroom.
There's a noise coming from it.
Yeah, my daughter
thinks bath time is playtime.
I will clean it up. Scout's honor. Sorry.
-All right. Have a nice day.
-Yeah.
You too.
-Michael!
-Michael.
-Michael, please, wait.
-He did this to you?
Lincoln!
He did this to you?
Did he do this to you?
Michael.
How could you do that
to another human being...
...with your own hands?
It's okay.
You're safe now.
He's not gonna hurt you anymore.
Come on.
Come with me and don't look back.
Michael!
Michael.
It's gonna be all right.
Sara!
Six months.
Six months I was in that place.
Where were you?
How long did you know?
I found you as soon as I could.
The state kept moving you.
Then you went away again.
You don't think it killed me
to leave you like that?
To leave in the first place?
Since the beginning, I was the problem.
Since day one.
Your lives are what they are because of me.
Yes, Linc told me about The Company.
You were some kind of analyst.
That's the job you chose over your family.
I thought I was doing the right thing,
protecting you.
From what, Dad? From who?
The Company had enemies.
I was important to The Company.
I became a target. Easiest way
to get to me would be to get to you.
I left as soon as I realized
how corrupt it was.
-How they were buying the government.
-You could've come back.
No, I couldn't!
Michael, turning on The Company
put me and you at even greater risk.
I had to stay away.
We were your sons.
And you still are, Michael.
We can fix this.
I came back so that we could fix this.
This can never be fixed.
There's a tape.
It gives us everything we need.
Linc will be set free if we find it.
You're not gonna believe
who he thinks has it.
Who?
Sara.
Yes, tall, slender,
brown hair, brown eyes.
She'd be pretty banged up.
No one matching that description
has been brought into the ER.
Kellerman.
The report on Sara Tancredi?
She's dead.
I'm dealing with the body right now.
-You must be relieved that it's over.
- Yeah.
-Yeah, I gotta go, Bill.
-One more thing.
Confirmation.
I need a photo of the body
before disposal.
Take one with your phone
and send it to me, and I'll--
Bill, not a good time right now, all right?
Paul, take a breath...
...then take the picture.
I'm waiting.
"They traveled
into a very dangerous place.
Now, Arvid knew that, but he held tightly
onto the dragon's leash anyway...
...as the creature ran
into the ever-dark forest...
...pulling the young boy behind him."
Why didn't he just let go of the leash?
Well, because he loved the dragon.
And when you love someone,
you'll do anything to hold onto them.
Anything to keep them safe and happy.
Is that why we're camping?
Yep, so we can all be together.
I'm happy.
You know, I'm happy too.
Here you go.
Well, it's all working out, huh?
Don't say that.
You know, this moment,
right here, right now...
...it's all worth it.
I love you.
Oh, that's old.
-The kids are bigger now.
-Sorry, I was just....
Oh, getting bored out of your wits
because you've been waiting so long.
I'm really sorry about all this.
We don't get a whole bunch
of homicides out here...
...and we're trying to play catch-up.
Please, have a seat.
I'm real sorry about your friend.
It's a sick world out there.
Ain't that the truth.
-So you guys out here in Kansas together?
-Yeah, that's right.
Doing what?
Well, you know, just seeing the sights.
You left Chicago to see the sights
in Tribune, Kansas?
Last I checked,
a man could go where he wanted.
-Mr. Bellick.
-Brad.
Brad.
I don't really care
what you were doing out here.
We're both in law enforcement.
We can each sniff out a perp like a hot fart.
Pardon my French.
And we both know
you're not a criminal...
...so I don't care if you boys were out here
whooping it without your wives...
...or going Brokeback.
What?
Hell, no.
My point is,
I don't care what you were doing.
I just need to know where you were doing it
and who you might've crossed paths with...
...so I can find out
who carved up Mr. Geary.
Geary and I got a lead that one
of the Fox River Eight was in town.
Which one?
-Theodore Bagwell.
-The man who did those horrible things...
-...to those teenagers?
-That's him.
We're gonna bring him in for the reward
money but we couldn't get a handle.
Geary and I split up,
we figured we didn't have a shot, but--
-But what?
-Well, after what happened...
...I'm starting to think maybe Geary
ran into old Bagwell after all.
Right here in Tribune?
Now, Brad, do you think
you could answer some questions...
...that might help us, you know,
track down Theodore Bagwell?
I'd be indebted.
I'll do whatever I can to help nail
that son of a bitch.
You think Sara has this tape?
The government does.
I just saw her yesterday.
If she does have anything...
...she doesn't know.
-Well, where is she now?
-I don't know.
Any way you can get in touch with her?
-We bought cell phones. I could call her.
-Please, please, please, bro.
Call her from Panama, please.
We got less than two hours.
I gotta make the flight.
What?
Run. Run!
-Where's this car you keep talking about?
-It's over the ridge.
Give me that. You guys head for the car.
Go!
Come on, come on!
Come on! Go, go, go!
Pick up Dad!
Dad, get in!
Come on, Dad!
We made it! Son of a bitch, we made it!
Linc.
Sucre, get us to a hospital.
-Out here? Where the hell am I gonna find--?
-Just get us to a hospital, please!
Don't worry, you're gonna make it.
It's bile. He got me clean through.
You're gonna be okay. Just hold on.
Listen to me, both of you.
Sorry.
I wish I'd never left.
Don't talk. Just breathe, okay?
Okay. So do you want a P.B.& B.?
Not really. My tummy hurts.
Where's her knapsack?
Her what?
-Her knapsack. Her medicine's in it.
-I don't know. I just grabbed her and ran.
She needs that medicine.
She can't go two days without it.
Okay, I know. I'm her father, all right?
Where is it?
Baby, baby. Look, look, calm down.
What are you looking for?
Just tell me what it is
and I'll go ahead and get it, okay?
Her prescription.
It's a backup. I keep an extra, in case.
Okay, okay.
So all I need to do is find a pharmacy.
Don't worry.
Hey, looks like we're going on a ride,
sweet pea.
If we nail Bagwell, he might still have
some of Geary's things on him...
...Iike his backpack,
which has his personal stuff in it.
I know his wife would love to have it.
If we find Bagwell...
-...give it to her personally.
-Thanks.
It's the least I can do
considering how you're helping me out.
Although some of the guys
on the force are concerned about....
-What are they concerned about?
-Oh, nothing.
You know what?
Why don't you tell me what you know?
We'll track down Bagwell,
get Geary's effects to his family.
I'll make sure everybody involved knows
your help was invaluable.
I'll even recommend that you get most of,
if not all of that reward money.
Well, what is it exactly that the guys
on the force were concerned about?
Some of them thought you weren't
being totally upfront about your injury.
I mean, to be fair, it does seem a little off
that you didn't see the guy...
...who hit you smack-dab
on the forehead.
You got me.
Geary and me had a little dust-up
over how to go about finding Bagwell.
It got physical and he hit me.
The two of us, we fought like brothers.
I didn't wanna rat him out to the cops.
After the fight, we split up.
And then....
Well, you know what happened to him.
I just wish to hell we'd never fought,
you know.
Maybe then, he'd still be....
Brad, you can't blame yourself.
Why don't we refocus our energy
on finding the man who killed your friend?
That's what Roy would've wanted.
Where you at, baby?
Insurance card?
No, I don't have insurance.
You're paying for dexamethasone
without insurance?
You got Medicaid,
Medicare or something?
Nope. I'll just pay cash.
It's 1 25.
Excuse me.
Excuse me?
Oh, sorry.
I'm sorry I don't have anything smaller.
I have to go to the back
to get change for a hundred.
So I'll be right back.
-Right there, hospital!
-I see it, I see it.
-Just get us there.
-No, you'll be caught.
Then we'll be caught.
I'm not gonna let you die.
Then listen to me.
You find Sara Tancredi.
She can end this.
It's up to you now.
Yeah, I want an alarm out
on a dark blue sedan, license AE 9268.
Forty miles southeast of Las Cruces.
Do it now.
Oh, come on.
What?
What hospital?
Came in with a bad GSW.
Docs called us in.
He's in here.
We ran his name.
Came back with two federal
drug-smuggling warrants out on him.
Heard you wanted to talk to me.
I got some information the feds want.
About Michael Scofield.
Like where he's catching a ride.
And where would that be?
It's not just the where, but the when.
That when is coming up soon.
But I wanna cut a deal first.
Give us a minute?
Anything you wanna say?
One day.
That's all we had.
Back then,
when things were at their worst...
...there were days I thought
I'd never see the sun again.
But he saved my life.
Just wish he could've let us
be a part of his.
Yeah.
I'll tell him.
Here's the deal.
All charges dropped,
government picks up medical costs...
...until you're fit to be deported.
All contingent upon your information
being accurate.
Where's Scofield?
No deportation. I want citizenship.
Citizenship?
A little incentive,
and I want it in writing.
Oh, I'm so tired of playing games.
Well, start typing.
No external pacemaker.
Hey, this is a good one.
No morphine drip.
-What are you doing?
-FBl. Out, out, out.
-What the hell are you doing?
-Giving you a little incentive.
Come on. Come on, you son of a--
And they found nothing?
Okay, thanks.
Well, your instincts are great, Brad.
But the precinct actually sent a unit over
to Hollander's house today.
An anonymous caller said they saw
an intruder but no one was there.
Damn it.
If you knew about
Bagwell and Hollander...
...why didn't you just head
over there yourself?
Oh, we couldn't find the house.
Really? It's listed.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Everything okay?
Yeah, yeah, everything's fine.
You ever been to the Fauntleroy Hotel?
It's about 1 5 minutes from here.
-Never heard of it.
-Well, that's strange.
Because they found this receipt
in Geary's hotel room.
It's from your credit card.
I don't know how that got there.
I think you're being evasive.
-You should tell me the truth, Mr. Bellick.
-What happened to "Brad"?
About seven years ago,
I got my first homicide case.
A woman. Pretty.
She was brutally attacked.
Animal boyfriend left her for dead.
But she was still breathing, barely.
But she punched into her cell phone...
...the killer's number,
so she solved the crime for us.
When we found the receipt, Brad,
it was in Geary's hand...
...his finger pointing to your name.
With his last ounce of strength...
-...he told us you killed him.
-Okay, listen.
Geary and I found Bagwell
in Hollander's house.
We roughed him up until he told us
where he'd hid the 5 million bucks...
...we knew he'd dug up in Utah.
When we found the money,
Geary double-crossed me...
...he hit me in the head
and took the cash.
I had nothing to do with Geary's death.
You hear what I'm saying?
I'm the victim here,
not that son of a bitch.
Oh, come on, come on, come on.
Where you at, baby?
Hey, could you hurry it up?
It's just it's getting really late
and I gotta get home.
And that's 20, 40, 50 and 20 is 70.
One, two, three, four, five is 75.
Excuse me.
You gotta be kidding me.
Ma'am.
Afternoon, officer.
Do you have any lD with you?
No, I walked over here,
so I didn't carry anything with me.
Did you? Where'd you walk from?
Is there a problem, officer?
There's only a problem
if you make one, Miss Franklin.
You want to tell us
where your husband is?
I don't know.
Place your hands behind your back,
please, ma'am.
Oh, baby, I'm so sorry.
Oh, my God.
Where is Mommy?
Mommy is gonna meet us later, okay?
-Yes?
-Where's the photo?
Bill, there was a tactical error.
I don't want terminology
from the Cover Your Ass Handbook, Paul.
-What happened?
-There were unforeseen circumstances.
-Things that could not be predicted.
-Where's Sara?
She's gone, isn't she?
Yes. She got away.
But there is no way that she--
Bill?
I'm not gonna let you die.
I love you.
You know that, don't you?
Too many.
Too many people died
because I wanted you to be free.
You couldn't have known, Michael.
You couldn't have known
it would've ended up like this.
But it did.
They wanted him.
They wanted him in the ground...
...and they got their wish.
This thing's not gonna end here, Michael.
-I know.
-It's gonna keep spreading.
Their hands are gonna get more
and more bloody.
The question is...
...is the blood on their hands or ours?
I'm sorry, guys.
We gotta go.
Get back on with border patrol.
Call the Navy Reserve Air Station in Dallas.
They've got planes on alert.
We need an intercept
of a white single-engine A-36 Beech...
...heading toward the border.
Call Mexico.
Get clearance for an international pursuit.
Tell them if they've gotta take
the plane down, just do it.
Come on, guys.
Guys, come on.
What?
We're staying.
Michael, this is what
we've been waiting for.
Maybe we'll see you
down there somewhere.
I can't talk you out of this one, can l?
Oh, I hope so.
Be good.
Thank you, Michael.
Thank you for everything.
-You take care of him, all right?
-I will.
Fly safe, papi.
Give them hell.
-Panama would've been good.
-Are you ready for this?
-Been waiting years.
-Good to hear it.
Because today's the day
we stop running.
-What now?
-We go back to the car...
...drive to a border town,
find a cell phone signal...
...and call Sara.
Where the hell are those jets?
-You hear that?
-Yeah.
Pull over.
They're going after Sucre.
They're gonna take him down.
-How'd they find out?
-I don't know.
Michael.
What the hell is going on?
If you could arrest me
you would have already.
-I'm out of here.
-Not really an option for you.
What've you got? A receipt?
He left it in his pocket. A fight? Big deal.
I got 1 0 pals in Chicago who'll tell you
Geary and I threw down once a month.
You're right. Any of those things
on their own, probably not enough.
But when you add this.
What the hell is that?
You left a message for Mr. Geary.
You thieving son of a bitch.
You better get down on your knees
and pray to God that I don 't find you.
Because if I do, mark my words,
I'm gonna gut you bow to stern.
You wanna hear it again?
Now, at this juncture, Brad...
...things will go a whole lot easier for you
if you admit to the crime.
Now, you listen to me,
you manipulative little bitch.
I did not kill Roy Geary!
You understand what I'm telling you?
Bagwell set me up!
Get your hands off of me!
You are under arrest for the murder
of Roy William Geary.
You have a right to remain silent.
Anything you say...
...can be used against you.
You have the right to a lawyer...
...and to have him present.
If you cannot hire a lawyer...
...the court will appoint one for you.
President Reynolds ' office.
This is Agent Paul Kellerman.
I need to speak with the president
right now, please.
I'm sorry, this administration
isn 't familiar with an Agent Kellerman.
June, it's me.
I need to speak with Caroline now.
If you don't put me through...
...I'll make certain the president knows
that you did not allow me...
...to provide her with some very
important information. Now.
I'm sorry, this administration
isn 't familiar with an Agent--
Please leave a message after the tone.
Bill, don't do this.
I've dedicated my life to this country.
To Caroline.
Everything I have, I give.
Every photo. Every file. Get rid of it all.
-Make him a ghost.
-I've been a perfect soldier.
I've never asked anything of you ever.
But I'm asking now.
Bill, don 't do this.
-I don ' t see him.
-Trust me, we haven ' t lost him yet.
Linc, stop the car.
-What?
-We gotta stop the car.
That's a radio tower over there.
It must be picking up
some kind of analog signal.
We gotta get closer. Turn around.
-What about your friend back there?
-lf we're gonna go down...
...might as well go down swinging.
All right.
Come on, come on, come on.
We are in business. It's going through.
All right.
Come on, Sara, pick up.
Pick up, pick up, pick up.
Sara.
Hello?
Hello, Michael?
Michael?
[ENGLlSH]
www.tvsubtitles.net