Previously on Prison Break
There's something about this guy.
It's like he knows where we're going
and what we're thinking.
If it's true, it won't be long
before he finds out
about the money in Utah,
our way into Mexico... Everything.
...have an attorney present
during questioning
now or in the future...
Caroline, they're taking her in.
Of course. I'll keep an eye on her.
I did it, Dad.
Just do as you're told.
Otherwise, there will be consequences
that will affect us all.
My dad's an Air Force colonel.
When I told him I was staying
in a hotel with a guy that...
I maybe sorta liked,
he lost it.
What are you doing here?
Where's Maricruz?
She's with me now.
He's gonna be where she is.
Hey, Fernando, slow down, man.
I was trying to tell you,
the wedding is in Vegas.
Which one of them was it?
Might be Scofield.
Probably gonna find his brother
in there, too.
Where to, sir?
Utah.
This morning, authorities in Illinois
issued an update on the escaped convicts
known until now as the Fox River Eight.
Chicago mob boss John Abruzzi
was gunned down
outside a Washington D. C. motel
last night,
after investigators received a tip
from an informant.
The other seven escapees
are still at large
and considered dangerous.
A Florida man wanted in...
I didn't think Abruzzi'd be
the first to hit it.
I have a feeling we're in
for lots of surprises.
They said seven are still out there.
So much for faking our deaths.
I bought us some time,
that's what counts.
How much further?
70, 80 miles.
Good. Means we should be hitting
the Double K Ranch by this afternoon.
Or we can pick up L.J. and hit Panama.
We can't hit Panama!
We can't hit anything! We can't do
anything without the money.
We need to find Charles's stash.
I know some other guys
who are thinking the same thing.
The money is buried under a silo
at the Double K Ranch
just outside of Tooele, Utah.
There's five million dollars there.
Tickets?
You know, when I was in Cheyenne,
I pulled my ticket out of the bag.
It tore in half, and...
I have no idea what happened
to the other part.
They didn't issue you a replacement?
No. The young lady,
I think her name was Sherry,
she actually said
that this half is okay
because the bar code is on it.
Well, you really need the whole ticket.
This is exactly
what I was trying to avoid.
She said that everything
would be fine because...
That's okay. It'll do for now.
But make sure you ask for a replacement
when you get to Provo.
I definitely will. Thank you.
It's always something, huh?
Oh, God, I know.
I don't wanna go home.
I wish we could keep driving.
I don't think your pops
will be down for that.
Wouldn't it be fun?
We could go to...
Hawaii?
Yo, you can't drive to Hawaii.
I know.
I'm just saying
I wish.
No, no. Don't get it. They'll leave.
Just let me see who it is.
It's a cop.
No, no, no, no.
Sorry to disturb you, ma'am.
Have you happened to see this person?
Transcript www.1000fr.com
Resync, corrections: www.sub-way.fr
Last night we got a few phone calls
that he was spotted in the area.
So we're going door-to-door.
Why are you looking for him?
He escaped from prison in Illinois
a couple of days ago.
Have you seen him?
No.
He doesn't look familiar.
Are you sure?
Yeah. I'm sure.
All right. Thanks for your time.
This ain't...
This is not what you think, all right?
Look.
Listen to me, this... Just... listen.
Okay?
All I did was steal a baseball card.
Okay? I'm not like those other fools
up in there.
I'm gonna go for a walk, okay?
- Listen...
- I'm gonna leave my keys right here.
And when I come back,
my car will be gone.
I'm sure,
in a few hours,
they'll find it somewhere...
abandoned.
Wait. Wait.
I wish it could be different.
I have to go.
"Too-le."
I think it's "To-ill-uh."
Hell of a town.
Small is good.
Means the ranch'll be easier to find.
All we got to do is get that money
and we'll be out of here by nightfall.
Right.
FBI FIELD OFFICE
Oh, sir. Soil test came back
from Scofield's crash.
Not that you need
any more proof, but...
he really went out of his way
this time.
What else do you have?
A man was violently assaulted
in Nebraska
by a hitchhiker matching
Bagwell's description.
He was headed west on the I-80.
Omaha's putting together photo lineup.
What do you have on Scofield?
What does anybody have on Scofield?
I've got some results
from his hard drive.
The one recovered from the river.
We were able to use the sector editor
to restore the master boot.
- So from that...
- I don't care how you did it.
What do you have?
More than half the contents
of the buffer.
About 60%.
It looks pretty random.
Print it up. All of it.
I want it on my desk.
Well, guess what?
No listing for a Double K Ranch.
Excuse me.
You know where I might find
a Double K Ranch?
What you call it?
Double K Ranch.
No.
You from around here?
Yeah. Born and raised.
There's no Double-nothing.
Great. Thank you.
Looks like Westmoreland
spent his last breath
blowing smoke up your ass.
There's one way to find out.
The county keeps property records.
Every plot is mapped out
with dimensions. It's public record.
But if there is
a tax assessor's office here,
it's gonna be in there,
the Municipal Building.
Lot of cops in there, Michael.
Dispatch.
Someone...someone
stole my car this morning.
I'm at the Lotus Motel
off Interstate 80.
Did you see who took it?
No. I went out for a walk
and when I came back, it was gone.
This morning?
Why didn't you call before?
I... I don't know.
Mr. Kellerman.
Mr. Kim.
Surprised to see
you in Chicago.
Just looking for updates.
Sara Tancredi. I'm on it.
Is pursuing her
the best use of your time?
It is.
She's in contact
with Scofield.
I was there when
he called yesterday.
We stay with her,
she takes us right to him,
he takes us to Burrows.
All right.
If you're that confident.
I am.
I'll let the President know.
I contact the President directly.
I'll contact her.
Keep me posted.
If you want to restore your dignity,
you need to take action.
Making amends requires much more
than saying "I'm sorry."
It means learning to change.
The apology is just the first step.
The most important thing
is that you display honesty,
courage
and compassion
when you extend
your apologies.
You need to earn
your forgiveness.
We'll talk about it more on Friday.
I've got a great idea.
What's that?
Since you are such a fan
of lame, store-bought
blueberry pie,
I am going to bake you
a real pie of your choice
tonight.
I can't.
I really don't need to be seeing
anyone right now
who isn't my therapist.
I've been a hermit lately, too.
My partner Daniel's
away on business.
I've been sitting around
every night by myself.
Kind of pathetic.
I am so sorry.
I thought you meant...
I thought...
The... The pie...
No.
- That's my ego.
- No, I was really talking about...
- Pie?
- Yeah.
Actual blueberries.
Like we'd make pie and watch
- Fried Green Tomatoes.
- I get it,
I get it.
I'm the best ex-junkie cook
in this town.
Thank you. I just... I gotta
clean my apartment.
It's disgusting, and I realize
that sounds like an excuse,
- it's not.
- No, no, no, I get it.
You do what you gotta do.
Have a good night.
Do you deliver?
Next batch.
Just...
put it on the desk.
- Does any of this stuff mean anything?
- I don't know. Ask me later.
You think he's a genius or a whack-job?
I think we answered that question
when we assigned
100 agents to the case.
So why don't you go and get
me the rest of it?
Does that work for you?
Lucky day!
I just found me
an in-betweener.
Where you going
in such a hurry?
None of your beeswax, yo.
I know where.
Same place as every other man
who was in that room that night.
They all coming around here
for a big family reunion
at the Ku Klux Ranch.
If they ain't here already.
Ain't no country folk in this town
ever heard of the Double K Ranch.
Seems like you've been misinformed.
Indeed there is a Double K.
It's just a matter of who
gets there 1st, all right?
The stars are gonna collide
in Tooele, my friend.
You'll need me on your side.
This ain't Fox River, all right?
I don't need any...
As you can see...
I need you.
Get your grubby paws
off me, you freak.
- I ain't your ditch digger.
- I don't need...
I don't need nothing from you!
I don't need nothing!
You might...
...if a man knew where
he was supposed to be looking.
Are you having
the Hector Avila
and Maricruz Delgado wedding today?
Avila.
No? Okay, thanks.
Hi. Are you having the
Hector Avila
and Maricruz Delgado
wedding today?
Avila.
Delgado.
Really?
When?
Stay calm. We'll be out in ten minutes.
One at a time.
Clear.
Back up.
Are you wearing a watch?
Yeah.
Nice day.
Thanks.
This is exactly
what we need.
It's a map
of every parcel of land.
Topography, buildings...
everything.
Karl Kokosing. Double K.
I don't like the way
this guy is looking at us.
1213.
Where's 1213?
Ms. Sebern, I need to speak with you.
Come on, man, we got to roll now.
Ms. Sebern?
Come on. You got the map?
No.
Someone else does.
Someone got here before us.
That's the only explanation.
Son of a bitch
is still alive.
Hey, pretty!
What are you going to do, scream?
How the hell...
you are still breathing?
What the hell did you do
to your hand?
Easy, easy...
I recently had some work done.
Where's the map?!
Easy... I don't have it.
- Well, where is it?
- I'm telling you,
I don't have it.
- Don't have it, huh?
- You were there. We saw you.
It was gone
when I got there.
Now why don't you keep
your pooch away from me.
I'll tell you everything I know.
It's the kid. He has it.
I saw him this morning
and I needed some help.
We made a deal, all right?
He said that he would dig.
I told him where we could get a map.
What kid?
The best thing
to do is nothing.
That's how I'm gonna get
the U. S. Senate
to confirm my Vice-Presidency,
do nothing?
Shows them you can do the job.
It's my daughter.
Sir, we need to talk
about your daughter.
What about her?
Well, the media is all over this
Fox River situation.
We think it would be best
if you could distance yourself
from her...
If I hear this one more time...
I paid her bail,
I walked away.
I have distanced myself.
Give me a minute.
Hey, Dad, it's me.
When you get a chance, I really need
to talk to you about some things.
Actually a lot of things.
The most important one is that...
I owe you an apology. I...
I realize that I've made
things difficult for you lately...
...and I want
to take responsibility for that.
Call me back. Bye.
Hi. I know I'm early,
but I brought dinner.
Come on in.
- You're not a vegetarian, are you?
- No.
Just shut that behind you.
- You mind if I check my e-mail?
- No, not at all. Here.
- You're so kind. Thank you.
- Absolutely.
Do you happen to have a pen
handy?
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
I'm so sorry to bother you.
No. Look, I have a
little pencil and a pad.
Thank you.
Sir?
Yeah?
There's no Sherry in Cheyenne.
Your ticket is not valid
for travel.
Oh, well, hold on now.
That can't be right.
- Excuse me for a second.
- Sure.
All right now, listen, brother.
I'm gonna give it to you straight.
Listen, I'm broke, okay?
That's the truth.
And I just ran into some trouble
a while back and...
I'm just really trying
to pull it all together now.
You understand?
You can tell it all to the authorities
in about five minutes.
Oh, come on, brother.
We don't have to get the authorities...
It's too late.
They're already waiting
at the next stop.
These guys here,
they're gonna sit with you
until we stop.
I understand. I understand.
Hey, you can't go in there!
Okay, we've got a confirmed
sighting on Franklin.
Jumped out of a moving train
in Preston, Idaho.
What is a black man
from Chicago doing in Idaho?
He's gotta be lost.
Franklin's in Preston, Idaho,
Bagwell's in Nebraska,
and both men have never been
across the Mississippi.
Visiting friends and family?
I don't think so.
And not...
south of the border.
They're due west and we need to know...
why.
Out.
- What's going on, friends?
- Where was Tweener headed?
Up on the main drag.
He was supposed to find a shovel.
- In.
- No.
- No, no, no.
- In!
You're coming back, right?
You're coming back?!
Yep.
Hey, you guys!
Come on, man,
I'm gonna help you here!
I was on my ATV, and I was hauling ass.
I was right on her tail,
and I pulled out my gun
and blam! That bitch treed herself,
and I brought her down in one shot.
- What'd she weigh?
- Least a hunny.
Maybe one-ten.
Come on out and see us if you want.
- It's gonna be a good time.
- Yeah, I just might do that.
Hey, now, what you digging?
Some stuff in my grandpa's yard.
We got a bigger one in the back
if you're going deep.
No,
this will do.
Damn it if I don't know you
from somewhere.
Maybe I know your grandpa.
I doubt it, man.
He moved here, like, a month ago, so...
What's his name?
His name's Grandpa.
A'ight? Look, man,
can you just ring this up?
I gotta get out of here.
Sure thing, fella.
I'll ring it up.
I'll ring it right now.
I know where I seen you on the TV.
You're one of them Fox River boys.
You got it wrong, man.
No, I think I got it right.
We're closed!
Sorry, bud.
Closing up early today.
Hold on.
Stay right there.
You're going down, just like
your buddy, you son of a bitch.
Where's the kid?
Where's the kid?!
He's back here.
Get up.
Come on, tough guy.
Let's go.
Maricruz.
Baby, open up.
Theresa!
It's me. It's me, okay?
Fernando, what are you doing here?
You can't be here.
I know, Theresa. I just got...
Where's your sister?
I need to see Maricruz.
She's getting her picture taken
with my mom and dad.
- The wedding's at 2:30.
- I need to see her now.
You have to go.
She's the mother of my kid, Theresa.
Please.
You don't want her to marry Hector,
do you? Do you?
I'll go see if I can go get her.
- Wait in here.
- Okay.
Lance, I got a question for you.
Yes?
You know who I am?
I happened to see the
news last night, yes.
Hey, I don't care. I've got
some skeletons in my closet, too.
One of them wears a dress.
Thank you.
I appreciate your lack of judgment.
From what I can tell,
you didn't do anything wrong,
but it's none of my business.
And you don't need to talk about it.
The whole thing just...
I never meant for it to happen.
Okay, you do not need
to answer this question.
But were you and that guy, like...
You're right,
I don't want to talk about it.
- You done?
- Yeah.
Does it worry you that he's...
out there?
Give me one second.
Dad.
Sara, hi.
I got your message.
Dad, please, come in.
Lance,
this is, my father Frank.
How do you do?
Dad, this is my friend Lance.
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
I voted for you.
Well, thank you. I appreciate that.
Sara, I can take off.
No, no need.
It'll only take a minute.
How about you step into my office
- and you make yourself at home.
- Sure.
So...
So, in my program...
we've been talking a lot
about making amends,
and I've been thinking a lot about...
about some of
the choices I've made lately,
and I know that that affects you.
and...
and I... I wanted to tell you
that I'm sorry.
You don't have to say you're sorry.
Yeah, I do.
And it must be hard to understand
why I did it.
I had no idea that I was
putting these guys
back out on the street.
I thought I was saving the life
of an innocent man and...
And I know that you didn't read
the information
I gave you on Lincoln Burrows,
but he is innocent and...
a lot of the people involved
right now are dead.
I'm sorry.
This isn't why I called you.
I'm fine...
but I'm scared.
Sara...
I'm gonna help you through this.
We're gonna get through this together.
Thank you.
I promise.
Kellerman.
We ran that trace you requested.
What'd you get?
The line is disconnected.
Whose was it?
Apparently, no one's.
What does that mean?
It's been out of service for 17 years.
Fernando.
Where is she?
Calm down. Calm down.
She's gonna come down and talk to you.
She's on her way down right now.
You and I got history.
We're family.
And out of respect for that,
I'm gonna let her make her own decision.
I'm not leaving without her.
That's for Maricruz to decide.
You've been filling her head
with all this crap.
She's a smart girl.
I personally don't think she's gonna
want to live her life on the run,
but we'll see.
You know, she doesn't love you.
I don't want to get into that right now.
You're not raising my kid.
¿Tu me estas entendiendo?
That don't sound good, cuz.
Maricruz!
- Baby! Mari! Where is she?
- You have to go.
- Where is she?
- Please, Fernando, they're coming!
Did you tell her I was here? Did you?!
Maricruz...
Mahone.
I'll be right down.
Mr. Mahone.
Where are they?
Had a hard time getting
my hands on these.
It'd be easier to go to a doctor,
tell him you need something
to calm your nerves.
Doctors take notes.
That's why I have a deal with you.
The way things been going,
I thought maybe our deal was over.
You don't ask me about Shales no more.
That part of our deal is over.
I no longer need an informant
on the case.
Thought that's all you cared about
was finding him.
You can't get them all.
If you want, I can keep an ear
out on the street.
Midazolam.
1,500 milligrams every 30 days.
That's all I want from you.
We understand each other?
You gonna pay me for it?
Right there.
What are you doing here?
We had to come for you, buddy.
How'd you know?
T- Bag.
Hand over the map.
- What?
- The map.
Hand it over.
He told you I had it?
We are going to sort this out
right now.
Tell me that's not what I know it is.
It is.
But don't worry, before I destroyed it
I committed it to
my photographic memory.
Coming from a compulsive liar,
I find that a little hard to believe.
I'da tattooed it to my body
but I didn't have the time.
Whenever you strip search a lifer,
you should always check his coin purse.
Tell us where the money is.
Now let's not dissolve
into threats, all right?
I'm going to take the high road here
and suggest a mutually
beneficial arrangement.
I have the information,
you have the manual requirements
necessary to unearth
Westmoreland's buried booty.
We're partners.
And why is that?
'Cause as of this moment,
I'm your map.
So then, yo, we split it four ways,
right?
Wrong. Get in.
You're not worth 1.5.
- Get in.
- Okay.
Excuse me. Can I help you?
Oh. Yeah.
Sorry, yeah.
It's hot.
I was really wondering
how much you selling your RV for.
Probably out of your price range.
Come on, give me a shot.
$40,000.
Look, I tell you what.
I'll be back in a couple days, okay?
I can't hold it for you.
I said I'll be back.
With cash.
Nice bike.
The wedding's at 2:30, Fernando.
We just got confirmation
on Fernando Sucre.
He was in Las Vegas around 2:00.
Then a gas station attendant
spotted a guy on a bike
matching his description
in Mesquite...
an hour
later.
Out west, just like
Bagwell and Franklin.
Yeah, but he was heading east.
And Bagwell's in Nebraska
on I-80 heading west.
And Franklin's train was heading west,
but he jumped off to the...
sou...
You know D. B. Cooper?
- Yeah, that hijacker.
- Hijacker.
But he was never found.
Yeah, but he's got to be somewhere,
right, because someone hijacked
that plane in Portland and jumped out
over the Pacific Northwest.
And someone was arrested two days later
in Bisbee, Arizona.
- Not the same guy.
- Same guy.
Same guy who was treated
for a broken knee
in a free clinic somewhere
around Salt Lake City.
Same guy whose Nova blew a head gasket
ten miles short of the border.
Same guy who almost got away
with a stolen car,
but he ran a woman down in Bisbee.
Vehicular manslaughter.
Arrested and booked
as Charles Westmoreland.
But he didn't have the money on him.
Which means,
he got rid of it somewhere
along the way.
Wait, wait, this is fact?
You figured all this out?
No. Scofield did.
That's why he was bringing
the old man along.
The money's in Utah.
And they're all going to get it.
You know, in... Thailand
they got a black market
where you can get
any kind of surgery you need,
even a hand transplant.
- You're sick, you know that.
- Keep going.
The turnoff's just up here somewhere.
Before or after Sheep Road?
What's the matter,
Theodore, did you forget?
How could I forget a road called Sheep?
It's after.
Don't you feel all warm inside
now that we're working together?
We aren't working together.
You're just here to lend a hand.
Now, slow down.
That was it, that little bitty road
right back there.
How far is it from here?
Quarter mile if I remember
the scale properly.
Start walking.
Frank?
Yeah, I'm almost ready.
What time did you say the flight was?
8:00.
Listen, I hope you get this nomination
more than anyone, but...
be prepared.
This Burrows thing may steamroll.
Well, we'll wait it out,
just like you said.
Problem is too many headlines.
His lawyer Nick Savrinn's already dead.
His kid's awaiting trial
for double homicide.
and now his lead counsel
is classified as missing.
Well, is she missing or is she dead?
I just thought you should know
before you go to Washington.
Bruce, is there something
connecting all of this?
It's probably best you don't ask
a whole lot of questions.
Where now?
Right up there.
The hill borders the property.
KK's on the other side.
First thing I'm gonna do
with the money?
Buy new shoes.
Second thing: tacos.
Third thing:
ice cold beer.
Fourth thing:
a little toothpaste.
Oh, damn!
Mahone.
Agent Mahone, your car's out front, sir.
The flight to Utah leaves in an hour.
I'll be there.
Thank you.
Ninth thing:
a shower.
Tenth thing: a good night's sleep.
A nice hotel.
Clean sheets.
Look, stakes marking the property line.
Should be dead ahead.
Can you see the silo?
The bastards built over it.
It's gone.
www.tvsubtitles.net