Previously on Prison Break:
I'm breaking out. And you're gonna
make sure my brother goes with me.
I'm sorry, Henry.
This message is for Maricruz. I'll be there
in the airport in lxtapa waiting for you.
Sucre, down the road, if you're in trouble,
post a note on the message board.
-What's it called?
-Europeangoldfinch.net.
That's a bird, right?
Go pack your things. We're moving.
We will be a family if it kills us.
Pull this off and you're halfway home.
You remember what home is like,
don't you?
Stay away from my family.
She needs that medicine.
She can't go two days without it.
-I don't feel good.
-Oh, sweetie.
I want for this to be over.
That makes two of us. A question of
looking at whatever your father gave you.
It's just a key.
It's locked in a box inside that cigar club.
I'm not a wanted fugitive.
Give me the key. I'll do it.
Wanna take a walk?
Ms. Tancredi.
I need to have a word with you.
-Ms. Tancredi.
-Of course.
Ms. Tancredi? Ma'am?
-Ms. Tancredi?
-It's time to go.
Ma'am?
They're going out back.
Come on.
Pediatrics, please.
-Hello?
-Cameron.
-Hi, Dad.
-How you doing, big guy?
-Good. I'm eating my lunch.
-Oh, how is it?
Pretty disgusting.
Maybe your mom can bring you
some dinner from home.
-Did you see the doctor today?
- Yeah.
He said I could go home this week,
as long as I stay out of the street.
You're a smart young man.
You know how to cross the street.
Are you mad at me?
Listen to me.
No one is mad at you,
and this wasn't your fault.
I should've been looking out for you.
You weren't even there.
But I should've been.
Oh, man. Hey, buddy, listen, I gotta go.
But I'll call you back later, okay?
-Okay. Bye.
-Cameron.
I love you.
Cam?
Yeah? What have we got on Franklin?
Nothing new since this morning.
Another witness from the Minnesota
diner robbery gave a positive lD.
Good, because I just landed
in Minneapolis 1 5 minutes ago.
-Anything else?
-Yeah, the girl, Dede.
Apparently, she's been ill.
Some chronic condition.
Fax Franklin's mug shot to every hospital
in southeastern Minnesota.
Already done. With any luck, she'll get sick
enough to need one and he'll show his face.
-You don't have kids, do you, Lang?
-Nope.
Call me when you have something else.
I'll take that.
-We didn't get it.
-What?
And we need to get back in there soon.
Once the Company finds out Sara
was in there...
...it won't belong before
they start wondering why.
Find a spot close to the club and sit tight.
We're gonna take the car.
-Be back in a couple of hours.
-Where you going?
Turns out that maybe there's one member
of that club who can help us.
Who?
Pope?
Just a minute.
Henry.
What are you doing here?
Aside from jumping bail
and evading the authorities?
There's something that you need to hear.
But first, I need to know if you'll listen.
Sara, we've got nothing to discuss.
Please, I need five minutes.
After that, if you want us to, we'll leave.
Who's us?
-I don't want any trouble.
-Good. Because that's not why we're here.
What the hell are you thinking about,
waltzing in here? You're a wanted criminal.
In case you've forgotten,
I dedicated my career...
...my entire life, to keeping people
like you behind bars.
You're talking about guilty people.
My brother is innocent.
-We have the evidence to prove it.
-I don't care. I want you out.
It's in a locked box at the Corona
de Oro Club and you're a member.
-Out.
-Henry, please listen.
Sara, I'm tempted to say
you should've known better.
But after what you did--
My father was looking into
the Burrows case when he was murdered.
This key is the only thing
I could recover from his body.
Where are we going?
They're hungry.
We've been driving all day.
Chick-O-Stick.
They need real food.
Soon enough, pumpkin.
Alackaday.
Miscreants. Defilers.
Defacers.
Despoilers.
What is this?
My home.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, really, no.
Okay. All right, sweetie,
why don't you sit over here, okay?
All right. I'm gonna go over there
and I'm gonna talk to the lady, all right?
So you need anything? You sure?
Okay.
-Yes?
-My daughter, Dede, she's really sick.
She's had this kidney thing
since she was real young.
-It's on the left--
-Where is she?
She's sitting right there.
-Have you been here before?
-No. We're from out of town.
Can I see your insurance card?
No. No, I don't have any insurance.
After I left the Army,
they discontinued my insurance.
Are you a resident of Hennepin County?
Like I said, we're from out of town.
Do you have a driver's license?
Look, I don't have a driver's license,
an insurance card or anything like that.
But I do know the law.
You have to see my little girl.
-I'm gonna go get my supervisor.
-Good.
I don't give a rat's ass about you
or your brother.
I trusted you. I took you under my wing.
I treated you like my own son.
I believed you.
Day after day, you lied to me.
What kind of a man does that?
-A desperate one.
-Yeah.
Well, you two made
a big mistake coming here today.
You gave me no choice.
I'm gonna notify the authorities right now.
I'm sorry...
...but I can't let you do that.
I don't wanna hurt you, Henry.
-Said by the man with the gun.
-lf it's the way I can convince you, so be it.
Well, you're not gonna convince me
by doing that.
-I'm not the man you think I am.
-I have a pretty good idea who you are.
If that's true, then you already know
I never wanted to be in Fox River.
I never wanted to meet you, Henry.
I certainly didn't wanna ruin your life.
Yeah? You've done
a pretty damn good job.
You're not saying anything to him
I haven't said myself, Henry.
I've looked into this.
What he's saying to you is true.
I just want my brother's life back.
I want people to know the truth.
I'd give anything for that.
I'd lay down my life.
That's easy for you to say,
standing on that side of the gun.
What if I'm standing on this side?
There are places
that can better serve your needs.
-Look, I know my rights, okay?
-This isn't a primary care facility.
We provide necessary care
in life-threatening situations.
I know. Are you gonna wait until
she's dead before you give her help?
-ls that what you're telling me?
-I'll not argue with you.
This is a hospital,
not a homeless shelter.
A what?
What did you just say to me?
I can't believe you people.
Come on.
The line is a little bit too long, okay?
We'll go somewhere else.
Where are we going?
We gotta find another doctor, sweetie.
My God.
Let's go.
Move!
Hold on, baby.
Franklin!
Thank you for riding
the Minneapolis Auto Train.
-Move out of the way!
-Please disembark quickly.
FBl! Stop! Stop!
Okay, okay. Okay, okay.
All right. Look.
-Baby, you gotta get down.
-No.
-No, no, you gotta get down.
-You gotta let him go.
-Get down.
-Come on.
-No.
The doors will be closing momentarily.
-She's not letting go.
-Don't let her pay for your mistakes.
You hear me?
I could shoot you right now
and not even think twice.
But you won't.
You've spent too much time around prisons
to throw your life away like that.
-What the hell are you trying to pull?
-It's simple.
That's the key to an innocent man's
freedom. Come on, Henry.
We both know there's something
going on here.
Too many people have died.
Look me in the eye.
Tell me you don't believe
there's a cover-up going on right now.
I've got no moral obligations here,
Michael.
As far as I know,
Lincoln is as guilty as hell.
Then take a 1 0-minute drive with me
and we'll find out. That's all I ask.
Henry, you've looked into this before.
You've thought about it.
I have.
And I've come to one conclusion.
This has nothing to do with me.
But I am a man of the law...
...and right now, I've got a convicted felon
standing inside my house.
Well, maybe there's something I can
offer you to make you change your mind.
What do you intend to do with us?
Dumb grease monkey.
You don't deserve minimum wage.
The hell I don't. Working graveyard?
There ain't no man
who deserves more pennies...
...on the dollar per hour
than they got lQ points in his head.
I ain't stupid.
Seems equal stupid as the rest of you.
Seems to run in the genes.
Teddy.
Ten synonyms. Pick a word.
Pick a word.
Destroy.
Ten synonyms for destroy.
Annul.
Mutilate.
Liquidate. Abrogate.
Quell. Ravage. Expunge.
Demolish. Extirpate. Extinguish.
-You see that?
-Stupid, my pail.
My boy's gonna be president.
How come you ain't studying?
Because I'm tired.
Because I feel like a circus freak.
Well, now...
...it's in your own best interest.
Don't you understand that?
Now, you gonna be president someday.
You mark my words.
Theodore.
Theodore, do you hear me?
What are you gonna do with us?
We're gonna put down some roots.
You wanted me dead, Paul.
Just following orders.
You sent me to the chair
for something I didn't do.
All for your president.
You were willing to do that.
-Just following orders.
-Steadman said you loved her.
Steadman was a deranged man
that lived in a locked box.
You don't love someone
that loves power more than life.
-Bitter, huh?
-Am l?
No offense, but you're not capable
of understanding the relationship.
Okay, any way you look at it,
there is no light at the end of this tunnel.
One way or another, you and l, we die.
Your brother too.
Which is a shame,
given all he's done for you.
I have a sister I haven't talked to
in 1 5 years.
-You think she's better off for it?
-We'll make it.
-What is that, faith?
-Yeah, that's faith.
All I see is a black hole.
And sooner or later,
they're gonna suck each one of us into it.
But when they come for me, I'm gonna
take as many of them with me as I can.
She must have really
broken your heart, Paul.
President Reynolds attended
a Chicago fundraiser last night...
...as part of her two-day stop
in the Windy City.
Reynolds ' popularity continues
to soar in the Midwest...
...with appearances scheduled
in Indianapolis, Detroit...
...and Flint, Michigan later in the week.
A t a Democratic fundraiser
in Milwaukee....
Mr. Kim,
Sara Tancredi surfaced in Chicago.
She was spotted at the Corona de Oro Club
about an hour ago.
-Corona de Oro Club?
-It's a cigar club. Her father was a member.
He kept a private humidor there.
Get me a jet to Chicago.
Tell me you're not still thinking
he's gonna show.
He's let you down so many times.
You know that.
Maybe it's the baby in me that's telling me
that this time, it's gonna be different.
I don't mean to burst your bubble,
but he's not gonna show.
Bubble's not burst!
-I got three words for you.
-Yeah?
We gotta run.
We'll see you, Theresa.
-I'm so glad you came.
-You're crazy.
How did they know?
You're certain?
-About what's in the box?
-No. But it's all we've got.
Thank you, Henry.
You sure about this?
Nope.
Either way, you still owe me dinner.
Is that so?
Yep.
First week in Fox River, you promised me
if you got out, you'd take me to dinner.
Well, maybe after we wrap this up,
we can stop off...
...and get you a burrito
on the way back to Pope's house.
I don't know what you're used to...
...but anything short of a filet mignon
is not gonna cut it with me.
It's a date.
Give me the phone.
-Hey.
-How'd you pull it off?
-I'll tell you later. Is he in yet?
-Yep.
This shouldn 't take more
than a couple minutes.
Any longer than that,
we'll know we've got trouble.
Good afternoon, Mr. Pope.
Right this way.
Thank you.
-Mr. Pope.
-Hey, Warren. How's it going?
You hear what happened this morning?
Sara Tancredi came in.
Yeah, so I heard.
Well, next time,
don't let her get away.
Thanks.
Excuse me. You mind if I borrow
your computer for a moment?
-No problem.
-Thanks.
Pitch in, chitlins.
We can't do this. We can't live here.
Of course, not like this.
We gonna clean. We are cleaning.
We gonna rebuild.
You can't do this to them. Look at them.
You all mind coming along here
for a minute?
Come on. I think we're past me waving
that gun around, don't you think?
In here. Now, come on.
-What are you doing?
-Nothing is gonna happen to them, Susan.
Suzy Q.,
do you think I'd bring you here...
...to so sacred a place to me as this,
if I meant you ill?
Look at me!
I am not the animal
you think you see before you.
I am the laws of karma
all come down wrong.
-Don't you understand?
-I don't.
What I'm trying to say...
...is that I am the sin of my father.
-Why are you telling me this?
-Because I love you.
Because I want you to understand me.
I am the last in the line of Bagwells.
The tail end of a corrupted breed.
The earth, thank God,
shall see no more of our generations.
I cannot procreate, Susan.
And yet there's something in that
that gives me great hope.
No more Bagwells shall roam this planet.
Not with that vile blood in their veins.
All I wanna do is end that bloodline,
extirpate it...
...and start another afresh.
-A new family.
-Oh, Teddy.
Those children are my salvation.
My chance to make this world
a better place.
I will be good, Susan.
I will love them. I will love you.
I will take communion,
be baptized under a truer light.
All I ask is that you love me back,
just a little.
Or learn to do so in time.
Can you do that, Susan?
I can't.
I'm sorry.
Please. Please.
Teddy, please. Oh, God.
Teddy.
Teddy, please.
Teddy, I'm sorry.
I can do it, I can do it....
-Where are we?
-At the doctor's office, sweetie.
Hello? Hello.
I have an emergency in here.
Hello?
Hello.
-Hey, you the doctor?
-You need to wait your turn.
No, it is my turn.
This is an emergency right here.
I need you to look at my daughter, okay?
Now, she's not feeling too good.
Please.
Here, sweetie. Hold on.
I'm sorry.
Hey, look,
this is all the money I got, okay?
That's $400.
Please look at my daughter.
-What's the matter with her?
-She has a kidney disease. PKD.
Normally, we have it under control,
but I don't like what I'm seeing now.
She's having stomach hurts, okay,
she's always hot.
-How's her appetite?
-It's gone.
-She's always tired. Ain't that right, baby?
-All right.
Hop up here.
Thank you.
Okay, he just wants to take
a good look at you, okay?
-I may need to run a few tests.
-Hey, just do what you have to do, man.
I'm gonna be right here, okay, baby?
Okay.
-Yeah?
-What's going on now?
He's still in there.
This is taking too long.
Wait, wait, wait. Here he comes.
-What's happening?
-We got company.
Hello, Henry.
-Didn't know you were a cigar man.
-Who are you?
A friend. A colleague, in fact.
We're both in law enforcement.
I'm not anymore.
That's right. You're retired.
-You know that guy?
-Yeah.
Looks like the lifestyle's treating you well.
Socializing over Cubans and cognac.
But that's not what you were doing,
is it?
Henry?
You don't mind if I ask you
to empty your pockets?
-As a matter of fact, I do.
-I'm not gonna play any games, Henry.
We both know why you came here today.
I suggest you get out of my way,
young man.
I can't do that.
Unless you'd like to cause serious trouble
for yourself and your family...
...I advise you to hand over
whatever it is you found.
Now.
Michael--
Get in!
Let's go! Linc!
Sara!
It's okay, it's okay. Easy, easy.
It's okay, it's okay.
Ma'am, you all right?
I don't understand.
We got a call. Someone said
there was a hostage situation here.
No one knew we were here.
Are you okay? Okay.
So, what's going on?
I'm afraid your daughter
shows signs of renal failure.
Has she ever had hemodialysis?
No. Hemo--? No, no.
This has never really gone that far.
What, are you planning
on doing it right here?
We're not set up for it. Neither is she.
But there is a county dialysis clinic
a few blocks away.
But we're going to have to place a catheter
in her neck, so she can be examined.
Hold still, sweetie. This'll be a little cold.
It's okay, baby.
Wait, wait, wait. What is that?
It's a trocar.
It's used for placing the catheter.
Lie down, honey.
-Do we really have to go this far?
-Look....
I'm doing the best I can here.
But you gotta understand something.
Your daughter is sick.
Now, this may look like
a desperate measure because it is.
This is gonna hurt a little bit, sweetie.
Stop! Stop.
Come on, baby.
Come on, baby. I can't do this.
What's going on?
I made a deal with Pope.
You made a deal with Pope?
What kind of deal?
If he came with us,
and if we got what we needed...
...I said I'd turn myself in.
What? We don't even know
what this thing is.
It could be nothing, Michael.
You know about this?
Not until it came out of his mouth.
It was the only thing I could think of.
You two can still finish this.
You'll just have to do it without me.
I'm not gonna let you do this, Michael.
There's no coming back from this.
-Now, look.
-What's the holdup?
Your brother's right.
I wouldn't count on the courts
to show you any leniency in this.
That doesn't matter.
I said I'd hold up my end of the deal.
You already did.
I listened to this.
You have something here.
There are gonna be a lot of people
who wish you didn't, but you do.
-Listen, Henry--
-I'd go now, if I were you.
And don't consider this forgiveness.
In fact, I'm about 1 0 seconds away
from changing my mind.
Thank you.
Okay.
Here, let's....
Let's tuck you in, all right? Okay?
Come on, let's go.
Listen, let's just sit
for a little bit longer, okay?
We're gonna go in a little bit, okay?
You know Daddy loves you
with all his heart, right?
I love you so much.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, baby.
-Yeah?
-I got a call for you.
I'll call back.
I just heard from some clinic up north.
They had contact with Franklin
half an hour ago.
I think you want to take this.
Put it through.
Yeah? Mahone.
-ls this the man in charge?
-Oh, yeah.
My name is Benjamin Miles Franklin.
And I wanna turn myself in.
But I got one condition.
My wife, well, she goes free.
My little daughter, she needs her mother.
I don't think I need to make
a deal with you, Mr. Franklin.
What if I got something you need?
Your wife was released an hour ago.
She'll be here soon.
Promise me that she will be okay.
Just hold up your end of the deal.
I will.
I'll get you Scofield.
Here we go.
You think it's a conversation?
One they don't want us to hear.
-You ready?
-Let's do it.
[ENGLlSH]
www.tvsubtitles.net