Previously on Prison Break:
Welcome home, boss.
-Where's Mommy?
-Mommy's gonna meet us later, okay?
-I'm not a murderer.
-Terrence Steadman.
-The president's brother.
-I didn't do it.
-Mr. Steadman, it's contraband.
-I brought it to protect myself.
That's what we're here for.
Can I write a check?
Because I don't have--
Hello, Mrs. Hollander.
Teddy's home.
It's Pam. What's going on?
I love you.
Give Cam a kiss for me, okay?
You call this number again,
you're a dead man.
You want my help.
I want my job back.
-What's your plan?
-When brothers get in the van.
It's the last thing they'll do.
Paul Kellerman is ready to move on
the caravan outside of Albuquerque.
When it goes down,
there's to be lots of bullets flying.
I need you there to make sure
Paul Kellerman catches one.
President Reynolds ruined your life...
...she ruined my life.
You wanna take the bitch down...
...you found your inside man.
But it's gotta be right now.
Let's go.
I know the way out.
I want a team flanking the west.
Give me another team
down by the river.
Man down. Give me a Medivac, ASAP.
Officer Tuggle.
Officer Tuggle?
I'm looking for Alexander Mahone.
I'm his direct supervisor.
I'm sorry to tell you this, sir,
but your boy's been shot.
Who are you?
I used to work for the president.
Why are you helping us?
Lay down on the floor. Now.
Federal agent. Let me through.
Air support is telling us that they saw
your vehicle traveling down Route 46.
Forty-six is a possible exit route
for the convicts. I was securing it.
No offense, sir,
but we're searching every vehicle.
No offense. Either you let me through
or you get me a supervisor.
I'm supervising this roadblock,
Agent Kellerman.
I'm sorry, but I need you
to get out of the vehicle.
Sergeant Humphries.
Burrows and Scofield
have been loose for less than1 0 minutes.
That means every second is critical.
So if you detain me...
...for one moment more,
I will have all of your jobs.
Do you understand me?
-Go ahead.
-What?
Just let him go.
You still haven't answered my question.
Why am I helping you?
Because the enemy
of my enemy is my friend.
You said something about taking down
the president. I assume you have a plan.
I do.
I used to have a Great Dane.
We had to put her down.
It was very peaceful.
One minute she was breathing,
the next she wasn't.
Turn around.
Get up.
Give me one reason why
I shouldn't blow your brains out.
Because I can give you the one
thing that's gonna set you free.
I know where Terrence Steadman is.
How do you know
where Steadman is?
Because I arranged this whole thing.
-You arranged to set me up?
-Right.
You arranged the killing
of all the people I know.
I was given orders.
I executed those orders.
And now I have a bull's-eye on my chest,
just like you two.
-I don't trust him.
-Hey.
If I wanted you dead, you'd be dead.
You guys want to keep running, fine.
You wanna be free, get in the car.
Last time I'm gonna offer.
What's up, fish?
Looks like you're having
a tough time of it.
-I'm all right.
-Well, I'm just curious.
Why don't you hang out with the rest
of the ex-guards who are locked up here?
Oh, yeah.
There ain't any.
It's just you.
Hey, hold. Hold up, hold up.
Now, I got what's called a mutual
beneficial arrangement in my mind.
I'll look out after you.
Make sure nobody get up in your mix.
And all you got to do is bring me
your dessert after the next meal.
It's real simple.
I'm just looking to do my time.
I don't want any trouble.
Yeah. It's what you want,
and it's what I want.
Your dessert after the next chow.
You bring it to me. You got it?
No. Wrong guy.
Hey.
Break it up, convicts.
We're good, boss.
We're good.
You bring me my treat...
...or this goes to the next level.
Do you understand?
He asked you a question, boy.
Yeah.
-I ain't hear him. You?
-I ain't hear him.
Yeah. Okay.
See how easy that was?
We're gonna be good friends now.
There's no reason for you to be scared,
Suzie Q...
...because you see, I've forgiven you.
And you, in turn can forgive me
for my indiscretions...
...which is far in the past they're nothing
but specks in our respective rear views.
It's been such a long time.
You look lovely.
Okay, let's go. Right now.
We can go away.
Spend some time together.
Susan, I'm not a Victrola,
so please don't play me like one.
There's not a white man's chance
in Harlem...
...you'd ever leave your children behind.
I'm sorry.
Don't fret, now.
When you came to Fox River...
...and you spat at me
like I was some kind of...
...rabid animal.
I was happy...
...because such a visceral reaction could
only come from a woman who still cares.
The children don't know.
I didn't wanna scare them...
...so I never told them about you
so please don't--
That is so perfect.
Because you see what we got
here now?
We got ourselves a clean slate.
Right?
So, this is the conspiracy, huh?
A bunch of little boys in suits
running around trying to kill each other?
It's pathetic.
Well, you were a little more
formidable than we anticipated.
We don't need compliments
out of you, jackass.
Oh, yes, there it is.
-The winning Burrows personality.
-Shut your mouth and drive.
The one we really knew would win
over a jury. Good work.
Mr. Kim.
What the hell is going on out there?
It was touch and go for a minute...
...but I got everything handled.
Mahone's been shot.
Yes, I know, Bill, I was there.
I saw Burrows pull the trigger.
-We lost a valuable asset, but--
-Mahone's alive.
That's good. It looked bad, so.
Where are Burrows and Scofield?
Burrows and Scofield are dead.
And they're in my SUV.
I'm heading out to bury them. Right now.
Don't bury them.
I need visual confirmation.
I'll get you a photo.
I'll say it one more time.
-Don't bury them.
-You know what would be nice to hear?
A thank you.
I'll report back
when they're in the ground.
You leave that on, they'll trace it.
Yeah. Secret Service.
It's untraceable, but thanks.
Hey, baby girl.
What?
What's the matter?
-Where's Mommy?
-Oh, come on.
Now, I told you that Mommy
was helping a friend.
All right? Now, we're gonna see
her real soon.
When?
Baby, we are gonna be
with your mommy real soon.
I promise you that.
Okay?
I don't believe you.
Dede.
Yo, Trey. It's me, man.
-What's up?
-Yo, what's going on with Kacee?
I'm at the courthouse.
She's getting arraigned soon.
Okay. Well, you talk to her?
Is she all right?
She's in jail, so, no, she's not all right.
What the hell happened?
-You think I wanted it this way?
-Whatever.
Gotta go.
My lawyer's gonna be here any minute.
No, no. Listen, listen.
Now, look, I want you to tell Kacee
to put it all on me, all right?
And she didn't know what to do.
She was scared. Okay? All that.
Yeah, I already told her to do that.
I'll do the talking.
-Owen Kravecki?
-That's me. Hey.
Hey. Ben and Phil.
Let's go, before our wives
figure out this is a fishing trip.
-Where's your gear?
-I keep it up north. Okay?
How long is the flight?
An hour, 40.
We don't have a choice.
Glad you're awake.
Collarbone and rotator cuff.
Six inches to the right, and you're dead.
Yeah, he just woke up.
Mr. Mahone.
Bill Kim. You're a lucky man.
-Am l?
-Kellerman finished the job you couldn 't.
But he, unfortunately, is still out there...
...and he's a loose end.
Finish what you were supposed to
take care of.
Something funny?
Kellerman's more of a loose end
than you realize.
He shot me.
The guy you wanted to double-cross
screwed you first.
Scofield and Burrows?
Are probably alive...
...and on the run with Kellerman.
Have a good day, Kimmy.
We neutered Kellerman.
He doesn't even officially exist
anymore.
He knows everything.
Reports have been coming in
from New Mexico officials...
... that escaped convicts
Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows...
...have somehow managed
to extricate themselves...
...from a transport van that was bringing
them back to the Chicago area.
According to this early information,
the convicts were....
You're great.
T op-notch. I swear to God.
Don ' t get yourself worked up,
Mr. Steadman.
I was supposed to have my life
back by now.
Playing golf...
...going to movies...
...seeing people. But because
you guys can't get a handle...
...on an engineer and a petty crook...
...I've been a ship in a bottle
for over three years.
You're perfectly safe here.
I wish.
I just spoke to Kim.
He wants you to finish the job.
Yeah?
That's not gonna happen.
This isn't a request.
And this isn't a negotiation.
Kim and Kellerman
can try to kill each other all day long.
But I'm out.
You must've forgotten how discreet
we've been with what we know.
Go tell about Shales.
In fact, I will.
I killed a predator, a man who
tortured and raped women...
...and I buried him in my back yard.
I'll do the time.
I don't care anymore. I'm out.
Is that clear enough for you?
My man.
That's delicious.
Whoa, hold up there. Hold, hold up.
We got a problem.
That's one brownie.
There's five of my boys.
You see the position you put me in?
They gotta stand with their stomachs
growling while I savor this delicious treat.
That makes me look like a real ass.
Are you trying to make me
look like an ass?
You said the deal was I was supposed
to bring you one dessert.
Yeah. Well.
I'm a fickle bitch.
Now, it's five desserts...
...every meal.
Now, if you can't come up with that...
...there are other ways
to making me happy.
Well, I got some other candy on me,
if you want some of that.
Well, break it out, bitch.
It's all good. You all want some candy?
Guard's coming.
If memory serves, I was at
Storytime Village that day too.
And I'm not in any of these pictures?
Could've sworn I was.
I'm just teasing, baby.
Every woman has burned
the photographs of her paramour...
...only to later realize her love burns
even hotter than the flames she used.
Please.
Teddy.
Uncle Teddy.
How's my girl been?
Good.
You still getting more A's
than an aardvark?
-Yeah. I missed you.
-Oh, same here, shortcake.
Yes, I painted my hair.
Look at you, Zack.
You are a boy no more.
I'm gonna have to lend you
my razor soon enough.
What are you doing here?
Mom said you got a job on an oil rig.
That's right. Right out in the
middle of the ocean.
But those metallic beasts
are dangerous.
Got myself injured.
Don't be, don't be frightened now, sugar.
The good lawyers at Dewey,
Cheatem and Howe...
...got me a million bones
for every digit I lost.
Five million dollars?
Which means with all that cash...
...I can do anything I want now.
And all I want to do...
...is spend all my money
and all my time...
...with you.
What's the neighborhood like?
No neighborhood.
The house sits on 50 acres.
We coming out the way we go in?
No. There's a back road we'll take.
-How many guards?
-Usually none.
At this point, I really couldn't tell you.
The second I feel this thing going bad...
...you get a bullet in the head.
I'd expect nothing less.
I will inform you every half-hour.
Understood.
Private jet was chartered
by Owen Kravecki this morning.
-Headed where?
-Montana.
Stop it from taking off.
It's already on the ground, sir.
Call Steadman.
If that's my sister,
I would like to speak to her.
Yes?
Right away, sir.
Evac.
Mr. Steadman, do you have a jacket?
We need to leave.
Leave? What? No.
Agents'll be arriving shortly
to take you to a safe house.
What do I need to be kept safe from?
Do you have a jacket, sir?
I don't wanna leave.
I wanna talk to my sister.
I've been authorized to use force
if necessary.
Now, is there anything you'd like
to bring?
My meds.
Go with him. Car's here in five minutes.
Well, I don't know, Stella.
She won't come out.
Who wants to be up in the trailer
all day, huh? Would you?
Exactly. Me, neither.
You feel like making a pie
or something?
A little cherry, or lemon meringue, or--
Daddy.
Is Mommy in trouble, like you?
Sweetheart, come here.
Come here.
Now, you listen to me, okay?
Mommy did nothing wrong.
She's helping out a friend.
Okay?
Okay, let me go see how Mommy's doing,
all right?
-I wanna talk to her.
-No, no, no.
You sit here, like a good little girl, okay?
Don't give me that.
-Hello.
-Things are looking up.
That's what I wanted to hear.
Kick it down to me.
Her lawyer knows what he's doing.
He thinks he can get the bail reduced.
Good. All right, well, listen.
When Kacee gets out...
...I want you to deliver
this message for me, okay?
Tell her...
...that we can all get lost.
You want her to jump bail now?
Be glad you ain't in front of my face,
I'd have my hands around your neck.
Punk, just deliver the message.
Okay. Then what you all gonna do?
Go live in a cave?
-I got a plan, all right?
-Let's hear it.
This guy back in my unit...
...when I was in lraq.
He used to go to Alaska,
work at these fish hatcheries, man.
They pay you cash.
-And nobody asks questions.
-Alaska?
Yeah, Alaska, man.
They don 't bother you up there, man.
You know, me, Kacee and Dede,
we could be a family again. You feel me?
Man, you don't quit.
You're damned straight I don't quit.
Do I get to know where I'm going?
You'll get all the information
you need upon arrival.
-Yes?
-Move Steadman to Location Beta.
We're sending a car.
It's already here, sir.
Couldn't be.
The car just left.
Weapons down.
Now.
Down.
Put your weapons down.
Don't get stupid.
Put your weapons down on the ground.
Now.
Terrence, step away. Get in the car.
You look pretty good for a dead man.
-Get in the car.
-Wait, wait, wait.
-Who's there?
-It's Kellerman. He's got Steadman.
Do not let him escape.
Kill Steadman. Kill them all, now.
-Paul, please. Don't-- Don't kill me.
-Get in. Get in the car.
Let's go.
Vomiting. It's the worst side effect
of anesthesia.
That should be the last of it.
-You figure I'm on empty by now?
-Yeah.
Pam.
Alex, Cameron's been hurt.
-What happened?
-lt was a car. Hit and run.
He's in the hospital.
His leg is broken in two places.
I'll be on the next flight to Colorado.
-He's in surgery now.
-I'll be right there. Just hold on.
They won't let me seem him.
They called me.
I got right here
and they won't let me see him.
Pam, please, just keep it together
until I get there. Can you do that for me?
Please. Please hurry.
Mr. Mahone, you cannot get on a plane.
You need to stay at least another day
for observation.
You've been shot.
Mr. Mahone, please.
-I've gotta go see my son.
-Mr. Mahone, I understand.
Please. At least stay and talk to a doctor.
Taxi. Taxi.
How's your boy?
Tib-fib fractures are bad.
But if the growth plate's affected
there's a whole host of problems.
-You made a mistake.
-No, you did.
You think you can just quit
like you work at a post office?
Now, you're needed back in.
Go clean up your mess.
Maybe there won't be another accident
on the streets of Durango, Colorado.
Understand?
Every road shut down. Every car searched.
I don't care if it's a group of nuns.
Their camper gets turned inside out.
-Logistically speaking, every road's gonna--
-It's Montana.
Not Manhattan.
-Get it done.
-Yes, sir.
If we get a camera, we can take
a picture of him holding a newspaper.
If we put that online,
that'll prove he's alive.
It'll prove that we found a guy that looks
kind of like the president's brother.
-Fingerprints. Dental records.
-We whitewashed him.
We pulled his teeth,
burned off his fingerprints.
DNA.
To compare against the homeless guy
we killed and put in Steadman's car.
But we destroyed
all exterior DNA samples...
...so that there'd be nothing
to compare them to.
There's gotta be someone somewhere
who can identify this man.
Which is why we did the surgery.
Cheekbones raised two centimeters,
ears lowered a quarter of an inch.
Not so much that someone
wouldn't recognize him...
...but enough that any forensic comparison
of a photograph of that man...
...would conclude that he is a look-alike.
A hoax. Trust me.
We are very good at what we do.
Please, just let me go.
Terrence, you made every man
in this room a prisoner, including yourself.
-It's time to set us free.
-Nothing you do will work.
-They will not let it--
-Cut the victim act, Terrence.
He's happy to play along
when he was lining his pockets...
...with taxpayer money funneled
through EcoField. And then...
...when the indictment is about to fall...
...who do you come running to for help,
Terrence?
We're gonna stay here for a day or two
until they think we're thousand miles away.
And then we're gonna make our way
to D.C.
Okay?
So that's the plan? We take him to a city
crawling with Company and Feds?
And government agents still in power
working from the inside with your father.
People who can get that pain in the ass
to safely tell his story on the record.
We just stroll right into the lion's den
then, huh? Pray we don't get mauled.
I don't think they're gonna come to
Montana, so we're gonna go to them.
No. Leave her alone.
-What do you want with her?
-What I want is to date her.
What do you want...?
-I'll make you some more popcorn.
-Honey.
If any of us could eat any more corn,
I'd be amazed.
See what I did there, Gracey?
Indian word for corn is "maize,"
and I just said, "amazed."
I don't get it. I'm corn-fused.
You are smarter than a bee sting.
The second female president
of these United States, right here...
...watching TV with us.
Look what I did.
-Honey, that's all right.
-No, I'll get a rag.
No, I can--
I thought we had wiped the slate clean.
Please.
I thought we had put the past
where it belonged.
We did. We did put the past
Do not lie to me, woman.
After turn coating me to the authorities...
...and everything we had. After breaking
my heart into so many pieces...
...that I will never be able to find them all
you can at least do me the favor...
...as to not stand there
and lie to my face.
Mom?
Zack, you get your ass
back on that couch.
Get Gracey. Go.
Give that to me.
I gave you all a chance.
Remember that.
Open up 22.
Opening 22.
Dude, you're crazy.
Is that what the other cons are saying?
-Yeah.
-Good.
But you took it to Banks. I don't think
you wanna be messing with him, man.
I'll mess with anybody tries
to punk me out.
Hey, you know,
I've just been testing you.
Yeah, well, the test results came back...
...and top bunk's mine now.
You got a problem with that?
-Hey, what's up, Stolte?
-You just screwed up, Brad. Big time.
No. I had a message to send
and that message got delivered.
The guy you schlocked, Banks.
He's got connections with the guards
working nights.
Word is, Banks is gonna have you
pulled out of your cell tonight.
-Well, can't you do nothing?
-Yeah.
I can warn you which is what I'm doing.
Can't you talk to some
of the guys working nights?
They're working nights
because you put them on nights.
You should've treated them better.
They ain't gonna do you any favors.
Well, I treated you right, didn't l?
Come on, Stolte.
Can't you do something? Please.
You did treat me right...
...but there is nothing I can do now...
...except warn you...
...watch your back.
We can use the roads that the
rangers use in Glacier National Park.
They don't patrol them at night. Get up into
Canada, head east. Cut through New York.
And the borders won't be a problem.
No, nobody'll look for us there.
-This fun for you, Terrence? Really?
-No, this isn't fun.
What was fun was when Caroline
and I would talk about you...
...and the schoolboy crush
that you had on her.
He proposed to her.
You actually thought that you would be
the first husband? Serf who would be king?
Caroline.
We laughed so hard--
You stood and watched them kill Veronica.
-Burrows.
-And you did nothing.
-She died because of you.
-Linc--
-Shut up.
Burrows, he has no value to us dead.
He has no identity.
-Kill him, he's just a John Doe.
-Put your gun down.
-When he puts his down.
-Linc, we're so close.
Was it worth it?
Killing those people? Ruining my life?
-Get a handle on your brother.
-Shut up. You're not helping.
Linc, you don't want to do this.
Trust me.
This isn't what you want.
You don't want to do this, okay?
Trust me.
So many people dead.
And he gets to live.
Hello? Hello?
They denied bail.
-What?
-The judge didn't buy that it was all you.
Kacee's going into the system now.
Aiding an escaped con.
She's looking at major time, man.
Now, I want you to tell her lawyer, all right,
you listen to me. You tell her lawyer...
I love you.
-...tell her lawyer I'll turn myself in, okay?
-No.
Kacee says you need to run.
If you turn yourself in,
Dede won't have either of you.
And they'll just throw her
into foster care.
Look, I'm gonna hang up
this phone right now...
...because I might say something
I'll regret.
Yo--
You just take care of Dede.
You know, Zack...
...my daddy wasn't really in the picture
much when I was growing up.
As a result, I never really learned
the art of carpentry.
But I figure Jesus was a carpenter,
and his daddy wasn't around to teach him...
...so I taught myself.
Over time, I got to be
a pretty good swinger of the hammer.
Now, the good news is...
...unlike my papa
and the Great Almighty, I am here...
...for good.
Don't make no mistake about it.
We will be a family...
...if it kills us.
It's so sweet.
Car's out front. Let's move out.
These two will never
make it in a car together.
-You keep your brother in check.
-You don't know him.
Then get my gun from him.
We don't have time for this.
You still think you're running
this show, don't you?
You still think I'm not?
Yes, I'd like the number for
Channel 1 1 News, please.
What are you doing?
This is not the plan. Hang up.
Yes, connect me. I'll hold.
Scofield, you call the news,
they call the cops.
Yes, put me through.
Hang up.
Hang up the phone now.
Hang it up.
Channel Eleven News. Can I help you?
This is Michael Scofield.
I'm at the Cutback Motel, room 1 1.
And I want to turn myself in.
Bradlee.
Warden's gone home, bitch.
The mice are gonna play.
Bradlee.
If anything jumps off, you get my back.
I won't forget it.
Why don't you just forget it right now?
Here in this cell,
you're top bunk. Out there...
...you're on your own.
Bradlee.
You want a piece of me, you sons
of bitches? Come and get me.
You hear me?
I ain't scared of you.
I ain't scared of nothing.
Bradlee.
Start praying.
Yes?
Mr. Kim.
I just wanted you to know...
...that I'm getting back to work.
Good.
So I take it you got my message.
Oh, yeah.
Loud and clear.
Please don't do this.
Please, come on, please.
I'm sorry, Terrence, it's too late.
The press is already on their way.
You can put the guns away now.
This goes wrong,
you guys are on your own.
No, if I go back home. Okay?
Let me, please. I'll go home.
You can't go home, Terrence.
None of us can, okay?
So just relax. Keep your head.
Okay, okay, okay.
-Terrence.
-Terrence, Terrence.
I'm leaving.
Terrence.
We can't let you do that, Terrence.
All we need is your mouth.
I will shoot out your knees right now.
I never liked you, Paul.
I won't hesitate to take your life.
All right, just....
Terrence, listen to me.
Just listen.
Terrence, for once in your life,
do the right thing.
All right?
So many people have suffered
because of this, because of you.
But when the press get here...
...you can tell the truth.
You can end this.
What is in it for me? Disgrace?
Life in prison?
You're already in prison, Terrence.
How many people have to die
so you can stay in some cabin...
...in the woods? It's over.
Okay.
-Sorry.
-Terrence, no.
We have to go.
Go where? We've got Steadman.
No, we have nothing.
All we got is a John Doe.
Michael.
Michael, let's go.
[ENGLlSH]
www.tvsubtitles.net